<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2019-03-08T00:01:15+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">oi-VAE: output interpretable VAEs</title>
		<link href="https://pillowlab.wordpress.com/2019/03/07/oi-vae-output-interpretable-vaes/"/>
		<id>http://pillowlab.wordpress.com/?p=3795</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T22:30:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 We recently read oi-VAE: Output Interpretable VAEs for Nonlinear Group Factor Analysis, which was published at ICML in 2018 by Samuel Ainsworth, Nicholas Foti, Adrian Lee, and Emily Fox. This paper proposes a nonlinear group factor analysis model that is an … &lt;a href=&quot;https://pillowlab.wordpress.com/2019/03/07/oi-vae-output-interpretable-vaes/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>dmz8</name>
			<uri>https://pillowlab.wordpress.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Pillow Lab Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Neural Coding and Computation Lab @ Princeton University</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://pillowlab.wordpress.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://pillowlab.wordpress.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Merging magnetic blobs fuel the sun’s huge plasma eruptions</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coronal-mass-ejection-magnetic-sun-plasma-eruption"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coronal-mass-ejection-magnetic-sun-plasma-eruption</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T21:46:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Solar eruptions called coronal mass ejections grow from a series of smaller events, observations show.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Human encroachment threatens chimpanzee culture</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-encroachment-threatens-chimpanzee-culture"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-encroachment-threatens-chimpanzee-culture</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T19:44:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Human activity is affecting chimps’ behavioral repertoire, a new study suggests. Creating chimp cultural heritage sites might save unique behaviors.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sujata Gupta</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How helpful gut microbes send signals that they are friends, not foes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/beneficial-gut-microbes-immune-system-pathogens"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/beneficial-gut-microbes-immune-system-pathogens</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T19:26:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Some beneficial gut bacteria use unique form of communication to let immune cells know that they’re friendly.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeremy Rehm</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Japan puts plans for the world’s next big particle collider on hold</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/japan-international-linear-collider-higgs-factory"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/japan-international-linear-collider-higgs-factory</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T17:32:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The jury is still out on whether Japan will host the world’s first “Higgs factory” — the International Linear Collider.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Nanosponges sop up toxins and help repair tissues</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nanosponges-toxins-blood-cell-membrane-drug-delivery"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nanosponges-toxins-blood-cell-membrane-drug-delivery</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T12:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Nanoparticles coated with blood cell membranes can move through the body to clean up toxins or heal tissues — without instigating an immune reaction.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Esther Landhuis</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Semi-automated fact-checking for scientific papers? Here’s one method.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/07/semi-automated-fact-checking-for-scientific-papers-heres-one-method/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87886</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T11:00:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Wouldn’t it be terrific if manuscripts and published papers could be checked automatically for errors? That was the premise behind an algorithmic approach we wrote about last week, and today we bring you a Q&amp;amp;A with Jennifer Byrne, the last author of a new paper in PLOS ONE that describes another approach, this one designed to … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/07/semi-automated-fact-checking-for-scientific-papers-heres-one-method/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Semi-automated fact-checking for scientific papers? Here’s one method.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s A Simple Trick For Anyone Who Finds Eye Contact Too Intense</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/07/heres-a-simple-trick-for-anyone-who-finds-eye-contact-too-intense/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36618</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T09:58:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-157522456.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36634&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36634&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D300&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;close-up of a face with blue eyes&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Merbe&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;blue eyes&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;blue eyes&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-157522456.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-157522456.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-157522456.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2058,1457&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/07/heres-a-simple-trick-for-anyone-who-finds-eye-contact-too-intense/blue-eyes-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-157522456.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re taught from an early age that it is polite and assertive to look people in the eyes when we’re talking to them. Psychology research backs this up – people who make plenty of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/28/the-psychology-of-eye-contact-digested/&quot;&gt;eye contact&lt;/a&gt; – as long as it’s not excessive – are usually perceived as more competent, trustworthy and intelligent. If you want to make a good impression, then, it’s probably a good idea to meet the gaze of the person you’re talking to. However, following this advice is not necessarily straight-forward for everyone. It’s well-documented that mutual gaze can be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20190108-why-meeting-anothers-gaze-is-so-powerful&quot;&gt;emotionally intense and distracting&lt;/a&gt;, even uncomfortably so for some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is your experience, you may welcome &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0301006619827486?journalCode=peca&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; published recently in the journal &lt;em&gt;Perception&lt;/em&gt; that documents a phenomenon known as the “eye contact illusion” – put simply, we are not that good at telling whether an interlocutor is looking us in the eye or not. In fact, we tend to think they are, even when they’re not (a bias that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/08/16/after-rejection-your-brain-performs-this-subtle-trick-to-help-you-make-friends/&quot;&gt;magnified&lt;/a&gt; after we’ve been rejected). Thanks to this illusion, you can give the impression of making eye contact simply by ensuring you are looking in the general direction of your conversant’s face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36618&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate the eye contact illusion, one member of the Edith Cowan University research team, Oliver Guidetti, held 4-minute “getting to know you” chats with 46 male and female university students. Both Guidetti, and the students he chatted to, wore eye tracking glasses. For half the students, Guidetti made plenty of eye contact (around 77 per cent of the time, resulting in mutual eye contact during 52 per cent of the chat) just as he usually would. For the other students, he chatted in the same casual way, but deliberately reduced his eye contact to around 25 per cent, focusing more on the mouth region of their faces instead (resulting in mutual eye contact for just 3 per cent of the chat).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The critical test was how much the students in the two groups believed Guidetti had tried to make eye contact and how much they enjoyed the chat. In fact both groups of students perceived the same amount of eye contact and enjoyed the chat the same amount. A follow-up experiment confirmed this wasn’t because the eye-tracking glasses made it hard to judge gaze direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, including lead author Shane Rogers, said their findings were consistent with past evidence suggesting that during normal conversation, the perception of eye contact is driven by the other person looking in the general direction of your face, not into your eyes specifically. The new findings may be reassuring to anyone who wants to be a good communicator but who finds eye contact uncomfortably intense. “Don’t get hung up on seeking out the eyes of the audience, just look more generally at their face, and let the eye contact illusion experienced by your partner do the work for you,” the researchers advised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0301006619827486?journalCode=peca&quot;&gt;Contact Is in the Eye of the Beholder: The Eye Contact Illusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:59+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Better prediction of the economic burden of multimorbidity from medical and long-term care expenditures</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/03/07/better-prediction-of-the-economic-burden-of-multimorbidity-from-medical-and-long-term-care-expenditures/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10872</id>
		<updated>2019-03-07T09:01:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/03/expeditures-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multimorbidity worldwide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multimorbidity, the coexistence of multiple chronic diseases in an individual, increases with age in older adults. Therefore, it is very common that older adults have more than one chronic medical problem at the same time, which impacts treatment for each of the conditions. Multimorbidity is a growing concern worldwide, especially in countries with aging populations. Numerous previous studies have reported that multimorbidity is associated with functional decline (i.e., older adults cannot take care of themselves in some aspects or more), decreased quality of life, and possibly even higher mortality, all of which are of concern to older adults and those who care for them. Aside from the burden on the individual from the conditions, there is also a societal burden from the costs associated with care for these individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical and long-term care insurance systems and these expenditures in Japan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan has a mandatory universal medical insurance system, established in 1961. It covers services provided by medical professionals (e.g., doctors, nurses, various therapists), diagnostic tests, prescriptions, surgery, and anesthesia. In addition to the universal medical insurance system, Japan also launched a mandatory public long-term care insurance system in 2000. Those aged 65 years and older, as well as those aged between 40 and 64 years with specific aging-related diseases, are eligible for services. These include not only institutional care, whether long-term admission or short-term stay in a long-term care facility, but also community- and home-based care such as adult day care, outpatient rehabilitation, home help, or home-visit nursing. Long-term care insurance is also available in other countries, such as Germany, the Netherlands, and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The economic burden on society caused by multimorbidity could be better evaluated by the sum of medical and long-term care expenditures … providing a more-accurate assessment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A steady increase in health-related spending has been a great concern in countries with aging populations. For example, in Japan in 2016, the annual medical expenditures were approximately US$372 billion and the annual long-term care expenditures were approximately US$88 billion. These figures represent 9% and 21% increases, respectively, over the past 5 years. These expenditures are projected to further increase with a rapidly aging society, both in Japan and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The associations between multimorbidity and expenditures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-019-1057-7&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;our recent study&lt;/a&gt;, we examined the associations between multimorbidity and the sum of medical and long-term care expenditures using medical and long-term care claims data from Kashiwa City, a suburb in the Tokyo metropolitan area, Japan. It was already known that multimorbidity is associated with higher medical expenditures. We found that multimorbidity is also associated with higher long-term care expenditures, thereby increasing the sum of both types of expenditures. Our study further indicated that the economic burden on society caused by multimorbidity could be better evaluated by the sum of medical and long-term care expenditures than by medical expenditures alone, providing a more-accurate assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan has one of the most rapidly aging societies in the world and has not only medical but also long-term care insurance systems. As far as we know, this is the first study to examine the associations of multimorbidity with long-term care expenditures and with the sum of medical and long-term care expenditures, worldwide. As the steady increase in health-related spending has been a great threat for maintaining sustainable healthcare systems in many countries with aging populations, our results are meaningful not only for Japan but also globally. Effective strategies for reducing the prevalence of multimorbidity could provide not only medical and functional but also economic benefits for individuals and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/03/07/better-prediction-of-the-economic-burden-of-multimorbidity-from-medical-and-long-term-care-expenditures/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Better prediction of the economic burden of multimorbidity from medical and long-term care expenditures&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Takahiro Mori</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:46+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">FDA has approved the first ketamine-based antidepressant</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fda-has-approved-first-ketamine-based-antidepressant"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fda-has-approved-first-ketamine-based-antidepressant</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T21:02:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A nasal spray with a ketamine-based drug promises faster relief from depression for some people.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hominids may have hunted rabbits as far back as 400,000 years ago</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hominids-hunt-rabbits-stone-age"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hominids-hunt-rabbits-stone-age</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T19:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Stone Age groups in Europe put small game on the menu surprisingly early.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Plan S: What strategy now for the Global South?</title>
		<link href="https://poynder.blogspot.com/2019/02/plan-s-what-strategy-now-for-global.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882.post-2789625904323210769</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T16:53:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since the 2002 Budapest Open Access Initiative (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.budapestopenaccessinitiative.org/&quot;&gt;BOAI&lt;/a&gt;) the OA movement has had many successes, many surprises, and many disappointments. OA initiatives have also often had unintended consequences and the movement has been beset with disagreement, divisiveness, and confusion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mwNAVpK-du8/XGbdx6UctZI/AAAAAAAAjSA/75L8fW-9KMQvddJSK4Pu-Fh9bgphnaHtwCLcBGAs/s1600/OJS.jpg&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;478&quot; data-original-width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mwNAVpK-du8/XGbdx6UctZI/AAAAAAAAjSA/75L8fW-9KMQvddJSK4Pu-Fh9bgphnaHtwCLcBGAs/s320/OJS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 8pt;&quot;&gt;Image Courtesy of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 8pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pkp.sfu.ca/ojs/ojs-usage/ojs-map/&quot;&gt;PKP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 8pt;&quot;&gt; CC BY-SA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In that sense, the noise and rancour surrounding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coalition-s.org/&quot;&gt;Plan S&lt;/a&gt; is nothing new, although the discord is perceptibly greater. What seems clear is that Plan S raises challenging questions for those in the Global South.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And even if Plan S fails to win sufficient support to achieve its objectives, ongoing efforts in Europe to trigger a “global flip” to open access, and the way in which open content is likely to be monetised by commercial publishers, both suggest that the South needs to develop its own (alternative) strategy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I have explored what I see as the issues and discuss a possible strategy in the attached essay &lt;a href=&quot;https://richardpoynder.co.uk/Plan_S.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The essay ends with an interview with Omar Barreneche, Executive Secretary of Uruguay’s National Agency for Research and Innovation (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anii.org.uy/&quot;&gt;ANII&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;A 1,400-word edited extract from this essay can be read on the LSE Impact Blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2019/03/06/plan-s-and-the-global-south-what-do-countries-in-the-global-south-stand-to-gain-from-signing-up-to-europes-open-access-strategy/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Richard Poynder</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>https://poynder.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Open and Shut?</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/7961882/posts/default"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T09:46:12+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tiny bits of iron may explain why some icebergs are green</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/green-icebergs-antarctica-iron"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/green-icebergs-antarctica-iron</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T16:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists originally thought the green hue of some icebergs came from carbon particles. Instead, iron oxides may color the ice.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeremy Rehm</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This spider slingshots itself at extreme speeds to catch prey</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/slingshot-spider-web-acceleration"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/slingshot-spider-web-acceleration</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T15:19:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 By winding up its web like a slingshot, the slingshot spider achieves an acceleration rate far faster than a cheetah’s.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Evaluating research: Who gets the money when the stakes are high?</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/evaluating-research-who-gets-the-money-when-the-stakes-are-high"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/evaluating-research-who-gets-the-money-when-the-stakes-are-high</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T11:01:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Research leaders confront challenges in deciding what to fund for the greatest societal impact</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A university thought its misconduct investigation was complete. Then a PubPeer comment appeared.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/06/a-university-thought-its-misconduct-investigation-was-complete-then-a-pubpeer-comment-appeared/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87752</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T11:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 When Venkata Sudheer Kumar Ramadugu, then a postdoc at the University of Michigan, admitted to the university on June 28 of last year that he had committed research misconduct in a paper that appeared in Chemical Communications in 2017, he also “attested that he did not manipulate any data in his other four co-authored publications … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/06/a-university-thought-its-misconduct-investigation-was-complete-then-a-pubpeer-comment-appeared/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A university thought its misconduct investigation was complete. Then a PubPeer comment appeared.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These Violent Delights Don’t Have Violent Ends: Study Finds No link Between Violent Video Games And Teen Aggression</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/06/these-violent-delights-dont-have-violent-ends-study-finds-no-link-between-violent-video-games-and-teen-aggression/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36626</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T10:03:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-180968005.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36627&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36627&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NEW YORK, NY - SEPTEMBER 18:  A display copy of Grand Theft Auto V (C) sits on a shelf at the 8 Bit &amp;amp; Up video games shop in Manhattan's East Village on September 18, 2013 in New York City. The video game raked in more than $800 million in sales in its first 24 hours on the shelves.  (Photo by Mario Tama\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1379518412&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2013 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;21&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1600&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.02&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Grand Theft Auto Video Game Rakes In 800 Million Dollars Within One Day Of Sales&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Grand Theft Auto Video Game Rakes In 800 Million Dollars Within One Day Of Sales&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-180968005.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-180968005.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-180968005.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,1994&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/06/these-violent-delights-dont-have-violent-ends-study-finds-no-link-between-violent-video-games-and-teen-aggression/grand-theft-auto-video-game-rakes-in-800-million-dollars-within-one-day-of-sales/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-180968005.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;Matthew Warren&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claims that violent video games lead to aggression have been around &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1988-26277-001&quot;&gt;since the days of &lt;i&gt;Space Invaders&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When young people are exposed to violent media, the theory goes, their aggressive thoughts become more prominent, leading them to commit acts of violence. But while several studies have found results that seem to back up this idea, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/18/hard-core-players-of-violent-video-games-do-not-have-emotionally-blunted-brains/&quot;&gt;evidence is far from unequivocal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a study published in &lt;i&gt;Royal Society Open Science&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/full/10.1098/rsos.171474&quot;&gt;has failed to find any association&lt;/a&gt; between the time spent playing violent video games and aggressive behaviour, adding to a growing body of literature that suggests that such a link has been overstated – or may not exist at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36626&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many past studies in the field suffered from important methodological limitations, such as relying on people reporting their own levels of aggression, which opens results up to “mischievous responding”, where participants give dishonest responses just for the sake of it –&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X14534297&quot;&gt;particular problem in research with young people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more worryingly, researchers have often taken a “flexible” approach to analysis. For example, when calculating scores that represent the level of violence in games or how aggressive an individual is, researchers have decided to use just a small subset of all the questions that they’ve asked participants, allowing them to pick and choose from their measures to produce results consistent with their theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new study, Andrew Przybylski and Netta Weinstein sought to examine the link between violent video games and aggression more rigorously, avoiding the methodological pitfalls of past work and sticking to an analysis plan they described before starting out the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pair asked just over one thousand British 14- and 15-year-olds to list the games they had played in the past month, and how long they played them for. Rather than relying on the teenagers to describe whether these games were violent, the researchers checked whether or not each game contained violent content according to the European video game rating system, PEGI (of the more than 1,500 games participants listed, nearly two in three, such as &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto V&lt;/em&gt;, were rated as violent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To measure aggression, the researchers again avoided questioning the gamers directly. Instead, they asked the teenagers’ caregivers to complete a survey on the aggressive behaviours their child had shown over the past month, such as whether they had fought or bullied other children.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;They also directly measured the teens’ “trait” levels of aggression, asking them the extent to which they felt that various statements characterised them (for example, “Given enough provocation, I may hit another person”). The researchers used this measure to control for baseline levels of aggression in the analysis.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Przybylski and Weinstein found that their participants played video games for two hours per day, on average, and almost 49 per cent of the girls and 68 per cent of the boys had played one or more violent games in the past month. But the amount of time they’d spent playing violent video games did not predict how aggressive they had been. These results remained the same when the researchers classified the games’ content on the American rather than European video game rating scale.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given on-going concerns from parents and policy-makers about the potential negative consequences of violent video games, a null finding from a large, carefully designed study should offer some reassurance. Of course, there’s always the possibility that gaming could be associated with other bad behaviour like bullying and trolling, and the authors say that these issues are worth further exploration. And while there are clearly benefits of having a third-party rate the teenagers’ aggression, it seems possible that some caregivers could still underplay or be unaware of their children’s aggressive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also true that the new study is just the latest in a field containing many contradictory results. But it stands apart from many past papers because of its methodology. The paper was published as a Registered Report, a format in which a journal provisionally accepts a paper based on its protocol, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bps.org.uk/news-and-policy/were-offering-registered-reports-across-all-eleven-our-academic-journals&quot;&gt;regardless of how the results turn out&lt;/a&gt;. The authors show that it would have been possible – though statistically inappropriate – to fish around in their data until they had found a significant result somewhere. For example, there was a correlation between aggression and self-reported time spent playing games generally (a question that wasn’t part of the planned analysis). “If we had not preregistered our empirical approach and felt motivated to publish a positive result we might have seized on this correlation and made it the central focus of our research report,” they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a time when many experts believe unsubstantiated fears surrounding technology are obscuring legitimate and more nuanced questions about the role of media in society, it is promising that researchers are grappling with these important methodological issues. As the authors write, “it is crucial that scientists conduct work with openness and rigour if we are to build a real understanding of the positive and negative dynamics and impacts of technology in people’s lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/full/10.1098/rsos.171474&quot;&gt;Violent video game engagement is not associated with adolescents’ aggressive behaviour: evidence from a registered report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto V&lt;/em&gt;, shown here in a Manhattan games store, raked in more than $800 million in sales in its first 24 hours on the shelves. (Photo by Mario Tama/Getty Images).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Warren (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;@MattbWarren&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Did Plant Cell learn from Voinnet Affair?</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2019/03/06/did-plant-cell-learn-from-voinnet-affair/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=38201</id>
		<updated>2019-03-06T08:46:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Plant Cell is an elite journal, its authors and editors are some serious heavyweights whose labs cannot be associated with data manipulation.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:04+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The first planet Kepler spotted has finally been confirmed 10 years later</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-planet-kepler-finally-confirmed-10-years-later"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-planet-kepler-finally-confirmed-10-years-later</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T20:13:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Astronomers had dismissed the first exoplanet candidate spotted by the Kepler space telescope as a false alarm.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A CRISPR spin-off causes unintended typos in DNA</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-spinoff-gene-editor-causes-unintended-typos-dna"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-spinoff-gene-editor-causes-unintended-typos-dna</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T17:30:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 One type of CRISPR gene editor makes frequent and widespread mistakes, studies in mice and rice reveal.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">We Couldn’t Do It without YOU</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/lQ7QZIA2FRk/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8455</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T17:08:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2019/03/Thank-you_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Every year, we get to work with new authors, reviewers, and editors who are ushering in the next wave of scientific advancement. We love publishing your work, reading your reviews, and learning from your expertise and we just want to say THANK YOU for supporting PLOS.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wow, did we really do all of that?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We did! This has been a banner year for PLOS journals. In 2018 we saw more research articles published in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; than ever before, began publishing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://collections.plos.org/topic-pages&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Topic Pages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS Genetics &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006494&quot;&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/a&gt; articles in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, partnered with bioRxiv to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/12/plos-authors-say-yes-to-preprints/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;post over 1,300 preprints,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and committed to moving forward with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/08/transparency-credit-and-peer-review/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;published and signed peer review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. That’s on top of all of the special issues, Calls for Papers, and collections we’ve published in topics ranging from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://collections.plos.org/climate-change-and-health&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Climate Change and Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosntds/article?id=10.1371/journal.pntd.0006681&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Gender and NTDs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We’d also like to extend a warm welcome to more than 3,000 new members of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/static/editorial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Editorial Board&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; who have joined us this year to provide more expertise for submission areas that need it most – we’re glad you’re here!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For everything we do at PLOS, we are supported by the dedication of our research communities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2019/02/PLOS-Stats-02.20.19_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-8464 size-full&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2019/02/PLOS-Stats-02.20.19_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2149&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Together, we’re stronger&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We are a community of more than 11,000 editors, 65,000 reviewers, and 150,000 authors. When we work together, we can make change happen in scholarly communication. Last year &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; editors hosted six writing workshops to help Early Career Researchers improve their skills and equip them with the tools they need to become authors. We also hosted interactive events like live-streamed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/10/live-streamed-preprint-journal-clubs/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;preprint journal clubs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to bring authors and experts from the community together for real-time feedback on their work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We’re listening to your feedback from our surveys, event meetups, and Section Calls and want to continue evolving our services in ways that matter to you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We’re working on new ways for reviewers to get credit for their work through ORCiD as well as signed and published peer reviews. We’re also going to continue the process improvements we’ve started on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to bring a faster, clearer process to our authors along with a number of exciting new options on other journals – stay tuned!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cite it, share it, celebrate it&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For everyone who has contributed to our success this year: our dedicated Editorial Board, incredible Guest Editors, and inspiring reviewers – these articles are for you!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3000177&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1006885&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1008031&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1002765&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0007252&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1007649&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0213287&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 2018 Reviewer and Editorial Board Thank You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We’re sure we will have many more opportunities to thank you this year but please join us in celebrating your achievements this week by sharing your PLOS contributions with #PLOSCommunity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/lQ7QZIA2FRk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Madison Crystal</name>
			<uri>https://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>https://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A second HIV patient has gone into remission after a stem cell transplant</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/second-hiv-patient-remission-stem-cell-transplant"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/second-hiv-patient-remission-stem-cell-transplant</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T16:37:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A second person with HIV has gone into remission after receiving blood stem cells from a donor unable to make a protein needed by the virus.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ripples race in the brain as memories are recalled</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ripples-brain-memories-recall"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ripples-brain-memories-recall</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T12:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A fast brain wave called a ripple often came before a person’s correct answer on a memory test.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal retracts creationist paper “because it was published in error”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/05/journal-retracts-creationist-paper-because-it-was-published-in-error/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87800</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 It’s become a sort of Retraction Watch Mad Libs: Author writes a paper that is so far, far, out of the mainstream. Maybe it argues that HIV doesn’t cause AIDS. Or that vaccines cause autism. Truth squads swarm over the paper, taking to blogs and Twitter to wonder, in the exasperated tone of those who … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/05/journal-retracts-creationist-paper-because-it-was-published-in-error/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journal retracts creationist paper “because it was published in error”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Suppressed Thoughts Rebound, Which Could Explain Why Ultra-religious Teens Have More Compulsive Sexual Thoughts – And Are Less Happy – Than Their Secular Peers</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/05/the-suppression-rebound-effect-could-explain-why-orthodox-jewish-teens-have-more-compulsive-sexual-thoughts-and-ultimately-why-they-are-less-happy-than-their-secular-peer/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36571</id>
		<updated>2019-03-05T09:24:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-481381140.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36616&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36616&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Human brain with conceptual sex text in the center&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lightcome&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Human brain with conceptual text&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Human brain with conceptual text&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-481381140.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-481381140.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-481381140.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1878,1596&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/05/the-suppression-rebound-effect-could-explain-why-orthodox-jewish-teens-have-more-compulsive-sexual-thoughts-and-ultimately-why-they-are-less-happy-than-their-secular-peer/human-brain-with-conceptual-text/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-481381140.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well-known effect in psychology is that if you try to suppress a thought, ironically this can make the thought all the more salient – known as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-24/edition-11/thoughts-suppression&quot;&gt;rebound effect&lt;/a&gt;“. What are the implications of this effect for highly religious teenagers who have been taught to believe that sexual thoughts are taboo? Before now there has been little research on the rebound effect in this context, but in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224499.2018.1461796&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Sex Research&lt;/em&gt;, Yaniv Efrati at Beit Berl College, Kfar-Saba, Israel, presents evidence that the rebound effect could explain why orthodox Jewish teens have more compulsive sexual thoughts and fantasies than their secular peers. What’s more, his results suggest this mental dynamic might be responsible for the religious teens’ lower scores on self-reported wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36571&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three studies involved hundreds of secular Israeli teen volunteers, boys and girls aged 14 to 18, and a similar number of teen orthodox Jews of both sexes, who will have been taught by the religious text the &lt;em&gt;Talmud&lt;/em&gt; that “thoughts of transgression are more severe than transgression” – as well as receiving other decrees to avoid impure thoughts and masturbation – and therefore may have learned to try to conceal and suppress their sexual thoughts and feelings out of fear of shame and guilt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True to this prediction, Efrati found that the orthodox Jewish teens tended to score higher on a questionnaire measuring their frequency of compulsive sexual fantasies and thoughts (for example, they agreed more often with statements like “I feel like my sexual fantasises hurt those around me”). He also found that higher scorers on compulsive sexual thoughts tended to report being less happy, and this association explained why the orthodox Jewish teens tended to report being less happy than their secular peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final and most revealing study, Efrati linked the earlier findings with the rebound effect. Using a questionnaire measuring sexual suppression (an example item was “very often I find myself trying to suppress my sexual thoughts”), he found that Jewish orthodox teens engaged in more suppression of their sexual thoughts, and in turn this was linked with their having more compulsive sexual thoughts and fantasies, and also lower overall happiness (presumably because of the shame and guilt associated with the taboo thoughts, although they didn’t score any higher for depression or distress). Efrati said this result “corroborates with studies on the rebound effect in many other domains … and shows that suppression of sexual thoughts only begets higher pre-occupation with sexual thoughts and fantasies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the findings are consistent with Efrati’s argument that the thought suppression rebound effect causes greater sexual thoughts among the religious teens, it’s important to note that the studies were purely correlational leaving them open to other interpretations. One alternative explanation, for instance, is to see everything in reverse – that the lower happiness among the Jewish orthodox teens (whatever is causing it) leads them to have more compulsive sexual thoughts, which triggers more attempts to suppress those thoughts. Even if Efrati’s interpretation is the correct one, it remains to be seen whether the same results will also apply among other religious groups besides orthodox Jews in Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Despite these shortcomings, ” Efrati concluded, “we view the current research as an important step in understanding adolescents’ suppression of sexual thoughts, taking into account the cultural- religious context as a major component in adolescents’ sexual development.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224499.2018.1461796&quot;&gt;God, I Can’t Stop Thinking About Sex! The Rebound Effect in Unsuccessful Suppression of Sexual Thoughts Among Religious Adolescents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A 2,000-year-old tattoo tool is the oldest in western North America</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-tattoo-tool-western-north-america"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-tattoo-tool-western-north-america</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T21:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The artifact is made of two pigment-stained cactus spines, and has been sitting in storage since its discovery in 1972.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hidden ancient neutrinos may shape the patterns of galaxies</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hidden-ancient-neutrinos-may-shape-patterns-galaxies"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hidden-ancient-neutrinos-may-shape-patterns-galaxies</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T16:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The gravitational pull of subatomic particles born in the universe’s first second seem to influence how galaxies cluster into rings.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Oral Health: Highlights of 2018</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/03/04/bmc-oral-health-highlights-of-2018/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10856</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T15:30:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/oral-health-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0684-2&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Consequences of community water fluoridation cessation &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community water fluoridation (CWF), the controlled addition of fluoride to a public water supply, has been described by the Centers for Disease and Control as one of the most positively impactful public health achievements of the modern day. CWF was first implemented in Grand Rapids, Michigan in 1945 and has since been employed across the United States and the wider world. CWF has been shown to significantly reduce childhood caries, the most common childhood disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This retrospective comparative analysis used dental claims records of 0-18 year old patients from Juneau (Alaksa) to explore the consequences of CWF cessation on dental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of CWF was confirmed by this investigation. The frequency of caries related procedures (particularly for 6-7 year olds) significantly increased during the fluoridation cessation period and there was an increase in the relative cost to treat the caries, suggesting an increase in caries severity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CWF can be viewed as a kind of government investment which works towards protecting young people from childhood disease and school absences whilst simultaneously reducing government spending on healthcare claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0490-x&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Reporting of child maltreatment amongst public dental health personnel&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organisation, child maltreatment can come in the form of physical, sexual, psychological abuse, as well as generalized neglect. One quarter of adults worldwide were physically abused as children. Although abuse reporting continues to rise, an estimated third of victims of childhood sexual abuse cases go unreported. The importance of developing frameworks to detect potential hidden victims or at-risk children is immeasurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The repeated missing of dental appointments is considered to be an early indicator of struggling households and possible maltreatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Norway, all children below the age of 19 are provided with free and regular dental treatments from the Public Dental Health Service (PDHS). The PDHS are required by law to report suspicion of child maltreatment to the Child Welfare Services (CWS). The CWS is required to respond to PDHS maltreatment concerns within 3 weeks, unless the concern is unsubstantiated. When PDHS concerns result in CWS investigation, the reporter is provided with outcome information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1200 PDHS employees answered questionnaires regarding their reasons for sending a report to CWS and the responses the CWS gave.  The most common reason for sending a report of concern was if a child did not attend a dental visit, and not direct suspicion of neglect or interaction with parents/guardians. The repeated missing of dental appointments is considered to be an early indicator of struggling households and possible maltreatment. Grave caries and a lack of hygiene came 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; and 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; on the list, respectively. 40% of PDHS reports of suspicion of psychological abuse and trauma resulted in CWS investigation and measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quarter of reports resulted in measures, but the PDHS was not aware of the outcome of a third of submitted reports. Sexual abuse, grave caries and suspicion of neglect were the most strongly associated with CWS led outcomes. Although the PDHS were shown to be efficient reporters of potential maltreatment, the relatively low measures taken by the CWS, and even feedback to the PDHS , highlights a gap between the two organisations that requires some work to close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0591-6&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Using machine learning to predict bad breath from the mouth microbiome&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oral malodour, otherwise known as halistosis, chronically affects around 50% of the developed world. It can lead sufferers to experience low self-esteem and bullying. The molecular culprits are volatile sulphuric and acidic compounds produced by periodontis-associated oral bacteria. Volatile sulphur compounds (VSCs) are produced by approximately 700 bacterial species residing in the human mouth. It is the concentration of the different compounds that each bacterial species produces, rather than presence of the species itself, which generates the resulting odour. For this reason it has been very difficult to establish a framework for predicting oral malodour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle this problem, the authors turned to Deep Learning, a machine learning process which is inspired by the communication patterns seen within the neurons of the human brain.  Bacterial samples were taken from 90 patients, half with malodour and half without. Bacteria present in each sample were identified via 16s rRNA gene amplification and sequencing. This data, bacterial identity and the odour profile of individuals, was then sorted via deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10857&quot; style=&quot;width: 629px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10857 size-full&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/cladogram.png&quot; width=&quot;619&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Cladogram created by the authors showing different abundance of mouth microbiome taxa&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy breath was associated with an abundance of Streptococcus, Granulicatella and Rothia, and malodour was associated with Veillonella, Peptostreptococcus, and Porphyromonas. The authors have provided evidence that saliva samples are a suitable substrate from which to assess oral malodour and have offered a potential deep learning based method in which the efficacy of malodour treatment can be measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0500-z&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;The association between stress, saliva and dental caries&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been much debate regarding the purported link between stress and the occurrence of dental caries. Stress can induce behavioural changes in people that can, in turn, be detrimental to oral health. A student’s tendency to increase sugar intake and neglect oral hygiene around exam time are examples of such behavioral changes. Stress can also induce flow rate changes in saliva. Behavioral and morphological changes collaborate to potentially increase the risk of dental caries amongst a stressed population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10859&quot; style=&quot;width: 970px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10859 size-full&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/stressed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;source: pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scoping review, the authors performed a search in OVID, Embase, MEDLINE, PsycINFO, CINAHL, and WoS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six studies, which used cortisol as the biomarker of stress, were included in the review. 4 of these studies identified a link between salivary cortisol and caries, and the remaining 2 did not. The authors do not concede a causative link between cortisol and caries; however they instead identify cortisol and caries as an oral health research gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding stress-induced salivary changes, the authors identify the limitation of the studies to have only measured acute stress responses instead of chronic stress exposure. The authors suggest the need for well designed, rigorous prospective cohort studies in which the extent that chronic stress (for example induced by low socio-economic status) effects caries is examined. The authors also suggest expanding cortisol-related measurements to more than just a single time-point (as seen in the examined studies) to better represent the complex factors contributing to human stress. The authors propose augmenting the measurement to also include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.     The source of stress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.     The subject’s perception of stress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.     Physiological stress responses, for instance heart rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors conclude that although evidence can be found to support links between stress and caries, the studies actually provide impetus for a pressing need for precise, detailed, methodologically sound studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0514-6&quot;&gt;Comparative effectiveness of school-based caries prevention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School-based caries prevention affords children greater access to dental care, and helps to homogenise the kind of care that children from different socio-economic backgrounds experience. School-based dental treatment involving the application of dental sealants is endorsed by The American Dental association. However, efficacy of such procedures has been identified as a knowledge gap and unexplored area of research by the Institute of Medicine (Washington, USA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, the authors conducted a prospective observational study on 2 populations of children receiving school-based dental treatments. Both cohorts received glass ionomer sealants, but only one of the cohorts received a secondary intervention: interim therapeutic restorations placed on all asymptomatic teeth with carious lesions. Both interventions across both cohorts were performed every 6 months, and data was collected over the course of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding teeth, examination of any decay, missing, filled, sound or pulpal abnormalities were noted. Variables such as pain, swelling, infection and abscess were also recorded. Data was collected by the dental hygienists and dentists performing these procedures in an e-Case Report Forms, which were electronically collated and analysed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no statistically significant difference in the number of decayed or filled teeth across the cohorts. Interestingly however, there was a significant interaction between treatment and time, interpreted by the authors to mean that the incidence rate of decayed or filled teeth slowed over time for the children who received both primary and secondary interventions. This study offers important information to those involved in school-based optimal program design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/03/04/bmc-oral-health-highlights-of-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;BMC Oral Health&lt;/i&gt;: Highlights of 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandria Latto &amp;#38; Liam Messin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:46+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Welfare reforms may have hurt some single moms’ teenage kids</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/welfare-reform-single-moms-teenage-kids-behavior"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/welfare-reform-single-moms-teenage-kids-behavior</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T14:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Welfare reform was meant to help the next generation, but making moms work and capping aid has led to more harm than gain, says a new study.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sujata Gupta</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Plagiarism prompts retraction of 25-year-old article by prominent priest</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/04/plagiarism-prompts-retraction-of-25-year-old-article-by-prominent-priest/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87677</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Retraction Watch readers may have heard about Fr. Thomas Rosica, a priest who recently apologized for plagiarism and resigned from the board of a college. The case, which involved Rosica’s speeches and popular columns, prompted at least two observers to take a look at his scholarly work. One of those observers was Michael Dougherty, who … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/04/plagiarism-prompts-retraction-of-25-year-old-article-by-prominent-priest/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Plagiarism prompts retraction of 25-year-old article by prominent priest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bears that eat ‘junk food’ may hibernate less and age faster</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bears-eat-human-food-may-hibernate-less-and-age-faster"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bears-eat-human-food-may-hibernate-less-and-age-faster</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Wild black bears snacking on leftovers of sugary, highly processed foods in Colorado show possible signs of faster cellular wear.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Q&amp;amp;A: Amref leader on why universal health coverage is crucial for Africa</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-amref-leader-on-why-universal-health-coverage-is-crucial-for-africa"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-amref-leader-on-why-universal-health-coverage-is-crucial-for-africa</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T10:46:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Dr. Githinji Gitahi, Group CEO of Amref Health Africa, talks about Africa’s unique path to UHC and what to expect at #AHAIC2019</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How machine learning can speed up “annoyingly hard” medical research</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-machine-learning-can-speed-up-annoyingly-hard-medical-research"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-machine-learning-can-speed-up-annoyingly-hard-medical-research</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T10:20:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researcher Alexander Mathiasen hopes to solve medical problems with machine learning while working across disciplines</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Your Romantic Partner Is Probably Less Intelligent Than You Think, Suggests New Study</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/04/your-romantic-partner-is-probably-less-intelligent-than-you-think-suggests-new-study/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36608</id>
		<updated>2019-03-04T09:44:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-1092632424.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36611&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36611&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Close up portrait of two she her he him his best friends siblings boy lady with open mouth arms up on head yelling from shock wearing casual shirts denim plaid outfit isolated on rose background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Close up portrait of two she her he him his best friends sibling&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Close up portrait of two she her he him his best friends sibling&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-1092632424.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-1092632424.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-1092632424.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2119,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/04/your-romantic-partner-is-probably-less-intelligent-than-you-think-suggests-new-study/close-up-portrait-of-two-she-her-he-him-his-best-friends-sibling/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-1092632424.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidrobson.me/&quot;&gt;David Robson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s now well known that many of us over-estimate our own brainpower. In one study, more than 90 per cent of US college professors famously claimed to be better than average at teaching, for instance – which would be highly unlikely. Our egos blind us to our own flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But do we have an even more inflated view of our nearest and dearest? It seems we do – that’s the conclusion of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289618302150&quot;&gt;new paper published in &lt;i&gt;Intelligence&lt;/i&gt; journal&lt;/a&gt;, which has shown that we consistently view our romantic partners as being much smarter than they really are.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36608&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, Gilles Gignac at the University of Western Australia and Marcin Zajenkowski at the University of Warsaw, also tested whether the couples’ actual IQs influenced their relationship satisfaction – with surprising results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There had been some previous signs that we are especially optimistic about our loved ones’ attributes. When it comes to physical attractiveness, for instance, we tend to think that we have managed to attract someone who is even hotter than us – an effect sometimes called the “love is blind bias”. But past studies had failed to find a similar optimism for estimates of partners’ intelligence. Overall, people seemed to judge their partners’ intelligence as equal to their own – rather than thinking that they were especially clever.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the new study, the researchers recruited 218 heterosexual couples, who had been together for an average of six years, and around a quarter were married. Rather that guessing IQ scores – which might be confusing for participants who have little knowledge of IQ tests and their scoring – the participants had to estimate their own intelligence and their partner’s intelligence using a more intuitive, graphical scale (see below). The researchers then converted those estimates to IQ points according to the known statistical distribution of intelligence – the famous bell curve. To find the participants’ actual, objective IQ scores, the researchers also asked them to take a standard test of non-verbal intelligence known as the Raven’s Advanced Progressive Matrices.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_36609&quot; style=&quot;width: 3063px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;1-s2.0-S0160289618302150-gr1_lrg.jpg&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-36609 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36609&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;1-s2.0-S0160289618302150-gr1_lrg&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/1-s2.0-s0160289618302150-gr1_lrg.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/1-s2.0-s0160289618302150-gr1_lrg.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/1-s2.0-s0160289618302150-gr1_lrg.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3063,250&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/04/your-romantic-partner-is-probably-less-intelligent-than-you-think-suggests-new-study/1-s2-0-s0160289618302150-gr1_lrg/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/1-s2.0-s0160289618302150-gr1_lrg.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289618302150&quot;&gt;Gignac &amp;amp; Zajenkowski, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the previous research on individual overconfidence had found, most participants over-estimated their own intelligence by a huge margin – the equivalent of around 30 IQ points on average. Overall, only 0.9 per cent of women and 1.8 per cent of men assessed their own intelligence as being below average (even though 68.8 per cent of the women and 55.0 per cent of the men in this study scored below 100 – the mean IQ of the population as a whole).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants’ estimates of their partners’ intelligence were even more skewed. The men thought their wives and girlfriends’ IQs were around 36 points higher than they really were; the women thought their husbands and boyfriends’ IQs were 38 points higher than the reality. In other words, if you are like the majority of people in this sample, your partner is probably much less clever than you believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_36610&quot; style=&quot;width: 204px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligence-Trap-People-Mistakes-Decisions/dp/1473669839/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Intelligence Trap Cover&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-36610&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36610&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The Intelligence Trap Cover&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/the-intelligence-trap-cover.jpg?w=421&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/the-intelligence-trap-cover.jpg?w=194&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/the-intelligence-trap-cover.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;421,650&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/04/your-romantic-partner-is-probably-less-intelligent-than-you-think-suggests-new-study/the-intelligence-trap-cover/&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/the-intelligence-trap-cover.jpg?w=194&amp;amp;h=300&quot; width=&quot;194&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligence-Trap-People-Mistakes-Decisions/dp/1473669839/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;Available for pre-order now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this eye-catching result, Gignac and Zajenkowski’s paper is rich with other findings. They were interested, for instance, in whether people tend to hook up with someone of similar cognitive ability – and whether that “intellectual compatibility” is important for their happiness together. As previous research has found, there was a moderate correlation between the partners’ actual IQ scores – so in general people do seem to pick partners who roughly match their intelligence.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we have a slight preference for people with similar smarts to ourselves, or maybe it’s due to the fact that we have more opportunity to get romantically involved with people of roughly similar intelligence – in education or at work. Whatever the reasons, the degree of similarity of couples’ IQs didn’t seem to influence their relationship satisfaction – overall, couples with lower “intellectual compatibility” appeared to be just as happy as the couples who were more closely matched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gignac and Zajenkowski also examined whether the men or the women in their sample were better at estimating their partners’ intelligence. According to some evolutionary psychologists, because the responsibility of pregnancy, childbirth, and usually childrearing, falls more directly on women, they should be pickier than men about the kind of person they choose to reproduce with. If true, it would make sense for women to have evolved to be more perceptive than men of differences in other people’s intelligence. Yet the researchers found no evidence of this.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers admit, there are some limitations to their study. They only used a non-verbal IQ test, for instance, and it’s possible you would see different results if you also looked at verbal questions. After all, the size of someone’s vocabulary and their linguistic fluency may be easier for a partner to judge accurately.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But overall, the findings help extend our understanding of our self-serving biases, showing our egotism and self-confidence can sometimes spill-over to our loved ones. Maybe we like to think we’re with a partner who reflects an even better version of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289618302150%23s0030&quot;&gt;People tend to overestimate their romantic partner’s intelligence even more than their own&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidrobson.me/&quot;&gt;David Robson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/d_a_robson&quot;&gt;@d_a_robson&lt;/a&gt;) for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;. David is the author of &lt;em&gt;The Intelligence Trap&lt;/em&gt;, published in the UK and commonwealth by Hodder &amp;amp; Stoughton on 7 March. It is available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligence-Trap-People-Mistakes-Decisions/dp/1473669839/ref=tmm_hrd_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&quot;&gt;pre-order now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:59+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: The fake sex doctor and his bizarre research; prof alleged to have stolen student’s work; worst scientific scandal of all time?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/02/weekend-reads-the-fake-sex-doctor-and-his-bizarre-research-prof-alleged-to-have-stolen-students-work-worst-scientific-scandal-of-all-time/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87651</id>
		<updated>2019-03-02T14:37:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of a highly cited paper on the effects … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/02/weekend-reads-the-fake-sex-doctor-and-his-bizarre-research-prof-alleged-to-have-stolen-students-work-worst-scientific-scandal-of-all-time/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: The fake sex doctor and his bizarre research; prof alleged to have stolen student’s work; worst scientific scandal of all time?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Celebrate Open Data Day with Us!</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/eCMuFBXT4t4/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8469</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T22:08:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2019/03/screenshot-3-1-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the world tomorrow groups from all sectors will be celebrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://opendataday.org/&quot;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt; – an annual event that highlights the benefits of open data and encourages the adoption of open data policies in government, business and civil society. As publishers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/data-availability&quot;&gt;data availability&lt;/a&gt; is crucial for the validation and foundation of new research and key to our mission to help researchers advance the scientific record. In the spirit of Open Data Day, we’ve decided to defer to researchers and data enthusiasts to answer the questions: why is data important and how can we make it better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got our answers from &lt;a href=&quot;https://prabakaran-group.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Sudhakaran Prabakaran&lt;/a&gt;, one of a number of dedicated volunteers at Cambridge University known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.data.cam.ac.uk/intro-data-champions&quot;&gt;Data Champions&lt;/a&gt; who are helping advise members of the research community on managing their data. Read his thoughts below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are the Data Champions? What kinds of data questions do you help researchers navigate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think it’s a fantastic forum. [We have] a lot of discussions and people exchange ideas and not necessarily just in the sciences but also in every other field. [Data management] can be kind of confusing, even simple things like can I put my [datasets] in Dropbox? Can I share them in Google Drive? You’re talking about even labeling stuff in desktop computers. There is no clarity because this landscape is fast-moving and people are not trained to catch up with that kind of speed at which things change.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you working on right now? How does open data play a role in it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our lab thrives on open data. We train machine learning algorithms that looks at specific regions of the human genome and trying to identify the most important mutations and then identify drugs to target them. Most of the datasets I work with people have already published and analyzed those datasets and they’ve extracted what they want. I’m kind of looking at things that they don’t want – I’m looking at non-coding regions, just kind of digging deeper into the datasets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you think open data is important? What do you think the future open data landscape looks like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t think open data is enough…it’s the analysis also. For example, we train a lot of machine learning algorithms and in the process we fail many, many times and we know the pitfalls we know what to avoid. But if you share that process with other people that will enable them to overcome it, to get there. It is very difficult and that process can be shared with people.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think future young people are going to be brought up in an environment where they can just click something and get access to the code and get access to the data themselves. And then the issues of reproducibility would be mitigated if you can share what you’ve done and the data set is there for other people to work with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give to authors and researchers to encourage them to share their data?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think we have encountered these scenarios even as a data champion in my own department. I think if you if you have incentives, as in [getting] your DOI and authorships for the dataset even before publication then it’s easy to share. It’s your data, [someone] can probably do a different kind of analysis and publish it but they have to cite this data and you will be benefited by that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;And it’s in the best interest of the authors to share it ahead of time because of reproducibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can you do to encourage good data management?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can practice the open data lifestyle by sharing your research data in an open repository and making it available when you submit your manuscript. If you’re reviewing a submission, knowing how to evaluate the associated datasets can be tricky which is why we’ve worked with the Data Champions to cover everything you need to know in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://plos-marketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Marketing/Peer+Reviewing+Datasets.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewer’s Quick Guide to Assessing Datasets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If the manuscript you’re reviewing doesn’t have an associated dataset, request it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the Data Champions Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Data Champions Programme is a network of volunteers who advise members of the research community on proper handling of research data. In this, they promote good research data management (RDM) and support Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Re-usable (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ukdataservice.ac.uk/news-and-events/newsitem/?id=4615&quot;&gt;FAIR&lt;/a&gt;) research principles. It is run by the Research Data Management Facility at the University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/eCMuFBXT4t4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Madison Crystal</name>
			<uri>https://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>https://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Ryohei Yasuda Receives $2.9M NIH Grant</title>
		<link href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/ryohei-yasuda-receives-2-9m-nih-grant/"/>
		<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=11878</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T20:20:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Dr. Ryohei Yasuda of the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI) has received a grant by the National Institute of Mental Health of the NIH. The award is for $2.9 million over 5 years and will continue the funding of Yasuda’s work with Rab proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using cutting-edge imaging techniques, Dr. Yasuda is studying Rab proteins’ impact on learning and memory by tracking how molecules become activated and interact with each other. By better understanding how these proteins communicate with each other, scientists may one day be able to develop interventions for Alzheimer’s, Parkinson’s Disease and other brain disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Yasuda is a Scientific Director of MPFI and leads the Neuronal Signal Transduction Lab. He has received many recognitions for his outstanding research in neuroscience, including the 2015 National Institute of Health’s (NIH) Pioneer Award, which recognizes scientists demonstrating creativity and groundbreaking approaches in biomedical or behavioral science. Dr. Yasuda was one of only 13 scientists in the country to receive the NIH Pioneer Award in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional awards include the Career Award at the Scientific Interface from the Burroughs Wellcome Fund, the Alfred P. Sloan Fellowship, the New Investigator Award from the Alzheimer’s Association, and Research Award for Innovative Neuroscience from the Society for Neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Yasuda received his PhD in Physics in 1998 from Keio University Graduate School of Science and Technology in Yokohama, Japan. In his PhD studies, he demonstrated that the enzyme ATP synthase is a rotary motor made of single molecule and that its energy conversion efficiency is close to 100%. From 2000 to 2005, he was a post-doctoral fellow at the Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory where he built an imaging device to monitor protein interactions in living cells with high sensitivity and resolution. From 2005 to 2012, he was an assistant professor of the Neurobiology department at the Duke University Medical Center where he developed a number of techniques to visualize signaling activity in single synapses. From 2009 to 2012, Dr. Yasuda served as an Early Career Scientist at the Howard Hughes Medical Institute before coming to MPFI in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Katie Edwards</name>
			<uri>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/"/>
			<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Eating a lot of fiber could improve some cancer treatments</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/eating-lot-fiber-could-improve-some-cancer-treatments"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/eating-lot-fiber-could-improve-some-cancer-treatments</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T17:32:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A high-fiber diet, which boosts the diversity of gut microbes, may make an immune therapy against skin cancer more effective.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s how long the periodic table’s unstable elements last</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/periodic-table-life-spans-unstable-radioactive-elements"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/periodic-table-life-spans-unstable-radioactive-elements</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T16:02:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Most elements on the periodic table have at least one stable form. But some don’t. Here’s how long those unstable members endure.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carmen Drahl</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sleeping in on the weekend can’t make up for lost sleep</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sleep-recovery-weekend-health"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sleep-recovery-weekend-health</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T12:54:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Using the weekend to catch up on sleep is ineffective at making-up for lost sleep and offsetting the consequences to a person’s health.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeremy Rehm</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-08T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Retraction Watch readers, we need your help to be able to continue our work</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/01/retraction-watch-readers-we-need-your-help-to-be-able-to-continue-our-work-4/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87585</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T11:00:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Dear Retraction Watch readers: Maybe you’re a researcher who likes keeping up with developments in scientific integrity. Maybe you’re a reporter who has found a story idea on the blog. Maybe you’re an ethics instructor who uses the site to find case studies. Or a publisher who uses our blog to screen authors who submit … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/03/01/retraction-watch-readers-we-need-your-help-to-be-able-to-continue-our-work-4/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch readers, we need your help to be able to continue our work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Martin Birchall innocent, UCL decides once again</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2019/03/01/martin-birchall-innocent-ucl-decides-once-again/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=38011</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T10:47:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In yet another investigation, UCL whitewashed Martin Birchall of all responsibilities. I publish here the confidential report and excerpts from a secret PhD thesis, which the UCL committee carefully avoided to read.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:04+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This Diary Study Just Happened To Be Taking Place When Disaster Struck, Providing A Rare Insight Into Vicarious Experience Of Traumatic Events</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/01/this-diary-study-just-happened-to-be-taking-place-when-disaster-struck-providing-a-rare-insight-into-vicarious-experience-of-traumatic-events/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36590</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T10:36:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-452721474.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36591&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36591&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;KOOG AAN DE ZAAN, NETHERLANDS - JULY 26: Graffiti on a wall commemorates the victims of the Malaysia Airlines Flight MH17 crash underneath a flyover July 26, 2014 in Koog aan de Zaan, The Netherlands. The aircraft was allegedly shot down by a missile and investigations continue over the perpetrators of the attack. (Photo by Michel Porro\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1406054949&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2014 Michel Porro&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dutch Reaction After 189 Of Their Citizens Perish On Flight MH17&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Dutch Reaction After 189 Of Their Citizens Perish On Flight MH17&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-452721474.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-452721474.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-452721474.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3500,1977&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/03/01/this-diary-study-just-happened-to-be-taking-place-when-disaster-struck-providing-a-rare-insight-into-vicarious-experience-of-traumatic-events/dutch-reaction-after-189-of-their-citizens-perish-on-flight-mh17/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/gettyimages-452721474.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;Matthew Warren&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major disasters clearly take a toll on the survivors who had the misfortune to go through them. But there is another group of people who can suffer mental and physical distress from disasters: those who experience them second-hand, through media coverage and conversation. After 9/11, for example, researchers found an increase in symptoms of &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/002214650504600304&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2014-10485-003&quot;&gt;stress&lt;/a&gt; among Americans who hadn’t directly experienced the terrorist attacks.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there have always been doubts about studies purporting to show evidence of vicarious distress. Because disasters occur randomly researchers are usually unable to gather data until weeks after the event, and they often have no record of people’s baseline mood before the disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By chance a new study was able to overcome these limitations. When tragedy struck the Netherlands in 2014, there was a ready-made group of participants who were already recording their daily experiences. In May of that year, Bertus Jeronimus and colleagues at the University of Groningen had begun a crowd-sourced diary study called “HowNutsAreTheDutch” to examine mental health in the Netherlands. Three times per day for 30 days, participants completed questionnaires on their phones that measured their mood and recent activities.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months into the project, on 17 July 2014, Malaysian Airlines flight MH17, en route from Amsterdam to Kuala Lumpur, was shot down over Ukraine by pro-Russian separatists, killing all 298 on board. One hundred and ninety-six of the victims were Dutch and the disaster received widespread attention in the Dutch media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their study published recently in the &lt;i&gt;British Journal of Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, Jeronimus and colleagues took advantage of this tragic twist of fate and &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/bjop.12358&quot;&gt;examined the data&lt;/a&gt; gathered from 141 participants who were taking part around the time of the MH17 crash, to see how they were affected by their vicarious experience of the disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36590&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team compared participants’ ratings of their mood and physical discomfort in the three days immediately following the crash with their average ratings earlier and later in the study. In each questionnaire, participants had rated themselves for six positive moods (e.g. energetic, cheerful) and six negative moods (e.g. irritable, tired). The questionnaires also measured the extent of general physical discomfort – for example, experience of symptoms like headaches or diarrhoea.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, in the three days after the crash the participants showed a higher level of negative emotion and a lower level of positive emotion, and also reported more physical discomfort. But although statistically significant these responses were pretty small: each rating scale ranged from 0 to 100, and the biggest effect (for physical discomfort) represented a change of just 2.78 points on this scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers then looked at whether these changes were associated with aspects of participants’ personality like neuroticism and extraversion. These results were surprising: they had expected that people high in neuroticism, who worry and ruminate a lot, might be more affected by the crash – but in fact these participants tended to show &lt;i&gt;less&lt;/i&gt; of a reduction in positive mood than people low in neuroticism. On the other hand, strong extraverts, who usually score higher on happiness and mood than introverts, tended to have a greater drop in mood than the quieter types.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors speculated that extraverts tend to socialise more and so could have spent more time talking about the disaster with others, precipitating a drop in their mood. High scorers on neuroticism, they suggested, might be more likely to respond to stress that directly involves themselves, rather than vicarious experiences.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personality had no association with changes to negative mood, and overall the authors concluded that “broad personality domains are of little importance in predicting differences in vicarious exposure effects.” In this respect, age seemed more important: older participants tended to have less of an increase in negative emotions. Older people may have better strategies for coping with traumatic events, the author say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the study was exploratory, it provides a rare insight into how indirect experience of disasters can affect the general population, albeit in small ways. But while the MH17 crash was a shocking event, it also occurred halfway across Europe and didn’t involve a continuing threat to the population of the Netherlands, which, the authors say, “may have allowed them to retain their sense of safety”. The effects of vicariously experiencing a more immediate disaster – and the importance of personality differences in this response – could be quite different.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/bjop.12358&quot;&gt;Acute stress responses after indirect exposure to the MH17 airplane crash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Graffiti on a wall commemorates the victims of the Malaysia Airlines Flight MH17 crash underneath a flyover July 26, 2014 in Koog aan de Zaan, The Netherlands (Photo by Michel Porro/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Warren (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;@MattbWarren&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">4 principles for unlocking the full potential of research data</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-principles-for-unlocking-the-full-potential-of-research-data"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-principles-for-unlocking-the-full-potential-of-research-data</id>
		<updated>2019-03-01T10:20:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Research data doesn’t just need to be available – it needs to be comprehensible and interoperable, says Elsevier’s VP of Research Data Management Solutions</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Help for Account Administrators</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/help-for-account-administrators/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2337</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T20:29:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 Access to this post restricted.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Wireless patches can comfortably monitor sick babies’ health</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wireless-patches-can-comfortably-monitor-sick-babies-health"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wireless-patches-can-comfortably-monitor-sick-babies-health</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T19:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New skin sensors that wirelessly transmit health data could offer a less invasive way to keep tabs on newborns in the neonatal intensive care unit.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How singing mice belt out duets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/singing-mice-duets-brain-patterns-human-speech"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/singing-mice-duets-brain-patterns-human-speech</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T19:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A precise timing system in the brain helps musical rodents from the cloud forests of Costa Rica sing to one another.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Oceans that are warming due to climate change yield fewer fish</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oceans-are-warming-due-climate-change-yield-fewer-fish"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oceans-are-warming-due-climate-change-yield-fewer-fish</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T19:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Warming water due to climate change is diminishing sustainable fishery yields in the world’s oceans.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What spiders eating weird stuff tell us about complex Amazon food webs</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spider-tarantula-eating-weird-stuff-complex-amazon-food-webs"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spider-tarantula-eating-weird-stuff-complex-amazon-food-webs</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T16:09:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 By documenting rare events of invertebrates eating small vertebrates, scientists are shedding new light on the Amazon rainforest’s intricate ecosystem.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeremy Rehm</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:49+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Watching hours of TV is tied to verbal memory decline in older people</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/watching-hours-tv-tied-verbal-memory-decline-older-people"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/watching-hours-tv-tied-verbal-memory-decline-older-people</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T14:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The more television people age 50 and up watched, the worse they recalled a list of words in tests years later, a study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, people thought MSG caused ‘Chinese restaurant syndrome’</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-msg-chinese-restaurant-syndrome"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-msg-chinese-restaurant-syndrome</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T12:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In the 1960s, people blamed monosodium glutamate in Chinese food for making them sick, but the claim hasn't stood up to time or science.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Allie Wilkinson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Nursing – Highlights of 2018</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/02/28/bmc-nursing-highlights-of-2018/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10845</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/Nursing-6-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnurs.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12912-018-0321-z&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Multimorbidity  – a Twitter investigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multimorbidity is the co-occurrence of two or more chronic medical conditions in a patient. Technological and social changes are resulting in increases in both sedentary lifestyles and life expectancy, which in turn lead to more people developing multimorbidity. This trends has begun putting significant pressures on the medical sector and its infrastructure. Nurses, in particular, are faced with significant challenges whilst coordinating multiple care plans for their patients’ individual conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10851&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10851 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;176&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/nurs-twitter-300x176.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Most frequently used words during the #FutNur Twitter chat, from O’Connor et al.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Florence Nightingale Fodunation took to Twitter to ask nurses four questions related to multimorbidity and encouraged Twitter users to suggest solutions and to debate amongst each other. Twenty-four users responded using the hashtag created by the foundation, #FutNur, potentially reaching over 50,000 Twitter users. In a recent paper, O’Connor &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; used these data to research what nurses believe is needed to care for patients with multimorbidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The replies were grouped into five particular themes of what the nursing profession must focus on in order to effectively cope with morbidity. Helping patients and their friends and family deal with the burden of having multiple chronic conditions was the initial focus. Next was the type of care nurses need to deliver, with the respondents believing holistic care is essential. Additional themes were the need for more evidence on methods of treating multimorbidity and the quality of education nurses receive regarding this issue. Finally, the respondents expressed a frustration in the way the health services were designed, and several suggestions were made to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors concluded that Twitter, and other social media, can potentially be very helpful in research amongst health professionals. Furthermore, they found that there are many ways in which coping with multimorbidity can be made easier. These include investing in research and nursing education surrounding the topic and creating better tools and guidelines to help nurses care for those with multimorbidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnurs.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12912-018-0277-z&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;From apprehension to advocacy:  nursing students’ experiences with care home placement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As populations around the world age, more nurses with experience caring for older adults are needed. However, lack of interest among nursing students and insufficient education in nursing schools focused on care of older adults have contributed to a nursing workforce, already stretched thin across all fields, that is not prepared to care for this growing demographic. One potential solution is placement of nursing students within residential aged care (RAC) settings for clinical education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to explore key stakeholders’ experiences with nursing student placement in RAC, Moquin &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; conducted a qualitative study using a participatory action research approach. Nursing students were interviewed both before and after placement, and their instructors, RAC staff, and residents were interviewed after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study found that although students began their placements with a range of concerns, over the course of the placement, they became comfortable in the setting and actively engaged with and advocated for the residents.  Although many of the students indicated that they were unlikely to pursue a career in RAC, they did value the skills learned and felt that they would be better prepared to care for older patients in other settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnurs.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12912-018-0309-8&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nurses’ experiences of an unfamiliar method of assisted suicide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assisted suicide in Switzerland is legal and not uncommon. Voluntary Stopping of Eating and Drinking (VSED) is a method of actively hastening one’s own death, and doesn’t require a doctor’s approval or a terminal diagnosis, though it does often require medical support from nurses or medical staff. It is the individual’s choice, and it allows them, and their friends and families, time to prepare for their death. But how do nurses feel about VSED in their professional role?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saladin &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; conducted an embedded single case study of a patient living in a long-term care institution choosing to end her life via VSED. By conducting group and individual interviews, they gathered information regarding the impact of this choice on those closest to the patient, including relatives and care institution staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the interviews showed that the nursing staff felt obliged to help the patient hasten her death via VSED, as it was her choice to do so. They further described how the general manager of the institution initially did not want to allow VSED to occur, but the nursing staff advocated for the patient. In doing so, the staff sometimes struggled between caring for the person and arguing with the institution they worked for. They had to find an acceptable way both for the patient to be allowed to choose her death and for the institution to be comfortable with the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10850&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10850 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;86&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2019/02/nurs-VSED-300x86.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;VSED in the field of tension between suicide and natural dying from Saladin et al.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study concludes that the attitude of the institution itself can be decisive in how VSED is dealt with; VSED can be perceived as suicide or as natural dying, and institutions are generally less comfortable with the former. Therefore, the authors believe it is important that health care professionals develop a professional opinion of VSED, thereby benefiting patients who choose VSED towards the end of their lives, as well as their relatives and those who care for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnurs.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12912-018-0272-4&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nursing education challenges and solutions in Sub-Saharan Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the healthcare interventions launched as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/&quot;&gt;Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/a&gt; rely on a sufficient workforce of nurses with relevant competencies, but Sub-Saharan Africa has an estimated shortfall of 600,000 nurses needed for these initiatives. Improvements in nursing education are needed to increase the nursing workforce and improve the quality of healthcare. This review from Bvumbwe and Mtshali integrated literature reporting on nursing education challenges and their solutions, in order to identify needs for and possible methods of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systematic and targeted searches of academic and gray literature led to a final sample of 20 academic and five gray-literature articles. Thematic analysis was used to identify six themes, representing different challenges and their possible solutions: curriculum reforms, professional regulation, transformative teaching strategies, collaboration and partnership, capacity building, and infrastructure and resources. Within each of these areas, gaps and unmet demands were identified along with reforms and interventions that were beginning to address them in some contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review highlighted common challenges in nursing education faced by many of the countries in Sub-Saharan Africa, from lack of infrastructure to insufficient faculty. Strategies to address these challenges are being implemented and this review points to those that have had positive effects and to where further efforts are needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2019/02/28/bmc-nursing-highlights-of-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;BMC Nursing&lt;/i&gt; – Highlights of 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tovah Honor Aronin &amp;#38; Lauren Mcmillan</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:46+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author, author? Dispute over authorship leads to two retraction notices, and confusion</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/28/author-author-dispute-over-authorship-leads-to-two-retraction-notices-and-confusion/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87325</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T11:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An endocrinology journal has pulled a 2017 paper by a group from Russia and Romania because, well, maybe it’s just better if you read for yourself. The article, “Testosterone promotes anxiolytic-like behavior in gonadectomized male rats via blockade of the 5-HT1A receptors,” appeared in General and Comparative Endocrinology, an Elsevier publication. The paper in fact … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/28/author-author-dispute-over-authorship-leads-to-two-retraction-notices-and-confusion/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Author, author? Dispute over authorship leads to two retraction notices, and confusion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Adam Marcus</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These Are The Pre-match Emotional Control Strategies That Higher-ranked Table Tennis Players Use More Than Lower-ranked Players</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/28/these-are-the-pre-match-emotional-control-strategies-that-higher-ranked-table-tennis-players-use-more-than-lower-ranked-players/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36560</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:59:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-691190188.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36570&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36570&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Bongarts\/Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;DUSSELDORF, GERMANY - JUNE 01: Bastian Steger of Germany in action during Men Single second round at Table Tennis World Championship at Messe Duesseldorf on June 1, 2017 in Dusseldorf, Germany. (Photo by Maja Hitij\/Bongarts\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1496333041&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;300&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.001&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Table Tennis World Championship - Day 4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Table Tennis World Championship – Day 4&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-691190188.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-691190188.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-691190188.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,683&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/28/these-are-the-pre-match-emotional-control-strategies-that-higher-ranked-table-tennis-players-use-more-than-lower-ranked-players/table-tennis-world-championship-day-4/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-691190188.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contact sports like boxing and rugby you can use your pre-match nerves to fuel your determination, speed and aggression. In contrast, in a sport like table tennis that involves fine motor control, nerves can also stifle your performance, making you stiff and clumsy. It seems obvious that learning to control your emotions prior to games should therefore be important to table tennis players (and competitors in other sports that require precision). Yet, surprisingly, as the authors of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jopy.12451?af=R&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality&lt;/em&gt; point out, “to date, only a few studies have investigated the relation between emotional regulation and … sport performance”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more, Jeanette Kubiak and her colleagues, at Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz, surveyed hundreds of league table tennis players in Germany about the ways they controlled their emotions prior to matches, and then compared these results against objective measures of the participants’ league performance. The research uncovered several emotional control strategies used more often by better and improving players. “Taken together, the findings provide evidence for the importance of emotion regulation regarding sport performance,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36560&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 300 table tennis players took part covering a wide range of ability and with an average of 24 years experience playing the game (the average age was 39 and there were 70 women). Reflecting on the prior season, players rated how often they tended to use ten different emotional control strategies based on the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/1047840X.2014.940781&quot;&gt;process model of emotion regulation&lt;/a&gt;” put forward by Stanford clinical psychologist James Gross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers looked at two end-of-season objective measures of success. The first was the players’ end-of-season ranking. They found that higher-ranked players more often calmed their pre-match nerves by: using physical preparation (e.g. swinging their arms and getting warmed up); using positive self-talk (e.g. telling themselves they will win); planning (e.g. thinking about their tactics); and by suppressing their negative emotions and deliberately giving off an impression of supreme confidence. At the same time, higher-ranked players &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; often reported catastrophising, such as thinking how badly the game could go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second outcome measure was improved performance over the previous season – that is, winning more games this season than last. Improving players more often used positive self-talk and less often indulged in self-blame (e.g. thinking they should have practiced more); ruminated less about their anxious feelings; and catastrophised less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study is limited by its cross-sectional design. For instance, it’s possible that winning and earning a higher ranking changed how players managed their emotions, rather than emotional regulation driving better performance. The retrospective nature of the survey is another short-coming – it’s even possible that winning changes how players think about and remember their emotional strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, as Kubiak and her team point out, “no [previous] studies have investigated several emotion regulation strategies affiliated with different stages in the process model of emotion regulation in handling emotions prior to a competition”.  They added that their findings “are interesting for sports psychology because they help to clarify why some competitive athletes fail to take full advantage of their performance potential, whereas others are successful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jopy.12451?af=R&quot;&gt;Keep your cool and win the game: Emotion regulation and performance in table tennis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Bastian Steger of Germany in action during Men Single second round at Table Tennis World Championship at Messe Duesseldorf on June 1, 2017 ( Maja Hitij / Getty Images Staff)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and represents the Steyning B team in the second division of the Worthing and District Table Tennis League.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Approval Workflow – How does the automatically added Approval feature work?</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/approval-workflow-how-does-the-automatically-added-approval-feature-work/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2329</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:38:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2329&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2329&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Direct integration – What is direct integration?</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/direct-integration-what-is-direct-integration/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2328</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:32:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Access to this post restricted.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Billing – How do I set up invoicing?</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/billing-how-do-i-set-up-invoicing/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2327</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:28:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2327&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2327&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Providers – Custom Contracts</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/providers-custom-contracts/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2325</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:24:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2325&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2325&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Providers – Provider notes</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/providers-provider-notes/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2322</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T06:10:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2322&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2322&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Providers – Sanctioned providers</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/providers-sanctioned-providers/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2319</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T05:58:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2319&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2319&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Billing – Currency</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/billing-and-purchase-orders-currency/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2316</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T05:51:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2316&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2316&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Administrator Dashboard – Group Membership</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/administrator-dashboard-group-membership/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2314</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T05:40:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2314&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2314&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Administrator Dashboard – Navigation and Access</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/administrator-dashboard-navigation-and-access-2/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2312</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T05:29:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2312&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2312&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protected: Administrator Dashboard – Navigation and Access</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/administrator-dashboard-navigation-and-access/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2281</id>
		<updated>2019-02-28T04:57:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;form action=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-login.php?action=postpass&amp;amp;wpe-login=true&quot; class=&quot;post-password-form&quot; method=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;pwbox-2281&quot;&gt;Password: &lt;input id=&quot;pwbox-2281&quot; name=&quot;post_password&quot; size=&quot;20&quot; type=&quot;password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/label&gt; &lt;input name=&quot;Submit&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Enter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science Exchange Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Managing R&amp;amp;D services with Science Exchange: How technology solutions are driving market success</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/managing-rd-services-with-science-exchange-how-technology-solutions-are-driving-market-success/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2217</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T20:36:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-2217&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-a9f6216 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;a9f6216&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-4957798 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;4957798&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-3891ad2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;3891ad2&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://cporising.com/2019/02/08/managing-the-long-tail-of-rd-spend-a-briefing-with-science-exchange/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on CPORising.com,  the largest website focused on procurement and supply management, analysts from Ardent Partners reviewed Science Exchange’s solution for managing a large, complex spend category: R&amp;amp;D services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;CPORising’s author, Andrew Bartolini, first outlined the market opportunity and core needs for R&amp;amp;D Services Management solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;He then described how Science Exchange helps organizations accelerate innovation with its secure, collaborative solution tailored to the R&amp;amp;D function.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Finally, Bartolini shared insights into the future of R&amp;amp;D services management and the importance of R&amp;amp;D marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Read the full post on CPORising.com:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9a3242d elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button&quot; data-element_type=&quot;button.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9a3242d&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
			&lt;a class=&quot;elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-lg&quot; href=&quot;http://cporising.com/2019/02/08/managing-the-long-tail-of-rd-spend-a-briefing-with-science-exchange/&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-content-wrapper&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-icon elementor-align-icon-left&quot;&gt;
				&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-book&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
			&lt;/span&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-text&quot;&gt;READ ARTICLE&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-5054ae9 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;5054ae9&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-6564b04 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image&quot; data-element_type=&quot;image.default&quot; data-id=&quot;6564b04&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-image&quot;&gt;
											&lt;a data-elementor-open-lightbox=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://cporising.com/2019/02/08/managing-the-long-tail-of-rd-spend-a-briefing-with-science-exchange/&quot;&gt;
							&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;elementor-animation-grow attachment-medium_large size-medium_large&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/CPO-Rising-Post-Thumbnail-768x851.png&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;								&lt;/a&gt;
											&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-7702cf2 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;7702cf2&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-97c488f elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;97c488f&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-1a68e9f elementor-widget elementor-widget-spacer&quot; data-element_type=&quot;spacer.default&quot; data-id=&quot;1a68e9f&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chandreyee Das</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:03:54+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This parasitic cuckoo bird shows cheaters don’t always get ahead</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/parasitic-cuckoo-bird-shows-cheaters-dont-always-get-ahead"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/parasitic-cuckoo-bird-shows-cheaters-dont-always-get-ahead</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T20:22:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Birds called greater anis that can slip extra eggs into other nests create a natural test of the benefits of honest parenting.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genes might explain why dogs can’t sniff out some people under stress</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gene-people-dogs-scent-smell-stress"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gene-people-dogs-scent-smell-stress</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T19:45:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Genes and stress may change a person’s body odor, confusing police dogs.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T12:00:49+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Treating mosquitoes may be a new way to fight malaria</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/treating-mosquitoes-drugs-new-way-fight-malaria"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/treating-mosquitoes-drugs-new-way-fight-malaria</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T18:35:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A lab test suggests it may be possible to treat mosquitoes infected with the malaria parasite to stop disease transmission.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T12:00:49+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">3 explanations for ‘Oumuamua that aren’t alien spaceships</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/explanations-oumuamua-not-alien-spaceships"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/explanations-oumuamua-not-alien-spaceships</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T16:18:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Astronomers are coming up with some creative ideas to explain the weird behavior of the first known interstellar object.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PreScouter Joins Science Exchange to Offer Online Access to Technology Scouting Services</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/prescouter-joins-science-exchange-to-offer-online-access-to-technology-scouting-services/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2181</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T15:50:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-2181&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-3430480 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;3430480&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-4a779bf elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;4a779bf&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-90e44fd elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-inner-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;90e44fd&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-049f85b elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-inner-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;049f85b&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9fe8047 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9fe8047&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/prescouter-inc&quot;&gt;PreScouter&lt;/a&gt; are partnering to offer online access to its scouting services, including tech landscaping, literature review, and vetting of new opportunities for scientists around the globe.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/prescouter-inc&quot;&gt;PreScouter&lt;/a&gt; is a Chicago-based research services firm whose mission is to connect pharma and biotech organizations with disruptive innovations and technologies being developed around the world. PreScouter helps innovation minded researchers cast a wide net with unmatched efficiency. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9fac2ab elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button&quot; data-element_type=&quot;button.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9fac2ab&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
			&lt;a class=&quot;elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-md&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/prescouter-inc&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-content-wrapper&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-text&quot;&gt;Explore Prescouter Services&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-a7a5b86 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-inner-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;a7a5b86&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-b144211 elementor-widget elementor-widget-testimonial&quot; data-element_type=&quot;testimonial.default&quot; data-id=&quot;b144211&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-wrapper&quot;&gt;
							&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-content&quot;&gt;“We are proud to team up with Science Exchange to offer end-to-end scouting and intelligence gathering services to R&amp;amp;D and innovation leaders within the healthcare community. We’ve assisted our clients in developing landscapes of areas such as: drug delivery systems, drug target identification, diagnostics, genome editing, A.I. applications, personalized medicine, digital biomarkers, new treatments, therapies, regulatory pathways and much more. These projects require an immense amount of time and over 500 companies have leveraged PreScouter to increase their scientific bandwidth.” &lt;/div&gt;
			
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-meta elementor-has-image elementor-testimonial-image-position-aside&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-meta-inner&quot;&gt;
											&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-image&quot;&gt;
							&lt;img alt=&quot;Prescouter logo on Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;attachment-full size-full&quot; height=&quot;382&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Prescouter-logo.png&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; /&gt;						&lt;/div&gt;
					
										&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-details&quot;&gt;
													&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-name&quot;&gt;Ashish Basuray&lt;/div&gt;
																			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-testimonial-job&quot;&gt;Chief Scientist &amp;amp; Co-Founder.&lt;/div&gt;
											&lt;/div&gt;
									&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-3a221d3 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;3a221d3&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-44232ee elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;44232ee&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-cdc34f6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;cdc34f6&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;About PreScouter&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PreScouter provides research support services to help healthcare leaders make better R&amp;amp;D,  product development, and corporate development decisions. PreScouter’s custom-selected teams of advanced degree researchers and industry experts connect leaders with new markets, commercializable technologies, industry-impacting startups, and other actionable insights and data. PreScouter’s client list includes top healthcare companies such as: Bristol Myers Squibb, Hill-Rom, and Becton Dickinson.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Max Smith-Gee</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-02-28T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">ASP: Learning to Forget With Adaptive Synaptic Plasticity in Spiking Neural Networks</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2019/02/27/asp-learning-to-forget-with-adaptive-synaptic-plasticity-in-spiking-neural-networks.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2019-02-27:/2019/02/27/asp-learning-to-forget-with-adaptive-synaptic-plasticity-in-spiking-neural-networks.html</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T15:41:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Sam Sutton's journal club session, where he will present the paper &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/8094937&quot;&gt;ASP, Learning to Forget With Adaptive Synaptic Plasticity in Spiking Neural Networks (Panda et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fundamental feature of learning in animals is the “ability to forget” that allows an organism to perceive, model, and make decisions from disparate streams of information and adapt to changing environments. Against this backdrop, we present a novel unsupervised learning mechanism adaptive synaptic plasticity (ASP) for improved recognition with spiking neural networks (SNNs) for real time online learning in a dynamic environment. We incorporate an adaptive weight decay mechanism with the traditional spike timing dependent plasticity (STDP) learning to model adaptivity in SNNs. The leak rate of the synaptic weights is modulated based on the temporal correlation between the spiking patterns of the pre- and post-synaptic neurons. This mechanism helps in gradual forgetting of insignificant data while retaining significant, yet old, information. ASP, thus, maintains a balance between forgetting and immediate learning to construct a stable-plastic self-adaptive SNN for continuously changing inputs. We demonstrate that the proposed learning methodology addresses catastrophic forgetting, while yielding significantly improved accuracy over the conventional STDP learning method for digit recognition applications. In addition, we observe that the proposed learning model automatically encodes selective attention toward relevant features in the input data, while eliminating the influence of background noise (or denoising) further improving the robustness of the ASP learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 01/03/2019 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: D118&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rebecca Miko</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2019-02-27T15:41:47+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Webinar March 5: Discover New Biology Using VERG</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/webinar-march-5-discover-new-biology-using-verg/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2296</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T15:27:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-2296&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2991300 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2991300&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26cab16 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26cab16&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9ff5ae9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9ff5ae9&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time: March 5, 2019 • 9am PDT | 12pm EDT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn about VERG, a novel high-throughput cell platform for characterizing genes and proteins of interest. VERG enables organisations to rapidly understand the effects of coding variations on their genes/proteins of interest as it relates to biology, drug development and synthetic biology. Helping to power VERG is VariantFind&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;, a patent pending technology for building DNA variant libraries. VariantFind’s three-step (design, build and validate) workflow helps organizations build scanning and combinatorial libraries in a powerful and flexible manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The webinar features VERG experts from Ranomics, an innovative biotechnology company that helps organizations enable transformative discoveries using genomics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-68b5144 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button&quot; data-element_type=&quot;button.default&quot; data-id=&quot;68b5144&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
			&lt;a class=&quot;elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-lg&quot; href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/VERGRanomicswebinar&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-content-wrapper&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-icon elementor-align-icon-left&quot;&gt;
				&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-calendar&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
			&lt;/span&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-text&quot;&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2f0bd775 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2f0bd775&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26df1849 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26df1849&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-7dffee7a elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;7dffee7a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Join this webinar to learn about:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How exploiting genetic variations can help you build and engineer better life sciences products&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How to find genetic variations, for example, that are in proximity to exon-intron junctions, therefore having a high chance of perturbing gene function, and which could result in disease causation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How VERG technology can help you measure binding interactions across thousands of protein variants in a single workflow.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;…and more.&lt;div class=&quot;description&quot; data-id=&quot;8104&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row speakers-container&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-12&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-33b960b elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;33b960b&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-3cbe186 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;3cbe186&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2fbe561 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;2fbe561&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Presenter: Nikko Torres, Ph.D.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;i&gt;Research Scientist, Ranomics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nikko Torres, Ph.D. is a research scientist at Ranomics, where he develops highly parallel cell-based functional assays and generates DNA variant libraries. Nikko is a cell biologist and data analyst with over a decade of experience in developing high-throughput methods to ask macro-level questions in microbiology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-5084c47 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;5084c47&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-dde38b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image&quot; data-element_type=&quot;image.default&quot; data-id=&quot;dde38b6&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-image&quot;&gt;
										&lt;img alt=&quot;Nikko Torres Ranomics Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Nikko-Torres-Ranomics-Science-Exchange.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;											&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-340b6e4 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;340b6e4&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-05e8b7e elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;05e8b7e&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-c01fe7e elementor-widget elementor-widget-spacer&quot; data-element_type=&quot;spacer.default&quot; data-id=&quot;c01fe7e&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chandreyee Das</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-02-28T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Will scientific error checkers become as ubiquitous as spell-checkers?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/27/will-scientific-error-checkers-become-as-ubiquitous-as-spell-checkers/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87304</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 How common are calculation errors in the scientific literature? And can they be caught by an algorithm?  James Heathers and Nick Brown came up with two methods — GRIM and SPRITE — to find such mistakes. And a 2017 study of which we just became aware offers another approach. Jonathan Wren and Constantin Georgescu of the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/27/will-scientific-error-checkers-become-as-ubiquitous-as-spell-checkers/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Will scientific error checkers become as ubiquitous as spell-checkers?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Benjamin Mazer</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Extreme elements push the boundaries of the periodic table</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-periodic-table-future-superheavy-elements"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-periodic-table-future-superheavy-elements</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The hunt for the next elements on the periodic table might turn up superheavy atoms that flaunt the rules of chemistry.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T12:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Language You Speak Predicts Your Ability To Remember The Different Parts Of Lists</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/27/the-language-you-speak-affects-your-ability-to-remember-the-different-parts-of-lists/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36556</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T10:43:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-925066994.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36562&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36562&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Human brain pop art background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Pop art vector illustration of side view human brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Pop art vector illustration of side view human brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-925066994.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-925066994.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-925066994.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/27/the-language-you-speak-affects-your-ability-to-remember-the-different-parts-of-lists/pop-art-vector-illustration-of-side-view-human-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-925066994.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;Matthew Warren&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, linguists have debated the extent to which language influences the way we think. While the more extreme theories that language &lt;i&gt;determines&lt;/i&gt; what we can and can’t think about have fallen out of favour, there is still considerable evidence that the languages we speak shape the way we see the world in more subtle ways.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, people are better at perceiving the difference between light and dark blue &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/11/02/your-native-language-affects-what-you-can-and-cant-see/&quot;&gt;if they have dedicated words for those colours&lt;/a&gt; (like in Russian) than if they don’t (like in English). But it turns out it’s not just the words that we use: the way in which a language is structured – its syntax – is also important. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-37654-9&quot;&gt;In a recent study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/i&gt;, Federica Amici and colleagues show that the word order of a language predicts how good its speakers are at remembering the first or last parts of a list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36556&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team conducted memory tasks with speakers of eight different languages around the world. Four of the languages were what’s known as right-branching – Ndonga, Khmer, Thai and Italian – and four were left-branching – Japanese, Korean, Khoekhoe and Sidaama. They included 24-30 speakers of each language, and tested them in their local area, with the help of a translator where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a right-branching language, the most important part of a phrase, known as the “head”, comes first, followed by words that give more information about that word. So in the phrase “The tiger who came to tea”, the head ‘tiger’ is at the beginning of the sentence, followed by words that reveal more about him (i.e. that he came to tea).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;A left-branching language is the opposite: the extra information comes first, and the head is at the end of the sentence. The same phrase in a left-branching language would be something like “who came to tea, the tiger”. (English is mainly right-branching, but has some left-branching tendencies: we put adjectives &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; the noun that they modify, as in “the hungry tiger”, rather than “the tiger hungry”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In right-branching languages, the meaning of a sentence is clear from the start because the head is encountered immediately. But in left-branching languages, speakers need to keep a lot of information in mind before they get to the important part of the sentence that clarifies what it’s all about. So the researchers wondered whether speakers of left-branching languages would be generally better at remembering the early parts of lists of stimuli.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants completed three tests designed to tap into working memory, which involves holding information in mind while also processing other information – a key skill in language. For each test, they viewed a sequence of pictures (or some other visual sequence) while simultaneously completing a second distracting task like performing mental arithmetic or judging whether an image was symmetrical. At the end of each series they had to recall the sequence they’d seen in the correct order. These sequences varied across tests and included pictures of animals and objects, different numbers of blue circles, and red squares in a series of grids.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team then compared how well the speakers of the two kinds of language remembered stimuli from the first and second halves of the sequences. As they predicted, left-branching speakers were better at recalling the first half of lists than right-branching speakers, and worse at recalling the second half.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results show how the languages we speak can have fairly broad influences on cognition, say the authors. “Specific characteristics of a language appear to predict not only the way we perceive and conceptualize the world,” they write, “but also the way we process, store and retrieve information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research also demonstrates how differences in culture and language can bias findings in psychology. For example, based almost entirely on Western participants, memory researchers have found that people tend to recall the first and last parts of lists better than the middle parts – phenomena referred to as the “primacy” and “recency” effects –&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;which have long been considered a fundamental aspect of how memory works. It is clear from this new study that the language participants speak could have a significant impact on these kinds of results, potentially challenging whether human memory always works that way.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for now, the study remains preliminary. The overall differences in memory between left- and right-branching languages appear fairly small, and the eight languages the authors studied are just a tiny fraction of the more than 7,000 spoken around the world. Whether the results will be replicated in a larger sample remains to be seen.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-37654-9&quot;&gt;The word order of languages predicts native speakers’ working memory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Warren (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattbwarren&quot;&gt;@MattbWarren&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Does being a woman matter in chemistry research?</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/does-being-a-woman-matter-in-chemistry-research"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/does-being-a-woman-matter-in-chemistry-research</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T09:37:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Three female chemistry professors share their experiences and advice about succeeding in this male-dominated field</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Colonel Cai, his postdoc Shen and the Weapons of Mass Fabrication</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2019/02/27/colonel-cai-his-postdoc-shen-and-the-weapons-of-mass-fabrication/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=37823</id>
		<updated>2019-02-27T06:00:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Smut Clyde and Tiger BB8 uncover a Chinese network which spreads over two cities and uses same stash of fake data to keep inventing  nanoparticle or TCM-based cures for diabetic brain damage and other diseases.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:01:04+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A long handshake can spread your DNA to objects you didn’t touch</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/long-handshake-spread-your-dna-objects-you-didnt-touch"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/long-handshake-spread-your-dna-objects-you-didnt-touch</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T19:53:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Two new studies show that even brief contact with another person or object could transfer your DNA far and wide.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T12:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Webinar Apr. 10: Clinical trial considerations in neurodegenerative disease</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2019/02/webinar-clinical-trial-considerations-in-neurodegenerative-disease/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=2290</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T17:59:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-2290&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2991300 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2991300&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26cab16 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26cab16&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9ff5ae9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9ff5ae9&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date/Time: April 10, 2019 • 1pm PDT | 4pm EDT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running clinical trials for neurodegenerative disease can be challenging, due to the complexity of studies, rapidly evolving knowledge of disease areas, regulatory considerations, obstacles facing patient recruitment, and difficulties in patient retention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing from her extensive experience in managing clinical trials in Alzheimer’s Disease, Parkinson’s Disease, Huntington’s Disease, and multiple other neurological disorders, Dr. Tina Soulis of Neuroscience Trials Australia will share best practices and helpful tips for moving clinical stage research forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2f0bd775 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2f0bd775&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26df1849 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26df1849&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-68b5144 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button&quot; data-element_type=&quot;button.default&quot; data-id=&quot;68b5144&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
			&lt;a class=&quot;elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-lg&quot; href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/l/89252/2019-02-17/5tdz1c&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-content-wrapper&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-icon elementor-align-icon-left&quot;&gt;
				&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-calendar&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
			&lt;/span&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-text&quot;&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-7dffee7a elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;7dffee7a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Join this webinar to learn about:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unique considerations for running clinical trials for neurodegeneration-related diseases, including choosing biomarkers, study design, and data management.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advantages of running clinical trials in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How to optimize patient recruitment and retention specifically for neurodegenerative diseases.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-33b960b elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;33b960b&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-3cbe186 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;3cbe186&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2fbe561 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;2fbe561&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Presenter: Tina Soulis&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;i&gt;CEO, Neuroscience Trials Australia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tina is considered an industry thought leader and Australian international advocate for clinical trials. She contributes to and is a pivotal member on many Australian and international clinical trial advocacy, policy and neurology focused leadership groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past 7 years, Tina has built up Neuroscience Trials Australia, a leading global specialised brand making Australia a destination for many overseas companies wanting to undertake neurology focused clinical research. This Contract Research Organisation (CRO) is globally unique and offers clients access to clinical trial sites, expertise and capabilities required to complete clinical development at global standard. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-5084c47 elementor-column elementor-col-50 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;5084c47&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-dde38b6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image&quot; data-element_type=&quot;image.default&quot; data-id=&quot;dde38b6&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-image&quot;&gt;
										&lt;img alt=&quot;Tina Soulis Neuroscience Trials Australia Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;attachment-medium size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.scienceexchange.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Tina-Soulis_300sq_desaturated.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;											&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-340b6e4 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;340b6e4&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-05e8b7e elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;05e8b7e&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-c01fe7e elementor-widget elementor-widget-spacer&quot; data-element_type=&quot;spacer.default&quot; data-id=&quot;c01fe7e&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-spacer-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chandreyee Das</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science Exchange Resources</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Stay abreast of the latest technologies, industry trends, and events that are shaping scientific communities.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2019-02-28T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">With its burning grip, shingles can do lasting damage</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/shingles-virus-rash-chicken-pox-complications"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/shingles-virus-rash-chicken-pox-complications</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T14:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Varicella zoster virus, which causes chickenpox and shingles, may instigate several other problems.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists set sail for the elusive island of stability</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-set-sail-elusive-island-stability"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-set-sail-elusive-island-stability</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T11:15:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Editor in Chief Nancy Shute discusses the search for the island of stability and the future of the periodic table.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nancy Shute</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-04T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Study claiming hate cuts 12 years off gay lives retracted</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/26/study-claiming-hate-cuts-12-years-off-gay-lives-retracted/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87411</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T11:00:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 After years of back and forth, a highly cited paper that appeared to show that gay people who live in areas where people were highly prejudiced against them had a significantly shorter life expectancy has been retracted. The paper, “Structural stigma and all-cause mortality in sexual minority populations,”  was published in 2014 by Mark Hatzenbuehler … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/26/study-claiming-hate-cuts-12-years-off-gay-lives-retracted/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Study claiming hate cuts 12 years off gay lives retracted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Mama’s Last Hug’ showcases the emotional lives of animals</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-book-showcases-emotional-lives-animals"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-book-showcases-emotional-lives-animals</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In ‘Mama’s Last Hug,’ Frans de Waal argues that emotions occur throughout the animal world.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erin Wayman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-04T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers ponder mitochondria, Neandertal diets, deep sea corals and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-ponder-mitochondria-neandertal-diets-deep-sea-corals-and-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-ponder-mitochondria-neandertal-diets-deep-sea-corals-and-more</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers had questions about mitochondrial DNA, Neandertal diets, deep ocean corals and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-04T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">The Lancet targets the gender gap in science, medicine and global health</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-lancet-targets-the-gender-gap-in-science-medicine-and-global-health"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-lancet-targets-the-gender-gap-in-science-medicine-and-global-health</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T10:23:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Special issue and campaign aim to break down systemic barriers to gender equity</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How Competitiveness Leads Us To Sabotage Other People’s Personal Goals At The Expense Of Our Own</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/26/how-competitiveness-leads-us-to-sabotage-other-peoples-personal-goals-at-the-expense-of-our-own/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36545</id>
		<updated>2019-02-26T10:10:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-656568732.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36546&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36546&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Motivational wide shot of young man and woman holding huge heavy barbells overhead looking at each other&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1457539810&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;160&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Weightlifter Champions in Gym&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Weightlifter Champions in Gym&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-656568732.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-656568732.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-656568732.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2094,1432&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/26/how-competitiveness-leads-us-to-sabotage-other-peoples-personal-goals-at-the-expense-of-our-own/weightlifter-champions-in-gym/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-656568732.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you’re planning to run a marathon, and you have a target time in mind. Or you’re on a weight- loss diet, and your aim is to lose six kilos in six weeks. Or, there’s an exam coming up, and you want to score above 75 per cent. These are all individual goal pursuits. In theory, you’re not in direct competition with anybody else, though of course if you’re part of a running club, or a weight loss group, or an undergraduate class, you will be aware that others around you are striving to achieve their own goals.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s plenty of evidence that sharing your own goals and hearing about other people’s can be helpful – in providing mutual encouragement, emotional support and motivation. However, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037/pspi0000170&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; shows how, in certain circumstances, we can’t help ourselves from competing with others – an effect that can be surprisingly counterproductive.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;The findings suggest that when we’re paired with an individual striving for a similar goal and who is similarly able, we begin to view this other person as an opponent – leading us to sabotage their efforts, ultimately to the detriment of our own performance.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Pursuing individual goals together with others can at times lead to counter-productive behaviours that not only harm others but also harm oneself,” report Szu-chi Huang at Stanford University, and her colleagues.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36545&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers ran six experiments. In the first, 200 participants performed rounds of a “word creativity” task, in which they had to make make as many words as possible from a string of letters. They were told they were paired with a “partner” (in fact, a fictional person) who had done slightly better on each round. The participants were given their own personal goal: if they created enough words, they’d be rewarded with a gift card. Another detail is that participants were also able to make the tasks harder or easier for their partner – an opportunity they exploited. Even though their partner’s performance was technically irrelevant to their own goal pursuit, as participants got close to achieving their goal, they tended to choose to make the task harder for their partner – “sabotaging” their partner’s chances. What’s more, after doing this, the participants eased up on their own efforts – they “coasted”.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequent experiments, some involving other tasks (such as a card game), revealed that the pattern of getting close to a personal goal, sabotaging one’s partner, then coasting, happened whether the participants were led to believe they were slightly ahead of or slightly behind their partner. However, a further study revealed that only participants who believed their sabotaging efforts were successful eased up on their own efforts.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers write: “This study thus provided further support that the main purpose of sabotage was to ‘take the opponent down’ a notch; when this positional gain was plausibly realised, people relaxed their effort, even though their sabotaging act did nothing to advance their own individual goal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang and her colleagues said their findings suggest that when we perform alongside other people who share similar goals to us, we can’t help ourselves from becoming competitive, which shifts our focus from bettering ourselves to defeating our “opponent”, and then relaxing our own efforts. “This is unexpectedly counterproductive to the attainment of people’s own individual goals,” the researchers note.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work contributes to a growing field of research on the social side of goal pursuit. It seems that although we can help each other in the early stages of own parallel journeys, these relationships can become harmful when our goal comes into sight. Being aware of this may help you to understand when to stop paying attention to other people’s progress, and to focus on keeping your own efforts up.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2Fpspi0000170&quot;&gt;When individual goal pursuit turns competitive: How we sabotage and coast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:58+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ancient Angkor’s mysterious decline may have been slow, not sudden</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-angkor-mysterious-decline-slow-not-sudden"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-angkor-mysterious-decline-slow-not-sudden</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T20:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Analyzing sediment from the massive city’s moat challenges the idea that the last capital of the Khmer Empire collapsed suddenly.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-04T06:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hermit crabs are drawn to the smell of their own dead</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hermit-crabs-are-drawn-smell-their-own-dead"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hermit-crabs-are-drawn-smell-their-own-dead</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T13:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new study finds that the smell of hermit crab flesh attracts other hermit crabs of the same species desperately looking for a larger shell.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yao-Hua Law</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T18:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">New study finds “important deficiencies” in university reports of misconduct</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/25/new-study-finds-important-deficiencies-in-university-reports-of-misconduct/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87315</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T11:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Retraction Watch readers may recall the name Yoshihiro Sato. The late researcher’s retraction total — now at 51 — gives him the number four spot on our leaderboard. He’s there because of the work of four researchers, Andrew Grey, Mark Bolland, and Greg Gamble, all of the University of Auckland, and Alison Avenell, of the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/25/new-study-finds-important-deficiencies-in-university-reports-of-misconduct/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;New study finds “important deficiencies” in university reports of misconduct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T12:04:01+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The FDA says don’t buy young plasma therapies. Here’s why</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fda-young-plasma-therapies-aging-research"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fda-young-plasma-therapies-aging-research</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Infusions of plasma from young people may hold the secret of youth, but there’s not much evidence to support the idea yet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T18:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Cancer Personality Scandal (Part 1)</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9848"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9848</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T10:09:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Journal of Health Psychology has just published an extraordinary pair of papers that call for a new inquiry into a 30-year old case of probable scientific fraud.

According to Anthony J. Pelosi, author of the main paper, the case was &quot;one of the worst scientific scandals of all time&quot; and yet has never been formally investigated. The journal's editor, David F. Marks, agrees and, in an editorial, also calls for the retraction or correction of up to 61 papers.

The scandal in question is on</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2019-02-25T12:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Norwegian Clinical Psychologists Reveal The Complexities Involved In Working With Children And Teens Experiencing Gender Dysphoria</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/25/norwegian-clinical-psychologists-reveal-the-complexities-involved-in-working-with-children-and-teens-experiencing-gender-dysphoria/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=36483</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T09:41:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-170046907.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-36540&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;36540&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Eleven year old boy talking to a parent,guardian or social worker. Toned black and white.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Richard Clark&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Parenting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Parenting&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-170046907.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-170046907.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-170046907.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2119,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2019/02/25/norwegian-clinical-psychologists-reveal-the-complexities-involved-in-working-with-children-and-teens-experiencing-gender-dysphoria/parenting-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/gettyimages-170046907.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jessesingal.com/&quot;&gt;Jesse Singal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;With the number of referrals to the UK’s only gender identity development service (GIDS, at the Tavistock and Portman NHS Trust) increasing sharply in recent years – a pattern seemingly mirrored in other European countries and the US (anecdotally, at least — many countries don’t keep comprehensive data the way the UK does) – debate has inevitably intensified over how best to help transgender and gender nonconforming (TGNC) youth. As some expert clinicians &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apa.org/images/sgd-sgd0000167_tcm7-211986.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;have pointed out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, there has been a tendency for commentators, campaigners and the general public to adopt an oversimplified view in which therapists are seen as fitting one of two categories: those who don’t believe their clients when they say they are trans (and who are therefore condemned by trans advocacy groups for practicing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;conversion therapy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;), and others who simply accept their clients’ statements about their gender, and who are therefore &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;affirming&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; or &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;affirmative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The clinical reality is more complicated: these days, there is a welcome consensus against actual &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bps.org.uk/news-and-policy/psychologists-back-call-end-conversion-therapy&quot;&gt;conversion therapy&lt;/a&gt; — forcing a young person to “go back” to being cisgender — but at the same time responsible clinicians do not simply nod along to what a young person with gender dysphoria says. There are complexities inherent to childhood and adolescent development, and many experts warn it’s important not to accidentally medicalise perfectly normal qualms about growing up, hitting puberty, and being exposed to powerful and often frustratingly restrictive gender roles. Young people present at gender clinics with a wide variety of issues ranging from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/17/most-children-and-teens-with-gender-dysphoria-also-have-multiple-other-psychological-issues/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;comorbid mental-health issues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to unexamined trauma, and the process of helping them determine the best path forward, particularly with regard to medical interventions like &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/23/systematic-review-puberty-suppressing-drugs-do-not-alleviate-gender-dysphoria/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;puberty blockers or cross-sex hormones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, is a lot more complicated than making a rapid decision to deny or approve such interventions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Indeed, in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adc.bmj.com/content/103/7/631.full?ijkey=HsMwyZDRtsKu83z&amp;amp;keytype=ref&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;an open-access practice review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; published in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;BMJ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; last year, clinicians at UCL, GIDS and Great Ormond Street Hospital explained that the thorough psychosexual assessment period for such clients “usually takes 6 months or more over a minimum of four to six sessions” and involves a range of psychometric measures and interviews, covering the client’s expectations and understanding of social and physical transition, their mood and emotional functioning. The review adds that, “With the adolescents, there is an in-depth consideration of their sexuality and fertility, and possible preservation approaches are discussed. The attitude of important people in the child’s life towards gender dysphoria needs to be explored and understood.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19419899.2019.1568290&quot;&gt;a study published in &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19419899.2019.1568290&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Psychology &amp;amp; Sexuality &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;by a pair of Norwegian researchers, Reidar Schel Jessen and Katrina Roen, has explored these complexities from clinical psychologists’ perspective, including what it means to help a young person work through the issues they are facing and to make important decisions about medical treatment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-36483&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For the study, “Five clinical psychologists working with gender non-conforming youth in an interdisciplinary team at a specialized gender identity clinic in Europe participated in interviews.” In reading their work, I was struck repeatedly by how similar their experiences were to what I heard when I spoke with American clinicians for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/07/when-a-child-says-shes-trans/561749/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;an in-depth article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; about transgender youth for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. For example, Jessen and Roen write that “Sometimes the clients themselves want to transition, but sometimes the possibility seems driven by the family or others in the young person’s life, such as school staff.” The pair include a poignant example of this:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;One young person I worked with […] was referred by school. Biological male, who presented in very… like stereotypically… call it female clothes, like pink and yellow, long hair. Often was read as female, and the school didn’t know what to do with the young person. But when I met the young person, the young person didn’t have any issues with the body or […] developing in a masculine way. So all, so I was kind of again looking at where the stress lies, and it was really in the separation or gender division at school […] and they would ask him to cut his hair short, because he is a boy […] and I think in my report I wrote that… you know, I would really advise you not to address… the pupils as girls and boys, but just call them pupils, students. (Participant C) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;I didn’t come across any examples quite so dramatic in my own reporting, but this was a common general storyline: I noted that “Several of the clinicians I spoke with, including Nate Sharon, Laura Edwards-Leeper, and Scott Leibowitz, recounted new patients’ arriving at their clinics, their parents having already developed detailed plans for them to transition. ‘I’ve actually had patients with parents pressuring me to recommend their kids start hormones,’ Sharon said.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Kids who are gender nonconforming often make adults uncomfortable, and in some cases one way adults attempt to dispel this discomfort is to push for transition. “The [clinical psychologist] participants have the impression that sometimes the school or family expect these young boys to transition to girls,” write Jessen and Roen, “because they do not want them to be feminine boys. This illustrates how difficult it can sometimes be to understand which expectations belong to whom, and how gender non-conforming youth can be referred to the clinic by adults who hold the opinion that gender non-conformity is a problem to be addressed clinically.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Similarly, as I wrote in my &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Atlantic &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;article, clinicians told me about instances in which “the child might be capably navigating a liminal period of gender exploration; it’s the parents who are having trouble not knowing whether their kid is a boy or a girl.” Sure enough, this theme of pressure to choose a gender ‘side,’ too, popped up among the Norwegian clinicians:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Participants were concerned about the possibility that binary gender norms force gender non-conforming youth to become “the opposite gender,” instead of allowing them space to explore their unique gender expression. According to the clinical psychologists interviewed, many clients and families believe that gender is binary, and that there are only two gender identities. This belief does seem to influence clients’ expectations of outcomes, and may encourage them to seek physical treatment at the expense of exploratory work. According to the participants, many clients and their families experience societal and community pressure to conform to gender norms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Exploration and nuance and liminality are key concepts that come up over and over again in interviews with experienced youth TGNC clinicians. But it can be challenging to tell a child who is in distress, or his or her parents, that it’s worth taking a bit more time to explore before proceeding to physical interventions or making other major decisions about transition — perhaps doubly so given the belief in some quarters that “exploration” or “therapy” are near-synonyms for “transphobia” and “conversion therapy.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;As “Participant B” told the researchers, “Not surprisingly, exploratory strategies can be aggravating to clients and families. We are always very subject to this discourse of the bigot […] this idea of you know transphobia […] so people that are bigoted are very narrow-minded […] this is where then you know the power that we then have starts to really create lots of tension and problems.” That is, at the end of the day, clinicians stand between young people (and their parents) and medical treatments they feel they need, so it’s an understandable reaction for delays caused by responsible, thorough clinical work to be misread as transphobia. This tension was partly what motivated last year’s practice review in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;BMJ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;: “Faced with very distressed young people, they [clinicians] may feel under pressure to initiate physical intervention without consultation with psychosocial colleagues,” the review states. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If gender clinics in three very different countries with three very different healthcare systems are experiencing the same sorts of scenarios over and over, that’s a signal that everyone should try to better understand what’s going on. Many of the young people mentioned in this study likely will, in the long run, benefit from puberty blockers and hormones. But some won’t — their gender exploration will lead them elsewhere, whether or not they come to identify with their biological sex. It’s important to understand what separates these two groups, and scientists have only barely begun to do so.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/19419899.2019.1568290&quot;&gt;Balancing in the margins of gender: exploring psychologists’ meaning-making in their work with gender non-conforming youth seeking puberty suppression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by Jesse Singal (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jessesingal&quot;&gt;@JesseSingal&lt;/a&gt;) for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Jesse is a contributing writer at &lt;em&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;New York&lt;/em&gt; Magazine, and he publishes his own &lt;a href=&quot;https://jessesingal.substack.com/&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; featuring behavioral-science-talk. He is also working on a book about why shoddy behavioral-science claims sometimes go viral for Farrar, Straus and Giroux.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2019-03-07T18:00:59+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Ageing in harmony: why the third act of life should be musical</title>
		<link href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/ageing-in-harmony-why-the-third-act-of-life-should-be-musical/"/>
		<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5828</id>
		<updated>2019-02-25T03:49:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Image 20160601 25573 yu48y8.jpg?ixlib=rb 1.1&quot; src=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/124690/original/image-20160601-25573-yu48y8.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot; /&gt;Playing music is good for people at all stages in their lives – including the elderly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Jeremy Brooks&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;license&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ageing in harmony: why the third act of life should be musical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/profiles/jennifer-macritchie-171595&quot;&gt;Jennifer MacRitchie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/institutions/western-sydney-university-1092&quot;&gt;Western Sydney University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s never too late to pick up a musical instrument. In fact, there are many reasons why it’s a great idea, particularly in old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We normally hear about reasons to increase music education for children, and for good cause. There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://ijm.sagepub.com/content/28/3/269&quot;&gt;many cognitive and social benefits&lt;/a&gt; to playing an instrument that aid a child’s development. Consequently, as an older adult, there are long-term effects of having taken part in these musical activities, as it can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21463047&quot;&gt;limit cognitive decline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/33/45/17667.full&quot;&gt;small amount of training&lt;/a&gt; can have long-lasting effects. But this doesn’t mean that those who have never played an instrument in childhood have missed the boat. The ageing brain is &lt;em&gt;plastic&lt;/em&gt;: that means it is able to learn new things all the time. So, should we consider an increase in music programs for those in the third age?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Playing music as a workout for the brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to play a musical instrument is an extremely complex task that involves the coordination of multiple sensory systems within the brain. Many instruments require precise coordination between the eyes, the ears and the hands in order to play a musical note. Using the resulting sound as feedback, the brain prepares for the next note and so it continues. The act of music-making is quite a brain workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the motor and auditory parts of the brain is strengthened when physically playing music. This may explain why adults trained to &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; certain melodies have an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/28/39/9632.long&quot;&gt;enhanced representation of music&lt;/a&gt; in the brain compared to adults only trained to &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to the same melodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As playing music involves many different parts of the brain, even a short-term program for older adult musical novices can lead to generalised improvements for &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00810/full&quot;&gt;cognitive ability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music as a workout for the fingers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to play an instrument such as the piano involves many complex finger sequencing and coordination tasks. As such, it can be a great test-bed for learning to move fingers independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creativity of music and the enjoyment people take in playing is particularly important for rehabilitation, as it encourages sustained practice leading ultimately to higher benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;align-center zoomable&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/124735/original/image-20160601-1964-11dnlm4.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.theconversation.com/files/124735/original/image-20160601-1964-11dnlm4.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;amp;q=45&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;w=754&amp;amp;fit=clip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;attribution&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s thanks to this that piano lessons have been used to successfully retrain hand function for &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2014.00662/full&quot;&gt;patients who have had a stroke&lt;/a&gt;. The immediate auditory feedback from each finger movement is thought to help adults &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25721795&quot;&gt;reduce errors in movement&lt;/a&gt; and work towards moving at a more regular pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music training is an excellent environment to train cognitive and motor abilities, both in the contexts of child development and for rehabilitation. The question for older adults is this: can learning a musical instrument not only put the brakes on cognitive and motor decline but actually allow development of new skills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older adults can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1995805/&quot;&gt;improve their motor learning&lt;/a&gt; – that is, they can improve their rate of learning new things – and the best environments for brain training are ones that are &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2012.00183/full&quot;&gt;novel and flexible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, many activities can be novel such as juggling or knitting, but the advantages of learning an instrument can be found in the breadth of skills required to play. At Western Sydney University, we are currently investigating how piano training can be used with healthy older adults to improve their general hand function in unrelated daily tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music for health and wellbeing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, the worry is that playing an instrument will be too difficult for older adults to manage. On the contrary, learning to play an instrument can provide a great sense of &lt;a class=&quot;broken_link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/41162324&quot;&gt;achievement&lt;/a&gt; and satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older adults relish the opportunity to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/02601370.2014.999361&quot;&gt;learn something new&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Cognitive benefits aside, music can also be a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/02601370.2014.991951&quot;&gt;social activity for older adults&lt;/a&gt;, facilitating social bonding and decreasing feelings of loneliness or isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music programs are linked to improvements measured in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0889159113005138&quot;&gt;markers of the body’s immune system&lt;/a&gt; such as the presence of antibodies and vital signs (heart rate/blood pressure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s suggested that this is a consequence of decreases in stress that can happen when taking part in musical activities. However, further research is needed to determine exactly how this relationship functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music for all&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s vital to understand how we can aid the current generation of older adults, in terms of both health and personal enjoyment. With the myriad benefits provided by playing a musical instrument, it would seem beneficial to have a wider variety of musical activities on offer to the older generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if the third age wasn’t viewed as a final descent from some mid-life peak, but some new act of life that opens up these opportunities? Perhaps we should give older adults the chance to develop in ways they could never have imagined before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Activities such as singing in a choir, or playing the piano can provide this opportunity, as well as offering many general benefits to health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So whether it’s in independent living, retirement or assisted care, let’s make the third act of life a musical one!&lt;img alt=&quot;The Conversation&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://counter.theconversation.com/content/57799/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0 !important; padding: 0 !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/profiles/jennifer-macritchie-171595&quot;&gt;Jennifer MacRitchie&lt;/a&gt;, Research Lecturer in Music Perception and Cognition, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/institutions/western-sydney-university-1092&quot;&gt;Western Sydney University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is republished from &lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com&quot;&gt;The Conversation&lt;/a&gt; under a Creative Commons license. Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/ageing-in-harmony-why-the-third-act-of-life-should-be-musical-57799&quot;&gt;original article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/ageing-in-harmony-why-the-third-act-of-life-should-be-musical/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ageing in harmony: why the third act of life should be musical&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McKay</name>
			<uri>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Your Brain Health</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Discover neuroscience. Explore the brain. Understand your mind.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/"/>
			<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</id>
			<updated>2019-02-25T06:00:41+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Top 10 science anniversaries to celebrate in 2019</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/top-10-science-anniversaries-celebrate-2019"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/top-10-science-anniversaries-celebrate-2019</id>
		<updated>2019-02-24T13:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Top 10 science anniversaries in 2019 include expeditions, treatises and tabulations.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Retractions at Nature and NEJM; editor resigns after paper with “racist characterizations;” CRISPR babies ethics paper retracted</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/23/weekend-reads-retractions-at-nature-and-nejm-editor-resigns-after-paper-with-racist-characterizations-crispr-babies-ethics-paper-retracted/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=87268</id>
		<updated>2019-02-23T14:36:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a new record for most retractions by a journal; the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/23/weekend-reads-retractions-at-nature-and-nejm-editor-resigns-after-paper-with-racist-characterizations-crispr-babies-ethics-paper-retracted/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Retractions at Nature and NEJM; editor resigns after paper with “racist characterizations;” CRISPR babies ethics paper retracted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-06T12:00:56+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hayabusa2 just tried to collect asteroid dust for the first time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/japan-hayabusa2-spacecraft-first-sample-asteroid-dust"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/japan-hayabusa2-spacecraft-first-sample-asteroid-dust</id>
		<updated>2019-02-22T20:07:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Japanese Hayabusa2 spacecraft touched down on asteroid Ryugu and attempted to gather a sample of its rock to bring back to Earth.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Colliding neutron stars shot a light-speed jet through space</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/colliding-neutron-stars-light-speed-space"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/colliding-neutron-stars-light-speed-space</id>
		<updated>2019-02-22T16:53:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A stream of particles created in a neutron star crash, detected in 2017 using gravitational waves, could explain certain mysterious flashes of light.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-03-01T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">African hominid fossils show ancient steps toward a two-legged stride</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/african-hominid-ardipithecus-ramidus-fossils-upright-walking"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/african-hominid-ardipithecus-ramidus-fossils-upright-walking</id>
		<updated>2019-02-22T16:11:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New Ardipithecus ramidus fossils reveal how hominids were shifting toward humanlike walking more than 4 million years ago.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-02-28T18:00:50+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Supernovas show the universe expands at the same rate in all directions</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/supernova-show-universe-expands-same-rate-all-directions"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/supernova-show-universe-expands-same-rate-all-directions</id>
		<updated>2019-02-22T12:00:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Analyzing supernovas indicates that expansion rates agree within 1 percent across large regions of sky.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2019-02-28T18:00:50+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal to retract article from 2000 that plagiarized one from 1984</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/22/journal-to-retract-article-from-2000-that-plagiarized-one-from-1984/"/>
		<id>https://retractionwatch.com/?p=86842</id>
		<updated>2019-02-22T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 When it comes to plagiarism, there is apparently no statute of limitations. That’s one lesson one might take from this tale of two papers, one published in 1984 in the American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology (AJOG), and the other published in 2000 in the Medical Journal of The Islamic Republic of Iran (MJIRI). Both … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2019/02/22/journal-to-retract-article-from-2000-that-plagiarized-one-from-1984/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journal to retract article from 2000 that plagiarized one from 1984&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2019-03-05T12:00:44+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
