<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:38+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Kids with food allergies are twice as likely to have autism</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/kids-food-allergies-are-twice-likely-have-autism"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/kids-food-allergies-are-twice-likely-have-autism</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T20:31:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Children with food allergies are more likely to have autism than kids without, a study finds. But that doesn’t mean a child will develop the disorder.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">If you thought the most recent flu season was bad, you were right</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-thought-most-recent-flu-season-was-bad-you-were-right"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-thought-most-recent-flu-season-was-bad-you-were-right</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T16:17:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The recent U.S. flu season was classified as highly severe overall, the third time since 2003 that the seasonal outbreak has earned that designation.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">More about open citations — Citation Gecko, Citation extraction from PDF &amp;amp; LOC-DB</title>
		<link href="https://medium.com/a-academic-librarians-thoughts-on-open-access/more-about-open-citations-citation-gecko-citation-extraction-from-pdf-loc-db-2ea982800a0d"/>
		<id>https://medium.com/a-academic-librarians-thoughts-on-open-access/more-about-open-citations-citation-gecko-citation-extraction-from-pdf-loc-db-2ea982800a0d</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T15:45:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Since I started to learn about open citations, I start seeing them everwhere.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Open Revolution - Book Launch</title>
		<link href="https://attending.io/events/open-revolution-book-launch"/>
		<id>https://attending.io/events/open-revolution-book-launch</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T15:40:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Join us for the launch of Rufus Pollock’s new book Open Revolution – New Rules for a New Age&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS ONE and Children’s Tumor Foundation partnership announce second cycle of DDIRR Awards</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/C33JDGXkqLE/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8233</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T14:54:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;The Children’s Tumor Foundation (CTF), the largest non-governmental funder of neurofibromatosis (NF) research, and PLOS ONE, a leading peer-reviewed scientific journal, are pleased to announce the successful completion of the first funding cycle of the Drug Discovery Initiative Registered Report (DDIRR) 2017 Awards, a funder-publisher partnership integrating the Registered Reports model into the grant application process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered Reports pre-determine the research questions, methodology and design of a study to be carried out, and are designed to enhance the rigor, reproducibility and transparency of the science produced. CTF and PLOS ONE partnered together to review the 2017 DDIRR applications and granted three awards: Dr. Andrea McClatchey of Massachusetts General Hospital, Dr. Lei Xu of Massachusetts General Hospital, and Dr. Aaron Schindeler from the University of Sydney. The researchers also obtained an in-principle acceptance (IPA) to publication in the journal PLOS ONE. Provided the study is conducted according to plan, acceptance in principle is honored regardless of study outcome – thereby eliminating publication bias and maximizing the transparency of the funded work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reports are being placed on the Open Science Framework registered report portal (&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/rr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://osf.io/rr/&lt;/a&gt;), where authors will have the opportunity to make public or embargo their reports until publication of results. The awards have a duration of 12 months and will conclude in May 2019. As soon as results are added to the registered report, PLOS ONE will review compliance with the proposed protocol and publish their results, even if they are negative. By securing publication before they start their research, applicants can eliminate the bias of a result-based approach. The process was designed to maintain independence of funding and publishing decisions, while at the same time optimizing processes, thereby avoiding duplication and preventing research waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new award constitutes an evolution of the Drug Discovery Initiative (DDI) Awards that CTF had introduced in 2006 as a funding program for promising ideas that could lead to larger studies or move drugs into the clinic. Feedback on the new DDIRR program from both applicants and reviewers has been unanimously positive, and the Foundation together with PLOS ONE editors have also announced a new cycle for DDIRR in 2018-2019. The Foundation will invite applicants to submit their proposals starting on September 24, 2018, with the anticipated assignment of new awards in the first quarter of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The overall outcome of this first round of DDIRR has been very positive. Reviewers have focused their attention to protocols and study designs, allowing researchers to have their statistics ready for publication,” said Salvatore La Rosa, Ph.D., Vice President of Research and Development for the Children’s Tumor Foundation. “As this particular grant program focuses on hypothesis-testing research, the quality and rigor of the applications are critical to soundly move proof-of-concept experiments from the lab into the clinic. This new program increases our ability to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to continue our collaboration with CTF on the Registered Reports model for the DDI Awards. We hope this can serve as a model for other funders. The Registered Reports provide researchers with peer reviewed study designs and an in-principle acceptance of the completed study at PLOS ONE. The deposited reports at the Open Science Framework portal ensure full transparency of the research project – a win for everyone involved,” adds Joerg Heber, Editor-in-Chief of PLOS ONE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctf.org/news/first-funding-cycle-of-the-ddirr-awards-announced&quot;&gt;First Funding Cycle of the Drug Discovery Initiative Registered Report (DDIRR) Awards Announced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/C33JDGXkqLE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">CORE becomes the world’s largest aggregator | Jisc scholarly communications</title>
		<link href="https://scholarlycommunications.jiscinvolve.org/wp/2018/06/01/core-becomes-the-worlds-largest-aggregator/"/>
		<id>https://scholarlycommunications.jiscinvolve.org/wp/2018/06/01/core-becomes-the-worlds-largest-aggregator/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:12:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;CORE, a global aggregator of full text open access scientific content from repositories and journals, has been growing at a fast pace over the last few months. As of May 2018, CORE has aggregated over 131 million article metadata records, 93 million abstracts, 11 million hosted and validated full texts and over 78 million direct links to research papers hosted on other websites. Our dataset of full text papers has reached 49TB.  CORE is a jointly run service between the Open University and Jisc.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Silver Sponsor National Library of Sweden Answers our Questions on Open Access Publishing and DOAJ – News Service</title>
		<link href="https://blog.doaj.org/2018/06/07/national-library-of-sweden-answers-our-questions-on-open-access-publishing-and-doaj/"/>
		<id>https://blog.doaj.org/2018/06/07/national-library-of-sweden-answers-our-questions-on-open-access-publishing-and-doaj/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:11:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;It is our firm belief that open access will strengthen the scholarly system as well as society at large. A broad collaboration between stakeholders is needed in order to achieve the goal of open access. Also, we aim to strengthen the control of the total costs of publishing while preserving the quality control system. This is no easy task, conflicting interests complicates the transition to a sustainable open access publishing system.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">https://intact-project.org/general/openapc/2018/06/08/couperin/</title>
		<link href="https://intact-project.org/general/openapc/2018/06/08/couperin/"/>
		<id>https://intact-project.org/general/openapc/2018/06/08/couperin/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:09:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://couperin.org/&quot;&gt;Couperin consortium&lt;/a&gt; collects data on APC expenditures from universities and other research institutions in France. A first batch of data has now been kindly made available to OpenAPC, more is to follow soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial data set provided by Couperin covers publication fees for 695 articles published in 2015. Total expenditure amounts to 1 173 258€ and the average fee is 1 688€.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Keynote : Transition to the Infosphere: A New Paradigm for Library &amp;amp; Information Science. Vilnius, 14th June 2018 | thelynxiblog</title>
		<link href="https://thelynxiblog.com/2018/06/07/keynote-transition-to-the-infosphere-a-new-paradigm-for-library-information-science-june-2018/"/>
		<id>https://thelynxiblog.com/2018/06/07/keynote-transition-to-the-infosphere-a-new-paradigm-for-library-information-science-june-2018/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:08:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Communication and information research helps to understand changes that happens when societies use digital technologies; to study how individuals, communities and organisations construct their identity, share ideas, make decisions and create new knowledge; to see opportunities and challenges in these and other communication and information processes. The goal of the conference is to bring together foreign and Lithuanian communication and information scholars and professionals for a discussion of socially significant communication and information issues and solutions in the networked society that have been identified by research and to increase student’s motivation and engagement in communication and information field.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">New open access book on politics of quality in education</title>
		<link href="https://www2.uta.fi/en/news/story/new-open-access-book-politics-quality-education"/>
		<id>https://www2.uta.fi/en/news/story/new-open-access-book-politics-quality-education</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:05:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The book &quot;Politics of Quality in Education: a comparative study of Brazil, China, and Russia&quot; (2018, Routledge) is available in open access: https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/e/9781351362528.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open access in the humanities : OpenAIRE blog</title>
		<link href="https://blogs.openaire.eu/?p=3314"/>
		<id>https://blogs.openaire.eu/?p=3314</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:04:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The event on open access in the humanities (and social sciences) took place on 22 May 2018 in Ljubljana, Slovenia, and was targeted to Slovenian researchers in the humanities and social sciences as well as to editors of Slovenian peer-reviewed journals from these scientific areas. More than 80 participants listened to presentations on collectively funded humanities megajournal, on infrastructure for open scholarly communication in the social sciences and humanities, on data and openness in the arts and humanities as well as on language e-infrastructure. Good Slovenian practices were presented, i.e., humanities open journals and open monographs publishing and Slovenian social sciences data archive. Panel discussion served to exchange opinions on the challenges of open access implementation in Slovenia.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Movimiento acceso abierto potencia universalidad del conocimiento</title>
		<link href="https://theworldnews.net/do-news/movimiento-acceso-abierto-potencia-universalidad-del-conocimiento"/>
		<id>https://theworldnews.net/do-news/movimiento-acceso-abierto-potencia-universalidad-del-conocimiento</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T13:01:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): Movement open access power universality of knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;El ingeniero José Armando Tavárez, presidente de la ADRU, durante su disertación El acceso abierto en República Dominicana: situación y perspectivas en la Educación Superior, afirmó que “el libre acceso a las producciones científicas y sus autores garantiza mayor alcance en la difusión de los resultados de sus investigaciones”.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;The engineer José Armando Tavárez, president of the ADRU,  during his dissertation  Open access in the Dominican Republic: situation and perspectives in Higher Education, stated that &quot; free access to scientific productions and their authors guarantees greater scope in the dissemination of results of their investigations.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Evento irá debater acesso aberto à memória científica — Universidade Federal do Estado do Rio de Janeiro</title>
		<link href="http://www.unirio.br/news/evento-ira-debater-acesso-aberto-a-memoria-cientifica"/>
		<id>http://www.unirio.br/news/evento-ira-debater-acesso-aberto-a-memoria-cientifica</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:55:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): Event will discuss open access to scientific memory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Nos dias 14 e 15 de junho acontece o evento Acesso aberto à memória científica: reuso de dados e conhecimento, organizado pelo Programa de Pós-graduação em Biblioteconomia (PPGB), em parceria com os Programas de Pós-graduação em Enfermagem, Enfermagem e Biociências e Tecnologia Hospitalar.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;On June 14 and 15, the event Open access to scientific memory: data reuse and knowledge , organized by the Graduate Program in Library Science (PPGB), in partnership with the Graduate Programs in Nursing, Nursing and Biosciences and Hospital Technology.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">A Researcher’s Guide to: GeneLab | NASA</title>
		<link href="https://www.nasa.gov/connect/ebooks/researchers-guide-to-genelab"/>
		<id>https://www.nasa.gov/connect/ebooks/researchers-guide-to-genelab</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:53:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The GeneLab team routinely processes, archives, and provides omics data to researchers around the globe. NASA’s plan expands the breadth of its open-access culture to include data and publications for all of the scientific research that NASA sponsors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Pandemics: spend on surveillance, not prediction</title>
		<link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-05373-w"/>
		<id>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-05373-w</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:52:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Once an emerging outbreak virus has been identified, it needs to be analysed quickly to establish what type it is; which molecular mechanisms (such as receptor type) enable it to jump between individuals; how it spreads through human populations; and how it affects those infected. In other words, at least four kinds of analysis are needed: genomic, virological, epidemiological and clinical. And the data must be passed to key stakeholders, from researchers and health workers on the ground to international agencies such as the WHO and the MSF. Data must be kept as free of restrictions as possible, within the constraints of protections of patient privacy and other ethical issues.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">UK National Archives Explores Blockchain to Ensure Authenticity of Digital Records</title>
		<link href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/uk-national-archives-explores-blockchain-to-ensure-authenticity-of-digital-records"/>
		<id>https://cointelegraph.com/news/uk-national-archives-explores-blockchain-to-ensure-authenticity-of-digital-records</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:49:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The ARCHANGEL project is considering using blockchain tech to create immutable entries for digital records in the National Archives of the UK, according to a blog post from the National Archives published June 6.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Peeriodicals</title>
		<link href="https://peeriodicals.com/"/>
		<id>https://peeriodicals.com/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:48:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;A peeriodical is a lightweight virtual journal with you as the Editor-in-chief, giving you complete freedom in setting editorial policy to select the most interesting and useful manuscripts for your readers. The manuscripts you will evaluate and select are existing publications—preprints and papers. Thus, a peeriodical replicates all the functions of a traditional journal, including discovery, selection and certification, except publication itself.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journals flag two papers by prominent researcher — who is also on trial for domestic abuse</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/08/journals-flag-two-papers-by-prominent-researcher-who-is-also-on-trial-for-domestic-abuse/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66452</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T12:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Adeel Safdar was once a rising star in the field of kinesiology. After completing his doctorate degree at McMaster University in Canada, working with one of the titans of his field, Safdar took a postdoc at Harvard, then accepted a newly created chair position at another university in Ontario. That all came crashing down last … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/08/journals-flag-two-papers-by-prominent-researcher-who-is-also-on-trial-for-domestic-abuse/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journals flag two papers by prominent researcher — who is also on trial for domestic abuse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Scholarly Communication Librarian (Houghton Library) Job Opening in Cambridge, Massachusetts - ALA JobLIST | Jobs in Library &amp;amp; Information Science &amp;amp; Technology</title>
		<link href="https://joblist.ala.org/job/scholarly-communication-librarian-houghton-library/41619005/"/>
		<id>https://joblist.ala.org/job/scholarly-communication-librarian-houghton-library/41619005/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T11:43:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Harvard University's Administrative Fellowship Program is one of the cornerstones of our diversity and inclusion efforts. We seek to attract talented professionals, and in particular members of historically underrepresented groups, to promote leadership opportunities and careers in higher education. The University encourages applications from individuals from diverse backgrounds and others who may contribute to the diversity of Harvard's leadership. To this end, the Administrative Fellowship Program offers a twelve-month talent management experience complemented by a professional development program. Please visit the program's website [https://hr.harvard.edu/administrative-fellows-program] for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houghton Library is pleased to offer a two-year Harvard Library Diversity Fellowship to immerse a rising leader in the library and archives profession in a wide variety of activities related to the management of a world class repository of rare books, manuscripts, archives, and other rare and unique library materials. Over the course of the two years, the Fellow will be exposed to and make contributions to the major functions of the library including scholarly communication, public programs, researcher services, and other areas as opportunities present themselves. The Fellow will also have the opportunity to meet and work with curators, librarians and archivists in other libraries that comprise the Arts and Special Collections of the Harvard College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A signature project will be core to the Fellow's experience. The incumbent will primarily work with the editorial team for the Harvard Library Bulletin (HLB), a peer-reviewed scholarly journal published by Houghton Library on behalf of Harvard Library. This position will allow the Fellow to develop expertise in scholarly communication, an area of rising emphasis in librarianship which is predicted to grow as an increasing number of university libraries assume responsibility for scholarly publishing and university presses.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Wikipedia:Meetup/Boston/Summer 2018 Edit-a-thon at BU - Wikipedia</title>
		<link href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Meetup/Boston/Summer_2018_Edit-a-thon_at_BU"/>
		<id>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Meetup/Boston/Summer_2018_Edit-a-thon_at_BU</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T11:40:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Join Boston University Libraries on Tuesday, July 10, from 1:00pm-4:00pm at Mugar Library for a Wikipedia Meetup. In anticipation of the upcoming Wikimania conference, our theme for this event will be the Global South: Bridging Knowledge Gaps.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">UCSF Open Science Group - LibCal - University of California, San Francisco</title>
		<link href="http://calendars.library.ucsf.edu/event/4218010"/>
		<id>http://calendars.library.ucsf.edu/event/4218010</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T11:39:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Graduate students, post docs, and research staff, we need your help! Come join the UCSF Library for some dinner and drinks to share your vision on the future of protocol searching, sharing and publishing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This theory suggests few workers were needed to cap Easter Island statues</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/theory-workers-easter-island-statues-hats"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/theory-workers-easter-island-statues-hats</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A small workforce may have put huge stones on the heads of Easter Island statues.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">George Oates: Making and Remaking Collections Online</title>
		<link href="https://olh.openlibhums.org/articles/10.16995/olh.325/"/>
		<id>https://olh.openlibhums.org/articles/10.16995/olh.325/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T10:51:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Abstract: &quot;George Oates is a web designer, producer and developer who has been working with digital collections since 2003. She was one the founding team of Flickr, and the originator of Flickr Commons. She currently heads heritage design studio Good, Form &amp;amp; Spectacle, working with institutions including the British Museum, the Wellcome Library and the V&amp;amp;A. In this interview with Mitchell Whitelaw, Oates discusses her developing practice in making and remaking digital collections, spanning web-scale services, unsolicited interfaces, messy metadata and gentle interventions in institutional practice.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Beyond the Horizon? A look at the details of Horizon Europe | Science|Business</title>
		<link href="https://sciencebusiness.net/framework-programmes/news/beyond-horizon-look-details-horizon-europe"/>
		<id>https://sciencebusiness.net/framework-programmes/news/beyond-horizon-look-details-horizon-europe</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T10:44:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The budget is divided into three “pillars”, on open science, open innovation, and global challenges and industrial competitiveness (“open to the world”, or international cooperation, is scattered throughout the programme.)&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Scientists and subscription journals tussling for power - SciDev.Net</title>
		<link href="https://www.scidev.net/index.cfm?originalUrl=/global/publishing/feature/scientists-and-subscription-journals-tussling-for-power.html&amp;"/>
		<id>https://www.scidev.net/index.cfm?originalUrl=/global/publishing/feature/scientists-and-subscription-journals-tussling-for-power.html&amp;</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T10:41:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Scientists are getting more and more interested in open-access journals. They see the advantages: more citations of their work, and a favourable eye from publishers, especially those based in Europe, who face political pressure to veer towards open access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But two years shy of a deadline set by the European Union to make all publicly funded scientific papers in the region open-access, some publishers continue to introduce new subscription-based journals — and in the process, face pushback from the global scientific community.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Studying mass murder</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/550863108/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=138474</id>
		<updated>2018-06-08T09:30:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;In the twentieth century, 40 to 60 million defenseless people were massacred in episodes of genocide. The 21st century is not faring much better, with mass murder ongoing e.g. in Myanmar and Syria. Many of these cases have been studied well, both in detailed case studies and in comparative perspectives, but studying mass murder is no picnic. Scholars have also examined how &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.ucpress.edu/book.php?isbn=9780520089945&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conducting research&lt;/a&gt;, including ethnographic fieldwork, archival investigation, and oral history interviews, can affect the researcher in profound ways. Among a broader set of difficulties that obstruct research on this wretched subject, two stand out in particular: political constraints and psychological attrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political constraints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All social research operates in a dense political field. Of all the political actors constraining research on mass murder, states stand out. They often have a vested interest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://books.google.nl/books?id=A0QlDwAAQBAJ&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;misrepresenting the truth&lt;/a&gt;, because for many, the memory of a genocide (or its denial), is part and parcel of their collective identity. States that consider themselves heirs to perpetrator regimes, such as Turkey, Russia, Indonesia, China, or Serbia, make great effort to influence the scholarship on episodes of mass violence. They deny access to archival collections and libraries, intimidate and prohibit them from conducting field work. (The opposite is also possible: governments may try to foster or manipulate research by funding politically useful research, by pushing for the establishment of academic chairs at home or abroad, or by offering scholarships.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having to contend with the taboos, restrictions, prescriptions, and outright threats of authoritarian regimes keeps scholars working on these topics under &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ssqu.2016.97.issue-4/issuetoc&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;permanent threat&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers bold enough to travel into these societies to visit sites, uncover evidence, interview witnesses, and have got to fear the security services and intelligence agencies of these states. One consequence of this discouraging atmosphere is that, in general, less research is carried out on those instances and episodes of mass murder, an undesirable blind spot due to the importance of the events. (Some researchers ingratiate themselves with the authorities for privileged access.) A second consequence poses a methodological dilemma: due to such constraints, does one launch a sting operation, like undercover journalism? Or does one use informants, fixers, and mediators on the ground? Does one pay the possible interviewees for taking the risks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt; We may not be willing or able to change our research topics, but we do need our colleagues and audience to be aware of these challenges. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological consequences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are significant emotional consequences of studying mass murder. All social research also operates in a dense emotional and moral field. As a general problem in the academy, involvement and detachment has been dealt with at some length, but the study of mass violence is particularly relevant from this perspective. Though a certain amount of passion and involvement can facilitate one’s commitment to the topic, it requires a great deal of detachment to sift through documents and memoirs containing very intimate details of killing. Detachment is even more challenging in &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~www.upenn.edu/pennpress/book/14525.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ethnographic fieldwork and oral history interviews&lt;/a&gt;, as empathy can transmit to scholars the interviewees’ powerful negative emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the Syrian crisis, I began interviewing Syrians about their experiences with violence, as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://niod.nl/en/news/new-research-project-syrians%E2%80%99-experiences-mass-violence-and-dynamic-violent-conflict&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a large-scale oral history project&lt;/a&gt; we are launching in the Netherlands. Having interviewed about 80 survivors and eye witnesses so far, their emotions of anger, sadness, fear, survivor guilt, and anxiety has affected me irreversibly. These types of interviews can be an alienating and isolating experience: the more one is absorbed into the stories of the eye witnesses, the more one is also drawn into their emotions. As a general rule of thumb, I felt compassion when interviewing victims, and indignation when interviewing perpetrators. But the interviews left a mark long after I stopped recording. When one young woman from Aleppo told me that she was raped in an ambush and witnessed a beheading up close, I was aghast at that moment. Ever since, I have not mustered my courage to go over those particular interview transcripts and notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the risks of political threats and psychological attrition need to be taken seriously by academic institutions, journals, and colleagues. These constraints can produce setbacks and potentially lower productivity, even with &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2017/11/on-burnout-trauma-erin-jessee/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;appropriate self-care&lt;/a&gt;. We may not be willing or able to change our research topics, but we do need our colleagues and audience to be aware of these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Flowers in a Khmer Rouge jail cell by alex.ch. CC BY 2.0 via &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.flickr.com/photos/alex-photos/408951646/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flickr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/studying-mass-murder/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Studying mass murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/550863108/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/550863108/oupblogpsychology,&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/etymology-gleanings-may-2018-part-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Etymology gleanings: May 2018 [Part 2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/safe-supportive-schools-lgbtq-gnc-students/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/plastic-pollution/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What you need to know about plastic pollution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Brixey</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Suicide rates have shot up in almost every U.S. state</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/suicide-rates-have-shot-almost-every-us-state"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/suicide-rates-have-shot-almost-every-us-state</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T22:46:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Suicide rates increased sharply in nearly all 50 states from 1999 to 2016, according to a new government report.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bees join an exclusive crew of animals that get the concept of zero</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bees-join-exclusive-crew-animals-get-concept-zero"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bees-join-exclusive-crew-animals-get-concept-zero</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T20:58:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Honeybees can pass a test of ranking ‘nothing’ as less than one.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why using genetic genealogy to solve crimes could pose problems</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-police-using-genetic-geneaology-solve-crimes-poses-problems"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-police-using-genetic-geneaology-solve-crimes-poses-problems</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Rules governing how police can use DNA searches in genealogy databases aren’t clear, raising civil rights and privacy concerns.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Curiosity finds that Mars’ methane changes with the seasons</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-finds-mars-methane-changes-seasons"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-finds-mars-methane-changes-seasons</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Curiosity rover found seasonally changing methane in Mars’ atmosphere and more signs of organic molecules in an ancient lake bed.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">In a conservation catch-22, efforts to save quolls might endanger them</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conservation-catch-22-efforts-save-quolls-might-endanger-them"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conservation-catch-22-efforts-save-quolls-might-endanger-them</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T16:33:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 After 13 generations isolated from predators, the endangered northern quoll lost its fear of them.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leah Rosenbaum</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Science Exchange First &amp;amp; Only R&amp;amp;D Outsourcing Platform to Achieve HIPAA Compliance</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/science-exchange-first-only-rd-outsourcing-platform-to-achieve-hipaa-compliance/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1355</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T15:16:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/HIPAA-PR-Social-Image-1200x628.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;HIPAA Compliance at Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1356&quot; height=&quot;156&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/HIPAA-PR-Social-Image-1200x628-300x156.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;HIPAA Compliance Demonstrates Commitment by Science Exchange to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Protection and Privacy of Protected Health Information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, June 7, 2018 –&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; today announced that it is the first R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform to achieve HIPAA compliance as required by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services under 45 C.F.R. 164. This achievement demonstrates the company’s commitment to the protection and privacy of Protected Health Information (PHI) as defined by 45 CFR §160.103 and shared by its customers and scientific research providers on the Science Exchange platform. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; “Protecting sensitive patient health information is a top priority for our clients and research providers,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “Achieving HIPAA compliance was a crucial step for Science Exchange, given the increasing portability and complexity of data processed by our software platform.”  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;HIPAA and HITECH: Noncompliance costing millions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) and the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health (HITECH) Act limit the disclosure of patient PHI, including data processed by any provider, technology platform, or other contractor. Since 2010, enforcement of HIPAA and HITECH has increased — with individual fines for noncompliance as high as $2 million. HIPAA compliance helps protect Science Exchange’s clients from these potential consequences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Science Exchange achieved HIPAA compliance by:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Establishing Business Associate Agreements for proper use and disclosure of PHI: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Business Associate Agreements are required agreements between covered entities and their business associates, such as Science Exchange, whose activities involve access to PHI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Implementing administrative, physical and technical safeguards against improper disclosures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Training every employee on protecting information subject to HIPAA and HIPAA requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Adopting best practices for limiting information use and sharing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Industry leaders in data privacy, security, and quality assurance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In addition to being the only HIPAA-compliant R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform, Science Exchange is also the only outsourcing platform to have earned EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification. This certification ensures compliance with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/gdpr-plan&quot;&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) regulations&lt;/a&gt; that went into effect on May 25, 2018, thereby protecting the many R&amp;amp;D organizations that have enterprise-level agreements with Science Exchange. Science Exchange is also SOC 2-compliant and ISO 9001-certified.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about how Science Exchange protects your data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise#security&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Learn More&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1357&quot; height=&quot;41&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/LEARN-MORE-button-e1528384407482.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">At-home telomere testing is not a reliable marker of aging, researcher says</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/home-telomere-testing-not-reliable-marker-aging-researcher-says"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/home-telomere-testing-not-reliable-marker-aging-researcher-says</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T14:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Telomere testing for consumers offers a poor measure of “biological age,” says Johns Hopkins oncologist Mary Armanios.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Cori Vanchieri</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Elsevier CIO in Forbes: “Machine learning is the catalyst, but …”</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-cio-in-forbes-machine-learning-is-the-catalyst-but"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-cio-in-forbes-machine-learning-is-the-catalyst-but</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T13:26:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 CIO Hall of Famer Dan Olley talks about tech trends, symbiotic technology – and a new era of “augmented intelligence”</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Karolinska told a journal to retract a paper by Macchiarini. It refused. The story didn’t end there.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-told-a-journal-to-retract-a-paper-by-macchiarini-it-refused-the-story-didnt-end-there/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66417</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T12:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The president of the Karolinska Institutet (KI) is frustrated. At the beginning of the year, Ole Petter Ottersen informed a journal that one of its papers — co-authored by former superstar Paolo Macchiarini — had been tainted by misconduct. But the journal declined to retract it. Despite the fact that KI had conducted its own … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-told-a-journal-to-retract-a-paper-by-macchiarini-it-refused-the-story-didnt-end-there/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska told a journal to retract a paper by Macchiarini. It refused. The story didn’t end there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, NASA astronauts prepared to return to space</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-astronauts-prepared-return-space"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-astronauts-prepared-return-space</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Apollo 7 crewmembers underwent their first major tests 50 years ago. Today, U.S. astronauts struggle to get into space.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Karolinska gets taught German medical ethics</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-gets-taught-german-medical-ethics/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24388</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T10:45:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A most bizarre thing happened. In the aftermath of the scandal around the thoracic surgeon and regenerative medicine enthusiast Paolo Macchiarini, which left many patients dead, his former employer Karolinska Institutet (KI) in Stockholm, Sweden, requested a retraction of one of his papers. It was not about a trachea transplant, but about unethical and painful … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-gets-taught-german-medical-ethics/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska gets taught German medical ethics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/550638442/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=138297</id>
		<updated>2018-06-07T09:30:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Within its first month, the Trump administration revoked federal guidelines designed to promote protections for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or gender non-conforming youth (LGBTQ-GNC) public school students. This move received significant media attention, much of which focused on the challenges of growing up LGBTQ-GNC, and the unique role of schools as places that should be safe and supportive for all students. At issue is defining the rights of students to be protected based on LGBT-GNC identity or status. And yet these rights are regularly compromised through: harassment and victimization that is unchecked; unfair, punitive, and exclusionary discipline practices; and unequal access to supports, services, and curriculum that validate their identities and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The groundbreaking study, &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.hrw.org/reports/2001/uslgbt/toc.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hatred in the Hallways&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;documented pervasive human rights violations perpetrated against LGBT youth in US schools. More recently, through an international convening and report, The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) firmly documented homophobic and transphobic violence as a global issue that has critical implications for positive development, health, and academic success of children and adolescence. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~en.unesco.org/themes/school-violence-and-bullying/homophobic-transphobic-violence&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UNESCO report&lt;/a&gt; argued that bullying generally, and bullying related to sexual orientation and gender identity (SOGI) specifically, comprise a threat to the universal right to education established in the 1948 Universal Declaration of Human Rights by the United Nations. This groundbreaking report provided a comprehensive review of the international literature on SOGI-related bullying in schools and documented the disproportionate rates of bullying for LGBTQ-GNC youth in countries on every continent across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these social and cultural norms and conventions impact the rights of all LGBTQ-GNC people, they are especially salient in relation to young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the landscape regarding human rights affordances, constraints, and abuses related to sexual orientation and gender identity (SOGI) is constantly in flux, any discussion of the SOGI rights of young people must take into account this larger global context. The rights of LGBTQ-GNC youth in countries where the expression of same-sex sexuality is criminalized are virtually non-existent; further, human rights violations against LGBTQ-GNC youth occur within most countries across the globe and are often justified by cultural and social norms and conventions regarding “acceptable or normal” definitions of sexuality and gender. While these social and cultural norms and conventions impact the rights of all LGBTQ-GNC people, they are especially salient in relation to young people. While several advances have been made in the last decade to advance the rights of LGBTQ-GNC people across the globe (for example see the 2006 Yogykarta Principles and the 2011 Human Rights Council’s resolution on LGBTQ-GNC rights) these documents rarely attend to specific SOGI rights of &lt;em&gt;young people&lt;/em&gt; or put forth any particular considerations regarding children and youth (a notable exception is in relation to access to education).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding intersecting forms of oppression—such as the ways that structural oppression related to gender and sexuality and its intersections with race, ethnicity, class, and religion affect young people, their parents, and educators in schools—is essential for designing and implementing effective processes, strategies, programs, and advocacy aimed at creating positive change within school contexts. Many of the SOGI-related inequities evidenced in schools can be traced, in part, to narrow definitions of masculinity and femininity, rigid frameworks regarding gender and gender roles, and hegemonic structures in schools that mark heterosexuality as not only compulsory but also the sole valid expression of sexuality. Other forms of structural oppression rooted in racism, religious, or social class bias, are intertwined with SOGI issues in schools through inequitable discipline practices, religious control of public education, or economic disparities across schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because SOGI issues in schools are embedded within larger systems of oppression, it is critical that research, practice, and policy engage with social justice and anti-oppressive education frameworks. Such approaches bring to the fore the ways that power, privilege, and bias structure schools in ways that tacitly sanction a range of educational inequities such as bullying, access to resources and services, and safety for young people in relation to sexual orientation and gender identity. As we continue to do this work, it has become increasingly evident that the SOGI safe schools movement is “inextricably linked” to broader education justice concerns. It is critical for the safe schools movement to work with others through intersectional, multi-issue coalitions—at the nexus of research, policy and practice—to ensure that all students’ educational rights, regardless of social position, are upheld. This type of cross-issue organizing, advocacy, and research takes time and needs to be grounded in the principals of the worth and dignity of all people, and that ensuring the rights of specific groups expands the rights of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Class by NeONBRAND. Public domain via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://unsplash.com/photos/zFSo6bnZJTw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/safe-supportive-schools-lgbtq-gnc-students/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/550638442/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/550638442/oupblogpsychology,&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/stroboscopic-medicine/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Stroboscopic medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/defining-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Defining a network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/double-helix-editing-levels-scientific-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Levels of editing of a scientific paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kimberly Ilkowski</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">There are benefits to prenatal yoga, but lingering questions remain</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/there-are-benefits-prenatal-yoga-lingering-questions-remain"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/there-are-benefits-prenatal-yoga-lingering-questions-remain</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T19:30:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Prenatal yoga offers benefits to pregnant women, but a bigger and more rigorous body of research is needed.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Krieger</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A new 3-D printer builds temporary electronics on your skin</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-3d-printer-builds-temporary-electronics-on-your-skin"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-3d-printer-builds-temporary-electronics-on-your-skin</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T18:30:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new 3-D printer that tracks and compensates for your slightest twitch can precisely print simple electronic devices onto your skin.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tropical cyclones have slowed over the last 70 years</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tropical-cyclones-have-slowed-over-last-70-years"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tropical-cyclones-have-slowed-over-last-70-years</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T17:34:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Tropical cyclones are moving 10 percent slower, on average, than they did in the mid-20th century, potentially making them more dangerous.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">If real, dark fusion could help demystify this physics puzzle</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-real-dark-fusion-could-help-demystify-physics-puzzle"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-real-dark-fusion-could-help-demystify-physics-puzzle</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T13:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fusing dark matter particles might explain why galaxy cores have evenly distributed dark matter.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Cancer Essentials — explore research on DNA repair</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/cancer-essentials-dna-repair"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/cancer-essentials-dna-repair</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T12:53:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 From experimental tools and methods, to pathways and signaling, genome instability, new drugs and clinical translation</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Misconduct probe of once rising star prompts retraction of cat’s meow paper</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/06/misconduct-probe-of-once-rising-star-prompts-retraction-of-cats-meow-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66378</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A group of Australian researchers who studied the cat’s meow as a model for urinary incontinence and other motor-neural issues in people have lost a 2015 paper in the wake of a misconduct investigation. The target of the inquiry was Hari Subramanian, a former senior research fellow at the Queensland Brain Institute, part of the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/06/misconduct-probe-of-once-rising-star-prompts-retraction-of-cats-meow-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Misconduct probe of once rising star prompts retraction of cat’s meow paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A big analysis of environmental data strengthens the case for plant-based diets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-based-diets-greenhouse-gases-environment"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-based-diets-greenhouse-gases-environment</id>
		<updated>2018-06-06T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new study calculates the bonus for the planet of choosing more foods from plants.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dogs carry a surprising variety of flu viruses</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dogs-carry-surprising-variety-flu-viruses"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dogs-carry-surprising-variety-flu-viruses</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T18:37:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Dogs in China carry a wider variety of flu viruses than previously thought, and may be capable of passing the flu to humans.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What we know — and don’t know — about a new migraine drug</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-we-know-and-dont-know-about-new-migraine-drug"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-we-know-and-dont-know-about-new-migraine-drug</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T18:17:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A migraine prevention drug was recently approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. But some questions about the therapy remain.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leah Rosenbaum</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s a look at the world’s deadliest volcanoes — and the ways they kill</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/worlds-deadliest-volcanoes-and-how-they-kill"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/worlds-deadliest-volcanoes-and-how-they-kill</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T17:09:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists gathered data on nearly 280,000 global volcano deaths from 1500 to 2017 and sorted fatalities by cause of death, such as lava flows or gas.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New Horizons wakes up to begin Kuiper Belt exploration</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-wakes-begin-kuiper-belt-exploration"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-wakes-begin-kuiper-belt-exploration</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T14:51:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The New Horizons spacecraft just woke up to get ready for its New Year’s Day flyby of the distant space rock Ultima Thule.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Acupuncture and Pain</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/05/acupuncture-and-pain/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23733</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T14:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is one of the oldest systems of traditional medicine. With roots in China, this medical system is more than 2000 years old. It differs from various other medical systems as it does not involve taking any herbs or substances. Instead, it involves inserting small needles at specific predefined points. From the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century onwards, it has continued to gain prominence in the Western world, although many remain skeptical about efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, researchers want to know the exact mechanism of action of any medical system. They only trust the therapy if it has been proven as effective in randomized placebo-controlled clinical trials. Acupuncture has been the subject of many such trials, and its usefulness has been established in certain pain-associated conditions, mood disorders, and even in some diseases of internal organs. This led to the recognition of this medical system by many healthcare providers and medical organizations. In the US, acupuncture is recognized as complementary medicine. The WHO also recommends it for a number of specific medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical evidence of efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of clinical trials provide evidence of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/10/21/the-science-of-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;the effectiveness of acupuncture&lt;/a&gt; in various medical conditions. Among the most relevant trials are the so-called German mega-trials named ARC, ART, COMP, and GERAC. The primary focus of these trials has been pain relief in various musculoskeletal conditions. GERAC and ART were high quality random clinical trials investigating low back pain. These trials compared real acupuncture with sham acupuncture and standard care. Sham acupuncture involved needling without the use of conventional acupuncture points. Whereas standard care included the use of physiotherapy, exercise therapy, and NSAIDs (non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs). Results were measured after three months, and the response was defined as adequate if there was an improvement of more than 33% on the pain scale (the Von Korff Chronic Pain Grade Scale). After 6-months, the response rate with real acupuncture was 47.6%, while it was 44.2% with sham acupuncture, and 27.4% with standard care. Though these trials clearly demonstrated the efficacy of acupuncture, they also showed &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/07/29/there-is-no-sham-in-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;the effectiveness of sham acupuncture&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers think that this phenomenon is linked to psychogenic factors involved with back pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, similar results were also demonstrated in various trials in the US. Though these trials show the usefulness of acupuncture in painful conditions, they also illustrate the value of psychogenic factors. Therefore, it is not surprising that acupuncture had also proven its utility in treating mood disorders and sleep disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chinese medicine, the use of acupuncture is not limited to pain-related conditions. Thus, there is need for more extensive trials across a diverse range of diseases. The existing data do indicate that acupuncture may be an alternative approach for many difficult to treat chronic ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possible mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the areas of debate regarding acupuncture has been the difficulty in explaining its mechanism of action. As per traditional explanation, acupuncture is used to correct the flow of energy (Qi) in the body. This life energy flows through the fixed paths or highways in our body called &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/02/03/a-primer-on-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;meridians&lt;/a&gt;. Practitioners of acupuncture believe that in disease conditions there is a blockade of energy highways or meridians. Acupuncture is about creating the balance between the internal forces called Yin and Yang. However, the trouble is that modern science is not able to demonstrate or even understand the concepts of Qi, Yin, Yang, and Meridians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few decades, practitioners of modern science have made various attempts to explain the mechanism of action of acupuncture, and they came up with multiple theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable effects of acupuncture&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the explanations is that needling does cause local changes and alterations in reflexes. It also has systemic effects, as it changes the working of the autonomous nervous system. Thus, acupuncture affects blood pressure, heart rate, levels of various hormones, and changes the levels of neurotransmitters. All of this results in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/01/mind-over-matter-mindfulness-meditation-for-pain-management/&quot;&gt;pain relief&lt;/a&gt; and other beneficial effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local mechanotransduction&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a theory promoted by a French physician in 1961, who wrote that acupuncture points have lower local resistance when compared to surrounding skin. He wrote that while normal dry skin has a resistance of 200,000 to 2 million Ohms, acupuncture points have a resistance of just 50,000 Ohms. The believers in this theory say that acupuncture causes minute traumas at the points of needle insertion and thus stimulates survival mechanisms of the body. Needling stimulates homeostasis, anti-inflammatory responses, tissue regeneration, and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neurohumoral theory&lt;/strong&gt;: it has been demonstrated that acupuncture is useful in pain relief, and naloxone blocks its analgesic effect. Thus, researchers propose that needling at specific points leads to the release of endogenous painkilling &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;opiate-like substances&lt;/a&gt; such as enkephalins, endorphins, dynorphins and some other neurotransmitters like serotonin and noradrenaline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gate-control theory&lt;/strong&gt;: This theory states that needling stimulates large myelinated nerve fibers. These fibers carry tingling sensations and feelings of warmth, and can inhibit the painful sensation that is transmitted to the brain by much smaller C-fibers via spinal tracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postsynaptic inhibition&lt;/strong&gt;: This is another explanation, which states that acupuncture results in the inhibition of pain through a central mechanism via disinhibition of RAF. This phenomenon typically works in cases of extreme trauma like loss of limb. This central mechanism has a role in protecting the body from extreme stress and pain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous nervous system&lt;/strong&gt;: Proponents of this theory suggest that acupuncture works by changing the balance of sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphogenetic singularity theory&lt;/strong&gt;: This is one of the more complicated hypotheses that tries to explain the existence of meridians. Advocates of this theory explain the presence of non-neural communication pathways in the body. During embryonic development, when neurons are not yet formed, cells must communicate among themselves to direct development. Meridians are just the remains of these early communication paths, which are still present in the adult body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;: In recent years, fMRI methods have advanced a lot, and in many clinical studies it has been demonstrated that stimulation of various acupuncture points by needling results in activation of different brain centers, thus explaining the mechanism of action of acupuncture. It is believed that both the elements of morphogenetic singularity theory (meridians) and components of the neurohumoral response are involved in the stimulation of the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that various theories have been used to describe the mechanism of action of acupuncture, and most probably there is more than one mechanism is involved. Clinical trials do seem to indicate that acupuncture is beneficial in specific health conditions. But the way it works still remains a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dong, B., Chen, Z., Yin, X., Li, D., Ma, J., Yin, P., … Xu, S. (2017. The Efficacy of Acupuncture for Treating Depression-Related Insomnia Compared with a Control Group: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. &lt;em&gt;BioMed Research International&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2017&lt;/em&gt;, 9614810. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/9614810&quot;&gt;10.1155/2017/9614810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kawakita, K., &amp;amp; Okada, K. (2014) Acupuncture therapy: mechanism of action, efficacy, and safety: a potential intervention for psychogenic disorders? &lt;em&gt;Biopsychosocial Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 4. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1186/1751-0759-8-4&quot;&gt;10.1186/1751-0759-8-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White, A., &amp;amp; Ernst, E. (2004) A brief history of acupuncture. &lt;em&gt;Rheumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(5), 662–663. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1093/rheumatology/keg005&quot;&gt;10.1093/rheumatology/keg005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wong MC, Shen HJ (2010) Science-based Mechanisms to Explain the Action of Acupuncture. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Association of Traditional Chinese Medicine (UK),&lt;/em&gt; 17(2), 5-10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/AusAcu-5549293/&quot;&gt;AusAcu&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Congrats! Your paper was accepted. (Except if the acceptance letter was forged.)</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/05/congrats-your-paper-was-accepted-or-was-it/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66341</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 You’ve worked hard on your research, spent time writing it up, and finally, the good news comes: The journal you submitted to has accepted your paper. Trouble is, for multiple authors, that good news turns bad — the acceptance was fake. Recently, in Scholarly Kitchen, Angela Cochran,  Associate Publisher, American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE), … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/05/congrats-your-paper-was-accepted-or-was-it/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Congrats! Your paper was accepted. (Except if the acceptance letter was forged.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">David Latchman, the reckless Master of Birkbeck</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/05/david-latchman-the-reckless-master-of-birkbeck/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24288</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T11:20:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 This is a story of David Latchman, Master of Birkbeck at University of London, professor of genetics at UCL and Commander of the Order of the British Empire. All this he achieved also by his impressive publishing record, part of which will be discussed below by my regular contributor Smut Clyde. Just part of it, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/05/david-latchman-the-reckless-master-of-birkbeck/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;David Latchman, the reckless Master of Birkbeck&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Privacy and consumer genetic testing don’t always mix</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/privacy-and-consumer-genetic-testing-dont-always-mix"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/privacy-and-consumer-genetic-testing-dont-always-mix</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Interested in taking a direct-to-consumer genetic test? Here are some things you should know.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Cassie Martin</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">How a salmon gets its spots</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/05/how-a-salmon-gets-its-spots/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10231</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T08:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/HI-034040-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now know that it is something in the farming environment that makes the salmon there have many spots, but we have yet to find out exactly how the spots are triggered. It could be anything from the lighting regime, temperature, diet, to the fish density or growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated whether a specific breed of domesticated salmon had different numbers of spots depending on whether it had been hatched in a river or lived on a salmon farm its entire life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We planted domesticated salmon into the Guddal river, Norway, where it hatched and stayed for 2-4 years before we took the salmon out of the river as smolts (juveniles) and moved it to our research station at Matre. After spending two years in land based tanks there, these salmon were still seven times less spotty than domesticated salmon that had lived its entire life at Matre under standard farming conditions, even though the salmon were the same breed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10234&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-10234&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Fig-spots-1024x483.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Photographed by Monica F Solberg and edited by Katarina Jørgensen&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both domesticated and wild salmon growing up in a farm environment had many spots, while all the salmon, both domesticated and wild, that were reared in the river had few spots. This means that we can be certain that it’s the environment that decides how many spots a salmon gets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we also identified a region on salmon chromosome, a quantitative trait locus (QTL), containing genes linked to the degree of spottiness. So, genetics does play a role, but it is small compared to the effect of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the wild salmon and the domesticated salmon from the Guddal river had few spots even though these salmon lived for two years in land based tanks at the research station at Matre. This indicates that the spots were established on the salmon before it was removed from the river at smolting. That the salmon receive their distinguishing marks before they have time to escape is a useful observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many spots are nevertheless a safe indicator of an escaped farmed salmon if you catch one in a river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleaning rivers of escaped farmed salmon currently happens based on visible traits such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://lakselva.no/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Salmopedia-h%C3%A5ndbok.pdf&quot;&gt;body shape, the wear of fins and spots&lt;/a&gt;. If farmed salmon survive for long in nature, they start to resemble wild salmon. Spots on salmon have been shown in &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jfb.13491&quot;&gt;several studies&lt;/a&gt; to be stable over time, so they probably don’t disappear upon escaping, although this is not what we have tested here. Many spots are nevertheless a safe indicator of an escaped farmed salmon if you catch one in a river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, experiments in Zebrafish show that when their stripes are disrupted experimentally they grow back in a way that is consistent with Alan Turing’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/329/5999/1616&quot;&gt;theory of how biological patterns form&lt;/a&gt;. Turing patterns are known for allowing the environment to influence the pattern in ways which create individuality in each one – &lt;a href=&quot;https://tbiomed.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1742-4682-8-24&quot;&gt;like in human fingerprints&lt;/a&gt;. Finding environmentally determined patterns in a well characterized species like Atlantic salmon points to new opportunities for studying biological pattern formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuality of patterns together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jfb.13491&quot;&gt;spot stability over time&lt;/a&gt; also suggests that spot patterns could be used for identifying individual fish using video surveillance, which may be used to monitor the environment in both fish farms and rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/05/how-a-salmon-gets-its-spots/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How a salmon gets its spots&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Katarina M Jørgensen, Monica F Solberg &amp;#38; Kevin A Glover</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T11:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Fastest Path to Freedom</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/the-fastest-path-to-freedom/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1348</id>
		<updated>2018-06-05T05:29:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Fastest-Path-banner.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fastest Path banner&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1353&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Fastest-Path-banner-300x66.png&quot; width=&quot;605&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Chandreyee Das, Ph.D., Science Exchange, b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ased on an interview with Mareb Hamed, (MBChB, MSc, PhD), University of Mosul&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Scientific research is challenging enough. But for Dr. Mareb Hamed, geopolitical upheaval in her home country of Iraq threatened not only her research, but also her survival.&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Flag-map_of_Iraq.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1349 alignright&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Flag-map_of_Iraq-300x300.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed’s story, and how Science Exchange became a part of that story, inspires our team to keep doing what we do — helping scientists connect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;Studying Growth-Restricted Fetuses in War-Torn Iraq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Mareb Hamed graduated at the top of her class from the Medical University in Mosul, Iraq, a city which was, at its peak, a cultural and educational center. In the 1990s, the political situation worsened under the regime of Saddam Hussein, and Dr. Hamed and her husband left Iraq and moved to Libya. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;When war started in Libya, Dr. Hamed returned to Iraq but could not re-obtain her former position of assistant professor, much to her frustration.“So I enrolled in the PhD program,” she explained, “in order to advance my career and because I liked research.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed began her research project in 2014, investigating the effect of intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) on placental biomarkers. IUGR can be caused by multiple factors and is a leading cause of neonatal deaths. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;From Researcher to Refugee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed had collected a number of placenta samples from local hospitals when the Arabs entered Mosul, killing or forcing the departure of countless scientists, engineers, doctors, lawyers, journalists, and other professionals.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“I became a refugee in Erbil city,” recounted Dr. Hamed. “I lost everything. My house, my car..even the placenta samples that I was collecting.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“But I knew I had to complete my PhD — I knew I had to start over and complete my research. So I continued my research at the University of Erbil, renting a small condo so that I could start working.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;Erbil to St. Louis: Science Exchange Opens Gateway to Collaboration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;At the University of Kurdistan in Erbil, Dr. Hamed started collecting placentas again, and she was able to complete the histology and the immunohistochemistry on these samples. But the remaining analysis, which required electron microscopy, proved very difficult and cost-prohibitive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“I started searching on the internet,” she continued, “and I found Science Exchange, and through Science Exchange, a provider who could do the microscopy for me.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed started sending her placenta capsule samples through DHL to the provider, an academic core laboratory at Washington University in St. Louis. The provider lab did the sectioning and the staining, and started sending Dr. Hamed the images by email. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“The microscopy images they sent me were very nice,” said Dr. Hamed. “Even during the defense of my thesis, I was told, “You have very nice pictures.”  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;The Surprise, and the Legacy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Mareb-Acknowledgment.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mareb Acknowledgment&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1351 alignright&quot; height=&quot;262&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Mareb-Acknowledgment-300x262.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Then, I got a surprise,” said Dr. Hamed, “and I am very grateful to Washington University for this. When I told the lab my story, about how I was a refugee from Mosul, and how they had taken everything, they performed the service without requiring any payment. They did not take even one dollar from me! Only I have paid the cost of sending the samples by DHL.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed successfully defended her thesis, in which she acknowledged Science Exchange and her collaborators in St. Louis. She has since gone on to continue her research in Mosul and also provide medical assistance and training to other dislocated and disadvantaged Iraqis — showing that the power of scientific connections goes far beyond an electron microscope.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Famous Harvard economist reused parts of 2002 paper multiple times, says journal</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/famous-harvard-economist-reused-parts-of-2002-paper-multiple-times-says-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66336</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T15:08:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A former Harvard economist and co-founder of a massive repository of free papers in social sciences has been accused of reusing similar material over multiple papers. The three papers share the same title. According to an investigation by one of the journals, two papers by Michael Jensen, now an emeritus faculty member at Harvard, are … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/famous-harvard-economist-reused-parts-of-2002-paper-multiple-times-says-journal/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Famous Harvard economist reused parts of 2002 paper multiple times, says journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Take a virtual trip to an alien world</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/take-virtual-trip-alien-world"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/take-virtual-trip-alien-world</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T14:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 NASA’s Exoplanet Travel Bureau website lets you view what alien landscapes might look like.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_35998542614309853=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">EAPC2018: Integration and scare of Palliative Care</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/04/eapc2018-integration-scare-palliative-care/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10219</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T13:40:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/20180531_150109-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 2500 Palliative Care researchers and clinicians traveled to the UNESCO World Heritage Site Bern to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eapcnet.eu/research2018/&quot;&gt;EAPC2018&lt;/a&gt;. With a stunning view of the Swiss Alps, the congress commenced with a musical interlude by members of the youthful local string ensemble &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cellobass.ch/Cellobass/PRJOJEKT.html&quot;&gt;CELLOBASS&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a welcome from the President of the Swiss Science Foundation, and the Mayor of the City of Bern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time for celebration!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s congress was marked by a double celebration, namely the 30th anniversary of the European Association for Palliative Care, as well as the commemoration of the 100th birthday of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cicelysaundersinternational.org/dame-cicely-saunders/&quot;&gt;Dame Cicely Saunders&lt;/a&gt;, widely regarded as the founder of palliative care as we know it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cicely trained as a nurse, social worker and physician, dedicating her work to pain and symptom relief through holistic care that not only addresses the physical needs of patients, but also meets the social, psychosocial and spiritual needs of patients, family and carers. She was involved in the foundation and running of the world’s first purpose-build hospice St. Christopher’s Hospice in London, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cicelysaundersinternational.org/&quot;&gt;Cicely Saunders Institute&lt;/a&gt;, a charitable organisation which promotes research to improve care and treatment for all patients with progressive illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hot topics in palliative (s)care research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was broadly divided into three major topics: cancer and palliative care, public health and policy, and ageing and palliative care. Furthermore, the first day saw a special Swiss session, which discussed controversial topics such as the wish to die and hastening of death, voluntary stopping of eating and drinking, and continuous deep sedation, as well as topics on palliative care services in Switzerland and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free standing sessions were also held, addressing various topics including family carers, palliative care in diverse chronic illnesses, advance care planning, education research, and research methods discussions. However, two themes emerged in talks across all sections: 1. the increasing requirements of palliative care needs worldwide, and 2. the recommendation to integrate palliative care alongside clinical care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term palliative care has become an unspeakable metaphor for one’s own death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter topic was addressed in two talks by the winner of this year’s Clinical Impact Award &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicine.duke.edu/faculty/thomas-william-leblanc-md&quot;&gt;Thomas LeBlanc MD&lt;/a&gt;, who discussed his own work on integrating palliative care in the clinical treatment of patients suffering from haemato-oncological diseases. His slip of the tongue “Palliative Scare” was an unintended example of how the service is often feared by medical professionals and patients as an end-of-the-line treatment. This thought was also emphasized by Early Researcher Award winner &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thegroundswellproject.com/anna-collins/&quot;&gt;Anna Collins&lt;/a&gt;, who stated that the term palliative care has become an unspeakable metaphor for one’s own death, and discussed the communication between patients and doctors about death, dying and the introduction of palliative care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These and other discussions at EAPC2018 indicated that integrating palliative care in the treatment of terminal (cancer) patients at an earlier stage helps relieve unaddressed symptoms, lessens psychosocial distress, and improves overall quality of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palliative care for the many and the few&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several talks at EAPC2018 addressed the specialist palliative care needs and requirements for minority groups. The variety in minority groups resulted in diverse topics discussing different aspects and needs of palliative care, including the spiritual needs of religious people in secular countries, and the cultural and linguistic barriers between carers and patients of different ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children form another minority group in palliative care, and their specialized needs can sometimes be overlooked by palliative care researchers and carers. In an excellent talk by Post Doctoral Award winner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.york.ac.uk/healthsciences/our-staff/lorna-fraser/&quot;&gt;Lorna Fraser&lt;/a&gt;, various data sets were linked to provide a better insight in the access to palliative care for children and young adults with progressive or terminal disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite was an insightful talk by Mary Turner on palliative care for dying prisoners, and in particular the difficulties faced by prison officers responsible for their care. The shortage of palliative carers in UK prisons means that most palliative support is provided by prison officers who are not trained to deal with the psychological aftermath of caring for the terminally ill. Furthermore, the facilities in UK prisons often do not allow for the installments of hospital beds, wheelchairs may not fit through doors, and palliative care resources are lacking. The lack of time, resources, and training relating to palliative care for dying inmates contributes to the general stress and job-related ill health of prison officers across the UK, and a poor quality of life for dying inmates. An open meeting to discuss a taskforce for care provision for prisoners in Europe was also part of the EAPC2018 program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal reflections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10222&quot; style=&quot;width: 322px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10222&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/hospice-1821429_960_720-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;312&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EAPC2018 was a very interesting conference that covered a wide range of thought-provoking, and sometimes controversial topics, and I would certainly recommend this congress to anyone with interest in the field. I would like to congratulate &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpalliatcare.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Palliative Care&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Associate Editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://research4kids.ucalgary.ca/profiles/shane-sinclair&quot;&gt;Shane Sinclair&lt;/a&gt; for receiving the Paper of the Year Award, and I would like to commend the organisers for handing out sturdy, reusable plastic cups, which greatly reduced the amount of plastic waste that I have experienced at other conferences. I am certainly looking forward to the 11th World Research Congress of the EAPC in Palermo, Italy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/04/eapc2018-integration-scare-palliative-care/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EAPC2018: Integration and scare of Palliative Care&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Zalm</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T11:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Outbreak’ puts the life cycle of an epidemic on display</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/outbreak-exhibit-puts-life-cycle-epidemic-display"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/outbreak-exhibit-puts-life-cycle-epidemic-display</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 At the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History, the exhibit “Outbreak” highlights how infectious diseases shape our world.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_37264624326629175=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">See a paper you like? PubPeer wants to help you create a “journal” around it</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/see-a-paper-you-like-pubpeer-wants-to-help-you-create-a-journal-around-it/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66298</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T10:00:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Not everyone is happy with journals these days — researchers in artificial intelligence have announced they were boycotting a new Nature journal for being subscription-only, and universities are cancelling subscriptions over fees. The founders of PubPeer — a site dedicated to commentary about already published papers — are trying a different approach. Today, the PubPeer … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/see-a-paper-you-like-pubpeer-wants-to-help-you-create-a-journal-around-it/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;See a paper you like? PubPeer wants to help you create a “journal” around it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Where is all the women’s brain health research?</title>
		<link href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/where-is-all-the-womens-brain-health-research/"/>
		<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5526</id>
		<updated>2018-06-04T01:01:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/argonne/4534362371&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-5529&quot; height=&quot;665&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/4534362371_3da9090e51_b-1024x680.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Photo by George Joch / courtesy Argonne National Laboratory.&quot; width=&quot;1002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt from the Introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/book/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade writing about brain science, I’ve developed a tried and tested method for researching an unfamiliar topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I’ll read the appropriate chapter in &lt;em&gt;Principles of Neural Science,&lt;/em&gt; the neuro-bible beloved by brain geeks the world over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll run a quick search on PubMed, an online search engine of biomedical literature, to find a recent review of the topic, typically written by a top scientist in the particular field, which will give me a feel for the topic’s controversies and consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll feel confident enough to read and understand original research papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ll seek out the experts themselves – the scientists, doctors and specialists, who, despite their busy schedules, usually give generously of their time to answer my questions and fill in the gaps of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, describing the neurobiology of women’s everyday lives hasn’t always been as straightforward as I expected when I began writing my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My meander through the world of women’s health often left me bewildered. Time and time again I’d open the textbooks or scan the literature to find scant research on some of the questions I’d been most curious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I assumed the literature would be replete with information on how the oral contraceptive pill affects women’s brains. A 2014 review summed up the current state of affairs with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4139599/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;50 Years of Hormonal Contraception. Time to Find Out What It Does to the Brain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I proudly announced to Facebook the day I finally dived into the neurobiology of multiple orgasms. But it was not a deep dive. PubMed spat out only five literature reviews, three of which were devoted to the possibility of multiple orgasms in men. One was amusingly titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2050052115000542&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple Orgasms in Men. What We Know So Far&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (FYI: Orgasms don’t rate a mention in neuroscience textbooks and we don’t know much so far about women’s orgasm either).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my best efforts, I was unable to pin down the statistics for how many women suffer emotional turmoil in the days leading up to their period, aka premenstrual syndrome (PMS). I eventually narrowed the range down to somewhere between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3972521/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twelve &lt;/a&gt;per cent and ninety per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was positive I’d be able to tell my mid-life readers whether or HRT would help protect against dementia or clear away their brain fog. Oestrogen protects the ageing brain, but we simply don’t have enough information about the benefits for brain health for any recommendations to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is the literature so sparse when it comes to neurobiology and women’s health?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, preclinical research (research conducted on lab animals such as rats, mice or monkeys) has mostly been conducted on male animals. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3008499/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2009 survey&lt;/a&gt; of over 2000 animal studies found a significant male bias in eight out of ten biological disciplines. The bias was most pronounced in the field of neuroscience where five and a half males were studied for every one female. Worryingly, pharmacology (the study of drugs) shares similar statistics, with five males studied to every one female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinical research (investigations conducted on humans) hasn’t fared much better. There are a few large, all-female projects such as the Women’s Health Study which I’ll discuss in later chapters, but for many years women were excluded from clinical studies and drug trials altogether. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4714546/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one critic notes&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many medical professionals can attest to the fact that for decades, the default human model subject was a 70-kg male.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is alarming because diagnoses for anxiety and depression are more than twice as common in women than in men, women have more strokes than men, twice as many women suffer from multiple sclerosis, and women have a higher susceptibility to adverse drug reactions compared with men. Indeed, between 1997 and 2000, eight out of ten drugs withdrawn from the USA market were, in part, due to more severe adverse effects in women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cumulative effect of excluding women from research studies, or assuming that biologically women are ‘little men’, is destructive. As has been pointed out in the journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20535186&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, medical care as it is currently applied to women is less evidence-based or ‘robust’ than that being applied to men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d be tempted to believe the straightforward sexism permeates the hallowed halls and ivory towers as readily as other global institutions. It does, but sexism isn’t the only reason for lack of gender equality. There are some legitimate reasons to skew the ratios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason is safety because if women fall pregnant during a drug trial there is the potential for harming the unborn baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that females – both animals and humans – complicate data gathering. Our cyclical reproductive hormones, especially during the fertile years between puberty and menopause, make our biology intrinsically more fickle than males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The menstrual cycle was once&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=cahill+L+2017++an+issue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; likened&lt;/a&gt; to “a pesky sort of feature essentially of the female, an unnecessary source of additional variability and one wisest to avoid.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further complicate matters, in humans, biological sex (anatomy and physiology) and gender (characteristics that a society or culture defines as masculine or feminine) are tightly entwined and hard to tease apart. It’s extraordinarily difficult to make statements such as, ‘It’s due to her hormones’, or ‘It’s all to do with cultural expectations’. Rather than tackle the intricacies of female sex and gender, female hormones and culture, researchers often choose the easier route of focussing on males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, research on sex and gender has been for a long time been almost taboo. This is especially so in the neurosciences where many researchers were deeply concerned that their findings could be hijacked to support outdated and inaccurate stereotypes and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fears are not unfounded. Women’s brains have historically been found wanting or biologically inferior compared to males, and such &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/how-neurosexism-is-holding-back-gender-equality-and-science-itself-67597&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has been co-opted to “keep women in their place”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neuroscientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=cahill+L+2017++an+issue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…exploring sex differences was once “a terrific way for a brain scientist not studying reproductive functions to lose credibility at best and, at worst, become a pariah in the eyes of the neuroscience mainstream.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to another who said she once believed including sex as a biological variable was ‘lazy’. This was before she came to the conclusion that studying the impact of a woman’s menstrual cycle on the brain might add a valuable dimension to her research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the research community is taking steps to address the dearth of neurobiological research in women, and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hachette.com.au/dr-sarah-mckay/female-brain-book&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Women’s Brain Book&lt;/a&gt; you’ll meet some of the researchers at the forefront of the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institutions such as the National Institutes of Health (NIH) in the United States and academic publications such as the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Neuroscience Research&lt;/em&gt; now mandate the inclusion of sex as a biological variable in all research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) clearly states the research into the health of women and girls is a particular priority. Here in Australia, we have the Australian Longitudinal Study on Women’s Health, a survey of the physical, mental and psychosocial health of over 58,000 women across their lifespan. Finally, there are some fabulous research initiatives such as Stanford University’s Gendered Innovations project that exist to ‘harness the creative power of sex and gender analysis for innovation and discovery’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from the Introduction to The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hachette.com.au/dr-sarah-mckay/female-brain-book&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Find out how to get your copy here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/where-is-all-the-womens-brain-health-research/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Where is all the women’s brain health research?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McKay</name>
			<uri>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Your Brain Health</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Discover neuroscience. Explore the brain. Understand your mind.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/"/>
			<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</id>
			<updated>2018-06-04T05:00:41+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What consumer DNA data can and can’t tell you about your risk for certain diseases</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/health-dna-genetic-testing-disease"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/health-dna-genetic-testing-disease</id>
		<updated>2018-06-03T10:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Consumers face lots of choices and unanswered questions when they get personal genomic information related to disease risk from the Internet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_37264624326629175=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Philosophy of Roseanne's Ambien Tweet</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9539"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9539</id>
		<updated>2018-06-02T18:39:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 As everyone knows, Roseanne Barr posted a racist tweet. She claimed that the sleeping medication Ambien affected her behavior, but her show got cancelled anyway.



Now, I think this scandal raises some surprisingly interesting philosophical questions about moral responsibility and the nature of self-control. What follows is a dialogue between two hypothetical speakers exploring some of these questions. To be clear, this is a post about philosophy, not about Roseanne. I don't know or care if</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-06-02T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Closing the loop for brain imaging in depression: What have we learned and where are we heading? By David Mehler</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/9Vnf2s_Zh4I/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19587</id>
		<updated>2018-06-02T18:08:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/06/DepressionImaging_larger-1-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depression can have a profound impact on affected individuals and those around them. It is one of the most common mental health conditions, and its symptoms include sustained feeling of sadness, hopelessness, and guilt. In severe cases, these symptoms may be aggravated by suicidal thoughts, or even attempts. The odds of experiencing a depressive episode are relatively high: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-244X-9-19&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at least&lt;/a&gt; one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/196765&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;six&lt;/a&gt; individuals will experience an episode in their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the term &lt;em&gt;depression&lt;/em&gt; suggests that it represents a single psychiatric condition, patients vary tremendously in their symptoms, risk factors, and response to available treatment. Risk factors include not only genetic variations and hormonal changes, but also destructive thinking patterns, or stressful and traumatising experiences. Current treatments primarily include medication and psychotherapy. Medication prescribed in depression targets different brain chemical systems, involving neurotransmitters that include serotonin and dopamine. These are involved in communication between nerve cells and, more generally, in the feeling of well-being. Psychotherapy aims to help patients develop effective coping strategies to use when they are faced with challenges and setbacks. Most depressed individuals will eventually recover – however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ajp.psychiatryonline.org/doi/abs/10.1176/ajp.2006.163.11.1905&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;up to one third&lt;/a&gt; may not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One branch of depression research focuses on finding biomarkers that can identify individuals that will most likely benefit from a specific therapy. The field also works on developing innovative treatments. However, both goals require a better understanding of the underlying biology. Brain imaging research, clinical psychology, and genetics have provided some fascinating answers, but have also posed new challenging questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We asked three experts and pioneers in depression research: &lt;em&gt;How do you study clinical depression, what role does brain imaging play in your research, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;and what challenges lie ahead for the field? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/group/mood/cgi-bin/wordpress/?p=243&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ian H. Gotlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Professor of Psychology, Department of Psychology, Stanford University):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Over the past two decades, we have learned that depression is a heterogeneous disorder, with wide variations in symptom presentation, age of onset, number and duration of episodes, and causal factors. In my lab, we take this heterogeneity seriously – we administer structured diagnostic interviews to every participant in our studies. And perhaps more important, we conduct multimodal assessments of depression – we examine &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-02062-y&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brain structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, function, and connectivity; endocrine function, both under acute stress and throughout the day; cognitive functioning, including biases in attention, interpretation, and memory; and digital phenotyping of depressed children, adolescents, and adults. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The number of brain imaging studies has grown exponentially, and there is now a burgeoning literature examining brain structure, function, and connectivity in depressed individuals. Neuroimaging studies have helped to elucidate the neural circuitry involved in reward processing and the processing of emotional experiences. Because the two cardinal symptoms of depression in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM) involve the persistent experience of negative affect and anhedonia, researchers studying depression have focused on examining their neural underpinnings. From these investigations we are learning about anomalous neural characteristics of depressed individuals that may be related to difficulties in daily functioning and that may serve as intervention targets. We know far less, however, about aspects of brain structure, function, and connectivity that place individuals at risk for developing depression, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/article-abstract/2675295?redirect=true&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;that keep high-risk persons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; from experiencing depression, and that influence the maintenance of and recovery from this disorder. We also know relatively little about the developmental trajectories of these anomalous neural characteristics, knowledge that is critical in understanding differences between children and adults in the presentation of depression.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mountsinai.org/profiles/helen-s-mayberg&quot;&gt;Helen Mayberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Professor of Neurology, Neurosurgery, Psychiatry and Neuroscience, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our lab takes a circuit approach to the study of major depression&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Studies integrate &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;multimodal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; neuroimaging strategies and quantitative behavioral and psychophysiological metrics within experimental clinical trial protocols to define brain mechanisms &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;that &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;mediat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; anti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;–&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;depre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;sant treatments. The overarching goal is to develop imaging biomarkers and algorithms that will &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;identify&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; patient subgroups and optimize treatment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;individual patients. This work &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;also &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;serves as a basis for ongoing testing and refinement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4413475/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;deep brain stimulation (DBS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;of the subcallosal cingulate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a technique that our lab is investigating&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; for treatment resistant depression. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imaging has provided new perspectives on understanding the pathogenesis of depression, as well as treatment mechanisms. Studies have systematically defined a core set of consistent regional abnormalities, correlations between symptoms and abnormal function of specific brain regions, and evidence of putative depression subtypes. Multimodal imaging and advanced analytic methods have further provided strategies to build depression circuit models that directly test &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4336918/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;treatment selection biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The challenge for the ‘field’ will be to define what method(s) are ‘good enough’ to warrant meaningful replication studies of an encouraging finding. Balancing a useful clinical biomarker that might improve treatment selection or response assessment from those addressing fundamental mechanisms of circuit dysfunction and pathophysiology require different strategies and standards.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/lindend.php&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David EJ Linden&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Professor of Translational Neuroscience, Cardiff University and Maastricht University):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;One of the main research techniques used in my group is real-time functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) neurofeedback training. fMRI allows researchers to trace activation patterns that are associated with external stimuli or internal mental states in real time, and we can feed these activation changes back to patients, so they can learn to regulate them themselves. This opens up interesting potential therapeutic avenues, for example, for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24733975&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;emotion regulation training in depression&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, but also &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.braintrainproject.eu/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;other mental disorders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functional brain mapping with fMRI has provided crucial new insights in the neural representations of affect and its disturbances. It has become clear that there are strong links between classical emotion and motivation areas, implemented through functional anatomical links between the limbic system and the basal ganglia, for example, in the ventral striatum. This has sparked renewed interest in the role of reward mechanisms in depression. A future challenge will be to work on the standardisation of imaging protocols across sites and conduct formal studies of the potential diagnostic and predictive value of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;these functional imaging patterns in order to produce clinically useful biomarkers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers and clinicians agree that depression can manifest differently in each individual. Neuroimaging and multimodal studies allow investigators to examine underlying mechanisms of such variability, although &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/fullarticle/2579940&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;identifying robust biomarkers&lt;/a&gt; remains challenging. This knowledge informs translational research into new brain circuit-based interventions, including clinical trials of DBS and neurofeedback treatment.  Thereby, the field may “close the loop,” yielding more effective and individually tailored treatments for depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunlop BW, Mayberg HS (2014). Neuroimaging-based biomarkers for treatment selection in major depressive disorder. &lt;em&gt;Dialogues Clin Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 16: 479–490.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holtzheimer PE, Mayberg HS (2011). Deep Brain Stimulation for Psychiatric Disorders. &lt;em&gt;Annu Rev Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 34: 289–307.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Koretz D, Merikangas KR, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; (2003). The Epidemiology of Major. &lt;em&gt;Am Med Assoc&lt;/em&gt; 289: 3095–3105.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linden DEJ (2014). Neurofeedback and networks of depression. &lt;em&gt;Dialogues Clin Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 16: 103–112.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Müller VI, Cieslik EC, Serbanescu I, Laird AR, Fox PT, Eickhoff SB (2017). Altered brain activity in unipolar depression revisited: Meta-analyses of neuroimaging studies. &lt;em&gt;JAMA Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 74: 47–55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patten SB (2009). Accumulation of major depressive episodes over time in a prospective study indicates that retrospectively assessed lifetime prevalence estimates are too low. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 9: 2–5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rush AJ, Trivedi MH, Wisniewski SR, Nierenberg AA, Stewart JW, Warden D, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; (2006). Acute and longer-term outcomes in depressed outpatients requiring one or several treatment steps: a STAR*D report. &lt;em&gt;Am J Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 163: 1905–17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacchet MD, Gotlib IH (2017). Myelination of the brain in major depressive disorder: An in vivo quantitative magnetic resonance imaging study. &lt;em&gt;Sci Rep&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1–14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image modified from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010945217303015#fig1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tianlu Wang et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00041/full&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alamian et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt; according to the Creative Commons license (CC-BY). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/01/David.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-19529&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/01/David-137x150.png&quot; width=&quot;137&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/mehlerd.php&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Mehler&lt;/a&gt; is an MD/PhD student at Cardiff University (UK) and the University of Muenster (Germany). He is a member of the Communications Committee for the Organization for Human Brain Mapping (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanbrainmapping.org/i4a/pages/index.cfm?pageid=3267&amp;amp;activateFull=false&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OHBM&lt;/a&gt;). He tweets as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neuroccino&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@neuroccino&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/9Vnf2s_Zh4I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emilie Reas</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2018-06-02T23:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Ghostwritten thesis apps; discriminatory authorship rules; group up to 14 retractions</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/02/weekend-reads-ghostwritten-thesis-apps-discriminatory-authorship-rules-group-up-to-14-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66290</id>
		<updated>2018-06-02T12:30:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction featured a paper by Kim Kardashian, four retractions for an author who … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/02/weekend-reads-ghostwritten-thesis-apps-discriminatory-authorship-rules-group-up-to-14-retractions/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Ghostwritten thesis apps; discriminatory authorship rules; group up to 14 retractions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Blame opioids for a fifth of young adult deaths in the United States</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cdc-opioids-fifth-young-adult-deaths-united-states"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cdc-opioids-fifth-young-adult-deaths-united-states</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T20:56:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Of young adults aged 25 to 34 who died in 2016, 20 percent of those deaths were opioid-related.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mysterious neutrino surplus hints at the existence of new particles</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-neutrino-surplus-hints-existence-new-particles"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-neutrino-surplus-hints-existence-new-particles</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T19:45:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Neutrinos show up in greater numbers than expected in an experiment, possibly bolstering the idea of a fourth type of the particle.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A neutron star crash may have spawned a black hole</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-crash-may-have-spawned-black-hole"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-crash-may-have-spawned-black-hole</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T17:52:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The neutron collision that took the astronomical community by storm last year probably created a black hole, researchers say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Future smart clothes could pack serious gadgetry</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-smart-clothes-could-pack-serious-gadgetry"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-smart-clothes-could-pack-serious-gadgetry</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T14:57:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Casual daywear may someday contain some serious tech. But engineers have to take conventional electronics and make them comfortable to wear.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming, Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How much cancer stems from diabetes, obesity? Lancet journal swaps high-profile paper</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/01/how-much-cancer-stems-from-diabetes-obesity-lancet-journal-swaps-high-profile-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66260</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T12:00:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Six months ago, the media was ablaze with the findings of a new paper, showing that nearly six percent of cancer cases are caused, at least in part, by obesity and diabetes. But this week, the journal retracted that paper — and replaced it with a revised version. The new paper doesn’t change the main … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/01/how-much-cancer-stems-from-diabetes-obesity-lancet-journal-swaps-high-profile-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;How much cancer stems from diabetes, obesity? Lancet journal swaps high-profile paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s why scientists are questioning whether ‘sonic attacks’ are real</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-are-questioning-whether-sonic-attacks-are-real"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-are-questioning-whether-sonic-attacks-are-real</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sonic attacks would be hard to pull off and a terrible way of incapacitating diplomats, experts say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T11:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">We’re taking a short break</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/were-taking-a-short-break/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34008</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T09:24:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-507875425.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34009&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34009&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 350D DIGITAL&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dogs and cats sleeping together.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1289921583&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bodza2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;232&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cat pillow, dog blanket&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cat pillow, dog blanket&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3543,2644&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/were-taking-a-short-break/cat-pillow-dog-blanket/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;We’re taking a break. Normal service will resume June 18, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T05:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A new study claims that, under pressure, imposter syndrome hits men harder than women</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/a-new-study-claims-that-under-pressure-imposter-syndrome-hits-men-harder-than-women/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34000</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T08:54:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-936097644.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34005&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34005&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1494399003&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/a-new-study-claims-that-under-pressure-imposter-syndrome-hits-men-harder-than-women/tired-and-overworked-stylish-red-bearded-manager-sitting-in-front-of-computer-and-trying-to-concentrate-his-eyes-are-dry-and-hurt/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that some of us experience “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-23/edition-5/feeling-fraud&quot;&gt;imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;” was first mooted in the 1970s by two US clinical psychologists who noticed the preponderance of high-achieving women who felt they had somehow cheated or fluked their way to success and feared being found out. Research on the syndrome has since exploded and it’s become clear that many men also experience similar fraudulent feelings. In fact, in their new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886918302435&quot;&gt;exploratory paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;, a team of US and German researchers claim that, under pressure, imposter syndrome may hit men harder than women, triggering more anxiety and worse performance – a difference they speculate may be due to traditional gender norms that place a greater expectation on men to be competent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34000&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Badawy and her colleagues recruited hundreds of female and male undergrads studying communication or business in northeastern USA. They measured their levels of imposter syndrome with an established scale that includes items like “Sometimes I’m afraid others will discover how much knowledge or ability I really lack”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one study, the researchers gave the students two sets of five verbal and numerical Graduate Record Exam questions (the GRE is used in the US to select students for graduate programmes). After the first set of questions, the researchers ramped up the pressure for half the students, giving them fake feedback that stated they had answered all of the first five questions incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although imposter feelings were overall higher among women, this harsh feedback seemed to especially affect male students with high imposter feelings – they reported higher anxiety, made less effort (as measured by time taken on the task), and showed a trend towards poorer performance, as compared to others given positive feedback. In contrast, female students with high imposter feelings responded to harsh feedback by increasing their effort and showing superior performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was similar in a second study in which heightened pressure was placed on half the students by telling them that their results on five Graduate Record Exam questions would be shown to a professor on their course (the researchers called this a “high accountability” situation). In this context, men with higher imposter syndrome scores again showed increased anxiety, reduced effort and a tendency toward worse performance, as compared with others who were told their scores would be shown anonymously to a stranger. In contrast, women with imposter feelings were largely unaffected (in terms of anxiety, effort or performance) by the increased accountability situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increase in anxiety, and reduction in effort, shown by men with imposter feelings could be interpreted as reflecting their fear of being found out, combined with a “self-handicapping” strategy – reducing their effort so that they can use this as an excuse to explain the poor performance that they are anticipating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Assuming that traditional gender norms hold, males [with imposter syndrome] may have exhibited  stronger negative reactions because they believe that society at large values males who demonstrate high competence and at the same time, do not believe that they can fulfil this standard,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the women with imposter feelings appeared less sensitive to the negative feedback and expectation of review by a professor – if anything, they arguably responded to negative feedback in an adaptive way by increasing their effort. The researchers linked this with the traditional cultural expectation that women should be warm rather than competent.  “Being less constrained by gender norm violations and backlash (i.e. they were already expected to perform poorly on competence-based tasks like exam questions), females [with imposter feelings] may have felt freer to attempt to improve their performance (and risk failure) rather than excusing it with lack of time or effort invested,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to know if and how these findings might relate to real-world situations in an  academic setting or workplace. Badawy and her team admit their findings are exploratory and may not generalise. In particular, if their explanation based around gender norms is accurate, one can imagine these norms might vary not just across international cultures, but even between different sub-cultures in the same country – depending, for instance, on the specific gender-based attitudes, beliefs and pressures in different occupations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues aside, Badawy and her colleagues suggest their key finding – of particular male vulnerability to imposter syndrome under pressure – may have practical implications for managers. “If managers of organisational specialists observe evidence of imposter syndrome in male workers currently performing at high levels, they may benefit from making attempts to restore those workers’ sense of agency if they are placed under high accountability situations,” they said. They added that mentoring by professors or managers, skills training and stretch assignments could be potential beneficial strategies (find &lt;a href=&quot;https://99u.adobe.com/articles/54774/how-to-beat-the-imposter-syndrome-feeling&quot;&gt;more ways to combat imposter syndrome in this 99U article&lt;/a&gt;). However, they warned these will only work “if mentors are trained to down regulate their own gender role expectations”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886918302435&quot;&gt;Are all impostors created equal? Exploring gender differences in the impostor phenomenon-performance link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sending a supportive text to your partner can reduce their physiological stress levels, but only if you’re subtle about it</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/sending-a-supportive-text-to-your-partner-can-reduce-their-physiological-stress-levels-but-only-if-youre-subtle-about-it/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34002</id>
		<updated>2018-06-01T08:37:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-865821668.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34003&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34003&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A Muslim woman is outdoors on a sunny day. She is wearing casual clothing and a head scarf. She is standing near a road and sending a message with her smartphone.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1505852785&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Using Technology&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Using Technology&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/sending-a-supportive-text-to-your-partner-can-reduce-their-physiological-stress-levels-but-only-if-youre-subtle-about-it/using-technology/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average young adult sends more than 100 texts per day, mainly to offer social support to friends and family. But until now, there has been little evidence whether it helps the recipient or not. New &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218300918&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/i&gt; confirms that sending a comforting text to a partner confronted with a difficult task really can make them feel supported. But more surprisingly, the study suggests that to actually reduce their stress, it’s better to send a message that isn’t explicitly supportive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34002&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Hooker and colleagues from the University of California asked 75 women to attempt a stressful set of tasks involving mental mathematics and public speaking. At the start of the experiment they were fitted with a blood pressure cuff to capture information about blood flow and heart rate. While waiting to perform, some participants received texts from their romantic partner who was waiting in the other room. Crucially, some of the partners sent texts (scripted by the researchers) that were comforting (e.g. “Don’t worry. It’s just a psych study. You’ll be fine.”) whereas others sent more mundane texts that were not explicitly supportive (e.g. “It’s cold in here.”). Participants also received a second reinforcing text with the same tone as the first (i.e. either supportive or mundane) while they prepared for their challenge (other participants acted as a baseline control group and received no texts at any point).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After delivering the task, participants who’d earlier received a comforting text reported feeling more supported by their partner (compared with the controls). However, it was only those participants who’d earlier received mundane texts who showed a physical reduction in their stress response, as shown by lower systolic blood pressure during preparation and the task itself.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is evidence that attempts to support other people that give the impression of social evaluation – “I can see that you’re struggling” – are ineffective at reducing stress, and Hooker’s team conjecture that the supportive texts, by making direct references to the stressful tasks, may have inadvertently triggered this effect, although this was not explicitly tested for in the study. If so, it adds to research suggesting that “invisible” support – like offering unrelated humour – can be one of the more effective forms of reducing stress through social support. In this case, simply the reminder that the boyfriend was next door, grumbling about the cold, affirmed that the person was not alone, and could receive comfort or validation should that be needed (e.g. if the stressful event went badly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This finding certainly needs follow-up research to figure out what are the ingredients in different forms of text-based social contact to affect how we feel. It’s worth noting that the effect of the mundane messages also involved a slower recovery to blood pressure baseline than the supportive text or the control condition. So it may be that different kinds of messages can have selective effects on different phases of the stress response. Studies have begun to show downsides of heavy texting use, such as school performance and sleep, although in many cases these may be confounded by use of mobile phones in general. It’s useful, then, to see evidence of something many of us assume and hope for – that contact with loved ones via text can provide them with a sense of being supported during stressful events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218300918&quot;&gt;It just takes a text: Partner text messages can reduce cardiovascular responses to stress in females&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Never-before-seen dunes on Pluto spotted in New Horizons images</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/never-seen-dunes-pluto-spotted-new-horizons-images"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/never-seen-dunes-pluto-spotted-new-horizons-images</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T18:01:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Images from the New Horizons spacecraft reveal dunes on Pluto — but the sand-sized grains must have had an unusual boost to get moving.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T11:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS Responds to Ebola Outbreak with New Channel &amp;amp; Expedited Peer Review</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/rfBzjXO3fqo/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8227</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T15:26:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/05/Ebola_Blogs_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early sharing and expedited peer review of relevant research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the ongoing Ebola &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/ebola/en/&quot;&gt;outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; we are creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/ebola&quot;&gt;PLOS Channel for Ebola Research&lt;/a&gt;.  The Channel will make it easy for researchers to keep up with developments and important research related to the outbreak. We will work with authors and our editorial boards to provide rapid review and facilitate the responsible dissemination of preprints. We believe these responses are urgently needed during serious and rapidly developing threats to public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All relevant articles published across PLOS will be included in the Ebola Channel, alongside major contributions curated from the broader literature. You can also send any questions or content recommendations to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ebola@plos.org&quot;&gt;ebola@plos.org&lt;/a&gt; or tweet us @PLOSChannels using the hashtag #PLOSEbola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I make my Ebola research available quickly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve created a taskforce to identify editors and reviewers, and to manage an expedited review process across all our journals and platforms.  For authors, we recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to share a single observation (no more than 1 figure or table with commentary) submit to PLOS Currents: Outbreaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submit any other research to one of the 7 PLOS journals; all Ebola-related submissions will be prioritized. (Note that&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/fee-assistance#loc-fee-assistance-programs&quot;&gt;fee waiver assistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; is available as needed)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share your data and manuscript ahead of submission: large datasets should be deposited in a relevant repository, and manuscripts submitted to a preprint server. Include the DOIs or accession numbers for datasets and preprint in your submission. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to expediting research publications, PLOS believes all data on the Ebola outbreak should be shared as rapidly and openly as possible. We endorse the Wellcome Trust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://wellcome.ac.uk/what-we-do/our-work/sharing-research-findings-and-data-relevant-ebola-outbreak-drc&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;statement&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;demanding availability of data and research on Ebola. Editorial consideration of research submissions to PLOS journals will not be prejudiced by the early sharing of data or preprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons learned: delivering rapid responses to emergency outbreaks &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS saw surges in submissions in previous outbreaks, notably the Ebola outbreak of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2014/09/05/plos-resources-ebola/&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt; and the Zika outbreak of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2016/01/07/will-zika-become-the-2016-ntd-of-the-year/&quot;&gt;2015/2016&lt;/a&gt;. In each emergency, we provided resources to serve the community. In addition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/data-sharing-make-outbreak-research-open-access-1.16966&quot;&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; about data sharing during the 2014 Ebola outbreak led PLOS and other journal editors to issue a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/medicines/ebola-treatment/blueprint_phe_data-share-results/en/&quot;&gt;joint statement&lt;/a&gt; encouraging early data sharing. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1002549&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt; showed that, while increased use of preprints in the 2016 Zika outbreak accelerated the dissemination of research results, the proportion of published articles on Zika that were preceded by preprints remained low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our shared responsibility in public health emergencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe research, healthcare, and publishing communities have a responsibility to work together to respond rapidly to public health emergencies. PLOS is committed to disseminating new research findings as efficiently and effectively as possible. We appreciate the opportunity to facilitate access to your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/rfBzjXO3fqo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Experts advise: Start colorectal screening at 45, not 50</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/experts-advise-start-colorectal-screening-45-not-50"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/experts-advise-start-colorectal-screening-45-not-50</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T14:50:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The American Cancer Society recommends that colorectal screening begin at the age of 45 for average-risk individuals.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T23:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Two-faced star reveals a pulsar’s surprising bulk</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-faced-star-reveals-pulsars-surprising-bulk"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-faced-star-reveals-pulsars-surprising-bulk</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T13:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An ultramassive pulsar is frying its stellar companion so that the star shows two different temperatures.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Dental journal pulls a dozen papers for recycled images and “unreliable data”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/31/dental-journal-pulls-a-dozen-papers-for-recycled-images-and-unreliable-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66214</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T12:15:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A leading orthodontics journal has retracted 12 papers after determining that they contained either reused images, questionable data or both. Several of the articles involved experiments conducted in dogs — and one person familiar with the case told us that the duplication was an attempt to avoid sacrificing more animals than necessary for the research. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/31/dental-journal-pulls-a-dozen-papers-for-recycled-images-and-unreliable-data/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Dental journal pulls a dozen papers for recycled images and “unreliable data”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Position: PhD studentship in Biocomputation Research Group</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/05/31/open-position-phd-studentship-in-biocomputation-research-group.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-05-31:/2018/05/31/open-position-phd-studentship-in-biocomputation-research-group.html</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T11:43:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a PhD studentship on Computational frameworks for
high-dimensional neural data with Dr. Shabnam Kadir in the Biocomputation
Research Group in the Centre for Computer Science and Informatics Research,
University of Hertfordshire, U.K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New developments in experimental technology have led to petabytes of raw data
being produced by experimental neuroscientists, which are increasingly publicly
available, e.g. Allen Institute data (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.brain-map.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.brain-map.org/&lt;/a&gt;). In particular,
we are in the realm where population recordings of tens of thousands of neurons
are feasible thanks to, e.g. a new generation of large dense probes for
electrophysiological recordings, imaging using 2-photon microscopy coupled with
calcium fluorescent sensors. Large scale neuronal recordings require novel
approaches for both processing and quantitative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as using techniques from high-dimensional statistics, machine learning,
information theory, we aim to explore new approaches from mathematical fields
outside statistics, such as algebraic topology. The study of networks is a
particularly important topic in neuroscience: neurons communicate with each
other electrically via synapses, forming intricate networks. These networks can
be studied using techniques from computational topology (e.g. persistent
homology, clique topology). These could be used to extract information about
subnetworks and assemblies, both from large scale recordings, and via
connectomics derived from simulations (Blue Brain Project).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim in this project to go beyond spike sorting and develop new tools and
computational frameworks which would help interpret high dimensional data and
interrogate how information is being processed by the brain, e.g.  How are
sensory stimuli (location in environment, visual and auditory stimuli) encoded?
How can we characterise the neural activity associated with memory, attention,
decision making and motor control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall be collaborating with labs at Imperial, Pennsylvania State University
and UCL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information can be found here:
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/187455/Dec2017-computational-frameworks-for-high-dimensional-neural-data.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/187455/Dec2017-computational-frameworks-for-high-dimensional-neural-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for candidates with the following profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong first degree in a quantitative field such as mathematics, physics,
computer science, engineering, computational neuroscience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong programming skills (e.g. Python, MATLAB, C++).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in neuroscience and biology would be helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A studentship from the PhD Programme in Computer Science provides approximately
£14,750 per annum bursary plus the payment of student fees. Applicants from
outside the UK or EU are eligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in Computer Science at the University of Hertfordshire has been
recognised as excellent in the latest Research Excellence Framework Assessment
(2014), with 50% of the research submitted rated as internationally excellent
or world-leading. The Centre for Computer Science and Informatics Research
provides a very stimulating environment, offering a large number of specialised
and interdisciplinary seminars as well as general training and researcher
development opportunities. The University is situated in Hatfield, in the green
belt just north of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact Dr Shabnam Kadir (&lt;code&gt;s.kadir2 AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;) for informal enquiries.
Application forms are available under
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&lt;/a&gt;
and should be returned to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Emma Thorogood, &lt;br /&gt;
Research Student Administrator, &lt;br /&gt;
University of Hertfordshire, College Lane, &lt;br /&gt;
Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9AB, &lt;br /&gt;
Tel: 01707 286083 &lt;br /&gt;
E-mail: &lt;code&gt;doctoralcollegeadmissions AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short-listing process will begin on 25th June 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shabnam Kadir</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-05-31T11:43:55+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Position: Professorship in Computational Neuroscience</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/05/31/professorship-in-computational-neuroscience.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-05-31:/2018/05/31/professorship-in-computational-neuroscience.html</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T11:29:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;School of Computer Science, &lt;br /&gt;
University of Hertfordshire, &lt;br /&gt;
College Lane Campus, Hatfield, UK &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary: £58,293 to £67,437 p.a. depending on skills and experience. &lt;br /&gt;
FTE: Full time position working 37 hours per week (1.0 FTE). &lt;br /&gt;
Duration of contract: Permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing date: 24 July 2018. &lt;br /&gt;
Interview date: Week commencing 17 September 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for an exceptionally well qualified Professor of
Computational Neuroscience of international standing, who shares our commitment
to research-informed teaching, embraces the research impact agenda, and values
collegiality. Applicants will strengthen existing activity within the School
and develop it further, enhancing the research strengths and external
reputation of the School of Computer Science and contributing significantly to
its performance in future research assessments and collaborations with
commercial and public partners. The successful applicant will complement the
research conducted by the Biocomputation Research Group within the Centre for
Computer Science and Informatics Research. As well as providing research
supervision at PhD and MSc level, the School of Computer Science offers modules
in neural computing and machine learning on the BSc and MSc programmes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applicants must hold a PhD (or equivalent) in a relevant subject, possess
excellent communication skills in English, an internationally excellent
research record and reputation, including publications of the highest quality
suitable for submission to the REF. Applicants must show evidence of experience
and success in research/commercial income generation, engagement with the
research impact agenda, engagement with key stakeholders in the Computational
Neuroscience community, and management and leadership ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The university offers a range of benefits including a pension scheme,
professional development, family friendly policies, child care vouchers, a fee
waiver of 50% for all children of staff under the age of 21 at the start of the
course, discounted memberships at the Hertfordshire Sports Village and generous
annual leave. The University  is situated in Hatfield, in the green belt just
north of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications must be made online at:
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&quot;&gt;https://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&lt;/a&gt;,
reference &lt;code&gt;016195&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For informal enquiries please contact Dr Volker Steuber (&lt;code&gt;v DOT steuber
AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;, Head of Biocomputation Research Group, Associate Dean
- Research) or Prof William Clocksin (&lt;code&gt;w DOT clocksin AT herts DOT ac DOT
uk&lt;/code&gt;, Dean of School of Computer Science).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Volker Steuber</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-05-31T11:43:55+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Guidelines call for limits to whole genome testing for fetuses</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/guidelines-call-limits-whole-genome-testing-fetuses"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/guidelines-call-limits-whole-genome-testing-fetuses</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Powerful tests offer unprecedented detail about fetal genomes. But whole-genome tests aren’t ready for widespread use yet, doctors caution.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Taking a photo of something impairs your memory of it, but the reasons remain largely mysterious</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/31/taking-a-photo-of-something-impairs-your-memory-of-it-but-the-reasons-remain-largely-mysterious/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33997</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T10:10:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avid photographers celebrate the viewfinder as a means of helping us see the world anew. But psychology research has shown that under some conditions taking a photo of something actually makes it harder to remember. One possible reason is that we give less attention to an experience when we know that it will be safely stored in a photograph. But in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211368117301687&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition&lt;/i&gt;, Julia Soares and Benjamin Storm from the University of California show that the photo-taker’s memory will suffer whether they expect to keep the photo or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33997&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work aimed to replicate and extend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24311477&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; by Linda Henkel that showed that taking photos of paintings in a museum could lead to poorer recall of those paintings. To make sense of this, Henkel drew on the body of research on&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/29/remembering-together-how-long-term-couples-develop-interconnected-memory-systems/&quot;&gt; transactive memory&lt;/a&gt;, which shows that longtime partners or friends distribute memory demands between them, creating a “shared” system where one will remember certain things so the other doesn’t need to. Henkel thought that in a similar fashion we may be treating the camera as a memory partner and offloading the effort onto it. Soares and Storm tested this explanation by separating photo taking from photo having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main experiment was a computerised version of Henkel’s museum task. Around 50 undergraduates viewed paintings one at a time onscreen. In one block, participants took a photo of each painting with a smartphone, and then had 15 seconds to look at the painting itself. In a second experimental block, the participants took a photo of each painting, deleted the photo immediately (so they knew it could never been accessed in the future), then had 15 seconds to look at the painting. Finally, in another experimental block, they took no photos and simply viewed each painting for 15 seconds.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a ten minute delay (during which phones were confiscated) came a multiple- choice memory test probing what the participants remembered about the various paintings. Compared to paintings that were simply viewed, performance was poorer for paintings that were photographed. Critically, this was true both for the condition where the photo was stored, and for the condition where it was deleted, meaning the participant knew they could not rely on it as a future memory partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests that offloading may not be the cause of the memory disadvantage associated with taking photos. One alternative explanation is that using a camera forces us to disengage from properly taking in the stimulus, as our attention flows to the mechanics of operating buttons, checking brightness, exposure etc. This is something commonly reported by people as part of their photo-taking experience, and also tallies with the fact that automatic wearable cameras that store images for later don’t produce the memory impairment. However, in the current experiment, after taking pictures (or not), every participant had the same amount of time to take in the paintings without use of equipment, so any distraction effect would need to include some sort of delayed effect on memory processing even after the act of taking a photo was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soares and Storm have a speculative second interpretation. They suggest that the effort involved in taking a photo – getting the framing right, ensuring the lens is in focus – leads to the sense that you’ve done a good job of encoding the object itself, even though you have been focusing more on peripheral features. So you’re not mentally slacking-off because you think the camera has it covered – but because you think you already have. It may be relevant that people who take photographs at events &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/07/25/taking-photos-will-boost-your-enjoyment-of-experiences-researchers-say/&quot;&gt;report afterwards&lt;/a&gt; feeling more immersed in the experience, which would tally more with this explanation than the disengagement-due-to-fiddling idea. In any case this is further evidence that those of us who approach exciting life events through the lenses of our electronic devices may be distancing ourselves from fuller participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211368117301687&quot;&gt;Forget in a Flash: A Further Investigation of the Photo-Taking-Impairment Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Decoding gas source proximity from turbulent plumes</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/05/31/decoding-gas-source-proximity-from-turbulent-plumes.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-05-31:/2018/05/31/decoding-gas-source-proximity-from-turbulent-plumes.html</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T09:15:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Estimating the distance of a gas source is important in many applications of chemical sensing, like e.g. environmental monitoring, or chemically-guided robot navigation. If an estimation of the gas concentration at the source is available, source proximity can be estimated from the time-averaged gas concentration at the sensing site. However, in turbulent environments, where fast concentration fluctuations dominate, comparably long measurements are required to obtain a reliable estimate. A lesser known feature that correlates with source proximity in a turbulent environment is the temporal variance of local gas concentration: Gas encounters become more intermittent farther from the source. However, is has commonly been assumed that exploiting this feature requires gas concentration measurements at the millisecond scale, usually requiring expensive photo-ionisation detectors. We have recently shown that, with appropriate signal processing, off-the-shelf metal-oxide sensors are capable of extracting rapidly fluctuating features of gas plumes that strongly correlate with source distance [1]. We present a straightforward analysis method to decode events of large, consistent changes in the measured signal, which we denote ‘bouts’. The frequency of these bouts predicted the distance of a gas source in wind-tunnel experiments with good accuracy. In addition, we found that the variance of bout counts indicates cross-wind offset to the centre- line of the gas plume. Our results offer an alternative approach to estimating gas source proximity that is largely independent of gas concentration, using off-the-shelf metal-oxide sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Michael Schmuker, Viktor Bahr, and Ramón Huerta, “Exploiting Plume Structure to Decode Gas Source Distance Using Metal-Oxide Gas Sensors,” Sensors and Actuators B: Chemical 235 (November 2016): 636–46. Open access version available at  &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.01815&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.01815&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 01/06/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Schmuker</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-05-31T11:43:55+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">CiteScore metrics updated with 2017 annual values</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-metrics-updated-with-2017-annual-values"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-metrics-updated-with-2017-annual-values</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T08:49:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Citation impact metrics are available for all peer-reviewed research journals, book series, conference proceedings and trade publications covered in Scopus</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">People who think their opinions are superior to others are most prone to overestimating their relevant knowledge and ignoring chances to learn more</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/31/people-who-think-their-opinions-are-superior-to-others-are-most-prone-to-overestimating-their-relevant-knowledge-and-ignoring-chances-to-learn-more/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33991</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T08:38:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-165763476.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33992&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33992&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector illustration - Head in the Sand.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;alashi&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Head in the Sand&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Head in the Sand&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-165763476.jpg?w=845?w=767&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-165763476.jpg?w=845?w=225&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-165763476.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1499,2000&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/31/people-who-think-their-opinions-are-superior-to-others-are-most-prone-to-overestimating-their-relevant-knowledge-and-ignoring-chances-to-learn-more/head-in-the-sand-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-165763476.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://tomstafford.staff.shef.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Tom Stafford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know someone who is convinced their opinion is better than everyone else’s on a topic – perhaps, even, that it is the only correct opinion to have. Maybe, on some topics, &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; are that person. No psychologist would be surprised that people who are convinced their beliefs are superior think they are better informed than others, but this fact leads to a follow on question: are people &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; better informed on the topics for which they are convinced their opinion is superior? This is what Michael Hall and Kaitlin Raimi set out to check in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002210311730714X&quot;&gt;a series of experiments&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33991&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers distinguish “belief superiority” from “belief confidence” (thinking your opinion is correct). Belief superiority is relative – it is when you think your opinion is more correct than other people’s; the top end of their belief superiority scale is to indicate that your belief is “Totally correct (mine is the only correct view)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pair set out to find people who felt their beliefs on a variety of controversial political issues (things like terrorism and civil liberties, or wealth redistribution) were superior, and to check – using multiple choice quizzes – how well they were informed on the topics about which they held these superiority beliefs.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across five studies Hall and Raimi found that those people with the highest belief superiority also tended to have the largest gap between their perceived and actual knowledge – the belief superior consistently suffered from the illusion that they were better informed than they were. As you might expect, those with the lowest belief superiority tended to underestimate how much they knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as simple background knowledge, the researchers were also interested in how people with belief superiority sought out new information relevant to that belief. They gave participants a selection of news headlines and asked them to select which articles they’d like to read in full at the end of the experiment. Categorising headlines as belief-congruent or belief incongruent, the researchers observed that those participants with higher belief-superiority were more likely to select belief congruent headlines. In other words, despite being badly informed compared to their self-perception, these participants chose to neglect sources of information that would enhance their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally and more promisingly, the researchers found some evidence that belief superiority can be dented by feedback. If participants were told that people with beliefs like theirs tended to score poorly on topic knowledge, or if they were directly told that their score on the topic knowledge quiz was low, this not only reduced their belief superiority, it also caused them to seek out the kind of challenging information they had previously neglected in the headlines task (though the evidence for this behavioural effect was mixed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studies all involved participants accessed via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk, allowing the researchers to work with large samples of Americans for each experiment. Their findings mirror the well-known &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&quot;&gt;Dunning-Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt; – Kruger and Dunning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10626367%20&quot;&gt;showed that&lt;/a&gt; for domains such as judgements of grammar, humour or logic, the most skilled tend to underestimate their ability, while the least skilled overestimate it. Hall and Raimi’s research extends this to the realm of political opinions (where objective assessment of correctness is not available), showing that the belief your opinion is better than other people’s tends to be associated with overestimation of your relevant knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the research presents a mixed picture. It shows, as others have, that our opinions are often not as justified as we believe – even for the opinions that we are most confident are better than other people’s. On the other hand, it shows that people are responsive to feedback, and aren’t solely driven by confirmation bias when they seek out new information. The final picture is of human rationality that is flawed, but correctable, not doomed.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002210311730714X&quot;&gt;Is belief superiority justified by superior knowledge?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;tom stafford head shot&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-33994 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33994&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;tom stafford head shot&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/tom-stafford-head-shot.jpg?w=400&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/tom-stafford-head-shot.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/tom-stafford-head-shot.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;400,400&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/31/people-who-think-their-opinions-are-superior-to-others-are-most-prone-to-overestimating-their-relevant-knowledge-and-ignoring-chances-to-learn-more/tom-stafford-head-shot/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/tom-stafford-head-shot.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tomstafford.staff.shef.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Tom Stafford&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tomstafford&quot;&gt;@tomstafford)&lt;/a&gt; for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Tom is a psychologist from the University of Sheffield who is a regular contributor to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mindhacks.com/&quot;&gt;Mind Hacks&lt;/a&gt; blog. His latest book is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B010O1Z018&quot;&gt;For argument’s sake: evidence that reason can change minds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">UCL trachea transplant inquiry: scapegoating, obfuscation and a lost nose</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/05/31/ucl-trachea-transplant-inquiry-scapegoating-obfuscation-and-a-lost-nose/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24120</id>
		<updated>2018-05-31T06:00:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In 2017, the great London university UCL invited an external expert commission to investigate its role into the deadly trachea transplants performed by the former UCL honorary professor and scandal surgeon Paolo Macchiarini. An already sacked UCL nanotechnology professor, Alexander Seifalian, whose lab made the two UCL plastic POSS-PCU tracheas in 2011, was announced as … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/05/31/ucl-trachea-transplant-inquiry-scapegoating-obfuscation-and-a-lost-nose/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;UCL trachea transplant inquiry: scapegoating, obfuscation and a lost nose&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Treating roads with oil and gas wastewater may spread harmful pollution</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/treating-roads-oil-and-gas-wastewater-may-spread-harmful-pollution"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/treating-roads-oil-and-gas-wastewater-may-spread-harmful-pollution</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T21:49:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 When spread on roads, wastewater from oil and gas production can leach radium and other contaminants into the environment, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The first land-walking vertebrates may have emerged from salty estuaries</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-tetrapods-may-have-emerged-salty-estuaries"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-tetrapods-may-have-emerged-salty-estuaries</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T21:29:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Early tetrapods were transitional creatures — not only between land and water, but also between fresh and salty environments.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T11:00:46+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Oldest known lizard fossil pushes group’s origins back 75 million years</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-known-lizard-fossil-pushes-origins-back-75-million-years"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-known-lizard-fossil-pushes-origins-back-75-million-years</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T20:24:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 CT scan reveals hidden identity of an unusual lizard fossil found years ago in the Italian Alps.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-06T05:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The first Americans could have taken a coastal route into the New World</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-americans-could-have-taken-coastal-route-new-world"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-americans-could-have-taken-coastal-route-new-world</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Alaskan glaciers retreated in time for ancient coastal entries of the first Americans.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How Self-Compassion Can Fight Perfectionism</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2018/05/30/how-self-compassion-can-fight-perfectionism/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23700</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T15:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;“Be kind to one another.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to be a die-hard Ellen DeGeneres fan to appreciate the value of that motto. And while we’re reminded how kindness goes a long way in our everyday interactions with others, we often forget to apply it to those who need it most: ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s setting a personal weight-loss goal, or believing that we can ace a final exam—all of us are familiar with the experience of setting high standards. We’re even more familiar with the inevitable let-down that comes from not living up to those very standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter, the life of a perfectionist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, importantly, not all perfectionists operate the same. There are different types that are associated with different psychological outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, if you strive to attain your ambitious goals and prevent yourself from being overly self-critical, you might be a  personal strivings perfectionist. This isn’t so bad. In fact, this type of perfectionism is more likely to lead to relatively higher levels of self-esteem and decreased levels of negative affect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you constantly believe that you are not good enough, if you judge yourself by your shortcomings, and if you are constantly &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/27/social-media-anxiety-disorders-whats-going-on-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;worried that other people won’t approve of you&lt;/a&gt;, then you might be more on the side of maladaptive perfectionism. This form of perfectionism has been linked to depressive symptoms in both adolescents and adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no wonder then that researchers are curious to know more about interventions that help buffer against this maladaptive perfectionism. In one  recent study, researchers examined the possibility that self-compassion can protect us against the negative effects of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/19/when-perfectionism-leads-to-an-imperfect-appearance/&quot;&gt;maladaptive perfectionism&lt;/a&gt;. The questions is, can self-directed kindness increase our chances of living a full, healthy life? Can it combat the symptoms of depression that come from this less ideal version of perfectionism?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding self-compassion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask, “What exactly is self-compassion? And is it something that can be cultivated by anyone, or is a skill that is only available to some of us?” To shed some light on these questions, researchers have broken down self-compassion into three main components: self-kindness, common humanity, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/21/mindfulness-may-be-the-secret-to-staying-healthy/&quot;&gt;mindfulness&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the first component is self-explanatory, the other two require careful consideration. When something terrible happens to us, often the initial reaction is to sit and wallow in our grief and self-pity. We convince ourselves that no one else is going through similar problems in their lives. But that is simply not true. Statistically speaking, it’s an erroneous judgment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to be more accepting of ourselves, we need to realize that we are never as alone and isolated as we think we are. This is at the heart of common humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, many of us are prone to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/03/26/different-coping-styles-may-cause-prevent-or-treat-ocd/&quot;&gt;over-analyzing painful experiences&lt;/a&gt;, or trying to avoid negative feelings altogether. Mindfulness then, is about acknowledging our thoughts, feelings, and emotions without judgement, and accepting them as part of the common human experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to our study. Taking into account these three sub-components, the researchers in the present investigation set out to predict that self-compassion would weaken the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/06/24/9-personality-traits-putting-mothers-at-risk-of-postpartum-depression/&quot;&gt;relationship between perfectionism and depression &lt;/a&gt;in both adolescent and adult populations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;541 adolescents from grades 7 to 10 were recruited for the first study. Participants were asked to complete three online questionnaires during school hours, as part of a larger well-being intervention study. The questionnaires tapped into perfectionism, mood/feelings, self-worth and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/01/25/boost-confidence-with-brain-training/&quot;&gt;self-esteem&lt;/a&gt;, as well as reported self-compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As predicted, self-compassion was found to moderate, or weaken, the relationship between maladaptive perfectionism and depression in this sample of adolescents. Next, the researchers wanted to see if the results would hold for adults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;515 adults from the general population were recruited through online advertisements. Again, participants were asked to complete the same questionnaires. Once again in line with the researchers’ predictions, self-compassion was found to weaken the relationship between perfectionism and depression in the adult sample. What was true for teens was also true for adults later on in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why it matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that more than anything, today’s culture values perfection. Parents and teachers may push us towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/13/how-does-starting-school-early-impact-educational-attainment/&quot;&gt;excellence at school&lt;/a&gt;, our friends may judge us by how we dress and act in their company, and perhaps worst of all, our social media accounts constantly fool us into thinking that there are people out there who actually have perfect lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good news, bad news. The bad news is that we can’t completely eradicate perfectionistic thoughts. Good news is that we can try to change our relationship to those thoughts through self-compassion. If we learn to cultivate self-kindness, connection, and mindfulness as we strive toward achieving our goals, any setback we face along the way will be met with greater resilience and mental strength. As a result, we are less likely to fall victim to the debilitating effects of depression, and more likely to live a happy, balanced life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as Ellen DeGeneres reminds us, always be kind to others. But before you do, be sure to look after yourself first. In this case, it’s okay to be a little selfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrari, M., Yap, K., Scott, N., Einstein, D., &amp;amp; Ciarrochi, J. (2018). Self-compassion moderates the perfectionism and depression link in both adolescence and adulthood. PLOS ONE, 13(2), e0192022. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192022&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0192022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hill, R., Huelsman, T., &amp;amp; Araujo, G. (2010). Perfectionistic concerns suppress associations between perfectionistic strivings and positive life outcomes. Personality And Individual Differences, 48(5), 584-589. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2009.12.011&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.paid.2009.12.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEFF, K. (2003). The Development and Validation of a Scale to Measure Self-Compassion. Self And Identity, 2(3), 223-250. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15298860309027&quot;&gt;10.1080/15298860309027&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stoeber, J., &amp;amp; Otto, K. (2006). Positive Conceptions of Perfectionism: Approaches, Evidence, Challenges. Personality And Social Psychology Review, 10(4), 295-319. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1207/s15327957pspr1004_2&quot;&gt;10.1207/s15327957pspr1004_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/nandhukumar-1208326/&quot;&gt;nandhukumar&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nicholas Hobson, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Newsletter #52</title>
		<link href="http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter-52"/>
		<id>http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/433 at http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T14:39:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;section field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item odd&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;font-size: 40px; margin: 2px; color: #00f02e; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; letter-spacing: 2px;&quot;&gt; Neuro&lt;span style=&quot;color: #01edc0;&quot;&gt;Mat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 16px; margin: 6px; color: #FFFFFF;&quot;&gt;Research, Innovation and Dissemination Center for Neuromathematics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 20px; font-weight: bold; color: #FFFFFF; padding-bottom: 7px;&quot;&gt;Newsletter - Nº 52 | May 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 10px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat, the largest institutional contributor on Mathematics on Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;The Research, Innovation and Dissemination Center for Neuromathematics (RIDC NeuroMat), funded by FAPESP, has chosen web, collaborative platforms as its main line of action in terms of science dissemination. This decision was made in 2014 and now the RIDC has become a relevant institutional contributor to Wikimedia projects and the largest institutional contributor on Mathematics on Wikipedia, according to reports from the Outreach Dashboard, that monitors institutional programs and activities on Wikimedia projects.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                        &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/neuromat-largest-institutional-contributor-mathematics-wikipedia&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 13px; background-color: #00f02e; color: #000000; padding: 5px; border-radius: 20px; margin: 2px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; → Read more here &lt;/a&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 5px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Helvetica; font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Last NeuroMat scientific publications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                                &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/physiology-and-assessment-low-hanging-fruit-education-overhaul&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ribeiro, S., Mota, N. B., da Rocha Fernandes, V., Deslandes, A. C., Brockington, G., &amp;amp; Copelli, M. (2016). Physiology and assessment as low-hanging fruit for education overhaul. Prospects, 46(2), 249-264.&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
                                &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/discrepancy-and-eigenvalues-cayley-graphs&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kohayakawa, Y., Rödl, V., &amp;amp; Schacht, M. (2016). Discrepancy and eigenvalues of Cayley graphs. Czechoslovak Mathematical Journal, 66(3), 941-954.&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding-top: 5px; padding-right: 5px; padding-left: 5px; padding-bottom: 10px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 5px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat opportunities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/openings-software-developers&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Opening for software developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/bjc-2&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Opening for science communicator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding-top: 5px; padding-right: 5px; padding-left: 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat Facebook Highlights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;padding: 0.75em 1em; width: 200px; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/neuromathematics/photos/pcb.1736965739697566/1736965403030933/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-gru2-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/32662589_1736965406364266_7102620918140108800_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=622bcd7516dede7b4d84af236e3bae3e&amp;amp;oe=5B7AAAB0&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 140px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat team members have visited USP's Parque CienTec to further the possibility of a partnership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;padding: 0.75em 1em; width: 200px; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/neuromathematics/photos/pcb.1736212683106205/1736207466440060/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-gru2-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/32555425_1736207473106726_8245782302840324096_o.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=55a672cb54468a3f8251a1c1a572e66d&amp;amp;oe=5BC46938&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 140px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;USP's dean of research, Sylvio Roberto Accioly Canuto, visited RIDC NeuroMat in early May to discuss possibilities of support to the RIDC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&quot;padding: 0.75em 1em; width: 200px; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/neuromathematics/photos/a.738376036223213.1073741828.689929331067884/1742977155763091/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://scontent-gru2-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/33183989_1742977159096424_3813693451451498496_o.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=ffb0ab8cd30034cb8f3cbaf949271a02&amp;amp;oe=5BB9A199&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 140px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;The NeuroMat science dissemination team presented at Conhecer, an event of science communication at USP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 10px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Follow our initiatives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; padding: 0.75em 1em; width: 300px; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
                     &lt;a href=&quot;https://amparo.numec.prp.usp.br/&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/sites/default/files/logo_amparo.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat Parkinson Network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; padding: 0.75em 1em; width: 300px; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a href=&quot;http://abraco.numec.prp.usp.br&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/sites/default/files/logoabraco.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat Brachial Plexus Injury Initiative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; src=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/sites/default/files/trace_of_science.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 5px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat Blog Highlights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://difusaoneuromat.wordpress.com/2018/05/28/criterios-de-autoria-preservam-a-integridade-na-comunicacao-cientifica/&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Critérios de autoria preservam a integridade na comunicação científica&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://difusaoneuromat.wordpress.com/2018/05/16/neuromat-disponibiliza-as-pinturas-em-dominio-publico-do-museu-do-ipiranga/&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NeuroMat disponibiliza as pinturas em domínio público do Museu do Ipiranga&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://difusaoneuromat.wordpress.com/2018/05/07/editatona-mulher-arte-e-midia-estudantes-ajudam-a-diminuir-a-desigualdade-de-genero-na-wikipedia/&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 15px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Editatona Mulher, Arte e Mídia: estudantes ajudam a diminuir a desigualdade de gênero na Wikipédia&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 10px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold; padding-left: 5px; border-left: 7px solid #01edc0;&quot;&gt;On NeuroMat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;
                        NeuroMat is a research center established in 2013 at the University of São Paulo that is dedicated to integrating mathematical modeling and theoretical neuroscience. Among the core missions of NeuroMat are the creation of a new mathematical system to understanding neural data and the development of neuroscientific open-source computational tools. The research center is headed by Prof. Antonio Galves, from USP's Institute of Mathematics and Statistics, and is funded by the São Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP).&lt;br /&gt;
                        To receive monthly updates on NeuroMat's work or pertaining news, please subscribe to NeuroMat's newsletter: &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter/subscriptions&quot; style=&quot;color: #009271;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter/subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;For more information or press inquiries on NeuroMat, please contact us at: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:comunicacao@numec.prp.usp.br&quot; style=&quot;color: #009271;&quot;&gt;comunicacao@numec.prp.usp.br&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;NeuroMat's website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #009271;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;Like us on Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/neuromathematics/&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #009271;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/neuromathematics.&lt;/a&gt; On this FB page we post updates on Neuromathematics, related news, forthcoming events and other pertaining information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#ffffff&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;ajustar100pc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 16px; color: #222527; line-height: 20px; padding: 10px 5px 10px 5px; text-decoration: none; font-weight: normal;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: bold;&quot;&gt;Previous issues of the NeuroMat Newsletter (features)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter-51&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #00c12e;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Newsletter #51 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                                &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/ten-research-directions-neuromat-team-coming-years&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 14px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ten research directions for the NeuroMat team in the coming years&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter-50&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #00c12e;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Newsletter #50 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                                &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/ernst-w-hamburgers-optimism-neuromat-video&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 14px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ernst W. Hamburger's optimism: a NeuroMat videon&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/pt-br/newsletter-49&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #00c12e;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Newsletter #49 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
                                &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/content/arms-nildo-and-rony-neuromat-story&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 14px; color: #546357;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &quot;The Arms of Nildo and Rony:&quot; a NeuroMat story&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-simplenews-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;li class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter/neuromat&quot;&gt;NeuroMat Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>ribas</name>
			<uri>http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter/neuromat</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">NeuroMat - NeuroMat Newsletter</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/taxonomy/term/1/feed"/>
			<id>http://neuromat.numec.prp.usp.br/newsletter/neuromat</id>
			<updated>2018-05-30T17:01:41+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Live from Harvard: Join us at the #FASPDA Postdoctoral Symposium</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/live-from-harvard-join-us-at-the-faspda-postdoctoral-symposium"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/live-from-harvard-join-us-at-the-faspda-postdoctoral-symposium</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T14:06:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Check out the poster session; meet Elsevier data scientists and our colleagues in the Harvard Data Science Initiative</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-08T17:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Want to earn $10k per month? Join the “journals mafia”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/30/want-to-earn-10k-per-month-join-the-journals-mafia/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66183</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T12:15:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Is running a journal becoming too much of a drag? Just get help from a new organization that is trying to make an offer that journals can’t refuse. On a website splashed with pictures that connote classic mob movies (Marlon Brando as The Godfather, Al Pacino, cigars), a new service called “Journals Mafia” tries to … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/30/want-to-earn-10k-per-month-join-the-journals-mafia/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Want to earn $10k per month? Join the “journals mafia”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Finally, a plan on how to include pregnant women in clinical trials</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/finally-plan-how-include-pregnant-women-clinical-trials"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/finally-plan-how-include-pregnant-women-clinical-trials</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The FDA is providing initial guidance on how to include pregnant women in clinical trials that study drugs, research that has largely excluded this group in the past.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">People with a keener sense of smell find sex more pleasant and, if they are female, have more orgasms during sex</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/30/people-with-a-keener-sense-of-smell-find-sex-more-pleasant-and-if-they-are-female-have-more-orgasms-during-sex/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33985</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T10:44:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scent plays an often &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00778/full&quot;&gt;under-appreciated&lt;/a&gt; role in sexual attraction, helping to account for why visual attractiveness alone can’t explain just how physically attractive a person is perceived to be. But what role does our ability to smell our partners – or potential partners – play in actual experience?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from past research that men born without the ability to smell tend to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/04/04/investigating-the-love-lives-of-the-men-and-women-who-have-no-sense-of-smell/&quot;&gt;have fewer sexual partners&lt;/a&gt;. And about half of people who lose their sense of smell, through infection or injury, report negative impacts on their sexual behaviour. However, this could be an indirect effect – an inability to smell is often also associated with depression or social insecurity, which can affect aspects of sexuality – and such studies do not tell us whether sense of smell is related to sexual experience among healthy people. Now, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10508-018-1203-x&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Archives of Sexual Behavior&lt;/i&gt;, Johanna Bendas at the Technical University of Dresden, Germany, and her fellow researchers report evidence from healthy, young adults showing precisely that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33985&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers studied 42 women and 28 men aged between 18 and 36. They found that there was no relationship between their odour sensitivity (measured using a test that establishes how much of a smelly chemical must be present for the individual to be able to detect it) and either sexual desire or sexual performance (defined as how many times they’d engaged in sexual activity during the previous month and how long, on average, a sexual encounter had lasted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, people with a keener sense of smell reported finding their sexual activities more “pleasant”, and women with a greater sensitivity to odours had more orgasms during sex.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our data suggest a positive influence of olfactory sensitivity on the sex life of young and healthy participants,” the researchers write. “The perception of body odors such as vaginal fluids, sperm and sweat seems to enrich the sexual experience” by increasing sexual arousal, they add.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some limitations to the study, including the correlational design which means other unknown factors might be playing a causal role. Also, while the researchers did control for the use of hormonal contraception in the women, they didn’t consider the stage of menstrual cycle of the female volunteers at the time of the study – something that is known to influence olfaction. Future research in this area should take this into account, and could further explore the influence of specific odours. “The direct measurement of sexual arousal or experience will give further insight into the assumption that olfactory sensitivity improves sexual experience,” the researchers write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10508-018-1203-x&quot;&gt;Olfactory Function Relates to Sexual Experience in Adults&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Physically active academic school lessons boost pupils’ activity levels and focus</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/30/win-win-physically-active-academic-school-lessons-boost-pupils-activity-levels-and-focus/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33977</id>
		<updated>2018-05-30T08:21:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-598216698.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33980&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33980&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6.3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Shot of a group of happy children standing in a classroom&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1472731937&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;KatarzynaBialasiewicz&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Saying 'good morning' to the teacher&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Saying ‘good morning’ to the teacher&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-598216698.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-598216698.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-598216698.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/30/win-win-physically-active-academic-school-lessons-boost-pupils-activity-levels-and-focus/saying-good-morning-to-the-teacher/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/gettyimages-598216698.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, children in many countries are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27848745&quot;&gt;increasingly sedentary&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/news/2017/10October/Pages/Childhood-obesity-soars-worldwide.aspx&quot;&gt;childhood obesity is a growing concern&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time, research tells us that physical activity is good for children’s minds and bodies, and that if they develop active habits in their youth, they tend to keep them up into adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would surely help if children were more active at school, but with growing academic pressures, teachers will tell you that it is difficult to justify sacrificing vital maths and English lessons for more PE classes or games. A possible solution: make academic lessons more physically active. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1090198118762106&quot;&gt;new trial&lt;/a&gt; of a 6-week intervention comprising 18 ten-minute active maths and English lessons, published in &lt;em&gt;Health Education and Behavior&lt;/em&gt;, suggests that such an approach has great potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33977&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emma Norris at UCL and her colleagues recruited hundreds of pupils aged 8-9 from 10 London schools. Half were allocated randomly to the active lesson intervention. While they were doing those special classes, the other half of the children acted as a comparison and completed typically taught 10-minute maths and English classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children enrolled in the intervention followed the “virtual traveller” protocol, which involved them performing physical exercises, such as running on the spot, while they travelled the world answering math or English quiz questions pertaining to different countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual travel from country to country was depicted via Google Earth videos and other materials embedded in the teacher’s interactive white board presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further physical activity came from the exercises the children performed to signal whether a given math or English quiz answer was true or false – such as jumping jacks for “true” or performing a football kick for “false”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Norris and her team had the children wear motion trackers during the classes and also outside of class for two school days per week and two weekend days (these measures were taken at baseline, during the six-week period, and for a few months beyond). Trained observers also monitored the children’s on-task behaviour in class, and the kids completed questionnaires about their engagement levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, the trial was a win-win: the children in the active intervention were more active (based on more light and moderately vigorous activity) during their “virtual traveller” lessons as compared with the control group kids, and what’s more, they also displayed more on-task behavior, in terms of staying more focused on the lesson, following instructions and making more eye contact with their teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very promising but perhaps not quite as good as might have been hoped. The children in the active intervention were mostly no more active than the control kids when averaged across entire school days, nor at the weekends, and this was this case both during and beyond the end of the study. That is, they were more active in the specially designed active lessons (it would have been odd if they weren’t), but mostly this didn’t boost their activity levels enough to make any difference when averaging across the whole day (and didn’t spill over into their habits at the weekend).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lack of a broader benefit could be because the activities in the “virtual traveller” class were not intense enough; the classes were too short and/or infrequent; or perhaps the children compensated for all their in-class exertion by relaxing more later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another disappointment is that the physically active lessons did not boost the pupils’ self-reported engagement levels. On the other hand, and interpreting this result more positively, the extra physical activity did not harm their engagement either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to follow this line of research and see whether longer and/more intense physically active lesson programmes could have bigger benefits for pupils’ lifestyles and whether active lessons might also have an impact on children’s educational performance in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1090198118762106&quot;&gt;Physically Active Lessons Improve Lesson Activity and On-Task Behavior:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1090198118762106&quot;&gt; A Cluster-Randomized Controlled Trial of the “Virtual Traveller” Intervention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-09T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hurricane Maria killed at least 4,645 people in Puerto Rico, a study estimates</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hurricane-maria-killed-least-4645-people-puerto-rico-study-estimates"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hurricane-maria-killed-least-4645-people-puerto-rico-study-estimates</id>
		<updated>2018-05-29T21:04:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers estimate Puerto Rico’s death toll from Hurricane Maria at more than 4,500 people based on household surveys — dwarfing the official count of 64.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-05T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Quick Biology Q&amp;amp;A – Provider Spotlight</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/05/quick-biology-tech-qa/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1343</id>
		<updated>2018-05-29T18:02:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1242&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/header.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1242&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/header.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/quick-biology-QA.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;quick-biology-QA&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1344 size-full&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/quick-biology-QA.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gursatya/&quot;&gt;Guru Singh&lt;/a&gt;, Director of Scientific Content of Science Exchange, recently spoke with a member of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/quick-biology-inc&quot;&gt;Quick Biology&lt;/a&gt;. Follow the interview below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Give us a quick overview of your company. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Quick Biology Inc. is a genomics startup in Pasadena, CA. We focus on developing new technologies provided to researchers, scientists, and physicians so that they may gain insightful and expedited results from their work. We offer a Next-Generation Sequencing (NGS) service as well as related reagents to investigate the functions of identified variants. We also help physicians to unlock the potential of NGS in disease diagnosis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What accomplishments make Quick Biology Inc. stand out amongst its competitors? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We are one of the first sequencing providers to offer an optimized ATAC-seq service for many cell types, and it provides genome-wide profiles of open and accessible regions of chromatin that are indicative of active regulatory regions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do you define the ATAC-seq technique?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;ATAC-seq is a sensitive technique used to rapidly assess genome-wide chromatin accessibility with fewer than 100,000 cells. When it is combined with NGS technology, we can obtain accurate results on chromatin accessibility at single-nucleotide resolution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does ATAC-seq stack up compared to traditional methods?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;There are three major advantages of ATAC-seq over existing methods. After library preparation, the DNA is sequenced with NGS technology. As a result, we can obtain accurate results on chromatin accessibility at single-nucleotide resolution. ATAC-seq requires no sonication or phenol-chloroform extraction like FAIRE-seq, no antibodies like ChIP-seq and no sensitive enzymatic digestion like MNase-seq or DNase-seq. Unlike similar methods, which can take up to four days to complete, ATAC-seq preparation can be completed in under three hours so we can provide a quicker turnaround time for our clients. Another clear advantage is the low biological sample requirements. To illustrate, only 50,000 cells are sufficient for ATAC-seq, as opposed to other methods like ChIP-seq, MNase-seq, or DNase-seq that require at least 1,000-fold more material.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tell us about your client base and where are they based.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Since our NGS service launched back in January 2016, we have served many clients from universities, hospitals and pharmaceutical companies with NGS projects (RNA-seq, ATAC-seq, ChIP-seq, WGS, and WES, etc.) from all over the world. Some of our major clients include Boston Biomedical, Cedars-Sinai Medical Center, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, NIH, VA medical center, Harvard University, Stanford University, USC, and UCLA, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Can you tell our readers what makes your company competitive in this crowded genomics space?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;We are equipped in-house with the latest technologies including Illumina NovaSeq 6000, HiSeq X Ten, HiSeq 4000, NextSeq500, MiSeq and Ion Proton instrumentation. Other factors that gives us an edge are our fast turnaround time and our competitive prices. We offer advanced bioinformatics analysis, including analysis for RNA splicing/RNA editing, and high-quality pictures to our clients for publication purposes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;You’ve made it apparent that Quick Biology Inc. has positioned itself as a leader in the genome sequencing field. What role has Science Exchange played in all of this? Has it made a positive impact on your company? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Since the launch of our NGS service on Science Exchange, we’ve had great experiences working with them. Science Exchange is an integral part of our sales and marketing strategies; it gives us exposure to a global scientific community, allows us to build an online reputation, and enables us to attract potential clients quickly. All of these benefits help Quick Biology Inc. to generate more revenue without exhausting our resources. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;Science Exchange’s Sourcing Team is the secret ingredient to their successful business model. They are accommodating in mediating conversations or resolving problems with the client promptly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-07T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
