<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:42+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New genetic sleuthing tools helped track down the Golden State Killer suspect</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/golden-state-killer-suspect-dna-genetics-genealogy"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/golden-state-killer-suspect-dna-genetics-genealogy</id>
		<updated>2018-04-29T13:49:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 DNA sleuths may have adapted new techniques for identifying John and Jane Does to track down a serial killer suspect.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Why I Became a Neuroscientist</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9495"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9495</id>
		<updated>2018-04-29T13:23:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 I’ve been thinking lately about the question of what leads scientists to choose a discipline. Why does someone end up as a chemist rather than a biologist? A geneticist as opposed to a cognitive neuroscientist?

We might hope that people choose their discipline based on an understanding of what doing research in each discipline involves, but I don't think this often happens. I know it didn't happen in my case. Here, then, is how I became a neuroscientist.



As far back as I can remember,</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘The Curious Life of Krill’ is an ode to an underappreciated crustacean</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curious-life-krill-ode-underappreciated-crustacean"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curious-life-krill-ode-underappreciated-crustacean</id>
		<updated>2018-04-29T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new book makes the case that Antarctic krill and the dangers they face deserve your attention.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Jailed for speaking the truth; sexual harassment allegations at the Salk; children at risk in trials</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/28/weekend-reads-jailed-for-speaking-the-truth-sexual-harassment-allegations-at-the-salk-children-at-risk-in-trials/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64810</id>
		<updated>2018-04-28T13:10:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a debate over a flawed climate change paper, seven new … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/28/weekend-reads-jailed-for-speaking-the-truth-sexual-harassment-allegations-at-the-salk-children-at-risk-in-trials/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Jailed for speaking the truth; sexual harassment allegations at the Salk; children at risk in trials&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Supporting grieving students at school following crisis events</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/542172078/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=137816</id>
		<updated>2018-04-28T10:30:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Tragic events such as recent natural disasters and shootings at school affect many children and families. Although these events typically receive immediate media coverage and short-term supports, the long-term implications are often overlooked. The grief among children and adolescents experiencing significant loss generally emerges during the weeks and months following such tragic events. Although there are variations in the expression of grief, bereaved children and adolescents often struggle to meet the cognitive demands of school. Professionals at school, including, school psychologists, school counselors, and other mental health professionals have a tremendous opportunity to help identify and support students in need. Such support at school is helpful in facilitating healthy adjustment and coping strategies among bereaved students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Understanding grief and mourning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;em&gt;grief&lt;/em&gt; refers to an individual’s personal experience, thoughts, and feelings associated with a loss. The term &lt;em&gt;mourning&lt;/em&gt; refers to the externalized manifestation of grief. Mourning rituals, such as funerals, memorial services, and commemorative activities can facilitate grief. Culture influences the grieving process, and it is important to consider the vast range of ways that individuals and families mourn the death of others. For example, being sensitive to family preferences surrounding funerals or memorials helps ensure that you’re honoring their beliefs and values. It is also critical to note that some individuals may not feel comfortable expressing their grief at school, and instead prefer to do it privately with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grief is often emotional and can bring up different feelings simultaneously, such as sadness, anger, fear, or worry. Grief is also physical and can be felt in different parts of a person’s body. A child or adult who is grieving may have trouble sleeping, eating, and may experience somatic difficulties such as headaches or stomachaches. Finally, grief can also show up in someone’s behaviors, such as through crying, separating oneself from other people, and having trouble focusing or sitting still. At the same time, other individuals may appear to be less affected, despite the fact that they may still be experiencing many of these symptoms. This is because for some people, depending on their age and ability to deal with their grief, they want to continue to have control over their life and maintain normal routines. This can sometimes be helpful for them to manage their grief, especially while at school or in public. Because of the widespread effects grief can have on an individual’s functioning, it is critical that students, school-staff, and parents obtain effective support when grieving the death of one or more significant person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elementary school children (6-12) are typically able to relate to death more easily than younger children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Considerations for schools and families&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children express grief differently due to a variety of factors, including their age, cognitive abilities, and cultural surroundings. Young children are typically better able to express their grief through play, make-believe, and drawings instead of verbally. They also tend to be more vulnerable to the withdrawal or excessive displays of grief of their caregivers and need consistent love and support. Elementary school children (6-12) are typically able to relate to death more easily than younger children and ask a lot of questions and obtain knowledge to better understand what happened. Within this age range, they understand that death is final and that all living things die. Adolescents (13-18) are sometimes more self-conscious and although they may be spending more time with friends, they may be less likely to share their feelings with their friends. Typically around ages 15-18, they feel more comfortable expressing their feelings and their grief is more similar to that of adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of age, grief can significantly affect children and teenagers in various ways. Because of the variety of symptoms someone may experience when grieving, he or she may be less focused or motivated in school, or appear more withdrawn or tired. Furthermore, because a grieving youth may be experiencing a range of emotions, with some being uncomfortable for that individual, the youth may experience sudden outbursts of either anger or sadness. Families and schools are encouraged to remember that this is to be expected, and that youth need to be supported when experiencing these difficult emotions. However, additional support and follow-up may be needed if the youth is exhibiting a significant loss of interest in daily activities, is chronically absent, and has a significant fear of being alone, among other symptoms. These changes should be significant and not minor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional support and follow-up may occur in a variety of ways, such as having a school-based mental health professional, like a school psychologist or counselor, provide individual or group support to the youth. This will enable the youth to process difficult feelings, have the opportunity to share their story, and talk about positive and difficult memories. When appropriate, receiving support through a grief group can be particularly effective, as it can help normalize their feelings and make the youth feel less alone. Ensuring that teachers and families are knowledgeable about the grief process and how to effectively support grieving youth is also critical. It may be particularly difficult for teachers or families who are also grieving the same death as the youth, emphasizing the importance of self-care and support for adults. Given that most children will experience the death of at least one close or special person prior to high school graduation, and because the vast majority of children ages 7 to 18 attend school on a regular basis, it is essential that school-based professionals be prepared to effectively support bereaved students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Chalk by Nikhita S. Public domain via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://unsplash.com/photos/NsPDiPFTp4c&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/supporting-grieving-students-school-crisis-events/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Supporting grieving students at school following crisis events&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/542172078/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/542172078/oupblogpsychology,&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/542172078/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/population-ageing-future-care/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How will population ageing affect future end of life care?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/safe-drugs-medicine-universal-healthcare/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The road to safe drugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/finding-meaning-pavilion-poetry-series/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Finding meaning in poetry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kimberly Ilkowski</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A DIY take on the early universe may reveal cosmic secrets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/early-universe-bose-einstein-condensate"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/early-universe-bose-einstein-condensate</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T20:45:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A conglomerate of ultracold atoms reproduces some of the physics of the early universe.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">FAU and Max Planck Team Up on First Joint Position</title>
		<link href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/fau-and-max-planck-team-up-on-first-joint-position/"/>
		<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10634</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T19:49:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;h4&gt;Ken Dawson-Scully Named Associate V.P. for Strategic Initiatives, Head of Institutional Partnerships at FAU and MPFI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida Atlantic University and Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI) have combined forces to form the first jointly supported position between the two institutions. As of May 1, Ken Dawson-Scully, Ph.D., will be newly appointed to the role of associate vice president for strategic initiatives and head of institutional partnerships for FAU and MPFI. Joining FAU in 2008, Dawson-Scully served as associate director of the FAU Brain Institute and most recently as an associate professor of biological sciences and associate dean for graduate studies in FAU’s Charles E. Schmidt College of Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For almost a decade, the close and synergistic partnership between Florida Atlantic University and Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience has been undeniably beneficial for our institutions and Palm Beach County,” said FAU President John Kelly. “This latest initiative will foster tremendous returns on our co-investment for educational and research opportunities, economic development, as well as faculty and student recruitment. Together, we will continue to strengthen our thriving alliance; enhancing recognition and visibility both locally and globally.”&lt;br /&gt;
In this joint FAU/MPFI position, Dawson-Scully will work closely with the executive leadership team of both institutions under the direction of Matthias Haury, Ph.D., MPFI’s COO and Jeff Atwater, FAU’s vice president for strategic initiatives and CFO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to further reinforce the flourishing relationship with our partners at Florida Atlantic University. Our joint efforts will continue to facilitate unique collaborative opportunities between our institutions and inspire a vibrant, creative space where groundbreaking innovations in science and technology will prosper,” said David Fitzpatrick, Ph.D., CEO and scientific director of MPFI. “This collaborative environment will allow us the opportunity to better tackle the areas of focus that are critical to the success of both of our institutions’ missions, goals and aspirations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his new role, Dawson-Scully will be responsible for developing and implementing key initiatives in areas that are crucial to FAU and MPFI. These initiatives will include co-branding programs, enhancing infrastructure, developing new educational programs, identifying and securing joint funding opportunities, conducting research training, building partnerships, and fostering collaboration between academic and administrative units.&lt;br /&gt;
Additionally, as the head of this new initiative, Dawson-Scully will act as a liaison for both institutes, developing and sustaining strong relationships with local and international foundations, corporations, government and community groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am both honored and excited to serve in this new capacity for Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience and Florida Atlantic University. My ultimate goal is to escalate our international reputation and expand our distinguished faculty, recruiting talented students and world-class scientists to our institutions,” said Dawson-Scully. “By combining our expertise, knowledge and resources, our close partnership will generate significant impact, benefitting the local, regional and international communities.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent joint program, where FAU and MPFI have partnered, is the FAU Max Planck Honors Program. The FAU MPHP is an elite undergraduate program that can be accomplished as an undergraduate student, in either FAU’s Harriet L. Wilkes Honors College or the College of Science, focused on the John D. MacArthur Campus at Jupiter. Applications for the first cohort for this fall are due April 30, and more information for the FAU MPHP can be found at http://fau.edu/mphp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dawson-Scully received his Ph.D. from the University of Toronto in 2003, and his M.Sc. from Queen’s University in 1998. He currently serves on the steering committee and is a faculty member of the newly formed International Max Planck Research School (IMPRS). A highly accomplished researcher, his work investigates ways to protect the brain from neurodegeneration caused by acute or chronic cellular stress using the genetic model organism, the fruit fly or D. melanogaster. Dawson-Scully has identified a number of molecular targets in the fruit fly nervous system that can rescue the damaging effects of pathological conditions such as high temperature, low oxygen, and oxidative stress. This impactful research opens up new avenues for the future treatment of human diseases such as stroke and epilepsy. His findings, which have been successfully translated from fly, to zebrafish, fresh water turtle, and mouse, have led to the submissions of four novel United States patents for the medical treatment of febrile seizure, migraine, and stroke in humans. Dawson-Scully also serves as the chief scientific officer for Neuro Pharmalogics, Inc., an FAU Tech Runway® start-up company that has licensed his intellectual property for the purpose of creating novel therapeutics aimed at combating brain related diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image:&lt;br /&gt;
From left: Jeff Atwater, FAU’s vice president for strategic initiatives and CFO; Matthias Haury, Ph.D., MPFI’s COO; Ken-Dawson-Scully, Ph.D., associate vice president for strategic initiatives and head of institutional partnerships at FAU and MPFI; FAU President John Kelly; and David Fitzpatrick, Ph.D., CEO and scientific director of MPFI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;About Florida Atlantic University:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida Atlantic University, established in 1961, officially opened its doors in 1964 as the fifth public university in Florida. Today, the University, with an annual economic impact of $6.3 billion, serves more than 30,000 undergraduate and graduate students at sites throughout its six-county service region in southeast Florida. FAU’s world-class teaching and research faculty serves students through 10 colleges: the Dorothy F. Schmidt College of Arts and Letters, the College of Business, the College for Design and Social Inquiry, the College of Education, the College of Engineering and Computer Science, the Graduate College, the Harriet L. Wilkes Honors College, the Charles E. Schmidt College of Medicine, the Christine E. Lynn College of Nursing and the Charles E. Schmidt College of Science. FAU is ranked as a High Research Activity institution by the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. The University is placing special focus on the rapid development of critical areas that form the basis of its strategic plan: Healthy aging, biotech, coastal and marine issues, neuroscience, regenerative medicine, informatics, lifespan and the environment. These areas provide opportunities for faculty and students to build upon FAU’s existing strengths in research and scholarship. For more information, visit www.fau.edu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;About Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI), a not-for-profit research organization, is part of the world-renowned Max Planck Society, Germany’s most successful research organization with over 80 institutes worldwide. Since its establishment in 1948, 18 Nobel laureates have emerged from the ranks of its scientists. It has produced over 15,000 publications, more than 3,000 inventions and over 90 spin-off companies, putting it on par with the best and most prestigious research institutions in the world. As its first U.S. institution, MPFI brings together exceptional neuroscientists from around the world to answer fundamental questions about brain development and function and to develop new technologies that make groundbreaking scientific discoveries possible. Their research is shared publicly with scholars, universities and other organizations around the globe, providing the necessary foundation of knowledge to develop treatments and cures for brain disorders such as autism, schizophrenia, Parkinson’s disease and Alzheimer’s disease. For more information, visit www.maxplanckflorida.org.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helena Decker</name>
			<uri>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/"/>
			<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pumping water underground for power may have triggered South Korean quake</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pumping-water-underground-power-may-have-triggered-south-korean-quake"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pumping-water-underground-power-may-have-triggered-south-korean-quake</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T15:19:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A 2017 South Korean earthquake may have been caused by human activities, two new studies suggest.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Prominent researcher dismissed following misconduct probe</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/27/prominent-researcher-dismissed-following-misconduct-probe/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64769</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T14:18:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The University of Tokyo has fired a high-profile cell biologist after a probe determined his group had falsified data. According to a news release issued today (in Japanese), the university has issued a “disciplinary dismissal” of Yoshinori Watanabe (according to our Google translate of the notice). In 2016, the institution began an investigation of seven … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/27/prominent-researcher-dismissed-following-misconduct-probe/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Prominent researcher dismissed following misconduct probe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Website privacy policies don’t say much about how they share your data</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/website-privacy-policies-dont-say-much-about-how-they-share-your-data"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/website-privacy-policies-dont-say-much-about-how-they-share-your-data</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T11:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Privacy policies don’t reveal the half of how websites share user data.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Contrary to popular belief, smiling makes you look older</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/27/contrary-to-popular-belief-smiling-makes-you-look-older/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33772</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T08:26:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-498317079.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33774&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33774&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Close-up portrait of a beautiful woman applying moisturizer on her face.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1403101372&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;damircudic&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;155&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman applying moisturizer&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woman applying moisturizer&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-498317079.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-498317079.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-498317079.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1957,1532&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/27/contrary-to-popular-belief-smiling-makes-you-look-older/woman-applying-moisturizer/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-498317079.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the adverts for anti-ageing skin products, everyone is smiling, positively blooming with youthfulness. A canny move by the marketeers you might think – after all, past research has found most of us believe smiling makes people look younger. It’s just that actually, it doesn’t. It makes you look older. That’s according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758%2Fs13423-017-1306-8&quot;&gt;a new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin and Review&lt;/em&gt; that explores an intriguing mismatch between our beliefs and perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33772&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzvi Ganel at Ben-Gurion University of the Negev and Melvyn Goodale at the University of Western Ontario began by asking 40 participants (23 women; average age 24) to estimate the age of 35 women and 35 men from photographs of their faces. Participants saw one of two versions of each model’s face, in which they were either smiling or had a neutral expression. On average, the participants rated the faces as older, by about a year, when they saw them smiling compared with when they had a neutral expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, most of the participants (33/40) stated afterwards that they believed smiling makes you look younger. Also, when asked to estimate the average age they’d given for all of the smiling faces they’d viewed and the average age they’d given to the neutral faces, they thought erroneously that they’d rated the smiling faces as younger (presumably in keeping with their belief that smiling makes you look younger).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new results are consistent with &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758%2Fs13423-015-0822-7&quot;&gt;an earlier series of studies&lt;/a&gt; by Ganel in which he presented evidence that the ageing effect of smiling (on this occasion of one to two years) is due to the way it increases wrinkles around the eyes. For instance, the ageing effect disappeared when he filtered out eye wrinkles or presented only the lower half of smiling faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the this latest research, Ganel and Goodale followed up with a second experiment in which 42 more participants estimated the ages of faces that were either smiling, neutral or looking surprised. Again, the same person’s face was estimated to be older when smiling compared with when holding a neutral expression. Meanwhile surprised faces were rated as younger than neutral faces, perhaps because the facial expression of surprise acts to smooth out eye wrinkles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When asked to estimate the average age they’d guessed for smiling, neutral and surprised faces, the participants again mistakenly thought that they’d rated smiling faces as younger than neutral faces. On the other hand, they estimated that they’d given the surprised faces the same average age as the neutral faces, seemingly unaware that they’d actually rated them as younger (presumably due to the lack of any specific beliefs about the effects of a surprised expression on appearance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The findings show, for the first time, that people can erroneously believe that smiling makes one appear younger, while at the same time rating smiling faces as older than neutral faces,” the researchers concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we can’t tell from these findings what part memory plays in the effects, if any. Did participants mistakenly think they’d estimated a younger average age for smiling faces because of the influence of their &lt;em&gt;belief&lt;/em&gt; that smiling faces look younger or because they actually &lt;em&gt;remembered &lt;/em&gt;the smiling faces as younger? Also, I wonder whether it makes any difference whether a smile is genuine or not – genuine or “Duchenne” smiles are known to involve more crinkling of the muscles around the eyes, so perhaps they have a greater ageing effect than feigned smiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These unresolved issues aside, the results suggest that if you’d like to present a more youthful version of yourself on your Twitter or Facebook page, you should delete that grinning selfie and switch for a neutral pose or even a look of surprise. Or you could just dig out an old photo of a younger you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758%2Fs13423-017-1306-8&quot;&gt;The effects of smiling on perceived age defy belief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 144 Language in the Brain with Angela Friederici</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-144-language-in-the-brain-with-angela-friederici"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/1a93de317f4d136019a4954bba6ed7bd</id>
		<updated>2018-04-27T02:10:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;This is an interview with Dr. Angela Friederici, author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2DRBuhq&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;amazon link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Language in Our Brain: The Origins of a Uniquely Human Capacity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Her book is an extensive review of decades of research, but this interview provides an accessible introduction to listeners of all backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don't miss our new monthly Facebook live sessions where listeners can submit questions about past episodes. Learn more at our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/brainsciencepodcast&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook Fan Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Full episode show notes and episode transcripts are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T02:29:10+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Anthropologists in Peru have unearthed the largest known child sacrifice</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mass-sacrifice-children-peru"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mass-sacrifice-children-peru</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T21:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The largest known mass sacrifice of children occurred around 550 years ago in the Chimú empire in Peru.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This plastic can be recycled over and over and over again</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plastic-polymer-recyclable"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plastic-polymer-recyclable</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T19:40:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new kind of polymer is fully recyclable: It breaks down into the exact same molecules that it came from.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Split atom clouds get entangled in quantum tests</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/split-atom-clouds-get-entangled-quantum-tests"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/split-atom-clouds-get-entangled-quantum-tests</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T18:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists create quantum links between clouds consisting of thousands of atoms.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Mining data for defect prediction</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/04/26/mining-data-for-defect-prediction.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-04-26:/2018/04/26/mining-data-for-defect-prediction.html</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T16:48:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Defect prediction relies on data and modelling techniques. Previous work has predominantly been focused to improving the latter. Despite numerous studies exploiting a wide range of machine learning techniques, prediction accuracies improve at a slow pace. On the other hand, the focus on data has somewhat been limited. High-quality data is difficult to obtain and mostly consists of metrics which have been lingering round for a long time. Due to the influx of digital data, other fields have developed some interesting techniques for its analysis. In this journal club I will discuss some of those techniques for data analysis and link them to their possible use in defect prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 27/04/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jean Petric</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T16:48:52+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Want to build a dragon? Science is here for you</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/build-dragon-fire-science"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/build-dragon-fire-science</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T16:15:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fire-breathing dragons can’t live anywhere outside of a book or TV. But nature provides some guidance as to how they might get their flames. If they existed, anyway.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">rGONAD: A new simple method for genome-editing in rats</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/26/rgonad-new-simple-method-genome-editing-rats/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10145</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T15:32:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/rGONAD-Blog-fig-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-10146&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/rGONAD-Blog-fig-e1524755679676.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome-edited animals are widely used in various fields of research. Recent advances in the field of genome-editing, especially the CRISPR/Cas9 system (Clustered Regulatory Interspaced Short Palindromic Repeats /CRISPR associated protein), have enabled rapid generation of genome-edited animals with ease. However, the procedure for producing such animals involves multiple complicated steps and also necessitates special techniques, such as handling zygotes &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Many researchers desire a simple and convenient method for generating genome-edited animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laboratory rat (&lt;em&gt;Rattus norvegicus&lt;/em&gt;) is a common model of human diseases. Although there are several advantages compared with using mice, technology for handling the rat genome has lagged behind. A new, more simple method for genome editing in rats is now available, namely rGONAD (rat Genome-editing via Oviductal Nucleic Acids Delivery).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the GONAD method has so far been successfully implemented in mice and rats, this concept can be adapted for other animals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rGONAD method involves two key steps: an injection with the solution containing Cas9 protein, guide RNA and single strand DNA (ssDNA) into the oviduct, followed by electroporation. Rats that have undergone rGONAD are bred as usual until birth, where offspring would be genome-edited and used for further analyses. Moreover, rGONAD is highly efficient in both knock-out and knock-in systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current standard method for genome-engineering in animals involves three major steps: isolation of zygotes from females, micromanipulation &lt;em&gt;ex vivo&lt;/em&gt; and then transfer into pseudopregnant females. These steps are complicated and require skillful training to perform; rGONAD overcomes these caveats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, in the ethical context of the 3Rs (Reduction, Replacement, and Refinement), the standard method consumes many females, whereas female rats can be recycled in the rGONAD system. Although the GONAD method has so far been successfully implemented in mice and rats, this concept can be adapted for other animals. Therefore, GONAD is a powerful method for genome-editing in animal research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/26/rgonad-new-simple-method-genome-editing-rats/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;rGONAD: A new simple method for genome-editing in rats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Takayuki Koyano Dr. Makoto Matsuyama</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Dr. David Fitzpatrick receives notable honor from Brandeis University for his leadership in Systems Neuroscience</title>
		<link href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/dr-david-fitzpatrick-receives-notable-honor-from-brandeis-university-for-his-leadership-in-systems-neuroscience/"/>
		<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10623</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T15:31:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;h4&gt;The recognition includes presentation of inaugural John Lisman ’66 Memorial Lecture in Vision Science&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, April 10, David Fitzpatrick, Ph.D., CEO and Scientific Director of the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI), delivered the inaugural John Lisman ’66 Memorial Lecture in Vision Science at Brandeis University. The medium-sized private research university, based outside of Boston and known for its excellent undergraduate education, also presented the award given in conjunction to the lecture to Dr. Fitzpatrick. The award is in recognition of his work as a leader in systems neuroscience, with a focus on the functional organization and development of neural circuits in the cerebral cortex. The public lecture was titled “Functional Synaptic Architecture in Primary Visual Cortex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formerly called the Jay Pepose ’75 Award in Vision Sciences, the name was changed in 2017 to memorialize John Lisman ’66, Ph.D., who earned his undergraduate degree in physics from Brandeis in 1966. He went on to earn a doctorate in physiology at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, followed by a postdoctoral fellowship at Harvard University under Nobel Laureate George Wald. He returned to Brandeis in 1974 as an assistant professor and then a full professor in 1987. Dr. Lismann passed away in 2017 at the age of 73.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am honored to receive the inaugural John Lisman ’66 Memorial Lecture in Vision Science,” said Dr. Fitzpatrick. “Dr. Lisman was a leader in neurosciences and an integral force behind the Pepose Award, from his work in selecting the recipients to his role as host of the lecture and dinner each year. I am truly thankful for both the opportunity and recognition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Fitzpatrick’s research has played a pivotal role in defining the functional organization of cortical circuits, exploring rules of intracortical connectivity, addressing mechanisms of neural coding, and probing the role of experience in the maturation of cortical circuits. His current research utilizes state-of-the-art in vivo imaging techniques to probe the functional synaptic architecture of circuits in primary visual cortex, defining the circuit mechanisms that build the selective response properties of cortical neurons, and the critical role that neural activity plays in the proper maturation of these circuits. He earned his doctorate from Duke University in Psychology and Neuroscience, and his bachelor’s degree from Pennsylvania State University in Biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past winners of the Pepose Award include David Williams, University of Rochester; William Newsome, Stanford University; Richard Masland, Harvard University; Gordon Fain, University of California, Los Angeles; Michael Stryker, University of California, San Francisco; Peter Schiller, Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Jay and Maureen Neitz, University of Washington; and Frank Werblin, a leading retina researcher at the University of California, Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Pepose is the founder and medical director of the Pepose Vision Institute in St. Louis and a professor of clinical ophthalmology at Washington University. He founded and serves as board president of the Lifelong Vision Foundation, whose mission is to preserve lifelong vision for people in the St. Louis community, nationally and internationally through research, community programs and education programs. He was part of the inaugural class of fellows of the Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology. While a student at Brandeis, he worked closely with John Lisman, who began his career at the University when Dr. Pepose was an undergraduate. Dr. Pepose was the first student to join Dr. Lisman’s research group on campus. Dr. Lisman was an influential mentor to him and they remained lifelong friends until his passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maxplanckflorida.org&quot;&gt;www.maxplanckflorida.org&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about Brandeis University, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brandeis.edu&quot;&gt;www.brandeis.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image:&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Stephen Van Hooser, Dr. Jay Pepose, and Dr. David Fitzpatrick.&lt;br /&gt;
Photo credit: Heratch Ekmekjian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helena Decker</name>
			<uri>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/"/>
			<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Chemists duke it out over who was first to discover a 30-year-old technique</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/26/chemists-duke-it-out-over-who-was-first-to-discover-a-30-year-old-technique/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64660</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T12:00:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Decades ago, unbeknownst to each other, two chemists were independently working on a screening approach to identify new potential drugs. Both published papers about the technique around the same time. So now, when scientists write papers that cite the technique, who should get credit for discovering it? Decades later, that question still hasn’t been answered … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/26/chemists-duke-it-out-over-who-was-first-to-discover-a-30-year-old-technique/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Chemists duke it out over who was first to discover a 30-year-old technique&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Ten years of Mendeley – and what’s next</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ten-years-of-mendeley-and-whats-next"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ten-years-of-mendeley-and-whats-next</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T09:09:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The revolutionary reference management platform continues to evolve to meet the changing needs of researchers</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Taking a mere five-day break from Facebook will lower your physiological stress levels, researchers claim</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/26/taking-a-mere-five-day-break-from-facebook-will-lower-your-physiological-stress-levels-researchers-claim/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33754</id>
		<updated>2018-04-26T08:26:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-903669474.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33767&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33767&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;Logout\&amp;quot; on the Screen.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;Logout\&amp;quot; on the Screen.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;“Logout” on the Screen.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-903669474.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-903669474.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-903669474.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2309,1298&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/26/taking-a-mere-five-day-break-from-facebook-will-lower-your-physiological-stress-levels-researchers-claim/logout-on-the-screen/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-903669474.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does the prospect of taking a “Facebook holiday” fill you with dread as you picture a life of social isolation, or does it sound like an appealing and refreshing chance to change priorities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2018.1453467&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; has investigated the psychological effects of taking time off from using Facebook. Given that Facebook helps keep us connected but can also expose us to many social stressors, like envy and gossip, the researchers, led by Eric Vanman at the University of Queensland, expected to find a Facebook break would be associated with a drop in life-satisfaction, but also a reduction in stress levels. Their findings are largely in line with their predictions “[and] consistent with the general ambivalent feelings that may typify most active users about Facebook”. However, the study also features ambiguities and limitations that may leave sceptical readers unconvinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33754&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanman and his colleagues invited 138 active Facebook users (they averaged 2.8 hours daily use) to the psych lab where they provided a saliva cortisol sample and completed psychological questionnaires tapping their Facebook use, life-satisfaction, stress, mood and loneliness. This initial data showed that more active Facebook users reported higher life-satisfaction and less loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critically, half of the participants learned at this time that they would be required to take a five-day hiatus from Facebook (they knew from the study advert that this might be a possibility). All the participants then wrote about what they thought the ensuing days would be like and they gave another saliva sample. Finally, all participants returned to the lab five days later, to repeat the questionnaires, report their social movements during the intervening Sunday, and provide one further saliva cortisol sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly all the participants in the Facebook-hiatus condition wrote that they expected it to be a pretty miserable time. “&lt;em&gt;I will probably feel … upset as my social life will be totally stopped if I cannot used Facebook and cannot find my friends in Facebook, I will also feel like left behind as I will not be able to know what has happened with my Facebook friends in the coming five days&lt;/em&gt;,” wrote one participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results matched these expectations in that the No-Facebook group reported lower life satisfaction at the end of the study than those in the Facebook-as-normal condition (the average life satisfaction for the Facebook-as-normal group had increased during the study whereas the No-Facebook group’s had not). There were no group differences in mood through the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The No-Facebook group experienced this hit to their life-satisfaction despite the fact they reported an average of more than two hours extra face-to-face socialising on the Sunday during the study period compared to the Facebook-as-normal group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on the positive side, the No-Facebook group showed a reduction in their cortisol levels over the course of the study. Cortisol is often described as a stress hormone and it may provide a physiological marker of stress levels. However, cortisol fluctuates a lot and it’s difficult to interpret the meaning of this change, especially based on so few measures. Indeed, the No-Facebook group didn’t actually report a decrease in their stress levels on the questionnaires (and cortisol levels within the group didn’t correlate with self-reported stress levels). It’s worth noting too that across all participants, cortisol levels at baseline were not associated with any of the study’s other measures, such as intensity of Facebook use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers said that their study is “the first to demonstrate the effects of Facebook use on a physiological measure associated with health outcomes” and they interpreted their results as showing that “taking short breaks from Facebook could be beneficial to one’s health, as any prolonged stress could contribute to mental and physical disorders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a conclusion may be premature, or at least overly specific. Other than the diary reports of the Sunday, we do not know if or how the participants in the No-Facebook group supplemented their usual time on Facebook with different activities, whether online or offline. Might the cortisol reduction have been linked to less time on the internet, and more time going for walks or chatting face-to-face, for instance, rather than taking a break from Facebook specifically? And just how meaningful is the cortisol result when the participants didn’t report feeling any less stressed, and considering that the cortisol levels for both groups were in the “normal range” at the start of the study?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to interpret the hit to life satisfaction too. As the researchers acknowledged, there is a big difference between choosing to take a break from Facebook and having one partly imposed, as was the situation in the current study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these ambiguities the results certainly provide food for thought and will surely inspire more research on the psychological effects of taking breaks from Facebook and other online social networks. In the wake of the Cambridge Analytica scandal and the ensuing “delete Facebook” campaign, it would be particularly interesting to find out the psychological effects of a permanent break from Facebook rather than a mere five-day holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2018.1453467&quot;&gt;The burden of online friends: the effects of giving up Facebook on stress and well-being&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Footprints prove humans hunted giant sloths during the Ice Age</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/footprints-prove-humans-hunted-giant-sloths-during-ice-age"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/footprints-prove-humans-hunted-giant-sloths-during-ice-age</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T20:08:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Footprints of humans and giant sloths show a dramatic chase sequence from more than 10,000 years ago.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The latest star map from the Gaia spacecraft plots 1.7 billion stars</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-map-gaia-spacecraft-milky-way"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-map-gaia-spacecraft-milky-way</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T19:45:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Gaia spacecraft’s latest data release brings the number of stars with precisely measured motions up from 2 million to more than 1.3 billion.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">In China, coffee shop habits show cultural differences tied to farming</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-coffee-shop-habits-show-cultural-differences-tied-farming"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-coffee-shop-habits-show-cultural-differences-tied-farming</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T18:22:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Farming histories have shaped behavior in northern and southern China.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Asteroids could have delivered water to the early Earth</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/asteroids-could-have-delivered-water-early-earth"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/asteroids-could-have-delivered-water-early-earth</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Shooting mineral pellets at a simulated planet suggests an impact wouldn’t have boiled all of an asteroid’s water away.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Spooky quantum entanglement goes big in new experiments</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spooky-quantum-entanglement-goes-big-new-experiments"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spooky-quantum-entanglement-goes-big-new-experiments</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists entangled the motions of two jiggling devices that are visible with a magnifying glass or even the naked eye — if you have keen vision.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researcher loses battle with Cell over wording of retraction notice</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/25/researcher-loses-battle-with-cell-over-wording-of-retraction-notice/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64654</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T16:20:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 For months, a researcher has wrestled with a journal over the wording of an upcoming retraction notice. It appears that she has lost. Earlier this week, Cell retracted the paper, despite the protests of first author Shalon Babbitt Ledbetter. When Ledbetter learned the journal was planning to retract the biochemistry paper over image manipulations, but … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/25/researcher-loses-battle-with-cell-over-wording-of-retraction-notice/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Researcher loses battle with Cell over wording of retraction notice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author under fire has eight papers retracted, including seven from one journal</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/25/author-under-fire-has-six-papers-retracted-including-five-from-one-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64612</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T12:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A researcher whose work on the use of nanomaterials has been heavily scrutinized on PubPeer — with one critic alleging a paper contained “obviously fabricated” images — has lost eight papers. [Editor’s note: See update below.] The eight articles — seven from Biosensors and Bioelectronics and one from Analytica Chimica Acta, both published by Elsevier … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/25/author-under-fire-has-six-papers-retracted-including-five-from-one-journal/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Author under fire has eight papers retracted, including seven from one journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Clues to an Iron Age massacre lie in what the assailants left behind</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/clues-iron-age-massacre-lie-what-assailants-left-behind"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/clues-iron-age-massacre-lie-what-assailants-left-behind</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient Scandinavian massacre may reflect power struggles after Rome’s fall.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Study of long-term heterosexual couples finds women over-estimate and men underestimate their partner’s sexual advances</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/25/study-of-long-term-heterosexual-couples-finds-women-over-estimate-and-men-underestimate-their-partners-sexual-advances/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33758</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T08:42:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-472269917.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33759&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33759&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Play footsie with a man.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dodeskaden&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Footsie Flirt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Footsie Flirt&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-472269917.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-472269917.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-472269917.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1971,1521&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/25/study-of-long-term-heterosexual-couples-finds-women-over-estimate-and-men-underestimate-their-partners-sexual-advances/footsie-flirt/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-472269917.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Imagine that, during a quiet evening at home watching a movie with your romantic partner, you feel intense sexual desire and sensually put a hand on your partner’s thigh. Your partner does not respond and blithely continues to watch the movie… Is your partner truly not interested in sexual activity, or did she/he simply miss your cue?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So begins &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0265407517743081&quot;&gt;a new paper&lt;/a&gt;, published in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Social and Personal Relationships&lt;/i&gt;, that explores how accurate heterosexual people are at judging their partner’s attempts to initiate sex – in terms of their ability to the spot their partner’s cues, and also their overall impression of how often their partner makes sexual advances. It’s important, because as the researchers, led by Kiersten Dobson at the University of Western Ontario in Canada, note, “Sexual satisfaction is associated with relationship happiness, whereas sexual dissatisfaction is associated with relationship dissolution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33758&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other studies have found that in casual, short-term relationships, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/15/men-and-women-interpret-the-sexual-intent-behind-dating-behaviours-very-differently/&quot;&gt;men tend to overestimate a partner’s sexual interest (while women either underestimate it, or show no bias either way; they’re fairly accurate)&lt;/a&gt;. An evolutionary psychology explanation for a male tendency to think women are more interested than they actually are is that – in a casual relationship – while incorrectly perceiving interest and being rejected might not feel great, missing the signs of interest, and so a chance to mate, is worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explore what happens in longer-term relationships, the researchers recruited 120 heterosexual couples aged 18-51 (but with a mean age of 22), who had been together for between three months and 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An initial, exploratory study involved half the couples. The participants all privately completed a battery of questionnaires, which included questions about how often they and their partner attempt to initiate sex and how often they and their partner turn down an opportunity for sex. Then they rated how often these events typically occur over a one-month period (from “never” to “more than 11 times a month”).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, they read short descriptions of 29 behaviours that might indicate sexual interest (such as “I put my hand on my partner’s thigh”) and were asked to rate the degree to which they and they partner use each of these behaviours to indicate that they are interested in having sex. The participants also completed questionnaire assessments of their sexual satisfaction and love for their partner.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results showed that both men and women were pretty good at identifying the behaviours that their own partners use to indicate that they’d like to have sex. However, on average, the women overestimated the number of times that their partner tried to initiate sex, whereas the men got it about right.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second, similar, confirmatory study, involving the other 60 couples, found that the participants were again pretty good at recognising the behaviours that their own partner uses to indicate interest in having sex. In this group, the women also thought that their partners made more sexual advances than they actually did (according to the partner data), but only marginally. However, the men &lt;i&gt;under&lt;/i&gt;estimated their partner’s advances.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again from an evolutionary psychology perspective, the researchers speculate that for men in a long-term relationship, compared with a casual one, the costs associated with missing the signs of sexual interest may be lower (as there will be plenty more opportunities to have sex) and the costs of rejection will be higher (as being rejected by a long-term partner could be more painful). But as the results from the two studies were in part inconsistent, more work is needed before any firm conclusions on bias can be drawn, they note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to sexual satisfaction and love, people who overestimated their partner’s sexual advances reported feeling more sexual satisfaction. This might be because they felt more attractive and desired by their partner, the researchers suggest.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, people with partners who under-estimated their own advances reported feeling more love and greater sexual satisfaction – perhaps because the under-estimater feels motivated to do something to strengthen the relationship, which may then make their partner feel more satisfied.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers note, “Navigating sexual activity can be difficult, especially when partners’ behaviours that indicate their sexual interest are subtle.”&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers would like to see studies investigating how perceptions – and misperceptions – of sexual advances may affect relationships in the long term. But it would also, I think, be interesting to see a more real-time version of this study. Since other work has found that men under-report their own sexual intentions, it’s hard not to wonder whether the women in this study were really over-estimating their partners’ advances. Asking participants to report back daily, or every time they thought they or their partner had made a sexual advance – and whether or not it led to sex – would surely provide more accurate data than retrospective estimates of what happened in the course of a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0265407517743081&quot;&gt;Are you coming on to me? Bias and accuracy in couples’ perceptions of sexual advances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">FYR Diagnostics Joins Forces with Science Exchange to Offer RNA Screening and Biomarker Services</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/04/fyr-diagnostics-joins-forces-with-science-exchange-to-offer-rna-screening-and-biomarker-services/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1314</id>
		<updated>2018-04-25T01:01:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/FYR-Press-release.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;FYR Diagnostics Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1315&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/FYR-Press-release-300x167.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, April 24, 2018 – Science Exchange, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services, announced a collaboration with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fyr-diagnostics&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;FYR Diagnostics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to offer online access to its RNA screening and biomarker development services to scientists around the globe.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;FYR Diagnostics is a privately held company headquartered in Missoula, Montana. The company offers unique biomarker discovery services including the identification and validation of genomic biomarkers such as miRNA. Since its inception, FYR Diagnostics has developed ongoing, collaborative relationships with both academic institutions and private companies all over the world to advance the discovery of objective measures of health leading up to and during disease.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“The FYR Diagnostics team has extensive experience screening miRNA samples, developing biomarkers, writing grants, and designing experiments with the goal of worldwide patent protection and commercialization. Our ability to quickly adapt and utilize novel technologies gives us a competitive edge over other research groups. We’re thrilled to join Science Exchange and looking forward to providing world-class research services to a global life science community,” says Sarj Patel, Ph.D., President of FYR Diagnostics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We are very excited to collaborate with FYR Diagnostics to make available its RNA screening and biomarker development services to scientists worldwide,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., cofounder and CEO of Science Exchange. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Science Exchange is committed to adding the most innovative and qualified service providers to our platform, so scientists have the services they need securely and readily available to aid their discoveries. FYR Diagnostics has impressed us with their superb progress in miRNA screening and biomarker development.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About FYR Diagnostics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;FYR Diagnostics is a Missoula, Montana-based company led by a team with diverse research and commercialization backgrounds. FYR Diagnostics provides miRNA screening and biomarker development services to other companies, leveraging its team’s successful background in these areas. Additionally, the company has a strong in-house pipeline focused on biomarker and diagnostic development.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect with FYR Diagnostics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit FYR Diagnostics’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fyr-diagnostics&quot;&gt;Science Exchange profile&lt;/a&gt; to learn more and obtain quotes for their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fyr-diagnostics&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1259 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;67&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/quote_button-300x67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The first penis-scrotum transplant is the latest to go beyond lifesaving</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-penis-scrotum-transplant-latest-go-beyond-lifesaving"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-penis-scrotum-transplant-latest-go-beyond-lifesaving</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T22:13:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Advances that give patients new faces, hands and more aim to improve quality of life</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How the brain learns to read: development of the “word form area”</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/ntF3hTVdcr0/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19569</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T21:28:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/04/4305510994_52ae7f40e1_b-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to recognize, process and interpret written language is a uniquely human skill that is acquired with remarkable ease at a young age. But as anyone who has attempted to learn a new language will attest, the brain isn’t “hardwired” to understand written language. In fact, it remains somewhat of a mystery how the brain develops this specialized ability. Although researchers have identified brain regions that process written words, how this selectivity for language develops isn’t entirely clear. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.2004103&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Biology study&lt;/a&gt; by researchers from the University Paris-Saclay adds significantly to our understanding of the changes supporting reading acquisition in the child brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier studies have shown that the ventral visual cortex supports recognition of an array of visual stimuli, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11912041&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;objects, faces, and places&lt;/a&gt;. Within this area, a subregion in the left hemisphere known as the “visual word form area” (VWFA) shows a particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11960895&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;selectivity for written words&lt;/a&gt;. However, this ventral occipitotemporal region is characteristically plastic. It’s been proposed that stimuli compete for representation in this malleable area, such that “winner takes all” depending on the strongest input. Supporting this idea, studies have reported that higher reading ability is related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21071632&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reduced responsivity to faces&lt;/a&gt; and stronger right lateralization of face representation, suggesting that word representation may invade neural real estate devoted to face processing. But this idea has yet to be confirmed, and the evolution of specialized brain areas for reading in children is still poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The emergence of brain’s word form area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their study, Dehaene-Lambertz and colleagues monitored the reading abilities and brain changes of ten six-year old children to track the emergence of word specialization during a critical development period. Over the course of their first school-year, children were assessed every two months with reading evaluations and functional MRI while viewing words and non-word images (houses, objects, faces, bodies). As expected, reading ability improved over the year of first grade, as demonstrated by increased reading speed, word span, and phoneme knowledge, among other measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at this young age, when reading ability was newly acquired, words evoked widespread left-lateralized brain activation, most strongly in ventral occipitotemporal cortex. This activity increased over the year of school, with the greatest boost occurring after just the first few months. Importantly, there were no similar activation increases in response to other stimuli, confirming that these adaptations were specific to reading ability, not a general effect of development or education. Immediately after school began, the brain volume specialized for reading also significantly increased. Furthermore, reading speed was associated with greater activity, particularly in the VWFA. Using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/functional-mri-2/lecture/vUC9d/module-25-multi-voxel-pattern-analysis-a-neuroscientific-perspective&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;multivoxel pattern analysis&lt;/a&gt; to examine patterns of brain activity, the researchers found that activation patterns to words became more reliable with learning. In contrast, the patterns for other categories remained stable, with the exception of numbers, which may reflect specialization for symbols (words and numbers) generally, or correlation with the simultaneous development of mathematics skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What predisposes one brain region over another to take on this specialized role for reading words? Before school, there was no strong preference for any other category in regions that would later become word-responsive. However, brain areas that were destined to remain “non-word” regions showed more stable responses to non-word stimuli even before learning to read. Thus, perhaps the brain takes advantage of unoccupied real-estate to perform the newly acquired skill of reading. The VWFA showed the expected word-specific multi-voxel activation pattern, but also showed activity patterns unique to other visual categories. This suggests that reading does not, in fact, invade and replace regions devoted to other functions, but that representations for words and other stimuli can overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading development model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings add a critical piece to the puzzle of how reading skills are acquired in the developing child brain. Though it was already known that reading recruits a specialized brain region for words, this study reveals that this occurs &lt;em&gt;without changing&lt;/em&gt; the organization of areas already specialized for other functions. The authors propose an elegant model for the developmental brain changes underlying reading skill acquisition (Figure). In the illiterate child, there are adjacent columns or patches of cortex either tuned to a specific category (e.g., faces, tools, etc.), or not yet assigned a function. With literacy, the free subregions become tuned to words, while the previously specialized subregions remain stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/04/journal.pbio_.2004103.g008.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-19571&quot; height=&quot;173&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/04/journal.pbio_.2004103.g008-300x173.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The plastic developing cortex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid emergence of the word area after just a brief learning period highlights the remarkable plasticity of the developing cortex. In individuals who become literate as adults, the same VWFA is present. However, in contrast to children, the relation between reading speed and activation in this area &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21071632&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;is weaker&lt;/a&gt; in adults, and a single adult &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/mbe.12143&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;case-study&lt;/a&gt; by the authors showed a much slower, gradual development of the VWFA over a prolonged learning period of several months. As the researchers note, “&lt;em&gt;the fast changes induced by reading acquisition that we observed here betray the intense plasticity of children’s immature ventral occipitotemporal cortex&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primed to read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the malleability of the VWFA and surrounding cortex, its location was consistent across children, stable and reproducible. This suggests that its location is, to some extent, pre-constrained. Yet the factors that predestine this region for word selectivity remain a mystery, and as the authors explain, “&lt;em&gt;the precise identification of those constraints, whether cytoarchitectural or connectional, is an important goal for further research&lt;/em&gt;.” Whatever the reason, this region appears primed to rapidly adopt novel representations of symbolic words, and this priming may peak at a specific period in childhood. This finding underscores the importance of a strong education in youth. The authors surmise that “&lt;em&gt;the success of education might also rely on the right timing to benefit from the highest neural plasticity. Our results might also explain why numerous academic curricula, even in ancient civilizations, propose to teach reading around seven years&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braga LW et al. (2017). Tracking Adult Literacy Acquisition With Functional MRI: A Single‐Case Study. &lt;em&gt;Mind, Brain, Edu&lt;/em&gt;. 11(3): 121-32. doi.org/10.1111/mbe.12143&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen L et al. (2002). Language-specific tuning of visual cortex? Functional properties of the Visual Word Form Area. &lt;em&gt;Brain&lt;/em&gt;. 125(Pt 5): 1-54-69.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dehaene S et al. (2010). How learning to read changes the cortical networks for vision and language. &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;. 330(6009): 1359-64. doi:10.1126/science.1194140&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dehaene-Lambertz G, Monzalvo K, Dehaene S. (2018). The emergence of the visual word form: Longitudinal evolution of category-specific ventral visual areas during reading acquisition. &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biol&lt;/em&gt;. 16(3): e2004103. doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.2004103&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malach R, Levy I, Hasson U. (2002). The topography of high-order human object areas. &lt;em&gt;Trends Cogn Sci&lt;/em&gt;. 6(4): 176-84.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit https://www.flickr.com/photos/holtsman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-17356&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emilie Reas&lt;/strong&gt; received her PhD in Neuroscience from UC San Diego, where she used fMRI to study memory. As a postdoc at UCSD, she currently studies how the brain changes with aging and disease. In addition to her tweets for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PLOSNeuro&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@PLOSNeuro&lt;/a&gt; she is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/etreas&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@etreas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/ntF3hTVdcr0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emilie Reas</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Private web browsing doesn’t mean no one is watching</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/internet-privacy-incognito-web-browsing"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/internet-privacy-incognito-web-browsing</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T19:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Many people misunderstand what private web browsing actually is. Web browsers’ explanations don’t help.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genetically modified plant may boost supply of a powerful malaria drug</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/genetically-modified-plant-may-boost-supply-powerful-malaria-drug"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/genetically-modified-plant-may-boost-supply-powerful-malaria-drug</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T18:56:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Using a DNA study and genetic engineering, researchers tripled the amount of an antimalarial compound naturally produced by sweet wormwood plants.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Webinar: Preclinical Animal Studies: Key Considerations for Success</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/04/webinar-preclinical-animal-studies-key-considerations-for-success/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1312</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T16:49:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/CARE-Research-Collage.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;CARE Research, LLC Preclinical Services&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-1313&quot; height=&quot;170&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/CARE-Research-Collage-300x170.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What parameters of an animal study should you consider at each step — from study design through histopathological analysis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tune into this &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/2018CAREResearchWebinar&quot;&gt;on-demand webinar&lt;/a&gt; to hear from Rajan Bawa, Ph.D., Chief Technology Officer of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/care-research-llc&quot;&gt;CARE Research LLC. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bawa is a leading preclinical research expert with decades of experience in drug and device development. You will learn best practices for setting up a preclinical study that will meet compliance requirements and give you the best chance for regulatory approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/2018CAREResearchWebinar&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;View Webinar button&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1302&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/View-Webinar-button.png&quot; width=&quot;244&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who Should Attend:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preclinical researchers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharmacology/Toxicology scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal study scientists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About Our Speaker:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rajan Bawa, Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt; is the Chief Technology Officer of CARE Research, LLC. Dr. Bawa has been in the pharmaceutical and biotechnology industry for over 40 years. Twenty years ago, he launched a histopathology/hematology/clinpath company, Colorado Histo-Prep. In 2010, the company acquired one of its preclinical CRO clients, which was CARE Research. The resulting enterprise now offers sponsors a single point of control for multiple facets of complex studies for diverse clients in the preclinical space. These range from large pharma, to small biotechs, startups and academic researchers performing translational research.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Though often forgotten, the placenta has a huge role in baby’s health</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/placenta-baby-embryo-health"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/placenta-baby-embryo-health</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T16:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Recent research in mice suggests that a lot of early problems in the embryo may actually have roots in the placenta.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Making a home for the Physical Sciences and Engineering in PLOS ONE</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/27uXBoHo9ec/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8169</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T14:59:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/04/supernova_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0002-9890-5451&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0002-9890-5451&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Calling all physicists, chemists, earth scientists, computer scientists and engineers: help PLOS ONE make science more open, more reproducible and more transparent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is known for its multi- and interdisciplinary approach. The journal is open for papers in all areas of science. From particle physics to pulmonology, we particularly welcome papers that break down barriers between disciplines. Historically speaking, however, most of our initiatives and publications have focused on biomedical topics. Given that all of PLOS’ founders came from biomedical fields, this focus arose organically. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE’s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; approach to consider all rigorous research irrespective of impact and PLOS’ commitment to driving innovations in Open Science and Open Access in a non-profit framework have always attracted a diverse group of researchers and disciplines. Indeed, communities in physics, chemistry, earth sciences, computer sciences and engineering have adopted &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; as an outlet of choice in the past. We have published influential papers on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/authors?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0059613%20&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;complex networks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0049365&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;3D printing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0133088&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;polymer chemistry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0081648&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0134254&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, to name but a few topics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To build on these strengths, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;has created a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Physical Sciences and Engineering team &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2018/02/26/towards-our-next-10-years/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;as part of a wider effort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to better serve our communities through subject-specific in-house editorial groups. The team is led by me, Division Editor Leonie Mueck (Physics, Computer Science, Engineering). I am proud to present the team working beside me:   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Associate Editor Victoria Black (Earth Sciences)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Associate Editor Helen Howard (Chemistry and Materials Science)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;You can meet us at many 2018 conferences, including the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acs.org/content/acs/en/meetings/national-meeting.html?sc=meetings_170416_mtg_BO18_od&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ACS National Meeting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macro18.org/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;MACRO2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goldschmidt.info/2018/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Goldschmidt2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrs.org/fall2018&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;2018 MRS Fall Meeting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fallmeeting.agu.org/2018/welcome/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;2018 AGU Fall Meeting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netsci2018.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NetSci 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Physical Sciences and Engineering is a vast remit and we are building an experienced editorial board in the different research fields, an editorial family which you are invited to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/join-editorial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;join &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;as an Academic Editor. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;is a journal that is run by the community for the community, and we invite researchers in the field to join us in our efforts. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Together with some of these communities, we have already started working on various editorial projects: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In consultation with new and veteran editorial board members, we have launched two Calls for Papers, in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2018/03/09/call-for-papers-ml4health/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Machine Learning in Health and Biomedicine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2018/03/02/call-for-papers-quantum/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in Open Quantum Computation and Simulation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, for which we expect authors to share their source code as well as their data. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;On 25 April, 10-11am Pacific Daylight Time, we will be discussing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2018/04/18/stop-hiding-your-code/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;why and how researchers should share their code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; on Twitter using the hashtag #ShareYourCode and invite everyone to join. Connect with me on twitter @LeonieMueck if you are active on social media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To support the younger generation of scientists in these disciplines we have recently launched the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/onetravelaward&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Early Career Researcher Travel Award&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; in the Physical Sciences. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In the PLOS Channel “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/rtcc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Responding to Climate Change&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;”, one of our Section Editors and his colleagues are curating an interdisciplinary community resource on climate change. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Going forward, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;’s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;new website design&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; will help in showcasing content from the different Physical Sciences and Engineering disciplines.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;There are more projects in Physical Sciences and Engineering in the pipeline, and we are committed to sharing our progress with you as we move forward. We want to hear from you, the researchers in these communities. Share your thoughts and help us s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;hape physical sciences and engineering at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;! Your perspectives will help shape future projects, topics for calls for papers and how to support you with Open Science initiatives. Please fill out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdbUgmt-pmFC3EWTyPfRb7OrndR_lfbWudgh1-h3asfP3S5kg/viewform?usp=sf_link&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; this form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; if you want to share your ideas with us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/27uXBoHo9ec&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonie Mueck</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Retraction Watch readers, we really need your help</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/24/retraction-watch-readers-we-really-need-your-help/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64550</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T12:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Dear Retraction Watch readers: We hope that you continue to enjoy Retraction Watch, and find it — and our database of retractions — useful. Maybe you’re a researcher who likes keeping up with developments in scientific integrity. Maybe you’re a reporter who has found a story idea in our database, or on the blog. Maybe … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/24/retraction-watch-readers-we-really-need-your-help/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch readers, we really need your help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New cross-cultural analysis suggests that g or “general intelligence” is a human universal</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/24/new-cross-cultural-analysis-suggests-that-g-or-general-intelligence-is-a-human-universal/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33750</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T09:38:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-685703560.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33752&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33752&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D750&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Globe Simulation Model&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1483017154&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Education Photos&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Education Photos&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-685703560.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-685703560.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-685703560.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2309,1299&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/24/new-cross-cultural-analysis-suggests-that-g-or-general-intelligence-is-a-human-universal/education-photos/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-685703560.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligence is a concept that some people have a hard time buying. It’s too multifaceted, too context-dependent, too Western. The US psychologist Edwin Boring encapsulated this scepticism when he said “measurable intelligence is simply what the tests of intelligence test.” Yet the scientific credentials of the concept are undimmed, partly because intelligence is strongly associated with so many important outcomes in life. Now Utah Valley University researchers Russell Warne and Cassidy Burningham have released evidence that further strengthens the case for intelligence being a valid and useful concept. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/uv673/&quot;&gt;PsyArXiv pre-print&lt;/a&gt; presents a cross-study analysis suggesting a single intelligence-like factor underpins mental performance across a wide range of non-western cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33750&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to work pioneered by Charles Spearman, we know that in Western populations performance on a range of mental tasks seems to reflect a more basic mental ability, a “general intelligence” or simply &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can’t see &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt; – it’s a statistical reality more than anything else, but it’s very robust, and modern research suggests that the &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt; factor accounts for roughly half the variability in performance within and between people on all kinds of mental tests. Being strong verbally doesn’t guarantee you will be mathematical too, but it tips the odds strongly in your favour.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s conceivable that &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt; is not culturally universal – after all, there are many countries, especially non-Western, where relatively greater value is placed on the social and emotional aspects of intelligent behaviour (and where these non-cognitive skills are more closely tied to a successful life) – for instance, in Zimbabwe it is considered socially intelligent to prioritise caring for your relatives over friends or strangers. Also, people from different cultures performing the same task will often tackle it in a different way: past research found that Zambian children struggled in a traditional expression task using pen and paper, but were talented clay-moulders, for example. Could these cultural variations in behaviour and in the conception of what is &lt;em&gt;considered&lt;/em&gt; smart reflect fundamental differences in how minds work?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, Warne and Burningham searched the literature to find mental ability studies in non-industrialised, non-Western cultures (defined as less than half the population being White or European). They selected datasets that included participant results on four or more cognitive tasks so that it was possible to perform a “factor analysis” to identify how many factors seemed to be driving variation in performance across the different tests. Mostly there were standard intelligence measures, but also other types of test, including Piagetian development tasks, and tests designed to be specific to the cultural conditions, such as children’s willingness to interact with unfamiliar toys after seeing them used.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis covered nearly 100 datasets from 31 cultures including Thailand, Uganda, Papau New Guinea, Guyana – from every inhabited continent and world region save Europe and Australia. The median sample size was 150, but due to some very large samples Warne and Burningham were working with 50,000 participants in all. They wanted to explore which cultures and which sets of tasks featured performance variation that could be reduced down to one factor akin to &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt;, and which would firmly resist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to do factor analysis, especially around the decision rule of when to stop generating underlying factors, and this choice obviously influences the results that follow. Warne and Burningham argue that they chose rules that are deemed the most accurate in these sorts of circumstances, and they ran the analysis with two versions of the decision rule for safety, but it’s worth noting that others may disagree and to remember that this study is a pre-print so it has not yet been subjected to peer review.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Warne and Burningham’s rules, between three quarters and four-fifths of the datasets immediately yielded just one factor that explained variability in participants’ performance across different tests. In other cases, two underlying factors emerged, but these were similar enough to also end up reducing to one factor in a second round of analysis, saving one single exception.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, reducing variation in test performance to a general factor in dataset after dataset doesn’t mean that it must be the same general factor for all datasets, but it’s an obvious explanation. More so when you note that, on average, the first factor extracted explained almost half of the variance in performance across different tests – very similar to the &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt; research in Western samples. Warne and Burningham state they “are astonished at the uniformity of these results” – given the wide variety of sample sizes, test content, and cultural locations.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds more evidence for &lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt;, which we know from previous research correlates with brain size, white matter tract integrity, genetic markers, and also seems to explain mental performance differences in other mammals, from primates to mice. The authors close by doubting whether we will ever solve the disagreement about what the culturally loaded term “intelligence” means worldwide. But we can still do the work to identify properties of the mind that are common to us all, and shape our ability to act in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/uv673/&quot;&gt;Spearman’s g Found in 31 Non-Western Nations: Strong Evidence that g is a Universal Phenomenon&lt;/a&gt; [this paper is a pre-print meaning that it has not yet been subjected to peer review]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Vaccine refusal is contagious</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/24/vaccine-refusal-contagious/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10138</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T08:26:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/iStock-490362470-e1524488762527-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of the current debate surrounding vaccination in the US centers on parental rights and whether parents should be compelled to vaccinate their children. Hesitancy towards vaccines is not a new phenomenon in the US or elsewhere around the world. Since vaccines were introduced, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.historyofvaccines.org/content/articles/history-anti-vaccination-movements&quot;&gt;there has been a subset of the population opposed to them (for a variety of reasons)&lt;/a&gt;. Modern vaccine hesitancy can likely be traced back to, at least partially, the now debunked research linking the Measles-Mumps-Rubella (MMR) vaccine with autism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there is no federal-level mechanism to compel vaccination, states are responsible for enacting and enforcing their own policies and regulations. Currently, all states except Mississippi, West Virginia, and California provide vaccine hesitant parents with an option to exempt their children from school-entry vaccine requirements for non-medical reasons. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/phlp/publications/topic/vaccinations.html&quot;&gt;Although the details and restrictiveness vary from state to state&lt;/a&gt;, non-medical exemptions can be obtained based on parents’ religious, personal, or philosophical beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A self-reinforcing process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this case the refusal of vaccines, operated in a manner similar to a contagious disease, geographically spreading from parent to parent or community to community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We examined how the use of non-medical exemptions changed over a 14-year period in California, a time in which non-medical exemption use more than quadrupled (to over 3% of all incoming kindergarteners in 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a health geographer, I was very interested in understanding whether vaccine-related behavior, in this case the refusal of vaccines, operated in a manner similar to a contagious disease, geographically spreading from parent to parent or community to community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We examined how the geographic patterns of non-medical exemption use evolved from 2000 to 2013, as there were no policy changes that would potentially affect parents’ behavior during this time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, we found evidence of a contagious-like process operating over this time period, as increases in the use of non-medical exemptions appeared to emanate from the initial high use regions over time. Furthermore, we observed that regions with the highest use of non-medical exemptions early in the study period also had the largest increases in use over this time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This second finding suggests that vaccine refusal is a self-reinforcing process, e.g., the more people that refuse vaccination in a region, the more acceptable it becomes. These findings are useful to better understand how vaccine refusal can progress from a behavior that is uncommon into one that is largely-accepted (and maybe even expected) in some communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eliminating non-medical exemptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the focus of our research, we did not examine the recent policy changes in California. The state implemented two new laws regarding non-medical exemptions after our study period. &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201120120AB2109&quot;&gt;AB2109&lt;/a&gt; was implemented prior to the 2014-15 school year, requiring parents to receive counseling from a health care provider prior to obtaining a non-medical exemption. &lt;a href=&quot;https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=201520160SB277&quot;&gt;SB277&lt;/a&gt; was implemented prior to the 2016-17 school year and eliminated the non-medical exemption provision entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While SB277 will ultimately increase vaccination rates in California’s schools, the law contained a “Grandfather clause” that allowed students already in school with a valid non-medical exemption to continue attending. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0277953616304336?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;This will ultimately delay the law’s intended effect&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, in the first year the law was in force, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2652640&quot;&gt;medical exemptions more than tripled in incoming kindergarteners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While California took the bold step of eliminating the non-medical exemption option, other states have yet to follow suit. With the use of non-medical exemptions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/66/wr/mm6640a3.htm&quot;&gt;continuing to rise in many states&lt;/a&gt;, we will likely continue to observe reports of vaccine-preventable disease outbreaks,  such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wral.com/whooping-cough-outbreak-impacts-chapel-hill-schools/17281082/&quot;&gt;whooping cough&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/news/best-states/kansas/articles/2018-04-17/measles-outbreak-that-started-in-kansas-day-care-grows-to-16&quot;&gt;measles&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hawaiinewsnow.com/story/37796779/mumps-outbreak-in-hawaii-nears-1000-cases&quot;&gt;mumps&lt;/a&gt; (and the list goes on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/24/vaccine-refusal-contagious/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vaccine refusal is contagious&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Paul L. Delamater</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Are mortality rates affected by age adoptees transfer to their adoptive families?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/24/mortality-rates-affected-age-adoptees-transfer-adoptive-families/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10106</id>
		<updated>2018-04-24T08:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/adoption-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous research has found that, compared with the general population, adoption is associated with increased rates of both all-cause mortality and of specific causes of death, such as infections, vascular disease and cancer as well as alcohol-related deaths and suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to explore long-term consequences of the age at transfer of adoptees into a new family, the authors of a study published today in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; have looked at mortality rates and cause-specific mortality rates in 10,592 Danish adoptees according to age at transfer. The researchers, based at Aarhus University and the University of Copenhagen, also set out to assess if the social class of the adoptive family modified the effects of age at transfer to the adoptive family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortality rates among adoptees were compared according to the age at which the adoptee was transferred to the adoptive family, using those who were transferred immediately after birth as a reference. For the purpose of this study, the social class of the adoptive family was based on occupation of the fathers, and was available from the adoption records for 96% of the adoptive fathers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that death rates from all causes were significantly higher in those transferred between age 1 month and 4 years compared to those transferred immediately after birth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the main analyses, adoptees were divided into six groups according to their age at the time of transfer to the adoptive parents: 0 months, 1-5 months, 6-11 months, 12-23 months, 2-3 years, and 4-7 years. The social class of the adoptive family was considered a factor potentially modifying the effects of age at transfer and was categorized into high and low social class. High social class included advanced professional, academic and sub-academic professions and self-employed, while low social class included subordinate clerks, skilled workers, semi-skilled workers, and unskilled workers. In the analyses including the potential modifying effect of paternal social class, age at transfer was reduced to four categories: 0 months, 1-5 months, 6-23 months, and 2-7 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that death rates from all causes were significantly higher in those transferred between age 1 month and 4 years compared to those transferred immediately after birth with the relative rate peaking for those transferred between 6 and 11 months. Death rates from natural causes were higher in those transferred between 1 month to 2 years of age. The later the age of transfer, the higher the rate of suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, transfer into an adoptive family later than at time of birth may have long-term consequences affecting overall and cause-specific mortality. These effects were, to the researchers’ surprise, not modified by the environment provided by the adoptive family as indicated by the social class of these families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the study is observational with limited information at baseline, it is of course difficult to make counterfactual inferences about what would have happened to the children if they had not been adopted away and transferred to the adoptive family at a certain age. The conclusions from the study are based only on the comparisons of adoptees with different ages at transfer to the adoptive families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/24/mortality-rates-affected-age-adoptees-transfer-adoptive-families/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Are mortality rates affected by age adoptees transfer to their adoptive families?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Natalie Pafitis</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Young galaxies are flat, but old ones are more blobby</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/young-galaxies-are-flat-old-ones-are-more-blobby"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/young-galaxies-are-flat-old-ones-are-more-blobby</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A survey of hundreds of star systems precisely links the shape of a galaxy to the ages of its stars.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T23:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Uranus smells like rotten eggs</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/uranus-smells-rotten-eggs"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/uranus-smells-rotten-eggs</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Planetary scientists detected hydrogen sulfide in Uranus’ upper clouds — the same compound that gives rotten eggs their terrible smell.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Flawed climate science paper “exposed potential weaknesses” in the peer review process</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/23/flawed-climate-science-paper-exposed-potential-weaknesses-in-peer-review-process/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64459</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T12:00:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this new post, a question: Do you enjoy reading Retraction Watch? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support our work? Thanks in advance. How did a deeply flawed paper, which contradicts mainstream science on climate change, pass peer review? That is what three editorial … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/23/flawed-climate-science-paper-exposed-potential-weaknesses-in-peer-review-process/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Flawed climate science paper “exposed potential weaknesses” in the peer review process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Informed wisdom trumps rigid rules when it comes to medical evidence</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/informed-wisdom-trumps-rigid-rules-when-it-comes-medical-evidence"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/informed-wisdom-trumps-rigid-rules-when-it-comes-medical-evidence</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Narrative reviews of medical evidence offer benefits that the supposedly superior systematic approach can’t.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are tweets a goldmine for psychologists or just a lot of noise? Researchers clash over the meaning of social media data</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/23/are-tweets-a-goldmine-for-psychologists-or-just-a-lot-of-noise-researchers-clash-over-the-meaning-of-social-media-data/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33742</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T08:32:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-500668390.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33743&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33743&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Illustration of a pink brain with a hash tag&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Blablo101&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Brain icon with a hash tag&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Brain icon with a hash tag&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-500668390.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-500668390.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-500668390.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/23/are-tweets-a-goldmine-for-psychologists-or-just-a-lot-of-noise-researchers-clash-over-the-meaning-of-social-media-data/brain-icon-with-a-hash-tag/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-500668390.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drbrocktagon.com/science-writing/&quot;&gt;Jon Brock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johannes Eichstaedt was sitting in a coffee shop by Lake Atitlan in Guatemala when he received a slack about a tweet about a preprint. In 2015, the University of Pennsylvania psychologist and his colleagues published a headline-grabbing &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797614557867&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; linking heart disease to the language used on Twitter. They’d found that tweets emanating from US counties with high rates of heart disease mortality tended to exhibit high levels of negative emotions such as anger, anxiety, disengagement, aggression, and hate. The study, published in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science,&lt;/i&gt; has proven influential, already accruing over 170 citations. But three years later, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/dursw/&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt; authors Nick Brown and James Coyne from the University of Groningen claimed to have identified “numerous conceptual and methodological limitations”. Within the month, Eichstaedt and his colleagues issued a riposte, publishing their own &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/p75ku/&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt; that claims &lt;i&gt;further&lt;/i&gt; evidence to support their original conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As recent revelations surrounding Facebook and Cambridge Analytica have highlighted, corporations and political organisations attach a high value to social media data. But, Eichstaedt &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/using-social-media-to-assess-health-from-afar/&quot;&gt;argues&lt;/a&gt;, that same data also offers rich insights into psychological health and well-being. With appropriate ethical oversight, social media analytics could promote population health and perhaps even save lives. That at least is its promise. But with big data come new challenges – as Eichstaedt’s “debate” with Brown and Coyne illustrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33742&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early 2015, Nick Brown was discharged from hospital. Getting his teeth into Eichstaedt’s paper was, as he put it, “my way of picking myself up.” In recent years, Brown has developed a reputation for uncovering irregularities in published research. His investigations into the work of Cornell food scientist Brian Wansink have contributed (at the time of writing) to &lt;a href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/19/caught-our-notice-retraction-eight-as-errors-in-wansink-paper-are-too-voluminous-for-a-correction/&quot;&gt;8 retractions and 15 corrections&lt;/a&gt;. But, as Brown stresses, the discussion of Eichstaedt’s paper is very different. His concern is simply that the study has been oversold. “People who might be thinking of using social media for public health need to be aware of the counter arguments,” Brown says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central claim in Eichstaedt’s 2015 paper is that Twitter data can provide new information about heart disease that is not available from other measures. The analysis began with 148 million tweets, written between 2009 and 2010 and geo-tagged to US counties based on the tweeter’s user profile. Each tweet was scored according to multiple emotion “variables” by comparing its constituent words against pre-specified lists of words related to that emotion. Information from a subset of counties was then fed into a machine-learning algorithm – a computer program that worked out the combination of Twitter variables providing the closest fit to the heart disease data. When tested on the remaining counties, the Twitter model predicted heart disease rates more accurately than did similar models based on conventional measures such as a county’s racial demographics, the income and education levels of its residents, and rates of smoking and obesity. This, according to the accompanying &lt;a href=&quot;https://penntoday.upenn.edu/news/twitter-can-predict-rates-coronary-heart-disease-according-penn-research&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;, shows that “tweets are aggregating information about people that can’t be readily accessed in other ways.” Twitter analysis “could be used to marshal evidence of the effectiveness of public-health interventions on the community”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown, however, is sceptical. His preprint lists numerous sources of bias and noise that would make it hard to find a genuine heart disease signal in the Twitter noise. Words can have multiple meanings depending on the context. Twitter data are unrepresentative of the population – and users who tag their locations may not represent the wider Twitter user base. In counties with small populations, the data may be dominated by a small number of prolific users. And tweets with certain racial terms – often used in a hostile fashion – appear to have been censored by Twitter prior to their release to researchers. There is noise too in the health records – autopsies are rarely carried out to establish cause of death and so variation in reported heart disease rates partly reflect variation in reporting practices. &lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For his part, Eichstaedt acknowledges that the data are noisy and in some ways biased. But, he says, the salient point is that they still found a signal. And their preprint responding to Brown and Coyne includes a new analysis of a larger and more recent sample of Twitter data, which again outperforms a model based on traditional demographic measures.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Perhaps there is a signal,” Brown acknowledges. “But there’s an awful lot of wrongness.” And, he adds, the fact that Twitter predicts heart disease better than other measures is “in some way irrelevant” because the best predictor of a community’s future heart disease rate is its current heart disease rate. This, Eichstaedt says, is “trivially true” for most outcomes with complex underlying causes. But prediction in itself was not the goal. “We are trying to use Twitter as a source of epidemiological insight,” he says. The first step is to show that there is a signal. The next step is to work out what it means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When his paper was published in 2015, Eichstaedt’s findings made &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeichstaedt.com/heart-disease-press/&quot;&gt;headlines&lt;/a&gt; around the world. “Angry Tweeting could increase your risk of heart disease” said the UK’s Telegraph. CBS News led with “Cheerful tweets may mean a healthier heart”. The association between Twitter language and heart disease has an intuitive appeal. As Brown notes, it speaks to the notion of a “Type A” personality – permanently uptight, angry at the world, and (according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3477961/&quot;&gt;controversial&lt;/a&gt; research) more prone to heart disease. But in their paper, Eichstaedt and colleagues were clear.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;“Obviously the people tweeting are not the people dying,” they wrote. Instead, they suggested, the sentiments expressed in tweets may reflect characteristics of the communities to which tweeters and heart disease sufferers belong – their “shared economic, physical, and psychological environment”.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown describes this as “pure speculation”. But it’s a testable idea. If Twitter language really does measure the psychological profile of a community then it should predict mental health even better than it predicts physical health. Adapting Eichstaedt’s methods, Brown and Coyne used Twitter language to try and predict deaths from suicide instead of heart disease. They found significant correlations but in the “wrong” direction. Counties with higher rates of suicide had relatively fewer tweets containing anger, negative emotions and negative relationships and more tweets about nature, romantic love, and positive social relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eichstaedt, however, is unperturbed by this finding. “Suicide is a weird variable,” he says. It’s much rarer than heart disease or cancer, for example, and rates are typically much higher in rural communities, perhaps due to social isolation and higher rates of gun ownership. In their response to Brown and Coyne, Eichstaedt and his team report that a county’s suicide rate correlates with its altitude above sea level and the percentage of people living in rural areas. When they controlled for these two measures, the correlations between suicide and Twitter language disappeared.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better direct measure of community mental health, Eichstaedt argues, is a survey report of “mentally unhealthy days”, which he and his colleagues have found to correlate with Twitter language in the expected direction. In fact, Eichstaedt notes, the pattern is very similar to that for heart disease. The question then is whether Twitter data can distinguish between heart disease and other conditions. Or does it reflect some underlying factor that relates to most diseases?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;“The jury is still out on this,” Eichstaedt admits. “We haven’t cracked that nut.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For psychology researchers, often criticised for their small sample sizes and the questionable relevance of their studies to everyday life, the appeal of social media data is obvious. But the price of big data is a loss of experimental control and the ability to tease apart cause and effect. There’s also a loss of transparency. The complex analytic procedures represent a serious challenge for psychologists attempting to understand and evaluate a study. “It becomes,” says Brown, “a question of do I trust your software?”&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eichstaedt, a physicist by training, is sympathetic to this view. “When you get super fancy and the reviewers can’t follow you any more and have to take you on faith, that’s problematic,” he says. “It’s hacking science.” The solution, Brown argues, may be to move away from traditional journals and peer review. “It has to become some sort of ongoing process,” he says. In a “better world” Eichstaedt’s paper would itself have been posted as a preprint and Brown’s critique could have been part of the post-publication review process. This scenario is similar to the approach adopted in physics where preprints and responses have long been the mainstay of scientific communication.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it’s clear that a similar culture shift in psychology will come with its own teething troubles and questions of etiquette. In Brown’s view, the original Eichstaedt paper was badged as “open science” so there should have been no need to seek further information from the authors. He decided not to contact them as a matter of principle. Eichstaedt, however, notes that a more collaborative approach would have allowed him to quickly address some misconceptions about the research and direct Brown and Coyne to analysis code that wasn’t available at the time of publication. “I think that would have been a much less painful way of getting to the same point”. Still, the exchange has provided an opportunity for his team to clarify some issues and make it easier for anyone in the field to replicate and adapt their analyses. “Probably an older wiser version of me will only see that positive side,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797614557867&quot;&gt;Psychological Language on Twitter Predicts County-Level Heart Disease Mortality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/dursw/&quot;&gt;No Evidence That Twitter Language Reliably Predicts Heart Disease: A Reanalysis of Eichstaedt et al. (2015a)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/p75ku/&quot;&gt;More Evidence that Twitter Language Predicts Heart Disease: A Response and Replication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;9okZiAV4_400x400&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-33745&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33745&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;9okZiAV4_400x400&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/9okziav4_400x400.jpg?w=400&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/9okziav4_400x400.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/9okziav4_400x400.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;400,400&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/23/are-tweets-a-goldmine-for-psychologists-or-just-a-lot-of-noise-researchers-clash-over-the-meaning-of-social-media-data/9okziav4_400x400/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/9okziav4_400x400.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://drbrocktagon.com/science-writing/&quot;&gt;Dr Jon Brock&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DrBrocktagon&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@drbrocktagon&lt;/a&gt;) for BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Jon is a Sydney-based science writer specialising in psychology and neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Medical knowledge doubles every few months; how can clinicians keep up?</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/medical-knowledge-doubles-every-few-months-how-can-clinicians-keep-up"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/medical-knowledge-doubles-every-few-months-how-can-clinicians-keep-up</id>
		<updated>2018-04-23T08:11:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A smart clinical search engine helps staff at Blackpool Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust access the latest information</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">We're Good At Recognizing Distorted Faces</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9485"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9485</id>
		<updated>2018-04-22T15:06:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new paper from MIT neuroscientists Sharon Gilad-Gutnick and colleagues reveals that we are remarkably good at recognizing faces even if they are highly distorted. Not only is this scientifically interesting, the deformed images used in this study are rather hilarious.



Here's an example of a face being distorted by horizontal and vertical compression (also known as thinning and flattening). The unfortunate victim of these distortions is Bill Clinton:



Gilad-Gutnick et al. found tha</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: A new publishing scam; reproducibility as a political weapon; prosecuting predatory publishers</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/21/weekend-reads-a-new-publishing-scam-reproducibility-as-a-political-weapon-prosecuting-predatory-publishers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64487</id>
		<updated>2018-04-21T13:23:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a neither-correction-nor-retraction that made no one happy, a debate over … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/21/weekend-reads-a-new-publishing-scam-reproducibility-as-a-political-weapon-prosecuting-predatory-publishers/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A new publishing scam; reproducibility as a political weapon; prosecuting predatory publishers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cicadas on different schedules can hybridize</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/cicadas-different-schedules-can-hybridize"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/cicadas-different-schedules-can-hybridize</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T21:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new genetic study suggests that cicadas that emerge every 17 years have swapped genetic material with those that emerge every 13 years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Attention to metabolic energy disturbance is needed to treat relapse of heroin</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/20/attention-to-metabolic-energy-disturbance-is-needed-to-treat-relapse-of-heroin/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10089</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T20:46:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;Heroin_powder&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/Heroin_powder-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animal models of addiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several animal models are used to study drug dependence in which self-administration has obvious advantages. The first benefit of self-administration is that it provides the most direct point-to-point correspondence with addictive behaviors that are found in people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical self-administration procedure in animals includes acquisition, extinction / abstinence and reinforcement. During the acquisition stage, animals undergo operant conditioning and learn to perform one action, typically a lever press, in order to receive a drug. Once a specific criterion is obtained, animals are regarded as addicted to a drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10091&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10091 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/Rat-self-adminsitration-300x206.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Rat self-administration chamber with catheter implanted in the jugular vein&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Picture provided with permission by Zhang Fuqiang from Ningbo Institute of Drug Treatment&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intravenous administration via catheterization is an optimal method for self-administration in that it maximizes drug bioavailability and has rapid onset. Humans suffering from addiction often resort to intravenous drug use for similar reasons. This parallel provides further benefits of this route of administration in animal studies in that it increases the validity of the self-administration methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After acquisition, animals are returned to their home cage and resume normal living conditions. This process is similar to people undergoing abstinence in that they can’t acquire drugs while carrying out their everyday lives. In animal models, after 14 days of abstinence, reinforcement is induced by either administration of the drug or returning the animal to an environment associated with the drug. Both of these events are analogous to events that can trigger relapse in human drug abusers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relapse and metabolomics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study published in&lt;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcneurosci.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, we set up an intravenous, heroin self-administration rat model and collected a serum sample during the reinforcement stage. As we want to get a complete picture that could reflect the status of this stage, we tried nuclear magnetic resonance based metabolomics analysis. Specifically, metabolomics is the “systematic study of the unique chemical fingerprints that specific cellular processes leave behind”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, metabolomics is the “systematic study of the unique chemical fingerprints that specific cellular processes leave behind”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results revealed that energy metabolism was greatly disturbed. An increase in glucose and decrease in intermediates of glycolysis and the TCA cycle indicate impairment in essential pathways for energy production. The finding that there was an increase in levels of 3-hydroxybutyrate and acetoacetate suggest that energy production was activated from fatty acids. These types of changes in fatty acids have been correlated with relapse and potential neurological dysfunctions associated with Alzheimer’s disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly phenylalanine, glutamine, and choline increased greatly. These molecules are precursors of the neurotransmitters γ-aminobutyric acid/glutamate, acetylcholine, and dopamine respectively. These neurotransmitters play an important role in learning and reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that when animals are re-exposed to a drug or a drug-associated environment the “happy memory” of the drug experience is awakened, and the compulsive drug seeking behavior reappears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that when animals are re-exposed to a drug or a drug-associated environment the “happy memory” of the drug experience is awakened, and the compulsive drug seeking behavior reappears. During this process, the increase of these three precursors of neurotransmitters in the circulatory system could partly explain why the motivation of drug seeking is so strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ultimate goal is to develop new therapies for drug addiction. The most challenging component is reducing the incidence of relapse. Although we don’t know whether the same changes would happen in humans with opiate addiction, the results found in our study remind us that more attention should be paid to the restoration of energy metabolism in addition to the neurotransmitters which have already received great concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/20/attention-to-metabolic-energy-disturbance-is-needed-to-treat-relapse-of-heroin/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Attention to metabolic energy disturbance is needed to treat relapse of heroin&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr Tingting Ning</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Closing the gender gap in some science fields may take over 100 years</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/closing-gender-gap-some-science-fields-may-take-over-100-years"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/closing-gender-gap-some-science-fields-may-take-over-100-years</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T17:19:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In some STEM fields, the gender gap won’t disappear for decades or even centuries, a new study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kyle Plantz</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_023308560808464107=0.9262053233637899</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T11:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">That study reporting worrisome levels of zinc in tuna? It’s being retracted</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/20/that-study-reporting-worrisome-levels-of-zinc-in-tuna-its-being-retracted/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64447</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T15:16:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Recently, a rash of news outlets posted concerns that canned tuna and other products may contain potentially dangerous levels of zinc. They were all wrong. News outlets such as The Daily Mail and The Sun reported findings from a recent study, which showed that canned foods such as tuna may contain 100 times the daily limit … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/20/that-study-reporting-worrisome-levels-of-zinc-in-tuna-its-being-retracted/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;That study reporting worrisome levels of zinc in tuna? It’s being retracted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Heat waves are roasting reefs, but some corals may be resilient</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heat-waves-are-roasting-reefs-some-corals-may-be-resilient"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heat-waves-are-roasting-reefs-some-corals-may-be-resilient</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T15:07:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The latest research on coral reefs clarifies the devastation of heat waves and looks at how coral might be able to adapt to warming waters.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_023308560808464107=0.9262053233637899</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T11:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Hans Asperger and the Nazis</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9479"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9479</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T14:04:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Big news this week as Hans Asperger, autism pioneer and namesake of Asperger's syndrome, is accused of having collaborated in the murder of children during the Nazi rule in Austria. The accusations come in the form of a long paper by historian Herwig Czech in the journal Molecular Autism.



Czech presents an analysis of Asperger's activities as head of the Heilpädagogik Ward of the Pediatric Clinic at the University of Vienna, from 1935 to 1943. Here, Asperger was responsible for the evalua</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">After issuing dozens of corrections to high-profile book, historian shuts down his blog</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/20/after-issuing-dozens-of-corrections-to-high-profile-book-historian-shuts-down-his-blog/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64402</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T12:00:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A historian has shuttered his personal blog, which he created to respond to critics of his high-profile book. Columbia University professor Charles Armstrong launched the blog in order to address the criticisms of his book about North Korea during the Cold War. Soon after Tyranny of the Weak appeared, Balazs Szalontai of Korea University uploaded … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/20/after-issuing-dozens-of-corrections-to-high-profile-book-historian-shuts-down-his-blog/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;After issuing dozens of corrections to high-profile book, historian shuts down his blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-30T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Celebrity names now mark places on Pluto’s moon Charon</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/celebrity-names-now-mark-places-pluto-moon-charon"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/celebrity-names-now-mark-places-pluto-moon-charon</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T11:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Pluto’s largest moon, Charon, now has 12 new names for its topological features.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">What can brain research offer people who stutter?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/540506444/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=137698</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T10:30:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;There’s something compelling about watching a person who stutters find a way to experience fluent speech. British TV viewers witnessed such a moment on Educating Yorkshire, back in 2013. When teenager &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A5Cm1-Qhs6U&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Musharaf Asghar&lt;/a&gt; listened to music through headphones during preparations for a speaking exam, he found that his words began to flow. Singers, like Mark Asari who is currently competing on &lt;em&gt;The Voice UK&lt;/em&gt;, also demonstrate how using the voice in song, rather than speech, can result in striking fluency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a range of techniques can temporarily enhance how fluently a person who stutters can speak. Changing auditory feedback by delaying it, or “drowning” it out with music, or altering habitual speaking patterns by singing, or speaking in time with a metronome, often results in an immediate increase in fluency. However, the effect disappears as soon these alterations are removed. Although the underlying mechanism isn’t completely understood, these effects indicate that people who stutter may show brain differences in how the signals guiding speech movements are integrated with feedback on the sound and feel of speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain imaging studies of adults who stutter do reveal differences in both the structure and the function of the circuits involved in speech production. For example, a number of studies show that the bundle of nerve fibers connecting the sensory and motor brain areas involved in speech production is less organized in people who stutter. This could affect communication between these brain areas, causing speech disfluency. There are also differences in the patterns of brain activity we see when people who stutter speak in the MRI scanner. An area in the left frontal part of the brain – an important hub in the circuit that plans and executes speech – is less active in people who stutter than in people who don’t. The equivalent area on the right side is often &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; active in people who stutter. We think this pattern of increased activity on the right could make up for the lack of activity on the left, but it might also reflect the stuttering process itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how can information about the brain differences in people who stutter be used? When discussing our research with people who stutter, and others with an interest in this area, it’s become clear that just knowing about these findings can help. The cause of stuttering has been debated for many years, and a “nervous personality” has erroneously been offered as a likely explanation. Another unhelpful belief is that it’s possible to “grow” or “snap” out of this way of speaking. So, being able to point to a neurological difference located in brain regions controlling speech, can be a welcome reassurance that such myths have no basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; style=&quot;width: 496px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;381&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/DVbk3hiyilI.jpg&quot; width=&quot;496&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit: An intervention session of the tDCS randomized controlled trial. Used with permission. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advances in neuroscience mean that brain imaging findings can now inform non-invasive brain stimulation studies aimed at increasing speech fluency. As speech therapy outcomes for adults who stutter can be limited, our team recently completed the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://academic.oup.com/brain/advance-article/doi/10.1093/brain/awy011/4831242&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;randomized controlled trial&lt;/a&gt; investigating whether transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS&lt;u&gt;)&lt;/u&gt; could be usefully applied in therapy. TDCS involves passing a very weak electrical current across two surface electrodes placed on the scalp, and through the underlying brain tissue. This changes the excitability of the targeted brain area. When it’s paired with a task, the change in brain excitability from the tDCS can interact with task-related brain activity, resulting in improved performance and learning. The parameters for safe, painless application of tDCS have been established from large body of research studies, and the equipment is portable, and relatively affordable. For these reasons tDCS has attracted interest as a therapeutic tool for conditions that affect how the brain functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used two temporary fluency-enhancing techniques: reading along with another person, and speaking in time with a metronome. In combination with this, we applied tDCS over the left inferior frontal cortex – the key area for planning and executing speech movements which is relatively less active in people who stutter. We were interested in whether pairing tDCS with the tasks, practiced in 5 daily sessions, would increase speech fluency after the intervention was completed. Thirty adult men who stutter were randomly assigned to real tDCS or an indistinguishable “sham,” or placebo, tDCS. The group receiving real tDCS showed persistent improvement in their speech fluency six weeks following the intervention, compared to the group receiving sham. TDCS reduced stuttering symptoms by around 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results show that tDCS is certainly a promising approach for fluency intervention, and we are continuing to study it’s use. However, the relationship between the fluency of our speech and our perception of ourselves as speakers is far from straight-forward. For this reason, increasing speech fluency may not necessarily give a person who stutters a useful therapy outcome. In fact sometimes feeling you are “chasing fluency” can be a particularly negative experience. For example, living with a covert stutter involves avoiding any possibility of stuttering, with the constant fear that a moment of disfluency might slip through. Overtly, speech appears completely fluent, but the burden to the person who stutters to maintain this illusion is huge. Speech and Language Therapy in the United Kingdom for adults who stutter is varied so that all experiences of stuttering can be addressed. Therapy may include approaches to increase fluency, to stutter with less struggle, or to build more positive thoughts and beliefs about living with a stutter. Some combination of these approaches often yields the best outcome for any one person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; style=&quot;width: 454px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;269&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/DVbj7DPkBRA.png&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit: Design of the tDCS randomized controlled trial intervention. Used with permission. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, some people who stutter choose no therapy at all. An approach that is universally beneficial for educating us all about stuttering, and supporting those of us who have this condition, is to acknowledge the strength, resilience, and considerable talents of people who stutter. Five years on from the first airing of Educating Yorkshire, &lt;u&gt;Musharaf Asghar&lt;/u&gt; is now a motivational speaker. He is an inspiration, not because his stutter has disappeared from his speech (it hasn’t), but because he speaks with confidence about his experiences of living with a stutter, as one facet of who he is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the brain differences that are associated with stuttering, and using this knowledge to shape and improve interventions, is one of the many ways that we can support people who stutter to live the life they choose. If a person who stutters chooses to work on their speech fluency, non-invasive brain stimulation could allow us to give them the best possible outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Brain by GR_Image. CC0 via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://pixabay.com/en/brain-mrt-magnetic-resonance-imaging-1728449/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/brain-research-offer-people-stutter/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What can brain research offer people who stutter?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/540506444/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/540506444/oupblogpsychology,https%3a%2f%2fblog.oup.com%2fwp-content%2fuploads%2f2018%2f04%2fDVbk3hiyilI.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/540506444/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/03/brain-tumour-awareness/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Brain tumour awareness: The end counts too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/chronic-pain-management/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;We can predict rain but can’t yet predict chronic pain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/04/modernization-of-mortuary-practice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Modernization of mortuary practice and grief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kimberly Ilkowski</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Our brains rapidly and automatically process opinions we agree with as if they are facts</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/20/our-brains-rapidly-and-automatically-process-opinions-we-agree-with-as-if-they-are-facts/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33727</id>
		<updated>2018-04-20T07:03:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-583690890.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33732&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33732&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector illustration of pastel color smile brain with glasses lifts thump up on blue background. Thumb up brain concept.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;OnBlast&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector illustration of pastel color smile pink brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Vector illustration of pastel color smile pink brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-583690890.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-583690890.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-583690890.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/20/our-brains-rapidly-and-automatically-process-opinions-we-agree-with-as-if-they-are-facts/vector-illustration-of-pastel-color-smile-pink-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-583690890.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a post-truth world of alternative facts, there is understandable interest in the psychology behind why people are generally so wedded to their opinions and why it is so difficult to change minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already know a lot about the deliberate mental processes that people engage in to protect their world view, from seeking out confirmatory evidence (the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/20/5-reasons-its-so-hard-to-think-like-a-scientist/&quot;&gt;confirmation bias&lt;/a&gt;“) to questioning the methods used to marshal contradictory evidence (the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2010/10/27/five-minutes-with-the-discoverer-of-the-scientific-impotence-excuse-geoffrey-munro/&quot;&gt;scientific impotence excuse&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a team led by Anat Maril at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1948550618762300&quot;&gt;report in &lt;em&gt;Social Psychological and Personality Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that they have found evidence of rapid and involuntarily mental processes that kick-in whenever we encounter opinions we agree with, similar to the processes previously described for how we respond to basic facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers write that “their demonstration of such a knee-jerk acceptance of opinions may help explain people’s remarkable ability to remain entrenched in their convictions”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33727&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background to this involves something you’ve probably heard of, the Stroop Effect – how we’re slower to name the ink colour of colour-denoting words when the word meaning doesn’t match the ink, like RED written in blue ink. The Stroop Effect occurs because our brains rapidly and involuntarily process the colour meaning of the word, which interferes with our processing of the ink colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back, psychologists showed there’s a similar phenomenon for facts (they called it the “Epistemic Stroop Effect”) – we’re quicker to verify that factual, than non-factual, statements are spelled correctly, suggesting that our rapid discernment of factual accuracy interacts with our judgment about spelling (even though the factual accuracy of the statements is irrelevant to the spelling task).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, across four studies, Maril and her team have found that something similar occurs for opinions. They composed 88 opinion statements, written in Hebrew, that covered politics, personal tastes and social issues, such as “The internet has made people more isolated” or “The internet has made people more sociable”. They presented dozens of  Israeli participants with versions of these statements that were grammatical or not (e.g. the gender or use of singular/plural were incorrect) and the participants’ task was to indicate as rapidly as possible whether the grammar was correct. Later, the participants were shown all the statements again and asked to indicate whether they agreed with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key finding was that participants were quicker to identify statements as grammatically correct when they agreed with the opinion expressed in the statement, compared with when they disagreed (there was no difference for time taken to identify ungrammatical statements as ungrammatical). This was the case even though their agreement with the opinion expressed in the statements was irrelevant to the grammatical task at hand. “The results demonstrate that agreement with a stated opinion can have a rapid and involuntary effect on its cognitive processing,” the researchers said, which is similar to the epistemic Stroop Effect observed for facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their final study, the researchers created a variation of the task that required participants to indicate whether statements (e.g. “coriander is tasty” or “coriander is disgusting”) indicated something positive or negative. For statements that they agreed with, participants were faster to answer “yes”, whether they were identifying that the statement was positive or identifying that it was negative. The researchers said this confirms that we have a rapid, involuntary cognitive bias is for answering in the affirmative to semantic questions about opinion statements that we agree with (ruling out effects of fluency or unfamiliarity that might have confounded the results for judging the grammar of statements in the earlier studies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The current findings suggest that despite adults’ understanding of the notion of subjectivity, they may react to opinion-incongruent statements as if they were factually incorrect,” the researchers said, adding, “The distinction between factual truths and opinions held to be true is pivotal for rational discourse. However this distinction may apparently be somewhat murky within human psychology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generally they said their paradigm provided “an addition to the social psychologists’ tool kit” that could be used as a new way to explore implicitly held opinions (providing an alternative to the implicit association test, for example). Further research could also explore whether the effect described here is moderated by factors like stress or peer pressure, or individual characteristics like one’s political leanings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1948550618762300&quot;&gt;That’s My Truth: Evidence for Involuntary Opinion Confirmation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Larger spleens may help ‘sea nomads’ stay underwater longer</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/larger-spleens-help-bajau-divers-stay-underwater-longer"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/larger-spleens-help-bajau-divers-stay-underwater-longer</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T19:04:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Bajau people of Southeast Asia have a gene variant associated with larger spleens, boosting their oxygen while breath-hold diving, researchers say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rising CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; levels might not be as good for plants as we thought</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-co2-levels-might-not-be-good-plants-we-thought"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-co2-levels-might-not-be-good-plants-we-thought</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A 20-year experiment spots a reversal in the way two kinds of plants take up extra carbon from the atmosphere.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erika Engelhaupt</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">One Small Step for Preprints, One Giant Step Forward for Open Scientific Communications</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/Te2WxXHVtek/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8160</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T17:39:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/04/preprint-moon-landing_4-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to our recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/02/plos-cold-spring-harbor-preprint-agreement-biorxiv/&quot;&gt;partnership&lt;/a&gt; with bioRxiv, PLOS authors will have the choice of posting their submitted manuscript on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bioRxiv preprint server&lt;/a&gt; on May 1st. Preprints enable authors to accelerate the dissemination of their work and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1001563&quot;&gt;invite commentary&lt;/a&gt; by a broader community, which PLOS editors will evaluate as part of peer review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posting your work &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; formal peer review has other significant advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can stake an intellectual claim to methods, results and ideas contained within that paper, while obtaining citations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your work can be discovered. Many journals, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006448&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, use preprint servers to identify and solicit manuscripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early posting can lead to collaborations by fostering connections with researchers in different disciplines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not convinced of the value of the preprint and its role in accelerating scientific communication? There are a lot of resources on this topic. Here’s a sampling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005473&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘&lt;/strong&gt;Ten Simple Rules&lt;strong&gt;’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a straightforward synthesis of key questions to consider regarding preprint submission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our friends at ASAPbio have led the life science community in conversation &lt;a href=&quot;http://asapbio.org/preprint-info/preprint-stories&quot;&gt;about &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; scientists should consider participating&lt;/a&gt; in preprints and &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to consider when they do participate. Visit their site for &lt;a href=&quot;http://asapbio.org/preprint-info&quot;&gt;a detailed breakdown of the benefits of preprints&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wondering how &lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt; will proceed with preprints? Read this editorial by our Chief Editor on &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1002563&quot;&gt;Progress and Principles.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tired of reading? Watch ‘What is a Preprint’ on YouTube:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS is committed to putting your science first. Please send any questions, concerns or delights that you have regarding preprints to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:preprints@plos.org&quot;&gt;preprints@plos.org&lt;/a&gt; following our launch on May 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;. Publish with PLOS and post your preprint on bioRxiv and let’s keep science open and accessible, together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/Te2WxXHVtek&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Male fruit flies enjoy ejaculation</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/male-fruit-flies-enjoy-ejaculation"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/male-fruit-flies-enjoy-ejaculation</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Red light exposure made some genetically engineered fruit flies ejaculate, spurring a surge of a brain reward compound — and less desire for booze.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T23:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Political science has a #metoo moment</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/19/political-science-has-a-metoo-moment/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64376</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T15:08:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Many political scientists are up in arms over an editor’s decision to use his journal as a platform to defend himself from allegations of sexual harassment. The editor, William Jacoby of Michigan State University, has since removed a statement denying the allegations from the American Journal of Political Science (AJPS), and posted an apology. Midwest … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/19/political-science-has-a-metoo-moment/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Political science has a #metoo moment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">New thematic series: Veterinary antimicrobial resistance and antimicrobial use</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/19/new-thematic-series-veterinary-antimicrobial-resistance-and-antimicrobial-use/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10126</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T13:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/feature-image-e1524144448921-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-10129&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/feature-image.png&quot; width=&quot;737&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antimicrobials are integral to current medicine, both veterinary and human, towards the treatment of zoonotic and infectious diseases. Unfortunately, inappropriate antimicrobial use (AMU) often renders them ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain the well-being of both companion and food animals, all existing antimicrobial types, along with the development of new ones, need to be continuously accessible. This must be achieved with the concurrent introduction of official legislation and guidelines on the responsible use of antimicrobials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the globe, medical doctors and veterinary practitioners share serious concerns over the public health implications from the misuse of antimicrobials and the development of antimicrobial resistance (AMR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bva.co.uk/&quot;&gt;British Veterinary Association&lt;/a&gt; (BVA) has issued&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bva.co.uk/uploadedFiles/Content/News,_campaigns_and_policies/Policies/Medicines/responsible-use-of-antimicrobials-in-veterinary-practice.pdf&quot;&gt; guidance&lt;/a&gt; on the responsible use of antimicrobials, which can be summarized in the phrase ‘Correct antimicrobial: as little as possible, as much as necessary’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concerns have resulted in a very elevated profile for AMR in the past couple of years, a fact expressly evident by the production of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/antimicrobial-resistance/global-action-plan/en/&quot;&gt;Global Action Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance&lt;/a&gt; in 2015, developed by the World Health Organization (WHO) in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oie.int/&quot;&gt;World Organisation for Animal Health&lt;/a&gt; (OIE) and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/home/en/&quot;&gt;UN Food and Agriculture Organisation&lt;/a&gt; (FAO), that will combat AMR through a one-health approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year later, at the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/antimicrobial-resistance/events/UNGA-meeting-amr-sept2016/en/&quot;&gt; 71st General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; of the United Nations (UN), the focus remained on constructing an international agenda to manage AMR. April 2017 saw the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldvet.org/index.php&quot;&gt; World Veterinary Association&lt;/a&gt; (WVA) issuing its&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldvet.org/uploads/docs/wva_position_on_the_use_of_antimicrobials.pdf&quot;&gt; official position&lt;/a&gt; on the use of antimicrobials. The purpose of this initiative was to limit the prevalence and development of AMR from the misuse of antimicrobials. In a similar initiative, the&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bva.co.uk/&quot;&gt; British Veterinary Association&lt;/a&gt; (BVA) has issued&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bva.co.uk/uploadedFiles/Content/News,_campaigns_and_policies/Policies/Medicines/responsible-use-of-antimicrobials-in-veterinary-practice.pdf&quot;&gt; guidance&lt;/a&gt; on the responsible use of antimicrobials, which can be summarized in the phrase ‘Correct antimicrobial: as little as possible, as much as necessary’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10128&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10128 size-large&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/2949148067_8e1502c9f8_b-1024x683.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/clownhousethethird/2949148067/in/photolist-5uB9Yt-HkC8Kw-fexs3v-5uFwMU-VT4xYQ-5uFvSW-5jSJTV-ej1T2G-c3LoSN-5uFyWj-5uBbqK-beYJdx-fjetgq-6FNuC8-5xmAXr-2nw1f7-88ahuh-cjdLKY-fSudF5-pxgpHy-8aJwGV-8knLeE-etgS24-difNoz-7EQHbR-Xzqtbx-HLzoR-oBjsgi-6ZWtMR-29cjJ-ckLa3W-ehi3Xk-9rbdiM-22SMqgN-9Aurcf-cBByNJ-fuhMbF-6frytG-9Artxp-8dR7aC-XXAxCp-daeTsQ-8dMRok-4SgQ6U-6Cs7Ti-9DYWyw-29cjs-f2y7n-efj6qH-6nNHNz&quot;&gt;Flickr, Tobias Akerboom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the aforementioned events, &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;BMC Veterinary Research&lt;/em&gt; draw further motivation for the roll-out of this thematic series from the interaction with our authors and readers in recent conferences. More specifically, &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asm.org/&quot;&gt;ASM Microbe&lt;/a&gt; 2017, where AMR was the single most central theme (read about our experience&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/22/battling-antimicrobial-resistance-at-asm-microbe-2017/&quot;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt;). The environmental aspects of AMR, the absence of official legislation for appropriate antimicrobial use, along with ways by which the farm can affect hospitals were prominent themes amongst the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, &lt;em&gt;BMC Veterinary Research&lt;/em&gt; attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.nl/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=6&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjNpvG4sq_aAhWE1ywKHWL0CWQQFghUMAU&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Firis.unito.it%2Fbitstream%2F2318%2F1646130%2F2%2FARAE2017-proceedings.pdf&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw2EubfoKXsoszUkhbquqvki&quot;&gt;ARAE 2017&lt;/a&gt;, which is an important cornerstone in global AMR research allowing those working across different fields of AMR to come together to discuss and share ideas with an aim to mitigate the impact of resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal !msorm;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the above reasons, we believe that there is no better time to roll out this long-awaited thematic series. Henceforth, &lt;em&gt;BMC Veterinary Research &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; would like to invite you to submit to our new thematic series: ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/call-for-papers-amr?utm_source=BMC_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Blog&amp;amp;utm_content=DavFal-BMC-BMC_Veterinary_Research-Veterinary_Sciences-Global&amp;amp;utm_campaign=BMCS_USG_APR2018_Veterinary_antimicrobial_resistance_and_antimicrobial_use&quot;&gt;Veterinary Antimicrobial Resistance and Antimicrobial Use&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thematic series will review and feature robust veterinary microbiology research and will consider studies with a broad scope of antimicrobials, ranging from antiparasitics, antiviral, antibacterial, fungicides and phytobiotics and from diverse, domesticated vertebrate animal sources, including livestock, poultry and companion animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome submissions on the drivers and mechanisms of AMR and its emergence and on the incentives/disincentives of AMU and knowledge in different production systems, and especially in food production. We will investigate the role of regulation and policies, the role of the farm environment and the animal attendants and the consequences of all of the above on public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical advances including molecular tools towards the construction of early warning systems and any other form of prevention, early diagnosis and treatment will be also considered. Review and Debate articles will also be considered, but are at the discretion of the Editors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that this topic is of importance to veterinary and medical practitioners, microbiologists and policy makers, and the published articles aspire to examine the current use of antimicrobials and their implications in animals and the environment. The articles will also endeavor upon the level of resistance to antimicrobials and their prominence in terms of animal and human health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please submit directly to &lt;em&gt;BMC Veterinary Research&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;BMC Microbiology&lt;/em&gt; stating in your cover letter that you are targeting the ‘Veterinary Antimicrobial Resistance and Antimicrobial Use’ collection. Alternatively you can email your pre-submission queries to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hayley.henderson@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;hayley.henderson@biomedcentral.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cecilia.devoto@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;cecilia.devoto@biomedcentral.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for submission of manuscripts is 15th December 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/19/new-thematic-series-veterinary-antimicrobial-resistance-and-antimicrobial-use/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;New thematic series: Veterinary antimicrobial resistance and antimicrobial use&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Hayley Henderson &amp;#38; Cecilia Devoto</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A hole in an ancient cow’s skull could have been surgery practice</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hole-ancient-cow-skull-could-have-been-surgery-practice"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hole-ancient-cow-skull-could-have-been-surgery-practice</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before performing skull operations on people, ancient surgeons may have rehearsed on cows.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Research problems at Australian university hit the news</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/19/research-problems-at-australian-university-hit-the-news/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64311</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T12:00:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A university in Australia that’s made headlines before over allegations of research misconduct has found itself in the news once again. Last week, the University of Queensland (UQ) announced some of its authors were retracting a paper after discovering data were missing. Just days later, the university made headlines over an investigation into three papers … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/19/research-problems-at-australian-university-hit-the-news/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Research problems at Australian university hit the news&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-27T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Harvard and beyond: 4 ways machine learning is making researchers more efficient</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/harvard-and-beyond-4-ways-machine-learning-is-making-researchers-more-efficient"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/harvard-and-beyond-4-ways-machine-learning-is-making-researchers-more-efficient</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T11:24:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 From tackling information overload to identifying manipulated images, machine learning is changing the way science gets done</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This plastic-gobbling enzyme just got an upgrade</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/plastic-gobbling-enzyme-just-got-upgrade"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/plastic-gobbling-enzyme-just-got-upgrade</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists tweaked a bacterial enzyme and made it more efficient in breaking down plastics found in polyester and plastic bottles.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Study of 20,000 finds an income advantage for those judged to be very unattractive</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/19/study-of-20000-finds-an-income-advantage-for-those-judged-to-be-very-unattractive/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33729</id>
		<updated>2018-04-19T09:02:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-888271472.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33730&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33730&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800E&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Rearview shot of a young businessman taking a break at his desk in a modern office&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1457629068&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Satisfied with the state of business&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Satisfied with the state of business&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-888271472.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-888271472.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-888271472.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2042,1469&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/19/study-of-20000-finds-an-income-advantage-for-those-judged-to-be-very-unattractive/satisfied-with-the-state-of-business/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-888271472.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do chiselled features garner better pay? Researchers have previously found that income is associated with attractiveness, leading to the idea of both a beauty premium and an ugliness penalty. A common explanation is discrimination: employers seek out beautiful people and reject or ignore those harder on the eye. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10869-017-9489-6&quot;&gt;in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Business Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Satoshi Kanazawa and Mary Still have published research aiming to upset this. The biggest takeaway is that being perceived as very unattractive may not incur an income penalty at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33729&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers drew on a longitudinal study of 20,000 young Americans, interviewed at home at age 16 and then on three more occasions up to the age of 29. Each time the interviewer rated the person’s physical attractiveness, from very unattractive to very attractive. While previous research often collapses below-average scores into one category, this research treated them separately, which turns out to be important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanazawa and Still wanted to see whether the participants’ gross earnings at 29 were associated with their physical attractiveness at that or any previous age. Overall, there was a positive association between attractiveness and earnings. But there was an anomaly: very unattractive participants kept bucking the trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those participants who were rated very unattractive at age 29 were earning significantly more than people judged more attractive than them, including (though to a lesser extent) the very attractive. For attractiveness measures earlier in life, which allow more persuasive claims of causality, echoes of this pattern were present, as the very unattractive went on to earn significantly more at age 29 than those who were earlier rated unattractive, and they earned in the same region or even slightly more than those who were earlier rated as attractive.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correlation between extreme unattractiveness and higher pay remained using median earnings and looking separately at men and women. The authors argue this is hard to square with the usual discrimination explanation for why attractiveness (or lack of it) is associated with income. After all, why would employers be less discriminatory towards the worst-looking people?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative explanation is that the highly unattractive and attractive each favour different high-value industries. But this wasn’t supported by the data – even within a given industry, those rated very unattractive still achieved higher incomes than their more attractive counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanazawa and Still prefer an explanation for the attractiveness-income link that is tied into Kanazawa’s focus on evolutionary psychology and his sometimes controversial interest in the biological significance of attractiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanazawa reasons that attractive people earn more because facial attractiveness is a marker of better developmental health, which in turn correlates with more intelligence, advantageous personality traits, and being stronger, fitter and taller – all factors that are associated with higher earnings. In this dataset, after accounting for these factors, the attractiveness–income link was no longer statistically significant, supporting Kanazawa’s claim that it’s these correlates of attractiveness that are driving the higher income for more attractive people, not their beauty per se. This analysis also accounted for some of the earnings benefit for the very unattractive, but not all of it – and why would it, if the assumption is that the unattractive should be less healthy developmentally, on average?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems likely to me that we are seeing two factors at work. One relates to the income advantage for increasingly attractive people, maybe the developmental health explanation, maybe something else, and then something separate is at work raising income for the very unattractive group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to what gives rise to the income advantage for the very unattractive group, the only speculation I can offer is that in this dataset the personality trait Openness to Experience – which is usually associated with higher pay – was surprisingly correlated with lower earnings and higher attractiveness, meaning it was the only “bad” trait associated with higher attractiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could this Openness-attractiveness association be an indicator that some of the very unattractive scored especially low on Openness, and were perhaps highly devoted to a specific topic area, pursuing it obsessively to the exclusion of all distractions and eventually entering the forefront of their field? We know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/15/lets-dial-down-the-hype-about-grit-new-paper-finds-no-association-with-creative-achievement/&quot;&gt;Openness correlates negatively with the passion component of “Grit”&lt;/a&gt;, so such effects are conceivable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very unattractive group was small, as extremes are in any population – just a few hundred participants – so we would want to investigate this again to see if these effects&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;hold.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;For now, this research challenges assumptions about the potential for those born without conventional looks to find uncommon success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10869-017-9489-6&quot;&gt;Is There Really a Beauty Premium or an Ugliness Penalty on Earnings?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">NASA’s TESS spacecraft launches to begin its exoplanet search</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/tess-launch-success-nasa-exoplanets"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/tess-launch-success-nasa-exoplanets</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T23:36:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 After reaching its orbit in about two months, the telescope will start scanning nearby stars telltale dips in light that signal a passing planet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How ravens caused a LIGO data glitch</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-ravens-caused-ligo-data-glitch"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-ravens-caused-ligo-data-glitch</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T19:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ravens pecking at frosty pipes caused a glitch in gravitational wave data.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This meteorite’s diamonds hint that it was born in a lost planet</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/meteorite-diamonds-hint-it-was-born-lost-planet"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/meteorite-diamonds-hint-it-was-born-lost-planet</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T18:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Bits of metal nestled inside diamonds suggest the space rock could have formed in a Mars-sized protoplanet in the early solar system.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why touch can be such a creepy sensation in VR</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-touch-can-be-creepy-sensation-vr-uncanny-valley"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-touch-can-be-creepy-sensation-vr-uncanny-valley</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Touch sensation in VR can go from immersive to unnerving as the feeling gets more realistic, if you can’t see the source.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Masses of shrimp and krill may play a huge role in mixing oceans</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/masses-shrimp-and-krill-may-play-huge-role-mixing-oceans"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/masses-shrimp-and-krill-may-play-huge-role-mixing-oceans</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T17:20:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Hoards of migrating shrimp and krill can cause large-scale turbulence in the ocean, a new study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=46</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-24T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Why did Reuters remove a 3.5-year-old story?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/18/caught-our-notice-why-did-reuters-remove-a-3-5-year-old-story/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64290</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T16:11:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Title: Oil producer Afren fires CEO, 3 other executives in scandal What Caught Our Attention: Two days ago, the news organization Reuters mysteriously withdrew a 2014 story about the firing of four people from now-defunct oil company Afren, including its CEO. The only explanation: “it did not meet Reuters standards for accuracy.” The executives were … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/18/caught-our-notice-why-did-reuters-remove-a-3-5-year-old-story/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Why did Reuters remove a 3.5-year-old story?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T11:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Nutrition paper claims intervention cuts child obesity. Experts disagree.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/18/nutrition-paper-claims-intervention-cuts-child-obesity-experts-disagree/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64235</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T12:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Does incorporating gardens and their harvest into school-based nutrition programs help children get healthier? A 2017 paper claims it does, but a group of outside experts disagrees — strongly. The 2017 paper reported that adding gardens to schools and teaching kids how to cook the harvest, among other elements, helped kids learn about nutrition — … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/18/nutrition-paper-claims-intervention-cuts-child-obesity-experts-disagree/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Nutrition paper claims intervention cuts child obesity. Experts disagree.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Speedy species divergence and the curious case of the blind cavefish</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/18/speedy-species-divergence-curious-case-blind-cavefish/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10121</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T10:49:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/cavefish-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world’s waters are full of weird and wonderful creatures. &lt;em&gt;Astyanax mexicanus&lt;/em&gt;, otherwise known as the Mexican Tetra, is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardly larger than a tin of sardines and visually unremarkable, the surface variety can be spotted in rivers from Eastern Mexico all the way to Southern Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the fame of &lt;em&gt;Astyanax mexicanus&lt;/em&gt; does not arise from this river dwelling surface population. Only when journeying into the dark depths of isolated limestone Central American caves, is it possible to find the oddball relatives of surface fish populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within different caves, the cavefish populations have independently evolved similar traits, while sharing a common evolutionary ancestor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each population of cavefish is characterized by a distinctive set of common traits. The loss of its eyes means it instead depends on detecting fluctuations in water pressure through its lateral lines to aid navigation. Unlike the shiny silver coloration of its river dwelling cousin, the blind cavefish populations have lost all pigmentation&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;causing their scales to appear a ghostly pale pink as a consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 30 cavefish populations have been identified to date, with each population inheriting the name of their respective cave of residence. Within different caves, the cavefish populations have independently evolved similar traits, while sharing a common evolutionary ancestor. It is for this reason &lt;em&gt;Astyanax mexicanus&lt;/em&gt; is the model of choice for the study of convergent evolution in the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their physical differences, surface fish and cave fish are more similar than they appear. Surface –cavefish hybrids have been observed in the Chica caves of Mexico, suggesting that surface fish DNA markers could be introduced into cavefish populations through the mating of hybrids with other members of the cavefish population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phylogenetic analysis using mitochondrial DNA led to the widely accepted theory that at least two distinct surface residing ancestors gave rise to the present day cave populations over the period of several million years. The older ancestral stock is now thought to be extinct, with the surviving stock then invading the Western Micos caves as well as others further to the south east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A recent origin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-018-1156-7?utm_source=BMC_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Blog&amp;amp;utm_content=DavFal-BMC-BMC_Evolutionary_Biology-Aerospace_Medicine-Global&amp;amp;utm_campaign=BMCS_USG_APR2018_Curious_case_of_the_blind_cavefish&quot;&gt;study in &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; takes a controversial view, arguing that the coalescence time of mitochondrial genes in a particular cavefish population, alone, should not be interpreted to indicate the age of the oldest cavefish populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors computationally analyzed variations in both nuclear and mitochondrial DNA in order to date the evolutionary divergence in populations of blind Mexican cavefish. The results suggest both cavefish populations may have had a far more recent origin than previously thought, with evolutionary divergence potentially dating back to less than 20,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this hypothesis were to be correct, the blind Mexican cavefish would have become eyeless in an impressively short time. It has been suggested that the necessary alleles must have been present in ancestral surface populations to allow these alleles to reach a frequency high enough for this to occur at a sufficiently fast rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selection pressures present in each cave that have allowed this to occur in parallel across different populations are also still keenly debated. The lack of need for eye development has been suggested to conserve energy for seeking food in habitats where food is scarce. A recent study has also suggested a molecular basis, where on inhibition of the protein chaperone Hsp90, increased eye size variation could be observed. However, the identification of different eye gene mutations in different cavefish populations suggests a combination of different evolutionary factors at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the findings of Fumey et al. were to be confirmed, it is likely &lt;em&gt;Astyanax mexicanus&lt;/em&gt; would become a favored model for deciphering the molecular basis surrounding its speedy rates of evolutionary adaptation. Nonetheless, this publication in &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt; only continues to fuel the intrigue and debate surrounding the evolution of this unusual species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/18/speedy-species-divergence-curious-case-blind-cavefish/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Speedy species divergence and the curious case of the blind cavefish&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Micklem</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Does it matter whether your therapist is similar to you?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/18/does-it-matter-whether-your-therapist-is-similar-to-you/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33722</id>
		<updated>2018-04-18T07:35:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-896857954.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33723&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33723&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;DMC-GX1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mastermind, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought together, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1475063428&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;29&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;160&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.02&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mastermind, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought together, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mastermind, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought together, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-896857954.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-896857954.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-896857954.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1998,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/18/does-it-matter-whether-your-therapist-is-similar-to-you/mastermind-chakra-power-inspiration-abstract-thought-together-world-universe-inside-your-mind-watercolor-painting/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-896857954.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you choose the best possible therapist for someone who needs help? Does it make any difference if the therapist is about the same age, for instance, or the same gender, or from the same socio-economic background?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems intuitive that it might be easier to relate to someone from a similar background. However, while a positive relationship between client and therapist is known to be one of the most important factors for a good treatment outcome, there’s been surprisingly little work on how their respective personal attributes might interact to create a successful alliance. &lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now work led by Alex Behn, affiliated to both the Pontifical Catholic University of Chile and the Millennium Institute for Research in Depression and Personality, in Santiago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22616?af=R&quot;&gt;published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Clinical Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, attempts to help plug that gap.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33722&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study involved 28 therapists and 547 adult clients, who had been referred to receive psychotherapy (of different types) for depression. Just over ten per cent had previously been hospitalised for psychiatric reasons and 90 per cent were taking psychiatric medication when they joined the study. All of the therapists had a degree in psychology, and they saw the clients in weekly individual sessions.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before their first sessions, the clients and the therapists reported on their gender, age and average monthly family income. Based on these responses, they were classed as male/female; young adults (18-25), adults (aged 25-40), middle aged (40-60) or older people (aged 60 years and up); and as low-middle income class, high-middle income class or “vulnerable”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week, from the second session until the seventh, when the study ended (but not necessarily the sessions), the clients also completed an inventory designed to assess the quality of the therapeutic alliance based on how much they agreed with their therapist on goals and the tasks necessary to achieve them, and also the quality of the emotional bond between them.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all their analyses, the researchers controlled for initial symptom severity because this is known to affect the therapeutic alliance (the alliance is usually rated more negatively by clients with more severe problems).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, having a therapist of the same or different gender made no difference to how clients rated the therapeutic relationship with one exception: male clients with a female therapist showed some sharper downturns in the alliance over the first few sessions. However, this recovered from the fourth session onwards. There wasn’t any evidence for the so-called “female effect” documented in earlier research, in which female clients enjoy a more positive alliance with a female therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the therapist was the same age, or especially if they were younger, there was evidence for extra positive relationship growth over the course of the study – what the researchers called a “youth effect”, although they don’t give any explanation for why this might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of socioeconomic class, you might think that it would be easier to strike a rapport with someone from a similar economic background. In fact the opposite seemed to be true – clients reported greater gains in therapeutic alliance when their therapist was from a wealthier background. The researchers called this an “affluence effect” and they said it might be “related to the increase in social trust observed when income status increases”.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Particular forms of age and income match appear to allow for an additional improvement in the rate of initial change in the therapeutic alliance,” the researchers concluded. However they admitted that it is not possible to say from this study whether the extra growth in alliance associated with the “youth effect” or “affluence effect” actually improved treatment outcomes (although other research on the importance of therapeutic alliance suggests that it might). &lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22616?af=R&quot;&gt;Client and therapist match on gender, age, and income: Does match within the therapeutic dyad predict early growth in the therapeutic alliance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These seals haven’t lost their land ancestors’ hunting ways</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seals-have-claws-land-ancestors-hunting"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seals-have-claws-land-ancestors-hunting</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T23:09:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Clawed pawlike forelimbs help true seals hunt like their land-dwelling ancestors.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=46</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-24T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This ancient Maya city may have helped the Snake King dynasty spread</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-maya-city-snake-king-dynasty-la-corona-archaeology"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-maya-city-snake-king-dynasty-la-corona-archaeology</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T18:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A rural hub in an ancient Maya state gets its due with some laser help.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=46</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-24T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Youth Guru” loses turkey-neck paper that overlapped with book chapter</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/17/youth-guru-loses-turkey-neck-paper-that-overlapped-with-book-chapter/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64181</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T16:50:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A prominent cosmetic surgeon and his daughter have lost a 2017 paper on treating men with excessive neck flab — otherwise known as “turkey neck” — because much of the work appears to have duplicated a book chapter he co-authored about the topic. The first author of the retracted article is Ronald L. Moy, a … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/17/youth-guru-loses-turkey-neck-paper-that-overlapped-with-book-chapter/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;“Youth Guru” loses turkey-neck paper that overlapped with book chapter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-25T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s why putting a missile defense system in space could be a bad idea</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-putting-missile-defense-system-space-could-be-bad-idea"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-putting-missile-defense-system-space-could-be-bad-idea</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T15:52:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Expanding missile defense capabilities could put the world on a slippery slope to space warfare.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-24T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Smokers have worse diets than non-smokers</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/17/smokers-worse-diets-non-smokers/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10100</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T14:18:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/smoking-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been suggested in the literature that concern about weight gain is a barrier to smoking cessation. Dietary energy density (ED; kcal/g) is an established risk factor for obesity and a marker for diet quality. Diets low in energy density may reduce risk of weight gain. However, little is known about the relationship between diet quality and smoking status in US adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their study, Dr Jacqueline Vernarelli and colleagues at Fairfield University and Yale University in the United States looked at dietary data taken from a nationally representative sample of 5,293 U.S. adults who had been asked to report what they had eaten in the past 24 hours. Smokers were identified as individuals reporting more than 100 lifetime cigarettes and never smokers as those reporting less than 100 lifetime cigarettes. Current smokers were further classified as daily smokers (smoking cigarettes every day) and nondaily smokers (identifies as a smoker, but does not smoke cigarettes every day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-10104 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/slimming-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;The researchers calculated the average dietary energy density of each participant’s diet and, after accounting for factors such as age, race, sex, physical activity and body mass index, found that smokers consumed around 200 more calories a day than non-smokers or former smokers, even though they ate significantly smaller portions of food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who had never smoked consumed around 1.79 calories per gram of food, daily smokers consumed 2.02 kcal/g and non-daily smokers consumed 1.89 kcal/g. The researchers also found that former smokers consumed more calories per gram of food (1.84kcal/g) than those who had never smoked, but the former smokers’ dietary energy density was still significantly lower than that of current smokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-10103 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/pepper-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;The calorie dense diets consumed by the smokers whose data was used in this study often included less fruit and vegetables, which means their intake of vitamin C was likely to be lower. The authors suggest that this deficiency could potentially put smokers at further risk of cardiovascular disease and cancer, presenting a major public health concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As dietary energy density is a marker for both diet quality and a risk factor for obesity, the results of the study suggest that the consumption of a diet low in energy density may be a successful strategy for preventing weight gain following smoking cessation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/17/smokers-worse-diets-non-smokers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Smokers have worse diets than non-smokers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Natalie Pafitis</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Don’t like a paper, but don’t want to retract it? Just issue an “editorial statement”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/17/dont-like-a-paper-but-dont-want-to-retract-it-just-issue-an-editorial-statement/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=64137</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T12:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Last April, the American Journal of Epidemiology and the American Journal of Public Health published a rare joint editorial statement. It concerned a pair of papers on the topic of mortality and obesity. Several complaints had prompted the journals to investigate. Their assessment: These papers contained inaccurate results. The statement was not a retraction—it was … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/04/17/dont-like-a-paper-but-dont-want-to-retract-it-just-issue-an-editorial-statement/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Don’t like a paper, but don’t want to retract it? Just issue an “editorial statement”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nick Stockton</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-04-24T11:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A new plastic film glows to flag food contaminated with dangerous microbes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-plastic-film-glows-flag-food-contaminated-dangerous-microbes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-plastic-film-glows-flag-food-contaminated-dangerous-microbes</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Plastic patches that glow when they touch some types of bacteria could be built into food packaging to reduce the spread of foodborne illness.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-04-23T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The public find articles about education more convincing when they contain extraneous neuroscience</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/17/the-public-find-articles-about-education-more-convincing-when-they-contain-extraneous-neuroscience/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33709</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T09:16:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-522798525.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33717&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33717&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;13&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D3X&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MRI Image Of Head Showing Brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1363093172&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Highwaystarz-Photography&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;42&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MRI Image Of Head Showing Brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;MRI Image Of Head Showing Brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-522798525.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-522798525.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-522798525.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1985,1511&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/04/17/the-public-find-articles-about-education-more-convincing-when-they-contain-extraneous-neuroscience/mri-image-of-head-showing-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/gettyimages-522798525.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brain science is mysterious and sexy and people are more inclined to believe claims that contain superfluous neuroscience references or neuro-imagery – an effect referred to as “the seductive allure of neuroscience” or “SANE” (that’s the short story, however the literature on the effect is messy, to say the least, with a mix of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/04/17/psychology-students-are-seduced-by-superfluous-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;successful&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/03/are-we-now-blase-about-brain-scans.html&quot;&gt;failed replications&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One context where we might expect the seductive allure of neuroscience to be particularly problematic is in the emerging field of educational neuroscience, which seeks to use findings about the brain to improve educational practice. While the field holds promise, experts have warned about the dangers of neuro-jargon lending a confusing veneer of credibility to educational practices that lack an evidence base (one prominent example would be &lt;em&gt;Brain Gym&lt;/em&gt; which has been widely criticised by neuroscientists and psychologists).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, however, no one had looked to see whether the seductive allure of neuroscience applies specifically in an educational context. A research group at the University of Minnesota has now attempted to plug this gap. They recently reported in &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/bjep.12162&quot;&gt;the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Educational Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; their “major finding” that the public find popular articles about the psychology of learning more credible when they contain extraneous neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33709&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soo-hyun Im and his colleagues presented 245 members of the US public with short articles (approximately 250 words) about the educational implications of psychology studies. For example, one article, based on a real psychological finding, explained that people are more likely to remember trivia answers that they feel more curious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each article was either devoid of neuroscience or accompanied by varying amounts of what the researchers called “extraneous” neuroscience: a brain-based claim in the text; the same textual neuroscience claim plus a basic chart; or the textual claim plus a colourful brain-scan type image (the neuroscience references were based on real pieces of research).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the article about curiosity either made no mention of the brain, or it stated that participants’ higher curiosity ratings were correlated with activity in brain areas involved in motivation, or it included this neuroscience reference plus a line chart, or the neuroscience reference plus a brain scan showing the location of the curiosity-related activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants’ task was to rate how credible they found each article, in terms of its quality, comprehensibleness, reasonableness, validity and how much they agreed with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants found the articles more credible when they contained the most extreme form of extraneous neuroscience – a textual neuroscience reference plus a brain scan image. This seductive allure of neuroscience effect (SANE) was greater among participants with more familiarity with educational topics and among participants with more prior knowledge of neuroscience (although their knowledge was modest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The current study extended the SANE effect to the important case of articles about educational topics” the researchers concluded. “Perhaps the most important direction for future research is to investigate whether the SANE effect for educational topics holds for educational professionals such as teachers, administrators, and policy makers”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no question this new research addresses an important issue. There is a lot of hype about educational neuroscience and it is important that policy-makers and teachers do not get misled by the allure of neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the study features several methodological shortcomings that make it difficult to interpret the findings as showing a true SANE effect. As the researchers partly acknowledged, the addition of extraneous neuroscience information was confounded with article length and image richness. Perhaps participants simply rated longer, more graphic articles as more credible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, we do not really know based on these findings that there is anything especially alluring about neuroscience in an educational context – for instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010027716301585&quot;&gt;the addition of extraneous information from genetics or another field&lt;/a&gt; may have had the same or even a greater effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, even though I am sceptical about neuroscience hype I think there’s an argument that the supposedly extraneous neuroscience added to the articles was rather relevant. The brain-based information was derived from real studies and provided converging, objective evidence relevant to the psychological findings being discussed, arguably lending greater credibility to the claims. A more convincing demonstration of the SANE effect would have tested whether participants were swayed by truly superfluous and non-sensical neuroscience claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/bjep.12162&quot;&gt;Extending the seductive allure of neuroscience explanations effect to popular articles about educational topics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and author of &lt;em&gt;Great Myths of the Brain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-04-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Weight misperceptions strongly associated with unhealthy dieting</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/17/weight-misperceptions-strongly-associated-unhealthy-dieting/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10094</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T08:00:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/04/iStock-641963334-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that the United States (US) is facing an obesity problem; adolescent obesity is currently three times more prevalent than it was in the 1980s. What is perhaps surprising is that at the same time, the prevalence of US households with both overweight and underweight members exceed 5% of the population. This highlights the US’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15505634&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;dual burden&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of weight mismanagement at both ends of the weight spectrum. Moreover, it is striking to note that this trend is accompanied by a high persistence of unhealthy dieting behaviors among youths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unhealthy dieting behaviors such as fasting for extended periods of time or purging via forced vomiting have been shown to be risk factors of several eating disorders (EDs). Unhealthy dieting is not the same as EDs since EDs are classically linked with psychological implications, but they may act as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eatingdisorderhope.com/treatment-for-eating-disorders/special-issues/dieting&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;precursors to more severe mental disorders&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and can lead to being dangerously underweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unhealthy dieting behaviors have also been shown to be ineffective for long-term weight loss for people who are overweight, and could cause weight gain in that population since they are associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0091743511003963?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;counter-productive practices&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; such as reduced physical activities and a decrease in fruit and vegetable consumption. As seen, these behaviors could potentially exacerbate the weight mismanagement issue in both directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceiving one’s weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although numerous public health strategies to combat weight mismanagement have been implemented over the years, many have focused on behavioral interventions such as diet and exercise education. In our research, we wanted to explore in detail the role of one’s perception of their own weight and so examined associations between self-perceptions of weight status, weight change intentions, and unhealthy dieting behaviors across the different sex, age, race and weight spectrum in US adolescents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, we analyzed data from 113,542 adolescents collected between 1999 and 2013 in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/data/yrbs/index.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Youth Risk Behaviour Surveillance System&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which monitors the health risk behaviors among 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; through 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; grade students in the US through school-based surveys. The survey included questions on self-perception of weight, weight change intentions and unhealthy dieting behaviors. Measures of self-reported unhealthy dieting behaviors were fasting for 24 hours or more, taking diet pills/powders/liquids, and vomiting/taking laxatives, in the last 30 days in order to lose weight or keep from gaining weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discovered that overestimating one’s own body weight and a desire to change it were most strongly associated with unhealthy dieting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that adolescent girls were more likely to overestimate their weight, while boys were more likely to underestimate. Also, unhealthy dieting was more common among girls than boys, with 26.2% of girls performing an unhealthy dieting behavior in 1999 and 22.7% in 2013. These figures for boys were 10.4% in 1999 and 10.1% in 2013. After adjusting for sex, age and race, we discovered that overestimating one’s own body weight and a desire to change it were most strongly associated with unhealthy dieting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also observed significant racial disparities in unhealthy dieting behaviors, with non-white groups displaying higher levels of fasting and purging, which are important precursors of anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa respectively. As racial disparities were found to have persisted over time, it could mean that minority groups may be disadvantaged in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings are important as unhealthy dieting behaviors are linked to serious health consequences and can further worsen the weight mismanagement observed in US adolescents. This study suggests that high levels of weight misperceptions, particularly overestimation, increase the likelihood of clinically inappropriate weight change intentions, which was found to be associated to unhealthy dieting behaviors. Hence, public health policies should look to helping adolescents have an accurate perception of their own weight to help reduce unhealthy dieting in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ever, there are caveats: as this study used self-reported survey data, information and recall bias may be a factor. Moreover, as we were unable to track the same individuals over time, causation between the factors could not be drawn conclusively. Nevertheless, the persistence of the high prevalence of unhealthy dieting behaviors, especially among females across all racial groups, is concerning. Further research into weight status perceptions may inform efforts to curb this worrying trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/04/17/weight-misperceptions-strongly-associated-unhealthy-dieting/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weight misperceptions strongly associated with unhealthy dieting&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Chin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-04-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Wider Life Gap</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/I_MHShZwu-8/scientificamerican0518-84"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-84</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 84 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-84&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-84&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mark Fischetti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. life span is rising disproportionately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/I_MHShZwu-8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Fischetti</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50, 100 &amp;amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/NdHwKmcDdjQ/scientificamerican0518-83"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-83</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 83 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-83&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-83&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/NdHwKmcDdjQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel C. Schlenoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mothering, Wild Style</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/zEGTe7q_MPU/scientificamerican0518-82"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-82</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 82 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-82&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-82&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some moms can be murder on the family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/zEGTe7q_MPU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Steve Mirsky</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">You Kant Be Serious</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/AHAtZDpbVns/scientificamerican0518-80"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-80</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 80 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-80&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-80&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilitarianism and its discontents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/AHAtZDpbVns&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Shermer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Recommended</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/nzIUV6gQEUQ/scientificamerican0518-78"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-78</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 78 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-78&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-78&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/nzIUV6gQEUQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Is Deep-Sea Mining Worth It?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/dabCvs2M0mI/scientificamerican0518-72"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-72</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 72 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Thomas Peacock &amp;amp; Matthew H. Alford&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race is on to exploit—and protect—the ocean floor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/dabCvs2M0mI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thomas Peacock</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Our Stuff, Ourselves</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/FN_0bnKcJvc/scientificamerican0518-66"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-66</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 66 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-66&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-66&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Francine Russo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low emotional security can intensify our relationships to our belongings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/FN_0bnKcJvc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Francine Russo</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Letters</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/HPFEfUlrbNE/scientificamerican0518-6"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-6</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/HPFEfUlrbNE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Catching Fever</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Kh2UWVeZFrc/scientificamerican0518-58"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-58</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 58 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-58&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-58&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Lois Parshley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate change is accelerating the spread of disease—and making it much harder to predict outbreaks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Kh2UWVeZFrc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lois Parshley</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">American Epidemic</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/cyd_CSxc_S4/scientificamerican0518-44"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-44</id>
		<updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 44 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0518-44&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0518-44&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Melinda Wenner Moyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resurgent outbreaks of infectious diseases are sickening thousands, and the causes are societal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/cyd_CSxc_S4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Melinda Wenner Moyer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-04-28T11:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
