<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are religious people really less smart, on average, than atheists?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/26/are-religious-people-really-less-smart-on-average-than-atheists/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33084</id>
		<updated>2018-01-26T09:10:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-628648170.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33103&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33103&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ILCE-7RM2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Close-Up Of Man Praying&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1481289732&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;okeyphotos&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;90&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Close-Up Of Man Praying&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Close-Up Of Man Praying&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-628648170.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-628648170.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-628648170.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/26/are-religious-people-really-less-smart-on-average-than-atheists/close-up-of-man-praying/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-628648170.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are examples of extremely intelligent individuals with strong religious convictions. But various studies have found that, on average, belief in God is associated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://emilkirkegaard.dk/en/wp-content/uploads/The-Relation-Between-Intelligence-and-Religiosity-A-Meta-Analysis-and-Some-Proposed-Explanations.pdf&quot;&gt;lower scores on IQ tests&lt;/a&gt;. “It is well established that religiosity correlates inversely with intelligence,” note Richard Daws and Adam Hampshire at Imperial College London, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.02191/full&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, which seeks to explore why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a question with some urgency – the proportion of people &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pewforum.org/2015/04/02/religious-projections-2010-2050/&quot;&gt;with a religious belief is growing&lt;/a&gt;: by 2050, if current trends continue, people who say they are not religious will make up only 13 per cent of the global population. Based on the low-IQ-religiosity link, it could be argued that humanity is on course to become collectively less smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33084&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One suggestion is that perhaps religious people tend to rely more on intuition. So, rather than having impaired general intelligence, they might be comparatively poor only on tasks in which intuition and logic come into conflict – and this might explain the lower overall IQ test results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate, Daws and Hampshire surveyed more than 63,000 people online, and had them complete a 30-minute set of 12 cognitive tasks that measured planning, reasoning, attention and working memory. The participants also indicated whether they were religious, agnostic or atheist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As predicted, the atheists performed better overall than the religious participants, even after controlling for demographic factors like age and education. Agnostics tended to place between atheists and believers on all tasks. In fact, strength of religious conviction correlated with poorer cognitive performance. However, while the religious respondents performed worse overall on tasks that required reasoning, there were only very small differences in working memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, some of the reasoning tasks, such as an extra-hard version of the Stroop Task known as “colour-word remapping”, had been designed to create maximum conflict between an intuitive response and a logical one, and the biggest group differences emerged on these tasks, consistent with the idea that religious people rely more on their intuition. In contrast, for a complex reasoning task – “deductive reasoning” – for which there were no obviously intuitive answers, there was much less of a group difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daws and Hampshire concluded: “These findings provide evidence in support of the hypothesis that the religiosity effect relates to conflict [between reasoning and intuition] as opposed to reasoning ability or intelligence more generally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, as this work suggests, religious belief predisposes people to rely more heavily on intuition in decision-making – and the stronger their belief, the more pronounced the impact – how much of a difference does this make to actual achievement in the real world? At the moment, there’s no data on this. But in theory, perhaps cognitive training could allow religious people to maintain their beliefs without over-relying on intuition when it conflicts with logic in day to day decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.02191/full&quot;&gt;The Negative Relationship between Reasoning and Religiosity Is Underpinned by a Bias for Intuitive Responses Specifically When Intuition and Logic Are in Conflict&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Plastic pollution increases risk of devastating disease in corals</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plastic-pollution-increases-risk-devastating-disease-corals"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plastic-pollution-increases-risk-devastating-disease-corals</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T22:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers estimate about 11 billion pieces of plastic are polluting Asia-Pacific corals, raising the risk of disease at scores of reefs.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists find 10 new defense systems used by bacteria</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-find-10-new-defense-systems-used-bacteria"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-find-10-new-defense-systems-used-bacteria</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T21:16:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists identify 10 groups of genes that appear to govern defense systems used by bacteria against virus attacks.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Overlooked air pollution may be fueling more powerful storms</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/overlooked-air-pollution-may-be-fueling-more-powerful-storms"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/overlooked-air-pollution-may-be-fueling-more-powerful-storms</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T19:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The tiniest particles in air pollution aren’t just a health threat. They also strengthen thunderstorms, new research suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">An ancient jaw pushes humans’ African departure back in time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-jaw-pushes-humans-african-departure-back-time"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-jaw-pushes-humans-african-departure-back-time</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T19:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 If an ancient jaw found in an Israeli cave belongs to Homo sapiens, the humans left Africa tens of thousands of years earlier than we thought.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Oops, wrong species</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/25/caught-notice-oops-wrong-species/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53584</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T16:00:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Virulent Diuraphis noxia Aphids Over-Express Calcium Signaling Proteins to Overcome Defenses of Aphid-Resistant Wheat Plants What Caught Our Attention: Sadly, it’s not uncommon for researchers to mistake the identity of what they’re working with — but not everyone comes clean and works to transparently correct the record. So it’s nice to see some authors […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/25/caught-notice-oops-wrong-species/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Oops, wrong species&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“GOOD NEWS!…we were able to retract your article:” Journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/25/good-news-able-retract-article-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53573</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T13:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A paleontology journal has retracted a recent paper after discovering it had published the uncorrected version of the manuscript. The mistake occurred after the authors submitted revisions to the manuscript without tracking the changes, prompting the publisher to believe nothing had been changed and publishing the previous version. The journal initially told the authors it […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/25/good-news-able-retract-article-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“GOOD NEWS!…we were able to retract your article:” Journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Robots map largest underwater volcanic eruption in 100 years</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-map-largest-underwater-volcanic-eruption-100-years"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-map-largest-underwater-volcanic-eruption-100-years</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 High-resolution mapping of a 2012 underwater volcanic eruption just goes to show there’s a lot we don’t know about deep-sea volcanism.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">It’s not all in their heads: people with low self-esteem really do have less responsive partners</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/25/its-not-all-in-their-heads-people-with-low-self-esteem-really-do-have-less-responsive-partners/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33075</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T09:17:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-157914805.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33097&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33097&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D300&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Teenage couple sitting on the bench.They are looking away and are not interested in each other..&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1316432051&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;101dalmatians&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;23&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.001&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A teenage couple with their backs to each other&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A teenage couple with their backs to each other&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-157914805.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-157914805.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-157914805.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2125,1411&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/25/its-not-all-in-their-heads-people-with-low-self-esteem-really-do-have-less-responsive-partners/a-teenage-couple-with-their-backs-to-each-other/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-157914805.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compounding the difficulties they have liking themselves, people with low self-esteem also tend to have poorer relationships. Previous investigations into why this may be haven’t made easy reading for the self-doubters. For instance, while they tend to claim that their partners have more negative views of them and love them less (than do people with more typical self-esteem), studies of their partners simply haven’t backed this up. This suggests that the neurotic and needy are projecting their insecurities and imperilling their relationships in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that is not the end of the story. People with low self-esteem also tend to report that, when they need them most, their partners are poor at responding and being supportive. Is this all in their heads too? Not according to a series of &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12370/abstract&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality&lt;/em&gt;, by Kassandra Cortes and Joanne Wood at the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Until this point, researchers have pointed the finger at LSEs [those with low self-esteem] as the likely cause for their lower quality relationships … However, our data suggest that LSEs may not be the only culprits,” Cortes and Wood conclude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33075&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers started by recruiting 122 romantic student couples and had everyone complete a self-esteem questionnaire. Next, the couples were divided in two. One partner from each pair was asked about times they’d disclosed bad news to their partner and how their partner had responded. The other partners – the “listeners” – were asked to recall times that they’d listened and responded to their partner’s bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, among the participants who recalled their past disclosures, those with low self-esteem tended to describe having less responsive partners. Crucially, this seemed to be corroborated by the participants in the listener role, who recalled times they’d listened. Those listeners with a lower self-esteem partner described themselves as having been less understanding and attentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many problems with that first study – not least the possibility that people with low self-esteem tend to share bad news that is harder to sympathise with. To get around this, Cortes and Wood next invited dozens more romantic couples to the psych lab, measured their self-esteem, and then contrived a situation whereby one partner in each couple had the same bad experience – they were excluded in a simple video game called cyber ball (no one passed the ball to them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, the rejected participants were reunited with their partners and secretly videoed telling them what had happened. When the researchers watched back the videos they found that the rejected participants with lower self-esteem received less support and understanding from their partners, again seeming to corroborate the claims of low self-esteem individuals that they don’t get much support or sympathy from their partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of why this should be, the researchers surveyed 99 more people online. They were asked to rate their partners’ self-esteem, to imagine that their partner had had a big fall out with a friend, and then to say how much support their partner would typically want in this kind of situation, and how their partner would typically go about sharing their bad news. The researchers compared the participants’ answers depending on whether they rated their partner as low or higher self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study asks us to place a lot of trust in the memories and interpretations of these participants, but if we take their answers at face value, they suggest that partners with low self-esteem want as much support and understanding, but that they go about sharing their bad news and their distress in a rather counter-productive way – for instance, they’ll be inconsistent, sometimes downplaying their feelings, sometimes exaggerating them. Or they’ll be indirect, acting as if something is wrong, but not saying why, as if expecting their partner to be a mind reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the findings from all three studies suggest that the consistent claim of people with low self-esteem that their partners are rather unresponsive has at least a grain of truth to it. However, it takes two to tango, and it seems those folk who are less assertive and self-confident probably don’t make it very easy for their partners to be responsive and supportive. Sometimes if you’re hurting and you want a shoulder to lean on, the best strategy is be transparent and to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortes and Wood believe their findings may have some practical implications: “Perhaps this research could lead to dyadic level interventions,” they said, “in which LSEs [low self-esteem people] are trained to improve their expression (making it easier for their partners to be responsive), and partners of LSEs are trained to be more responsive (so that LSEs may feel more secure in expressing openly in the future)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12370/abstract&quot;&gt;Is it really “all in their heads”? How self-esteem predicts partner responsiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 141 Rodrigo Quian Quiroga on Memory and Perception</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-141-rodrigo-quian-quiroga-on-memory-and-perception"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/552495f079a8199e0dab7745caf39302</id>
		<updated>2018-01-25T01:35:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;BS 141 is an interview with Rodrigo Quian Quiroga, author of &lt;em&gt;The Forgetting Machine: Memory, Perception, and the &quot;Jennifer Aniston Neuron.&quot;  &lt;/em&gt;We explore how our brains construct both perception and memory, with an emphasis on meaning over exact detail. We also explore why this is important and how it makes humans very different from artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For detailed show notes and episode transcripts please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&quot;&gt;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Send feedback to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&quot;&gt;brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This show relies on listener support. Please &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com/donations/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to learn how you can support the show.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T03:10:46+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lasers trace a new way to create hovering hologram-like images</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lasers-trace-new-way-create-hovering-hologram-images"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lasers-trace-new-way-create-hovering-hologram-images</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T19:30:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Hovering 3-D images pave the way for futuristic displays that could be used for education or entertainment.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Human brains rounded into shape over 200,000 years or more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-brains-rounded-shape-over-200000-years-or-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-brains-rounded-shape-over-200000-years-or-more</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T19:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient humans’ brains slowly but surely became round, scientists say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Memory remains elusive, but the search continues</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/memory-remains-elusive-search-continues"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/memory-remains-elusive-search-continues</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T18:35:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill explores the history of memory and scientists' search for its physical trace in our brains.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers wonder about the universe's expansion and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-wonder-about-universes-expansion-and-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-wonder-about-universes-expansion-and-more</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T18:34:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers had questions about the universe's accelerating expansion, a hidden void in the Great Pyramid of Giza and what happens to human waste in space.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Baby macaques are the first primates to be cloned like Dolly the Sheep</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/baby-macaques-primates-clones-dolly-sheep"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/baby-macaques-primates-clones-dolly-sheep</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T18:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have cloned two baby macaque monkeys with the same technique used to clone Dolly. The research could help advance the cloning of other species.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Questions swirl around CNRS director’s decision to step down early</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/24/questions-swirl-around-cnrs-directors-decision-step-early/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53567</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T18:27:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Today, a French council was set to confirm the new head of a prominent research institute, the National Center for Scientific Research (CNRS). But the appointee took the job a few days early, after the interim director stepped down last week — and the speculation about why she left hasn’t stopped ever since. An official […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/24/questions-swirl-around-cnrs-directors-decision-step-early/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Questions swirl around CNRS director’s decision to step down early&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How The Lancet mobilized scientists to tackle a silent scandal</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-the-lancet-mobilized-scientists-to-tackle-a-silent-scandal"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-the-lancet-mobilized-scientists-to-tackle-a-silent-scandal</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T17:39:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Highlighting the data behind stillbirths to bring about change</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The X-ray glow keeps growing after the recent neutron star collision</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/x-ray-glow-keeps-growing-after-recent-neutron-star-collision"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/x-ray-glow-keeps-growing-after-recent-neutron-star-collision</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 X-rays from a neutron star collision have been getting brighter, and scientists are debating why.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“The most terrible experience of my life:” Authorship dispute leads to lawsuit</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/24/terrible-experience-life-authorship-dispute-leads-lawsuit/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53555</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T13:45:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A journal has retracted a 2014 paper because of an authorship dispute that became the subject of litigation. Last year, the Allegheny Health Network in Pittsburgh requested the paper be retracted to resolve the dispute. The Journal of Applied Biomaterials &amp;amp; Functional Materials retracted the paper in October. According to the retraction notice, the principal […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/24/terrible-experience-life-authorship-dispute-leads-lawsuit/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“The most terrible experience of my life:” Authorship dispute leads to lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Somewhere in the brain is a storage device for memories</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/memory-brain-engram-neuroscience"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/memory-brain-engram-neuroscience</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New technology and new ideas spur the hunt for the physical basis of memory.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">There’s an evolutionary explanation for why we’re surprisingly bad at recognising each other’s laughter</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/24/theres-an-evolutionary-explanation-for-why-were-surprisingly-bad-at-recognising-each-others-laughter/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33086</id>
		<updated>2018-01-24T09:18:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-667207606.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33089&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33089&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Diversity in people&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laughing out loud&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Laughing out loud&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-667207606.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-667207606.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-667207606.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;4080,1580&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/24/theres-an-evolutionary-explanation-for-why-were-surprisingly-bad-at-recognising-each-others-laughter/laughing-out-loud/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-667207606.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a mostly impressive ability to identify people we know based on the sound of their voice, but prior research has uncovered an intriguing exception – we’re not very good at discerning identity from laughter. Now Nadine Lavan and her colleagues have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1090513817301319&quot;&gt;published research&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Evolution and Human Behavior&lt;/i&gt; that looks into why this might be and what it says about our evolutionary past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33086&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main reasons why laughter may be hard to read. It might be because when you laugh for real, your vocal apparatus and lungs act in an involuntary way, unlike in many other vocalisations, and this difference in production might block the identity cues normally found in the voice. Alternatively, listeners of genuine laughter might get distracted by it’s contagious emotional content, meaning they don’t pick up on the identity cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test these possibilities, Lavan’s team recruited helpers to produce fake laughs (while trying to sound natural) and genuine laughs, provoked by playing them amusing sound and video clips. A team of judges then listened back and rated all the laughs as highly authentic sounding genuine laughs, unauthentic sounding fake ones, and also genuine and fake laughs that sounded somewhat authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers categorised the laughs this way is because genuine laughs can sometimes sound flat, whereas a forced laugh can sound remarkably authentic (as you’d know if you’ve ever been around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laughter_yoga&quot;&gt;laughter yoga&lt;/a&gt; – or participated, as I did this month, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://the-smoke.org/2018-programme/the-best-medicine/&quot;&gt;a live-action game session&lt;/a&gt; where you could use gestures to command people to laugh at anything you said).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, 37 participants, around 24 years old, completed hundreds of trials, in which they listened to two of the recorded laughs, each a few seconds long, and had to decide whether they came from the same individual or not. As in prior research, the participants’ accuracy was poorest when judging the identity of two spontaneous laughs, rather than deliberate laughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about authentic sounding fake laughs? If fact, participants were just as good at discerning identity from authentic sounding fake laughs as from non-authentic sounding fake laughs (and the degree to which spontaneous laughs appeared authentic also made no difference to performance). It was only the fact of being spontaneously produced that made laughs harder to identify, which suggests the difficulty reading identity isn’t due to listeners getting distracted, but by the fact the sounds are squeezed out in an involuntary way that is so different from human intentional speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings fit with an evolutionary account that is speculative but intriguing. It goes like this: animal vocalisations evolved primarily to signal information about threats or food, not identity, and even today our evolutionarily old, spontaneous vocalisations, including laughter, remain as personally undifferentiated as those of animals (which would explain why can’t distinguish slowed-down spontaneous laughter from slowed-down animal calls). However, as humans became increasingly comfortable with making voluntary sounds through developing speech, we began to lean towards peppering those sounds with elements that are distinctive. In ever-larger social groups, it became important for us to signal identity, a prerequisite for developing trust and reciprocity over time. According to this story, the distinctive voice is a hallmark of our species that we acquired on the road to becoming savvy social beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1090513817301319&quot;&gt;Impoverished encoding of speaker identity in spontaneous laughter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New device can transmit underwater sound to air</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-device-can-transmit-underwater-sound-air"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-device-can-transmit-underwater-sound-air</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newly created metamaterial takes a shot at solving the problem of hearing underwater sounds from the surface.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Your phone is like a spy in your pocket</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/smartphones-data-collection-security-privacy"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/smartphones-data-collection-security-privacy</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Smartphones’ powers of perception make them more user-friendly and efficient. But they also open new opportunities for privacy invasions.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Evolution doesn’t give a damn what you think a brain region is called</title>
		<link href="https://medium.com/the-spike/evolution-doesnt-give-a-damn-what-you-think-a-brain-region-is-called-1c9c5f80ab89?source=rss----c92c31591e3a---4"/>
		<id>https://medium.com/p/1c9c5f80ab89</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T16:59:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;h4&gt;A cortex by any other name&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/540/1*q5dqA14b5EAhZlfAZm7KzQ.jpeg&quot; /&gt;Credit: Pixabay&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;We do love naming things. Nouns are the first words we learn: mummy; daddy. Or if you’re my kids: “digger” and “Bob” (the cat) — because who needs parents when there’s a big ginger cat to play with? That love for tagging an object with a label never goes away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neuroscientists are no different. In large brains, like ours or rats or ferrets, we give hundreds of names to their constituent parts. Some name vast swathes of brain tissue: cortex, brainstem, midbrain. Some name tiny subdivisions of those swathes, like the almond shaped subthalamic nucleus (literally, the cluster of neurons underneath the thalamus). In tiny brains, like maggots or roundworms, even individual neurons have names. (Boring ones like “P4”; sadly, there is no neuron in &lt;em&gt;C Elegans&lt;/em&gt; called Boris).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By naming these bits of brain, we can communicate effectively, we can talk about brains and know we are talking about the same bit. We can navigate where we are in the brain by knowing the names of the brain regions. We can even identify ourselves by the bit of brain we study: “I work on cortex”; “I work on hippocampus”; “I couldn’t decide what I wanted to do when I left school; now I work on the nucleus ambiguus”. Naming bits of brain greases the wheels of scientific communication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it is also a dangerous game. If we confuse the convenience of naming with the reality of the brain, we end up in deep trouble. Because evolution does not give a crap what we call a brain region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The danger is that naming a bit of brain makes us think it is a discrete thing, a bit that just lifts right out, which we can study and marvel at in isolation. But how evolution (and development) conspire to disperse and wire together neurons pays no attention to these names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider primary motor and somatosensory cortex. They sit next to each other. But they appear in different chapters in textbooks. Entirely separate fields of research have grown up around them. Work on primary somatosensory cortex looks at how the activity of its neurons represent touch. Work on motor cortex looks how the activity of its neurons represent movement. These are starkly different: work on somatosensory cortex focuses on its inputs; work on motor cortex focuses on its outputs. They are treated so separately that papers merely showing the flow of activity from one to the other end up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zora.uzh.ch/id/eprint/80903/&quot;&gt;in high-profile journals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But these bits of cortex are next to each other. Either we believe that there are border guards who turn away the motor cortex neuron axons at the crossing with somatosensory cortex, and the same from the other direction. Or we have to assume that these two names loosely delineate a continuous network of neurons by the fact that a small set of neurons in somatosensory cortex get direct sensory input, and small set of neurons in motor cortex connect to the spinal cord. Most of the neurons in these bits of cortex neither get sensory input from the thalamus nor project to the spinal cord. They are wired to other neurons all over cortex, and very much to each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mean, look at this nutter:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZK8WIcZ8-EMeYtr1AphZbg.png&quot; /&gt;The projections of the axon of a single neuron in rodent motor cortex. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2017.85&quot;&gt;Zeng &amp;amp; Hanes 2017&lt;/a&gt; (Nature Neurosci Reviews)&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evolution has deemed it necessary for this neuron in motor cortex to send its output wires, its axons, all over the shop. To the somatosensory cortex. To prefrontal cortex, so that the apparent seat of “executive function” — cogitating, planning, turning things over in your mind — apparently needs to know what your foot will be doing shortly. To the ectorhinal cortex (no, me neither). All over the striatum. And to the other side of the brain — yes, the brain has two sides. We call it a motor cortex neuron; it is studied for how it represents simple movements; but it is not a neuron that sits neatly tucked up in one neatly labelled part of the brain — it is part of the the brain’s sprawling, tangled network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cortex is divided up into many different areas. Old schemes for dividing up the areas just used numbering. These numbers have been handed down to us from epic studies by unfathomably dedicated neuroanatomists in the early twentieth century. They finely sliced up brains, stained the slices to pick out the neurons, and then minutely examined the changes in the density, size, and shape of neurons across the brains. Each place where there was a change in one of those things got a number. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The temptation is to then think that these subtle differences in neurons correspond to different functions. We followed that temptation by turning many of those numbers into names: primary motor cortex; secondary motor cortex; primary somatosensory cortex; visual cortex. But in the human cortex Brodmann found 52 areas. von Economo and Koskinas found 107. Hmmm. One may reasonably ask: if just dividing up the cortex by changes in the shape, size, or density of neurons actually tells us something about what the different areas do, how come the numbers of areas were so different?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature18933&quot;&gt;massive fMRI study&lt;/a&gt; used a bunch of ways to isolate different parts of cortex, and ended up with 180 different regions. Far more then the slice-and-stain guys. Which is right? None of them. Those lovely differences in cells are immaterial to actual function. Any given function we care to name — seeing, jumping, talking, putting our DVDs in thematic order because we’re not culturally illiterate barbarians — engages many areas of cortex, and many areas of the brain, at the same time. The names and numbers are misleading, are irrelevant to how evolution has driven the wiring of the brain to perform a function.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cortex has names for its layers too. Names straight out of a Dan Brown novel: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and — wait for it — 6. In rodents, some areas have six layers, and some have five because they are missing layer 4. And as the textbooks will tell you, it stands to reason that motor cortex and somatosensory cortex have different functions because motor cortex doesn’t have a layer 4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an object lesson in the problems of naming: we could not name a clear cell “layer 4” in motor cortex, because we couldn’t see one. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.05422&quot;&gt;there is one&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/37/9/2435&quot;&gt;it’s&lt;/a&gt; been there all along. What would you bet me that it will turn out the rat prefrontal cortex does have a “layer 4” after all — a set of neurons that are specifically targeted by input from thalamus and then connect to other neurons in the cortex without projecting outwards — just not in a distinct layer we can see by colouring in neurons? Evolution doesn’t care that we can name five layers in one region, or six in another. In only cares what they do to keep the animal alive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To evolution, the brain is just a gigantic bag of cells, wired together. The purpose of that gigantic bag of cells is to contribute to the survival of the organism in which it resides, to surviving long enough to reproduce. Those that reproduce, win; those that don’t, don’t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a random mutation causes or changes the wiring of some neurons to another group of neurons, and that mutation improves the chances of having offspring, it will likely spread through the population. If that random mutation adds connections from prefrontal cortex to visual cortex; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2017.04.024&quot;&gt;cortical interneurons to a structure outside cortex&lt;/a&gt;; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwj3-rPFu-7YAhVRSsAKHc88AqkQFgg0MAE&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cell.com%2Fneuron%2Fabstract%2FS0896-6273%252812%252900281-4&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw2p6o-v_lthY7HSWHGFWdUe&quot;&gt;motor cortex to midbrain dopamine neurons&lt;/a&gt;, then it will happen. Evolution will not feel sorry that it’s just ruined another set of textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it is just a giant bag of cells wired together. Our best evidence that it is not — that we can cling to our names of all the bits — come from studies where we cut a bit out or turn a bit off. When we cut out area X and we see a “deficit” in behaviour Y of an animal (like tying its shoelaces), then we think “aha! Area X is for tying shoelaces”. No. For starters, we never see a complete and permanent end to behaviour Y. We normally see that the animal is simply worse at doing or learning Y — not that it cannot do Y at all. The brain can carry on doing Y just fine, thanks, just not as well — there is massive redundancy in the brain. Like what you’d find if it was a giant bag of cells, wired together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, seeing that behaviour Y gets worse logically tells us little about what area X is actually doing. It just tells us that damaging area X causes problems. Which on reflection isn’t surprising as you just ripped a chunk out of the brain. The logical fallacy is simple to demonstrate. I am right now going to make a new startling new prediction of how the mouse brain works: the ventrolateral medulla is necessary for mice to learn to associate pictures of Benedict Cumberbatch with food. Cut out the ventrolateral medulla, and a mouse will not learn to associate pictures of Benedict Cumberbatch with food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because it will be dead. The ventrolateral medulla contains the neurons which control the rhythm of breathing. Cut it out: no breathing. Ergo, no learning. Is the ventrolateral medulla a crucial brain area for learning? No. But by damaging it, we damage something vital to the process of learning. Thus, cutting a bit that we’ve given a name can have an effect on that named thing, and we learn nothing at all. Except that we have damaged a big bag of cells, wired together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s more remarkable is when cutting bits out has &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; effect. If we cut some bits of brain out before learning we see an effect — learning is made slower or worse or both; but when we cut them out after learning, it has no apparent effect whatsoever. These bits of brain have become completely redundant. Again: giant bag of cells, wired together — there are many ways within that bag of cells to solve the problem at hand, enough for the brain to just stop using a bit of itself altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And people get hyper-excited about finding odd signals where they were utterly unexpected. Like finding that reward changes activity in primary visual cortex. Or finding that sound is encoded in the hippocampus. These are great, interesting studies. But to be surprised by them is to fall into the naming fallacy. Evolution does not know nor care that we called this chunk of neurons the “hippocampus”. It is just another bag of neurons, connected to many other bags of neurons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Names. Names are vital. Names mean we can all be sure we’re talking about the same thing. They identify whopping great phalanxes of neural tissue; they identify individual neurons; they let us compare brains of different creatures. But we have to handle them with care, less we confuse the label with the contents. Evolution only cares about the contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And development doesn’t give a damn what we call a brain region either. But that’s a tale for another time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=1c9c5f80ab89&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike/evolution-doesnt-give-a-damn-what-you-think-a-brain-region-is-called-1c9c5f80ab89&quot;&gt;Evolution doesn’t give a damn what you think a brain region is called&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike&quot;&gt;The Spike&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Humphries</name>
			<uri>https://medium.com/the-spike?source=rss----c92c31591e3a---4</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Spike - Medium</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The science of the brain, from the scientists of the brain - Medium</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://medium.com/feed/the-spike"/>
			<id>https://medium.com/the-spike?source=rss----c92c31591e3a---4</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Stars with too much lithium may have stolen it</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/stars-too-much-lithium-may-have-stolen-it"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/stars-too-much-lithium-may-have-stolen-it</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Some small stars have extra lithium before they grow old, suggesting they get extra amounts of the element from an external source.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researcher at Japan stem cell institute falsified nearly all images in 2017 paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/23/researcher-japan-stem-cell-institute-falsified-nearly-images-2017-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53549</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T15:42:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;An investigation by Kyoto University in Japan has found a researcher guilty of falsifying all but one of the figures in a 2017 stem cell paper. Yesterday, Kyoto University announced that the paper’s first author, Kohei Yamamizu, had fabricated and falsified data in the Stem Cell Reports paper. According to the investigation report, none of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/23/researcher-japan-stem-cell-institute-falsified-nearly-images-2017-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher at Japan stem cell institute falsified nearly all images in 2017 paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author under fire on PubPeer issues puzzling correction to chem paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/23/author-fire-pubpeer-issues-puzzling-correction-chem-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53538</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T13:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher whose work has been heavily questioned on PubPeer has corrected a figure on a 2015 paper in Talanta — but the text of the correction doesn’t match the actual changes. Recently, Rashmi Madhuri at the Indian Institute of Technology (Indian School of Mines) in Dhanbad corrected a 2015 paper about a diagnostic sensor that uses […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/23/author-fire-pubpeer-issues-puzzling-correction-chem-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author under fire on PubPeer issues puzzling correction to chem paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New technique could help spot snooping drones</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-technique-could-help-spot-snooping-drones"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-technique-could-help-spot-snooping-drones</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T12:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 There may be a new way to tell if a drone is creeping on you or your home.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">At Harvard, developing software to spot misused images in science</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/at-harvard-developing-software-to-spot-misused-images-in-science"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/at-harvard-developing-software-to-spot-misused-images-in-science</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T10:08:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 With support from Elsevier, a team is developing a tool to detect manipulated and misused images en route to publication</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Something we could use a little more of – studies link intellectual humility with openness to other viewpoints</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/23/something-we-could-use-a-little-more-of-studies-link-intellectual-humility-with-openness-to-other-viewpoints/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33080</id>
		<updated>2018-01-23T10:04:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-657572862.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33082&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33082&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tell Me More&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1483269109&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;67&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tell Me More&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tell Me More&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-657572862.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-657572862.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-657572862.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2237,1340&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/23/something-we-could-use-a-little-more-of-studies-link-intellectual-humility-with-openness-to-other-viewpoints/tell-me-more/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-657572862.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in 2018, the default reaction to encountering someone who disagrees with you is to place your fingers in your ears. The US government went into shut down following an impasse in Congress. Meanwhile, the UK remains bitterly divided over Brexit. We could all benefit from a dose of intellectual humility, according to the authors of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15298868.2017.1361861&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Self and Identity&lt;/em&gt;. People with this trait are open to other viewpoints and see disagreement as an opportunity to learn. Promisingly, early findings suggest that it may be possible to foster intellectual humility relatively easily, as least over the short term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33080&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenelle Porter and Karina Schumann at the University of Pittsburgh created a new intellectual humility questionnaire that asks participants to rate their agreement with 9 items like “I am willing to admit if I don’t know something”. The questionnaire is based on their conception of intellectual humility as recognising your own fallibility and the value and intellectual competence of others. Find the full list of items below (the letter R at the end of a statement means that greater agreement is a sign of &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; humility):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33081&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-01-22 15.25.44.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33081&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33081&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-01-22 15.25.44&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-22-15-25-44.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-22-15-25-44.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-22-15-25-44.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2960,948&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/23/something-we-could-use-a-little-more-of-studies-link-intellectual-humility-with-openness-to-other-viewpoints/screenshot-2018-01-22-15-25-44/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-22-15-25-44.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15298868.2017.1361861&quot;&gt;Porter and Schumann, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an initial study, nearly 200 students completed this questionnaire, as well as other personality measures, and then they were asked to imagine various scenarios at college that involved a classmate disagreeing with them, for example over the causes of World War I in history class, or a passage of text in English class. Finally, the students stated what they would think of the person who disagreed with them and how they would respond. A second study was similar, but this time nearly 200 more participants, recruited online, imagined a disagreement with another person over more hot-button issues, such as gun control and same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across both studies, even after accounting for the influence of many other factors such as a person’s self-esteem, narcissism, and overall agreeableness, openness and humility, the students who scored higher on intellectual humility tended to think about the person who disagreed with them in more constructive ways – for instance, believing the other person has their own unique perspective and experiences to draw on – rather than dismissing their views as due to low intelligence or lack of understanding. Moreover, those participants with greater intellectual humility were more likely to say that, given the chance, they would try to learn more about the other person’s views, rather than simply argue with them or try to change their mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a limit to how much we can read into participants’ responses to hypothetical scenarios. To test actual behaviour, Porter and Schumann turned to Amazon’s Mechanical Turk survey website and asked nearly 200 people to complete the intellectual humility questionnaire before revealing their position on gun control or capital punishment. Next, the participants had the chance to read opinions (written by the researchers but made to look like the opinions of other survey participants) that either agreed with their stance or took the opposite view. The researchers counted the in-survey links the participants chose to click on to read the different views. Higher scorers in intellectual humility held views that were just as strong as those low in intellectual humility, but they spent a greater proportion of time reading views that were opposed to their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be great if we all had a little more intellectual humility? The researchers tested an intervention that they hoped would increase intellectual humility via the promotion of a “growth mindset” – that is, belief in the malleability of intelligence. It makes sense that if you see intelligence as malleable, then you will be less worried about finding out you are wrong or that you don’t know the full story. After all, with this perspective, just because you are wrong or ignorant about something doesn’t mean you are forever condemned to being stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final study showed that participants who read a popular magazine article about the malleability of intelligence (designed to foster a “growth mindset”) subsequently scored higher on intellectual humility than another group who read an article about intelligence being fixed. What’s more, those in the growth mindset condition went on to display a more positive approach when imagining dealing with someone with opposing views, and this seemed to be driven by their increased intellectual humility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world in which we seem to find it harder than ever to listen to the other side, this research is welcome. On the other hand, it’s sure to attract accusations of demonstrating the obvious. For their part, the researchers claim this is the first attempt to show there is a relation between intellectual humility and openness to opposing views. Another problem is the studies relied rather too much on hypothetical scenarios and all involved participants resident in the US. Hopefully, though, this paper will serve as a launch pad for future research that will overcome these shortcomings, and discover more about the roots of intellectual humility and how to nurture it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Promoting intellectual humility may offer one path to making disagreements more constructive,” the researchers concluded, “and our research suggests that teaching people a malleable view of intelligence may be one promising way to foster intellectual humility and its associated benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15298868.2017.1361861&quot;&gt;Intellectual humility and openness to the opposing view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Fracking paper overstated size of methane leak from Marcellus Shale, earning retraction</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/fracking-paper-overstated-size-methane-leak-marcellus-shale-earning-retraction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53542</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T22:31:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last spring, a group of environmental scientists reported an impressive finding: Hydraulic fracturing (better known as fracking) in the Marcellus Shale region of the eastern United States was leaking enough methane to power a city twice the size of Washington, D.C. (We didn’t come up with that comparison, apt though it may be.) Turns out […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/fracking-paper-overstated-size-methane-leak-marcellus-shale-earning-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fracking paper overstated size of methane leak from Marcellus Shale, earning retraction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s the key ingredient that lets a centipede’s bite take down prey</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/centipede-bite-epilepsy-drug"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/centipede-bite-epilepsy-drug</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T22:25:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newly identified “spooky toxin” launches a broad attack but might be eased with a version of a known drug.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mysterious high-energy particles could come from black hole jets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-high-energy-particles-could-come-black-hole-jets"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-high-energy-particles-could-come-black-hole-jets</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T20:48:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Three types of high-energy cosmic particles could all have the same source:  black holes in galaxy clusters.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: When data went missing, lab tech filled in the gaps</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/caught-notice-data-went-missing-lab-tech-filled-gaps/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53532</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T16:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Effects of cyclin E gene silencing on the proliferation of esophageal cancer cell lines, EC9706, Eca109 and KYSE30 What Caught Our Attention: When a reader noticed that six panels in one figure from a 2013 paper looked a little fishy, the authors decided to take a closer look. Following an internal investigation, the authors […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/caught-notice-data-went-missing-lab-tech-filled-gaps/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: When data went missing, lab tech filled in the gaps&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Massive dust storms are robbing Mars of its water</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-dust-storms-water"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-dust-storms-water</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mars was once lush with water. A new analysis of Martian climate data shows a mechanism that might have helped dehydrate the planet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author retracts 2009 chemistry paper with “heavily doctored” images</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/author-retracts-2009-chemistry-paper-heavily-doctored-images/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53500</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T13:00:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher has retracted a 2009 chemistry paper after discovering that a figure had been “inappropriately edited.” According to the journal, a reader brought the images in question in Figure 1 to the editors’ attention last September. Timothy P. Lodge, distinguished professor at the University of Minnesota in Minneapolis — and editor of Macromolecules through December […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/22/author-retracts-2009-chemistry-paper-heavily-doctored-images/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author retracts 2009 chemistry paper with “heavily doctored” images&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘First Face of America’ explores how humans reached the New World</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-face-america-explores-how-humans-reached-new-world"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-face-america-explores-how-humans-reached-new-world</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New documentary shows how an ancient teen and an infant have illuminated scientists’ understanding of the peopling of the Americas.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Helping PhD students collaborate internationally with Fulbright-Elsevier partnership</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/helping-phd-students-collaborate-internationally-with-fulbright-elsevier-partnership"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/helping-phd-students-collaborate-internationally-with-fulbright-elsevier-partnership</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T10:13:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fulbright scholarships sponsored by Elsevier give young researchers the opportunity to study at top US universities</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">New Consulting Editor for BMC Cancer</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/22/new-consulting-editor-for-bmc-cancer/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9782</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T10:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/Mathematics-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-9590&quot; height=&quot;293&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/Mathematics-e1509098029578.jpg&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal journey to biostatistics has been quite unorthodox and convoluted; funnily, many colleagues around the world share my non-linear experience. After I received my degree in pharmacology, I spent some years in different post graduate courses, while working for a small pharmaceutical company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story suddenly changed when I fell in love with clinical pharmacology and pharmacokinetics (PK). After a training course at Karolinska Institutet in Stockholm, I got a Ph.D. dedicated to PK trials in oncology and then a post-doctoral position at University of Southern California, PK Lab in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very quickly realised that it would be impossible to manage complex PK studies without a good training in statistics; PK was more and more becoming a critical add-on to many oncology studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I qualified as a clinical epidemiologist/biostatistician, I found that the leap from PK models to biostatistics for oncology clinical trials was almost immediate. I could directly take part in the development of new chemotherapeutics regimens, even without the dependence on the facilities of a classical drug monitoring lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to share my ideas, interact with the study’s physicians and to support their inferences with my biostatistics models (or sometimes denying them too!) has been very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since, I have been closely collaborating with oncologists, planning, performing and reporting more than a hundred human trials: hospital life has been one of the most enriching experiences of my life, not to mention its didactics value. The opportunity to share my ideas, interact with the study’s physicians and to support their inferences with my biostatistics models (or sometimes denying them too!) has been very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, I have been focusing on my editorial responsibilities, particularly with the &lt;em&gt;BMC-s&lt;/em&gt;eries journals. I have been given the opportunity to serve as Associate Editor in three different &lt;em&gt;BMC-&lt;/em&gt;series journals, &lt;em&gt;BMC Cancer&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes.&lt;/em&gt; I also serve as an Editorial Advisor for the &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series. My collaboration with the &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series has been highly rewarding, as I have been driven by two main motivations; my curiosity to continuously learn new and emerging topics from our international authorship and the opportunity to stay updated on established ones: both of them have been satisfied. Naturally, this has translated into a notable improvement in my research career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always tried to be a very humble and open minded assessor, but the chances to be critical have not been lacking: new manuscripts in the field of cancer research show a widespread level of quality with regards to biostatistics. Why does this happen? There could be several different reasons. So here is some advice for potential authors on getting biostatistics right:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for the support of statistical advisers not only before but even during the peer-review process, since it’s not always solicited by default from the single editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the minimum acceptable criteria for basic statistical reporting in biomedical journals, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/sampl/&quot;&gt;SAMPL&lt;/a&gt; guidelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the minimum acceptable criteria for the standardization of clinical protocol items, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/spirit-2013-statement-defining-standard-protocol-items-for-clinical-trials/&quot;&gt;SPIRIT&lt;/a&gt; guidelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systematic reviews and meta-analyses might not meet the classical standards; in that case, you should properly consider the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/prisma/&quot;&gt;PRISMA&lt;/a&gt; guidelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A formal sample size estimation is not always present in the manuscripts. Don’t forget that this information is critical for your reviewers and readers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, there is a myriad of considerations and arguments that deserve to be covered. I look forward to working with the esteemed editorial and statistical advisory boards of &lt;em&gt;BMC Cancer&lt;/em&gt; and I warmly encourage the respectable reader to share their ideas or insights on the intersection of biostatistics with the field of cancer research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/22/new-consulting-editor-for-bmc-cancer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;New Consulting Editor for &lt;em&gt;BMC Cancer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Roberto Passera</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Self-control and cognitive control are not the same thing</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/22/self-control-and-cognitive-control-are-not-the-same-thing/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33047</id>
		<updated>2018-01-22T09:23:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-478587633.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33071&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33071&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cogs in the shape of a human brain.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;JOZSEF HUNOR VILHELEM&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cogs in the shape of a human brain.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cogs in the shape of a human brain.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-478587633.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-478587633.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-478587633.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1802,1663&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/22/self-control-and-cognitive-control-are-not-the-same-thing/cogs-in-the-shape-of-a-human-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-478587633.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s common for psychologists to use the terms “self-control” and “cognitive control” interchangeably. Consider the introduction to a review &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364661313002945&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published recently in &lt;em&gt;Trends in Cognitive Sciences&lt;/em&gt; on whether our &lt;em&gt;self-control&lt;/em&gt; is limited or not (I’ve added the emphases): “Whereas &lt;em&gt;cognitive control&lt;/em&gt; relies on at least three separate (yet related) executive functions – task switching, working-memory, and inhibition – at its heart, &lt;em&gt;self-control&lt;/em&gt; is most clearly related to inhibitory &lt;em&gt;cognitive control&lt;/em&gt; …”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When scholars do make a distinction, they mostly use self-control to refer to the ability to delay immediate gratification in the service of a longer-term goal, whereas they use the term cognitive control to refer to the related ability to ignore distracting information or stimuli. Defined this way, do self-control and cognitive control essentially involve the same mental processes? According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001691816303870#bb0115&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; by Stefan Scherbaum at Technische Universität Dresden and his colleagues in &lt;em&gt;Acta Psychologica&lt;/em&gt;, they do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33047&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forty-eight student participants completed alternating trials of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simon_effect&quot;&gt;Simon Test&lt;/a&gt; and “inter-temporal” decision making (i.e. deciding between immediate or more distant rewards). This was a mash up of a well-established cognitive control test and an established self-control test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Simon task, which taps cognitive control, required the participants to indicate as fast as possible the direction of an on-screen arrow, while ignoring the arrow’s screen location. On incongruent trials where the arrow’s direction and screen location are in opposition (e.g. a left-ward pointing arrow on the right side of the screen), it takes cognitive control to perform well at the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the inter-temporal decisions, the students had to choose between smaller cash rewards now or larger cash rewards later (they were asked to pretend these were real decisions). It takes self-control to resist smaller immediate rewards for longer-term larger gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A critical phenomenon that occurs during the Simon Task is that while people are generally slower on incongruent trials, completing one incongruent trial leads to improved performance on a subsequent incongruent trial, as if one’s powers of cognitive control have been activated or engaged. Scherbaum and his colleagues’ ingenious idea was to see if this effect would spill over into the decision making trials. Would participants, after having their cognitive control activated by an incongruent Simon Task trial, show more self-control when making a financial decision immediately afterwards?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If cognitive control and self-control essentially involve the same cognitive processes, then the researchers should have found this spill-over effect between the two types of trial, but in fact there was no evidence for this in the results, not a hint of it. In a further analysis the researchers also couldn’t see any evidence of self-control processes, as measured by participants’ making more patient financial decisions, having any effect on their cognitive control, as measured by their subsequent Simon Task performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this study isn’t conclusive. It’s possible that different measures of cognitive control and self-control might in future uncover some overlap. However, what the new findings do suggest is that, at least to a degree, the two constructs depend on different mental processes that operate independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers concluded: “While both cognitive control and self-control may be observed when we control and steer our behavior toward the pursuit of long-term goals, they may depend on different underlying processes such as the avoidance of distraction – in the case of cognitive control – or resisting short-term temptations – in the case of self-control.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most contentious areas in psychology at present is the question of whether our willpower or self-control is a limited resource or not, as proposed by the theory of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/?s=ego-depletion&quot;&gt;ego-depletion&lt;/a&gt;“. This new paper may lead us to wonder whether confusion around the related concepts of self-control and cognitive control has contributed to disagreements and inconsistencies in the research into ego-depletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A greater understanding of the different mental processes that contribute to self-control and cognitive control might also contribute to better designed interventions for improving people’s focus, goal-planning and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001691816303870#bb0130&quot;&gt;No evidence for common processes of cognitive control and self-control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Does Psychology Need SWaG? The Ethics of Naturalistic Experiments</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9323"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9323</id>
		<updated>2018-01-21T16:59:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Diederik Stapel. Brian Wansink. Nicolas Guéguen. Anyone who's been following recent debates over research integrity in psychology will recognize these as three prolific and successful academic psychologists who have suffered a total (Stapel) or ongoing (Wansink, Guéguen) fall from grace in the past few years.

If you're not familiar with these cases, you can start by reading over Nick Brown's blog. Brown has been at the centre of the investigations into irregularities in Wansink and Guéguen, a</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Why scientists respond badly to criticism; hidden retractions; journal cancels issue</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/20/weekend-reads-scientists-respond-badly-criticism-hidden-retractions-journal-cancels-issue/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53526</id>
		<updated>2018-01-20T14:22:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a researcher whose ideas were stolen at least three times, a victory for Crossfit in its attempt to reveal peer reviewers, and the second delisting of a cancer journal by an index that praised it just months ago. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Peer review trains scientists to respond […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/20/weekend-reads-scientists-respond-badly-criticism-hidden-retractions-journal-cancels-issue/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Why scientists respond badly to criticism; hidden retractions; journal cancels issue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New twist on a flu vaccine revs up the body’s army of virus killers</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-twist-flu-vaccine-revs-bodys-army-virus-killers"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-twist-flu-vaccine-revs-bodys-army-virus-killers</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T20:42:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new approach to flu vaccine development makes influenza virus extra sensitive to a powerful antiviral system.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1262</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T18:00:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Judge orders journal to identify peer reviewers: CrossFit lawyer</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/19/judge-orders-journal-identify-peer-reviewers-crossfit-lawyer/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53515</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T19:05:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A court is reportedly telling a journal to unmask a retracted paper’s peer reviewers, part of a defamation lawsuit involving the journal’s publisher and the CrossFit exercise brand. According to an attorney representing CrossFit, yesterday Judge Joel Wohlfeil of the San Diego Superior Court decided that the National Strength and Conditioning Association (NSCA) must turn […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/19/judge-orders-journal-identify-peer-reviewers-crossfit-lawyer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Judge orders journal to identify peer reviewers: CrossFit lawyer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cilia in the brain may be busier than previously thought</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cilia-brain-may-be-busier-previously-thought"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cilia-brain-may-be-busier-previously-thought</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T18:16:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A hairlike appendage sticking out of brain cells may be much more important in the brain than scientists realized.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1262</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T18:00:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Light pollution can prolong the risk of sparrows passing along West Nile virus</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/light-pollution-can-prolong-risk-sparrows-passing-along-west-nile-virus"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/light-pollution-can-prolong-risk-sparrows-passing-along-west-nile-virus</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Nighttime lighting prolongs time that birds can pass along virus to mosquitoes that bite people.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1262</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T18:00:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Indexing company praises cancer journal, then kicks it out</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/19/indexing-company-praises-cancer-journal-kicks/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53496</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T13:11:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A company that indexes journals — which, in turn, designates their impact factors — has delisted Oncotarget, a cancer journal that was recently removed from MEDLINE. Just three months ago, on October 18, the indexing company Clarivate Analytics (formerly part of Thomson Reuters) named Oncotarget a “rising star” in the field of molecular biology and genetics. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/19/indexing-company-praises-cancer-journal-kicks/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Indexing company praises cancer journal, then kicks it out&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, IUDs were deemed safe and effective</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-iuds-were-deemed-safe-and-effective"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-iuds-were-deemed-safe-and-effective</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 50 year ago, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration declared intrauterine devices safe and effective, though officials didn’t know how the IUDs worked.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1262</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T18:00:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Psilocybin (from magic mushrooms) plus meditation and spiritual training leads to lasting changes in positive traits</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/19/psilocybin-from-magic-mushrooms-plus-meditation-and-spiritual-training-leads-to-lasting-changes-in-positive-traits/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33066</id>
		<updated>2018-01-19T08:59:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-512153806.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33067&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33067&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Closeup shot of experimental growth of Psyllocubin mushrooms aka psychedelic mushrooms. Lit by gel colored flashes to represent the effect.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1456430525&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;gilaxia&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Magic mushrooms.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Magic mushrooms.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-512153806.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-512153806.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-512153806.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1800,1666&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/19/psilocybin-from-magic-mushrooms-plus-meditation-and-spiritual-training-leads-to-lasting-changes-in-positive-traits/magic-mushrooms/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-512153806.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Conferences on psychedelics are popping up everywhere, like mushrooms!” said Jakobien van der Weijden, of the Psychedelic Society of the Netherlands, when I met her in Amsterdam last week. Indeed, research into the use of psychedelic (mind-altering) drugs as tools in the treatment of depression, post-traumatic stress disorder and end-of-life angst, is on the increase. Psilocybin, the active ingredient in magic mushrooms, may help to alleviate symptoms of depression by altering brain activity in key areas &lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.imperial.ac.uk/newsandeventspggrp/imperialcollege/newssummary/news_12-1-2018-14-13-41&quot;&gt;involved in emotional processing&lt;/a&gt;, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0269881117731279&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Psychopharmacology&lt;/i&gt;, led by Roland Griffiths at Johns Hopkins University, has found that for mentally and physically healthy volunteers, two doses of psilocybin in conjunction with a programme of meditation and other “spiritual” practices was enough to bring about lasting, positive changes to traits including altruism, gratitude, forgiveness and feeling close to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33066&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers recruited 75 healthy adults, with an average age of 42, from the general population, and allocated them at random to one of three groups. The first group enrolled in “standard-level” support for spiritual practice, which consisted of a meditation book plus five hours meditation and spiritual training with an experienced “guide”. These participants then took two very low doses of psilocybin (just 1mg per 70kg – intended to act as a placebo), spaced one month apart, with each dose followed by a discussion of the experience with their spiritual guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second group of participants had the same level of spiritual practice support, but they were given higher doses of psilocybin – 20 mg/70kg for the first dose, and 30mg/70kg for the second (both fit into the range of dosages likely from recreational use of magic mushrooms.). Earlier studies have shown that psilocybin has various effects on the brain. It &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-13282-7&quot;&gt;reduces blood flow in the amygdala&lt;/a&gt;, which is involved in emotional responses, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third group took the higher doses of psilocybin but also had far more extensive support and face-to-face time with their guides, and this continued for four months after their second dose of psilocybin. This included taking part in twice-monthly, 90-minute group dialogue sessions, in which they were encouraged to focus on discussing their successes and challenges in sustaining the regular spiritual practices of meditation, awareness and journaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither the participants nor the guides knew which psilocybin doses they had received. Six months after the start of the study, both of the high-dose groups showed large, statistically significant positive changes on measures of interpersonal closeness, gratitude, life meaning or purpose, death transcendence, daily spiritual experiences, and religious faith and coping, whereas the placebo group did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high-dose, high-support group scored highest on all the scales. In some cases, such as life meaning and a rating of life “strivings” as being sacred or spiritual, they scored much higher. Unlike the high dose/standard support group, they also showed a big increase in trait forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers noted, “Strikingly, more than half of participants in the high spiritual support condition rated their experience in one or both psilocybin sessions as the single most spiritually significant experience of their life, with 96 per cent rating it as among the top five most spiritually significant experiences.” In contrast, the percentages for the high-dose, standard support group were 40 per cent and 76 per cent respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the differences in their perception of the sessions, and their rates of engagement with meditation and other spiritual practices, that explained why the high-support, high-dose group showed larger trait changes and more intense spiritual experiences than the modest-support high-dose group, the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that the people recruited for the study all responded to an advert for volunteers who were interested in “developing their spiritual lives by participating in a study of the combined effects of meditation and psilocybin”. It’s not clear, then, whether this kind of programme could help people who aren’t particularly interested in developing their spiritual lives. Since there was no low-dose, high-support group, it’s also hard to be sure how important psilocybin was to the observed effects – perhaps the intensive “spiritual practices” and support were the more critical ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the work does suggest that further investigation of the effects of psilocybin may in theory lead to new interventions, not only to help people with a mental health disorder, but to create positive changes in attitudes and behaviour in healthy people. But there would have to be a change in the law. At the moment, in the UK, as in many other countries, psilocybin can only be consumed legally as part of an approved academic research programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other researchers involved in studies of psychedelic drugs have stressed that this work is still experimental, and have warned against self-medication. Magic mushrooms and closely-related psilocybin-containing truffles (which are legal in the Netherlands), contain varying levels of the drug, so it’s impossible to be sure of the dosage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0269881117731279&quot;&gt;Psilocybin-occasioned mystical-type experience in combination with meditation and other spiritual practices produces enduring positive changes in psychological functioning and in trait measures of prosocial attitudes and behaviors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The secret to icky, sticky bacterial biofilms lies in the microbes’ cellulose</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/secret-bacterial-biofilms-microbes-modified-cellulose"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/secret-bacterial-biofilms-microbes-modified-cellulose</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T19:31:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Bacteria use a modified form of cellulose to form sticky networks that can coat various surfaces.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T12:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Volume of fracking fluid pumped underground tied to Canada quakes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/volume-fracking-fluid-pumped-underground-tied-canada-quakes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/volume-fracking-fluid-pumped-underground-tied-canada-quakes</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T19:16:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Study links volume of fracking fluid injected underground with hundreds of quakes in central Canada, and not the rate at which the fluids were injected.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=8206</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A robotic arm made of DNA moves at dizzying speed</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/robotic-arm-made-dna-moves-dizzying-speed"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/robotic-arm-made-dna-moves-dizzying-speed</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T19:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A DNA machine with a high-speed arm could pave the way for nanoscale factories.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=8206</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dwight Bergles PhD</title>
		<link href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Entries/2018/1/18_Dwight_Bergles_PhD.html"/>
		<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/61708b34-d640-40ea-9db3-805b26a2c2f6</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T17:29:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 Dwight Bergles (Johns Hopkins) discusses a fourth and mysterious class of CNS glial cells, oligodendrocyte precursor cells. 

Duration: 46 minutes

Discussants:(in alphabetical order)
Carlos Paladini (Professor, UTSA)
Salma Quraishi (Res Asst Prof, UTSA)
Todd Troyer (Assoc Prof, UTSA) 
Charles Wilson (Ewing Halsell Chair, UTSA)

acknowledgement: JM Tepper for original music.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dwight Bergles PhD</name>
			<uri>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">NEUROSCIENTISTS TALK SHOP</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Neuroscientists Talk Shop is the University of Texas at San Antonio's (UTSA) Neurobiology Podcast, showcasing the current research of internationally renowned guest Neuroscientists. Each episode features a moderated discussion with a cross section of UTSA</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/rss.xml"/>
			<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Salma Quraishi</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hunter-gatherer lifestyle could help explain superior ability to ID smells</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hunter-gatherer-lifestyle-could-help-explain-superior-ability-id-smells"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hunter-gatherer-lifestyle-could-help-explain-superior-ability-id-smells</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T17:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Hunter-gatherers in the forests of the Malay Peninsula prove more adept at naming smells than their rice-farming neighbors, possibly because of their foraging culture.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=8206</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Is our database missing a retraction? Tell us!</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/18/database-missing-retraction-tell-us/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53479</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T16:00:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;As many readers know, we’ve been hard at work curating a comprehensive database of retractions, and are now up to more than 16,000 entries. Despite that large number — as much as triple what you’ll find in commonly used databases — we know there are notices we’re missing. We’re doing our best to fill in […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/18/database-missing-retraction-tell-us/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Is our database missing a retraction? Tell us!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“A painful lesson:” Authors retract paper after discovering mislabeled mouse lines</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/18/painful-lesson-authors-retract-paper-discovering-mislabeled-mouse-lines/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53469</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T13:00:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Neuroscientists have retracted a 2016 paper examining the genetic underpinnings of a degenerative motor neuron disease, after discovering that two mouse lines had been accidentally mislabeled. According to the retraction notice, published in December in Acta Neuropathologica Communications, mice engineered to have a specific genetic mutation were mislabeled as the normal or wild type group. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/18/painful-lesson-authors-retract-paper-discovering-mislabeled-mouse-lines/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“A painful lesson:” Authors retract paper after discovering mislabeled mouse lines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T00:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">“Not as bad as you think”: women who’ve gone through the menopause have a more positive take than those who haven’t</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/18/not-as-bad-as-you-think-women-whove-gone-through-the-menopause-have-a-more-positive-take-than-those-who-havent/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33056</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T09:32:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-495802268.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33063&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33063&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1Ds Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Happy middle aged woman with arms outstretched in autumn&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1446828136&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;absolutimages&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Happy middle aged woman with arms outstretched&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Happy middle aged woman with arms outstretched&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-495802268.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-495802268.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-495802268.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/18/not-as-bad-as-you-think-women-whove-gone-through-the-menopause-have-a-more-positive-take-than-those-who-havent/happy-middle-aged-woman-with-arms-outstretched/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-495802268.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion of the menopause tends be negative. Take the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p05tx859&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; introduction to “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p05tpw79&quot;&gt;menopause week&lt;/a&gt;” held this week on BBC Radio 4 and BBC Radio Sheffield. The well-meaning presenters talk of “distress”, the impact, the “troubling” changes, and “how to get through it”. Of course the aim is to support and educate, and it’s important to acknowledge the seriousness of some women’s problems. However, there’s arguably a risk that an overly negative tone perpetuates beliefs and stereotypes that may foster unjustified dread about the menopause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0167482X.2017.1368486&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of PsychoSomatic Obstetrics and Gynecology&lt;/em&gt;, involving nearly 400 women aged between 40 and 60, overall women have a positive view of the menopause. What’s more, women who’ve gone through the menopause have a more positive take on it than those who’ve yet to start or who are in the middle of it. “In other words,” write Lydia Brown at the University of Melbourne and her colleagues, “for most women the menopausal transition may turn out to be not as bad as they think”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33056&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers asked their participants to complete the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/247510899_Cognitive_appraisal_of_the_menopause_The_menopause_representations_questionnaire_MRQ&quot;&gt;Menopausal Representations Questionnaire&lt;/a&gt; that includes questions about symptoms they attribute to the menopause, their thoughts and beliefs about the consequences of the menopause, the menopause timeline, and their perceptions of control. The researchers also devised a new scale addressing the participants’ emotions in relation to the menopause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, participants said whether they felt (or expected to feel) anxious or less confident; whether they thought the menopause would last a long time; whether they were anxious about it; whether they were, or would be, pleased to be free of the risk of pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women’s responses were positive overall. On average they disagreed that the menopause made them feel upset, angry or afraid, although they agreed it made them feel somewhat anxious and slightly more depressed. The women agreed most strongly with statements about what may be considered advantages to going through the menopause, such as the end of periods and the end of using birth control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33064&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-01-17 11.07.11&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33064&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33064&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-01-17 11.07.11&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-17-11-07-11.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-17-11-07-11.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-17-11-07-11.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1392,1090&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/18/not-as-bad-as-you-think-women-whove-gone-through-the-menopause-have-a-more-positive-take-than-those-who-havent/screenshot-2018-01-17-11-07-11/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/screenshot-2018-01-17-11-07-11.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0167482X.2017.1368486&quot;&gt;Brown et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the sample, 54 of the women were premenopausal, 48 were in the early or later stages of the menopause, and 286 had finished going through the menopause. The postmenopausal women were more positive about the menopause than the women currently going through it, although this difference was modest. In terms of their emotions, the postmenopausal women were more positive about the menopause than the premenopausal women and those currently in the menopause, and the magnitude of this difference was “clinically significant”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers speculated that perhaps the more negative views and emotions of the premenopausal and early menopausal women is related to “affective forecasting theory”, which describes how we tend to overestimate the impact of future events on our emotions, and underestimate our ability to adapt and cope. Alternatively, perhaps the findings are explained by a more general trend for people to become more optimistic as they get older. Alternatively, or as well, maybe the postmenopausal women had developed more effective coping strategies over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the explanation, and while acknowledging that their study was limited by its cross-sectional design (it would be better to study the same women before, during and after the menopause), the researchers said their findings suggest that the more negative views held by premenopausal women may reflect a “degree of stereotype internalisation”. It may be “that the ‘dread’ of the upcoming menopause is culturally influenced”, they said, adding: “Our data show that cognitive and emotional representations of the menopause are most positive in the post menopause, when women have had the lived experience of the menopause”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0167482X.2017.1368486&quot;&gt;It’s not as bad as you think: menopausal representations are more positive in postmenopausal women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Discover the data behind the Times Higher Education World University Rankings</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/discover-the-data-behind-the-times-higher-education-world-university-rankings"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/discover-the-data-behind-the-times-higher-education-world-university-rankings</id>
		<updated>2018-01-18T08:57:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 As a renewed multiyear partnership draws on Elsevier’s Scopus data, we look at how those rankings are created</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ultrathin 2-D metals get their own periodic table</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ultrathin-2-d-metals-get-their-own-periodic-table"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ultrathin-2-d-metals-get-their-own-periodic-table</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T21:34:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new atlas of atom-thick metals could help researchers figure out how these 2-D materials might be used.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=8206</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The mystery of vanishing honeybees is still not definitively solved</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mystery-vanishing-honeybees-still-not-definitively-solved"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mystery-vanishing-honeybees-still-not-definitively-solved</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T18:42:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The case has never been fully closed for colony collapse disorder, and now bees face bigger problems.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=8206</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T18:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal retracts letter for missing disclosure author says he tried to submit</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/17/journal-retracts-letter-missing-disclosure-author-says-tried-submit/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53465</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T16:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;An emergency medicine journal has retracted a letter to the editor, saying it didn’t include the author’s relevant commercial interest—which the author says he tried to disclose when he submitted the paper. The author, Guy Weinberg, told Retraction Watch he had noted his conflict of interest when he submitted the letter last March, but said […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/17/journal-retracts-letter-missing-disclosure-author-says-tried-submit/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal retracts letter for missing disclosure author says he tried to submit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-23T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Authors who lost two papers for plagiarism will be fired from university: report</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/17/authors-lost-two-papers-plagiarism-will-fired-university-report/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53432</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T13:00:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers from Nepal who had two papers retracted last year for plagiarism will face sanctions, according to a local media report. According to coverage last month from Republica, a news outlet in Nepal, the editor of Bali Medical Journal said he will blacklist the six authors. In a follow-up article, Dipak Shrestha, associate dean of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/17/authors-lost-two-papers-plagiarism-will-fired-university-report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors who lost two papers for plagiarism will be fired from university: report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-23T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Most children and teens with gender dysphoria also have multiple other psychological issues</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/17/most-children-and-teens-with-gender-dysphoria-also-have-multiple-other-psychological-issues/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33058</id>
		<updated>2018-01-17T09:22:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-811322022.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33059&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33059&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800E&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Studio shot of a boy wearing a t shirt with \u201cI\u2019m a boy\u201d printed on it against a gray background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1490793305&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Fashion that makes a statement&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Fashion that makes a statement&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-811322022.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-811322022.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-811322022.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/17/most-children-and-teens-with-gender-dysphoria-also-have-multiple-other-psychological-issues/fashion-that-makes-a-statement/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-811322022.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research on gender identity disorder (also known as gender dysphoria, in which a person does not identify with their biological sex) questions how best to handle the condition when it arises in children and adolescents. Should biological treatments be used as early as possible to help a young client transition, or is caution required, in case of complicating psychological issues?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie Bechard of the University of Toronto and her colleagues examined the prevalence of “psychosocial and psychological vulnerabilities” in 50 child and teen cases of gender dysphoria, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0092623X.2016.1232325&quot;&gt;writing in a recent issue of the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Sex and Marital Therapy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, they argue their findings show that physicians should be considering these factors more seriously when deciding on a treatment plan. Salting the situation, one of the paper’s co-authors is Kenneth Zucker, an expert on gender dysphoria who was last year considered too controversial for Canadian state television.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33058&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As recently as 2013, Zucker headed the American Psychiatric Association’s group deciding &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:http%252525253A//displus.sk/DSM/subory/dsm5.pdf&quot;&gt;the diagnostic criteria&lt;/a&gt; for gender dysphoria, but he fell from grace in 2015 when he was fired from his clinic at the Toronto Centre for Addiction and Mental Health for failing to follow the now prominent “gender-affirmative” approach that places a clinical emphasis on smoothing the process of gender transition for children and adolescents who say they no longer identify with their biological sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zucker’s approach, in contrast, was more hesitant and he questioned the ease with which young people can draw conclusions about their gender identity during a universally tumultuous stage of life. He also placed more emphasis on the costs that transition may bear upon an individual. To say that he considered transition a last resort would be as much of a caricature as saying the gender affirmative approach considers it a first resort, but they clearly represent different points on this spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Zucker’s critics he was a transphobe, his approach analogous to gay conversion therapy (the now widely condemned use of psychological therapy to attempt to alter a client’s sexual orientation) – for example, he reportedly advised some parents to discourage their younger children from behaving in ways that contradicted their assigned gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, hostility toward Zucker’s views was substantive enough to lead the Canadian broadcaster CBC to pull a BBC documentary that reported his perspective. For his part,  Zucker continues to maintain that his priority has always been the wellbeing of his clinical charges. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0092623X.2016.1232325&quot;&gt;recent article&lt;/a&gt; that he co-authored with Bechard and others puts into the scientific record one of the concerns of his clinic, that gender dysphoric youth are a psychologically vulnerable population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper examines the case files of 17 people assigned a male gender and 33 people assigned a female gender, at birth, based on their biological sex. Following their experience of gender dysphoria, the clients had been referred to a specialist gender identity service for young people, at which time they were aged 13 to 20. Sixty-four per cent of the clients were homosexual with respect to the gender they were assigned at birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers looked for evidence of 15 factors that can signify or contribute to psychological issues, from self-harm to a previous outpatient therapy visit, and found that over half their sample had six or more of these factors. The majority had two or more prior diagnoses of a psychological disorder, the most common being a mood disorder such as depression. More than half had reported thinking about suicide, a third had dropped out of high school, a quarter had self harmed. A history of sexual abuse was rarer, observed in ”only” 10 per cent of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these measures are likely to be underestimates because they depended on the clients’ own descriptions during their initial interview at the gender identity clinic. Without a control group, it’s hard to say whether these rates of psychological distress are higher than for other client groups. Certainly though, the findings are consistent with the sense that these individuals were already in a state of psychological vulnerability when they were referred for gender dysphoria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bechard’s team present in-depth examples of two clients, both assigned as female at birth, that bring these psychological complexities to life, demonstrating the kinds of situations these cases often involve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first individual was very intelligent but struggling socially, especially around girls. They were fixated on emphasising their femininity in selfies, leading the parents to suspect body dysmorphic disorder (a troubling belief that there is something wrong with one’s body). This individual’s boyfriend then came out as gay. Sometime following this, the client disclosed that they identified as a boy. This change in identity happened “overnight” with no developmental history of cross-gender identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second client’s history is more convoluted: at around age 12-13 this individual had disclosed that they were transgender (now identifying as male), and had felt this way for a while. This individual also had a history of anxiety, social problems interacting with girls, and extreme anxiety about sexuality. From the point of disclosing their gender dysphoria, they also reported that they were gay (oriented towards men) but had no interest in romantic/sexual relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both these cases, after an initial assessment the individual was given testosterone treatment by a physician against the wishes of the parents – in the first case, the physician actually refused to meet the parents, and in the second, the physician recorded that the issues raised by the parents regarding anxiety, sexual and social problems weren’t relevant for the course of action. Sadly, in the case of the second individual, a few months after the start of the hormone treatment, they made a suicide attempt that required hospitalisation; the reasons for this were not reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are the indicators of psychological vulnerability identified in these case histories the consequence, cause or simply coincident to gender identity disorder? If they are all solely a fall-out from the gender dysphoria, then the decisive approach of the physicians described above has a certain sense to it. But if some of the psychological complications pre-dated the gender dysphoria, or were separate from it, then at the very least this would suggest that the consulted physicians should have considered a broader treatment plan, and considered the psychological complications when judging their clients’ “readiness” to commence biomedical treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibility that disclosure of gender dysphoria may in some cases be driven by earlier psychological vulnerabilities and social problems seems likely to be greater than zero. This is a controversial idea among many online trans activists, but actually it isn’t among health practitioners, even those who espouse the gender affirmation philosophy, who recognise that some young gender identity referrals may be transiently mixed-up individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue of pre-existing or concurrent psychological vulnerabilities also speaks to the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sexologytoday.org/2016/01/do-trans-kids-stay-trans-when-they-grow_99.html&quot;&gt;a substantial proportion, perhaps even the majority&lt;/a&gt;, of children who experience some form of gender identity challenge, later come to endorse the gender they were raised as (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sexologytoday.org/2017/12/faulty-statistics-on-how-many-trans.html&quot;&gt;further commentary and discussion&lt;/a&gt;); the new findings may also be relevant to the experience of detransitioning individuals, who reach similar conclusions, but often after a much greater investment in the process of transition – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/education/2017/sep/25/bath-spa-university-transgender-gender-reassignment-reversal-research&quot;&gt;a phenomenon that is struggling to get scientific attention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when a child with gender dysphoria is “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thecut.com/2016/02/fight-over-trans-kids-got-a-researcher-fired.html&quot;&gt;insistent, persistent, and consistent&lt;/a&gt;” over an extended period, then (under the gender affirmative approach) this is typically treated as a good indicator that it is appropriate to begin facilitating the transition process. The trouble is, psychological vulnerabilities can also be persistent, and if a young person feels like they’ve found the solution, it’s understandable that they might not want to let go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life can sometimes feel as complicated as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordian_Knot&quot;&gt;Gordian knot&lt;/a&gt;, the legendary challenge that was seemingly impossible to disentangle. It’s understandable to weigh up a radical solution, like Alexander the Great cleaving the knot with a single sword-stroke: to abandon your external environment for a new home, to step outside of the confines of an identity that may be the source of the myriad issues plaguing you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research from Bechard, Zucker and company provides preliminary evidence about the psychological vulnerabilities of children and teens with gender dysphoria, extending &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/287578799_Merkmale_von_Kindern_und_Jugendlichen_mit_Geschlechtsdysphorie_in_der_Hamburger_Spezialsprechstunde&quot;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25431051&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; that’s shown high rates of self-harm and suicidal ideation in this group, but more research is required to give us the full clinical picture. As such, this new paper represents just the latest sally in a difficult, complicated conversation that’s far from over: a conversation about how we can most compassionately treat those who feel out of step with where they find themselves in the social world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0092623X.2016.1232325&quot;&gt;Psychosocial and Psychological Vulnerability in Adolescents with Gender Dysphoria: A “Proof of Principle” Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Evidence grows that normal childbirth takes longer than we thought</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/evidence-grows-normal-childbirth-takes-longer-we-thought"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/evidence-grows-normal-childbirth-takes-longer-we-thought</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T19:49:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Another study finds that labor lasts longer than is traditionally taught — an insight that could mean fewer unnecessary cesarean deliveries.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_5476601595564273=0.14274284668200365</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:47+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Waneta Hoyt: The Serial Killer Paper</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9311"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9311</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T18:16:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 I just learned about a truly remarkable case in which a doctor apparently wrote a paper about a serial killer who murdered her five children - without realizing what had happened. It's an old case, but it doesn't seem to be widely known today.

The paper is called Prolonged apnea and the sudden infant death syndrome: clinical and laboratory observations and it was written in 1972 by Dr Alfred Steinschneider of Syracuse, New York. In this paper, Steinschneider described the case of a woman, &quot;Mr</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Speed of universe’s expansion remains elusive</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/speed-universe-expansion-remains-elusive"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/speed-universe-expansion-remains-elusive</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T17:52:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A discrepancy between two measures of the universe’s expansion rate suggests the presence of some unknown astronomical feature.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_5476601595564273=0.14274284668200365</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:47+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">CrossFit asks court to unmask peer reviewers of retracted study</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/16/crossfit-asks-court-unmask-peer-reviewers-retracted-study/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53455</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T16:45:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Another front has opened up in the legal battle between the CrossFit exercise brand and a competitor, spurred by a now-retracted paper about the risk of injury from the workout program. Soon, a judge will decide whether CrossFit is entitled to learn the names of the study’s peer reviewers. CrossFit has tried and failed to […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/16/crossfit-asks-court-unmask-peer-reviewers-retracted-study/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CrossFit asks court to unmask peer reviewers of retracted study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Developmental Biology: top three articles of 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/16/bmc-developmental-biology-top-three-articles-of-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9770</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T14:00:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/featureimage-140x110.gif&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcdevbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12861-017-0160-2&quot;&gt;In vivo imaging of epithelial wound healing in the cnidarian &lt;em&gt;Clytia hemisphaerica&lt;/em&gt; demonstrates early evolution of purse string and cell crawling closure mechanisms.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanisms of wound healing have always been a highly discussed topic across many fields of science. In their paper, Kamran et al. discuss cell crawling and purse string mechanisms (a supracellular contractile ring that contracts to draw the wound margins inward) in the cnidarian &lt;em&gt;Clytia hemisphaerica&lt;/em&gt;, a cousin to the jellyfish. Although these mechanisms are well documented, Kamran et al.’s study presents a fascinating insight into wound healing in vivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a combination of electron microcopy, staining techniques and various imaging techniques, Kamran et were able to document the wound healing mechanisms in live subjects. As well as developing a wound healing assay in the cnidarian &lt;em&gt;Clytia hemisphaerica&lt;/em&gt;, Kamran et al. were also able to establish which wound healing mechanisms occur in this species, discovering that wound healing occurs rapidly and independently of cell proliferation. In addition, they also establish that the implementation of either Lamellipodia-dependent cell crawling or the classical purse string mechanism depends on the integrity of the basement membrane. This fascinating article has shown potential for a &lt;em&gt;Clytia&lt;/em&gt; model for wound healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9771&quot; style=&quot;width: 578px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9771 size-full&quot; height=&quot;762&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/image-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;568&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure taken from the article documenting lamellipodia-dependent cell migration within the cnidarian &lt;em&gt;Clytia hemisphaerica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcdevbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12861-017-0158-9&quot;&gt;The asymmetric cell division machinery in the spiral-cleaving egg and embryo of the marine annelid &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of asymmetric cell division goes without question. The division of cells within a zygote is imperative to the organization of cellular fates, which, in summary, is essential for the development of organs.   Spiral cleavage (the division of cells in a spiral manner), however, only occurs in species such as mollusks and annelids. In their fascinating paper, Nakama et al. sought to analyze the machinery that is involved in spiral-cleaving egg and embryo of the marine annelid &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During their study, Nakama et al. were able to identify and classify genes that are important to asymmetric cell division in the eggs and early embryos of &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt; by analyzing their stage-specific transcriptome data. They were able to establish that most of the components in the spiral cleavage of marine annelid &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt; are maternal, which suggests that the sprialian egg in this species requires most of the components for asymmetric cell division to ensure rapid cell division. Furthermore, Nakama et al. have effectively carried out a systems-level analysis which has allowed them to identify key regulatory components that are expressed in the &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt; zygote, providing an in-depth insight into the early development of the marine annelid &lt;em&gt;Platynereis dumerilii&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9773&quot; style=&quot;width: 482px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9773&quot; height=&quot;557&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/image-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;472&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure taken from the article documenting maternal ACD transcript levels in oocytes and zygotes&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcdevbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12861-017-0146-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A compendium of developmental gene expression in Lake Malawi cichlid fishes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite comparative gene expression being important in developmental and evolutionary research, it seems that spatial expression surveys are restricted to models such as zebrafish and other laboratory models. In this fascinating paper, Bloomquist et al. have produced a compendium of developmental gene expression in a Lake Malawi cichlid fishes, a model that is used to conduct research into the developmental and genetic basis of trait diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this exciting study, Bloomquist et al. have managed to acquire expression data for many important expression pathways in the Lake Malawi cichlid fishes, including the TGF-β/BMP pathway, FGF pathway and the notch pathway, pathways which are well documented in many laboratory models, including zebrafish, xenopus and the more distantly related chicken. In addition, Bloomquist et al. have also observed stem cell/mitogenic factors, as well as calcium and endocrine signals, at 4 and 6 days post-fertilization, which are rarely seen in whole mount studies such as these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Bloomquist et al. have managed to start crafting a compendium which has opened the door for possible future studies into the function of the genes expressed at the early development of Lake Malawi cichlid fishes, which could be applied to many species of Eastern African cichlid fishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9774&quot; style=&quot;width: 577px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9774&quot; height=&quot;715&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/image-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;567&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure taken from the article documenting the Expression of genes from the TGF-β/BMP pathway at pharyngeal and larval stages&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/16/bmc-developmental-biology-top-three-articles-of-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Developmental Biology&lt;/em&gt;: top three articles of 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Branch-Hollis</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Doesn’t anyone do a literature review any more?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/16/caught-notice-doesnt-anyone-literature-review/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53429</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T13:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Titles: (1) Whole-Genome De Novo Sequencing of the Lignin-Degrading Wood Rot Fungus Phanerochaete chrysosporium (ATCC 20696) (2) Structure revision of aspergicin by the crystal structure of aspergicine, a co-occurring isomer produced by co-culture of two mangrove epiphytic fungi What Caught Our Attention: Two articles by different groups of authors recently suffered from the same (fatal) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/16/caught-notice-doesnt-anyone-literature-review/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Doesn’t anyone do a literature review any more?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Diversity Program Consortium offers new hope for inclusive science training</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/16/diversity-program-consortium-offers-new-hope-for-inclusive-science-training/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9776</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T12:10:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/DPC_logo_v_hires-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-9780&quot; height=&quot;1920&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/DPC_logo_h_hires-1.png&quot; width=&quot;6720&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of minority underrepresentation in science is not new and yet it remains deeply challenging. Just 8 percent of science and engineering doctorate holders in the United States are underrepresented minorities, compared to 30 percent in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gives us hope that we can yet achieve inclusive science is the National Institutes of Health-funded Diversity Program Consortium (DPC) which we learn about in depth in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcproc.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-11-supplement-12&quot;&gt;The Diversity Program Consortium: Innovating Educational Practice and Evaluation Along the Biomedical Research Pathways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; supplement dives into the critical work of the DPC and its components: the Building Infrastructure Leading to Diversity (BUILD) Initiative, the National Research Mentoring Network (NRMN), and the Coordination and Evaluation Center (CEC). These are based on a comprehensive approach to changing institutional culture and practice, combined with rigorous evaluation that supports the success of a stronger, diverse biomedical research workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Biomedical research advances healthcare for all Americans. It is strengthened when we include researchers who bring a broad range of perspectives to the work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is a priority for our nation. When we wrote the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine report, &lt;em&gt;Expanding Underrepresented Minority Participation: America’s Science and Technology Talent at the Crossroads, &lt;/em&gt;our focus on the &lt;u&gt;crossroads&lt;/u&gt; was intentional because we have choices to make. Do we want a robust scientific enterprise fueling innovation that drives our future? Do we want the best STEM workforce for that enterprise?  Will we draw on our nation’s talent – from all backgrounds – for the strongest workforce possible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biomedical research advances healthcare for all Americans. It is strengthened when we include researchers who bring a broad range of perspectives to the work. Our focus on health disparities ensures advances in healthcare reach every community and address their needs. This work is strengthened when researchers from diverse communities engage in formulating the questions and conducting the research. We achieve this through inclusive science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A long way to go&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly we have never been close to realizing a fully inclusive research workforce. &lt;em&gt;In Rising Above the Gathering Storm&lt;/em&gt;, the National Academies recommended we increase the percentage of our 24-year-olds with a first university degree in STEM from 6 to 10 percent. To be inclusive as we achieve this, we would need to triple, quadruple, or quintuple the numbers of underrepresented minorities in STEM.  Just 3.3 percent of Native Americans/Alaska Natives, 2.7 percent of African Americans, and 2.2 percent of Hispanics hold these degrees. This stems from persistent underrepresentation of minorities in science that deepens as we ascend the ladder from primary grades, through college, to research careers capped with R01 research funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcproc.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-11-supplement-12&quot;&gt;This supplement of &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes how BUILD actively supports minority students through innovative training strategies that address academic and psychosocial factors, support persistence, and overcome the negative effects of implicit bias, hostile climates, or isolation. The work is systemic, focusing on curriculum development, undergraduate research, mentoring, and institutional partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC) is one of 10 BUILD grantees. We are using our grant to extend what we learned from our Meyerhoff Scholars Programs for high-achieving minorities to a broader population of undergraduates in the sciences. Nine other BUILD campuses are implementing programs organic to their populations, drawing on exemplary practice and innovating in their curricula, pedagogy, faculty development, and mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For us, at UMBC, quality is defined by the rigor of the work plus the support that allows students to achieve high standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many well-prepared students, including minorities, who arrive on our campuses intending to major in STEM or the biomedical sciences. Unfortunately, many departments still define quality in terms of the number of students they can weed out, which removes talent that our nation needs. For us, at UMBC, quality is defined by the rigor of the work plus the support that allows students to achieve high standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When people come to our campus they are often surprised to find minorities among the highest achieving students in science. That is our vision at UMBC. For institutions to be successful in fostering inclusive excellence, this must be the vision on all campuses, as well. Too often these initiatives are left to junior faculty without the authority to re-think policies and practices. To the extent that respected researchers become involved and academic administrators take ownership of this initiative, we will see substantive progress in increasing the numbers of successful students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This supplement also describes the NRMN and the CEC. The NRMN has five regional hubs that recruit skilled mentors and partner them with underrepresented minority mentees who do not have a mentor to guide them. The CEC at UCLA coordinates across grantees and conducts assessments to identify long-term outcomes and scalable, best practice. We believe that evaluation is critical to the DPC’s work as it supports both program development and dissemination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of change agents who recruit supporters and allies and working tirelessly for success cannot be overstated. The next step is to disseminate what is working to other institutions in a way that inspires academic leaders to become invested and allows campus change agents to readily adapt best practice to their institutional settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/16/diversity-program-consortium-offers-new-hope-for-inclusive-science-training/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Diversity Program Consortium offers new hope for inclusive science training&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Freeman A. Hrabowski III &amp;#38; Peter H. Henderson</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">DNA solves the mystery of how these mummies were related</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-solves-mystery-how-these-mummies-were-related"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-solves-mystery-how-these-mummies-were-related</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Two ancient Egyptian mummies known as the Two Brothers had the same mother, but different dads.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7262838032630161=0.23611271174156157</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-23T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When tears turn into pearls: Post-traumatic growth following childhood and adolescent cancer</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/16/when-tears-turn-into-pearls-post-traumatic-growth-following-childhood-and-adolescent-cancer/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33021</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T10:04:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-619368670.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33049&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33049&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Abstract pearl background with shimmering mother of pearl lilac and rainbow colours&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1477744511&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ToscaWhi&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mother of pearl background with mauve colour&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mother of pearl background with mauve colour&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-619368670.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-619368670.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-619368670.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2236,1341&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/16/when-tears-turn-into-pearls-post-traumatic-growth-following-childhood-and-adolescent-cancer/mother-of-pearl-background-with-mauve-colour/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-619368670.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to imagine a crueller fate than when a child receives a diagnosis of an illness as difficult as cancer. A young human being, still not fully formed, is suddenly and irrevocably thrown into a situation that many adults are unable to cope with. Each year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.3322/caac.21219/abstract;jsessionid=A25F53B917E2715D7E8CDFE1D5BDF3AD.f04t02&quot;&gt;around 160,000 children and youngsters worldwide are diagnosed with cancer&lt;/a&gt;, and this trend is growing in industrialised societies. Faced with such facts, it is particularly important to understand how children cope. What traces of the experience remain in their psyche if they manage to survive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partial answers to these questions come from a trio of Australian researchers in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/pon.4577/abstract&quot;&gt;systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; of existing research into the psychological effects of cancer on children, published recently in &lt;i&gt;Psycho-Oncology&lt;/i&gt;. Their findings give us reason for some optimism. It turns out children and adolescents affected by cancer are no more likely to develop post-traumatic stress symptoms than their healthy peers. In fact, several studies have found that children affected by cancer go on to experience greater than usual adjustment and quality of life and lower anxiety and post-traumatic stress symptoms. In psychology, we refer to this as the post-traumatic growth (PTG) effect, which can arise from the struggle with highly challenging life circumstances or trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33021&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results from the analysed body of research – 18 studies in all – indicated that participants who were older when surveyed, or older when diagnosed with cancer, were more likely to experience PTG. Most likely, this is a product of the development of abstract reasoning that occurs sometime after the 11th or 12th year of life, when adolescents begin to formulate their own value systems, take an interest in philosophical ideas, and think about the meaning of life – cognitive processes that are involved in the development of PTG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meta-analysis also revealed a small but statistically significant correlation between post-traumatic stress and PTG. By definition, the struggle with trauma is necessary for the development of PTG, because it is during such struggles with disease that a teenager may experience both obsessive thoughts about death, but also may begin to appreciate life more. The vision of losing the normalcy that healthy people take for granted can turn into affirmation of that very normalcy. It is precisely these difficult experiences in youth that contribute to the formation of individuals who psychologists refer to as “prematurely mature”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The least surprising result was the positive link between PTG and having greater social support, as well as between PTG and being more optimistic. Unfortunately, these correlations don’t tell us whether social support and optimism lead to PTG, or if the reverse is true. Further studies may identify the causal relations between these factors. In turn this may help inform the development of support programmes targeting children with cancer and other difficult illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new meta-analysis also looked for potential correlations between PTG and depression, anxiety, pessimism, and quality of life, but all were statistically nonsignificant. Jasmin Turner and her colleagues suspect that this could be caused by small sample sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades, psychology has treated negative human experiences as unequivocally harmful to people, assuming that they lead to post-traumatic stress disorder, and poorer psychological and physical functioning. Regardless of their actual psychological state, people who have survived negative experiences have sometimes been treated like patients in need of help, and at times &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/01/16/is-it-time-to-resurrect-post-trauma-psychological-debriefing-for-emergency-responders-and-aid-workers/&quot;&gt;this help has even proved harmful to them&lt;/a&gt;. The discovery that following some traumatic situations, tears can turn into pearls is one of the more significant and promising discoveries of psychology. Understanding when and why this happens is a means for science to make a clear contribution to improving people’s well-being. And while the new results are not very strong, nevertheless they may help guide future research, potentially helping social support and clinical interventions for cancer patients. Also important is consideration of the factors leading to PTG and how to share this information appropriately and sensitively with people suffering illnesses. However, before we can label any such programmes as “evidence based”, further studies are necessary, particularly longitudinal research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, it is not worth waiting passively for the results of such studies. With the knowledge that the experience of trauma can lead to PTG, we can begin providing intelligent support to people whose luck is down – encouraging reflection on the experience of trauma, rather than mechanical consolation with exhortations to think positively. &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/20/new-meta-analysis-undermines-the-myth-that-negative-emotions-can-cause-cancer/&quot;&gt;Intelligent support should be an unobtrusive presence, without encouraging the rejection of negative emotions, and without attempts at eliciting positive ones&lt;/a&gt;. In all certainty, this kind of approach will be different from the offerings we have received for many years from some &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/11/14/positive-psychology-exercises-can-be-harmful-for-some/&quot;&gt;unreflexive positive psychologists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/pon.4577/abstract&quot;&gt;Correlates of post-traumatic growth following childhood and adolescent cancer: A systematic review and meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-14208&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;14208&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski – doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=682&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1181,1772&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/24/why-do-we-enjoy-reality-tv-researchers-say-its-more-about-empathy-than-humiliation/tomasz-witkowski-doktor-psychologii-pwsin-20061020fot-k-zuczkowski/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Dr Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tomasz is a psychologist and science writer who specialises in debunking pseudoscience in the field of psychology, psychotherapy and diagnosis. He has published over a dozen books, dozens of scientific papers and over 100 popular articles (some of them in &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;). In 2016 his latest book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Psychology-Led-Astray-Science-Therapy/dp/1627346090&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychology Led Astray: Cargo Cult in Science and Therapy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was published by BrownWalker Press. He blogs at &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Antarctic exploration in the digital age</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/antarctic-exploration-in-the-digital-age"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/antarctic-exploration-in-the-digital-age</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T09:23:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A software engineer reveals his Mendeley encounters while working on a research voyage in the South Pole</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-01-25T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Universal Flu Vaccine Is Vital</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/x0eZNnFjuJw/scientificamerican0218-8"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-8</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 8 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-8&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-8&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors: Catharine I. Paules &amp;amp; Anthony S. Fauci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A century after the deadly pandemic of 1918, we're still not safe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/x0eZNnFjuJw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Catharine I. Paules</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Misled Penguins</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/7mpPkr4Z9JY/scientificamerican0218-72"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-72</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 72 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Katie Peek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young birds follow the right signal to foraging grounds, but when they arrive there are no fish to eat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/7mpPkr4Z9JY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Katie Peek</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50, 100 &amp;amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/iw1Iar_xkiQ/scientificamerican0218-69"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-69</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 69 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-69&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-69&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/iw1Iar_xkiQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel C. Schlenoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bee Sides</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/IDLFzrotZO0/scientificamerican0218-68"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-68</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 68 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-68&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-68&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A surprising number of animals exhibit handedness—bees included&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/IDLFzrotZO0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Steve Mirsky</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Alvy's Error and the Meaning of Life</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/jiBnD6UtRBA/scientificamerican0218-67"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-67</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 67 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-67&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-67&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science reveals our deepest purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/jiBnD6UtRBA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Shermer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Recommended</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/IDWfCWqYxvQ/scientificamerican0218-66"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-66</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 66 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-66&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-66&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/IDWfCWqYxvQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Guardian Dogs of the Mongolian Steppe</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/0veOXXnU1gs/scientificamerican0218-60"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-60</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 60 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-60&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-60&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Jason Overdorf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An American entrepreneur is working to convert Mongolian herders into conservationists by reintroducing the region's traditional livestock protection dog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/0veOXXnU1gs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jason Overdorf</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Go Public or Perish</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/DEdp_2b83R0/scientificamerican0218-6"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-6</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When universities discourage scientists from speaking out, society suffers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/DEdp_2b83R0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Vanquishing Diabetes</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/WW1eCCpiXjM/scientificamerican0218-54"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-54</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 54 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-54&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-54&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Kristen M. Drescher &amp;amp; Steven Tracy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleaner environments in the industrial world have led to an increase in the incidence of type 1 diabetes. This history shows the way to a novel vaccine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/WW1eCCpiXjM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kristen M. Drescher</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Tribalism of Truth</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Szf5usW66gQ/scientificamerican0218-50"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-50</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 50 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-50&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-50&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Matthew Fisher, Joshua Knobe, Brent Strickland &amp;amp; Frank C. Keil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As political polarization grows, the arguments we have with one another may be shifting our understanding of truth itself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Szf5usW66gQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthew Fisher</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Troubled Waters</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/dyfbtrZN7Us/scientificamerican0218-44"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-44</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 44 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-44&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-44&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Olive Heffernan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big marine reserves look good on maps, but it takes tough rules close to shore to improve fisheries and biodiversity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/dyfbtrZN7Us&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Olive Heffernan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Letters</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/UZ0mol9TwJE/scientificamerican0218-4"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-4</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 4 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/UZ0mol9TwJE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">[Redacted]</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/4Zmd2l5v4Rk/scientificamerican0218-38"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-38</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 38 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-38&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-38&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Charles Seife&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the Food and Drug Administration withholding certain touchy drug trial data to protect the sensitive corporate secrets of pharmaceutical companies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/4Zmd2l5v4Rk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Charles Seife</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are Smartphones Really Destroying the Adolescent Brain?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/bKSXnaj4lwM/scientificamerican0218-30"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-30</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 30 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-30&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-30&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Carlin Flora&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent headlines would have us believe that device-hooked teens are mentally and socially doomed. The reality isn't so simple&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/bKSXnaj4lwM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carlin Flora</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Depths of Space, Oceans and Politics</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/SSsPhMSKwVk/scientificamerican0218-3"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-3</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 3 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-3&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/SSsPhMSKwVk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariette DiChristina</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The First Monster Black Holes</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/PUJhAJzoVEw/scientificamerican0218-24"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-24</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Priyamvada Natarajan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astronomers are puzzled about how the oldest supermassive black holes could have grown so big so early in cosmic history&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/PUJhAJzoVEw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Priyamvada Natarajan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Robotic Artist Problem</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/ka0Vouc6UI8/scientificamerican0218-23"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-23</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 23 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-23&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-23&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When AI creates compelling art, the meaning of creativity gets blurred&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/ka0Vouc6UI8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Pogue</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why Fake Operations Are a Good Thing</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/WAIwFZHGUTk/scientificamerican0218-22"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-22</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can reveal whether popular surgeries are actually effective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/WAIwFZHGUTk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Claudia Wallis</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quick Hits</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/oriis-m1T8w/scientificamerican0218-21"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-21</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 21 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-21&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-21&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Yasemin Saplakoglu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/oriis-m1T8w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yasemin Saplakoglu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Wearable Data</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/zXya76zhzU0/scientificamerican0218-20"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-20</id>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0218-20&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0218-20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Yasemin Saplakoglu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnetic clothing could store pass codes and unlock doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/zXya76zhzU0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yasemin Saplakoglu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-01-24T12:00:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Meet the scientist whose ideas were stolen at least three times</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/15/meet-scientist-whose-ideas-stolen-least-three-times/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53407</id>
		<updated>2018-01-15T13:00:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Jeff Offutt, a professor of software engineering at George Mason University, has some stories to tell. He says that when one of his students wrote his first paper, the student reused four paragraphs from another source, not knowing he couldn’t do that. And then he tells of attending a PhD thesis defense where the student […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/15/meet-scientist-whose-ideas-stolen-least-three-times/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Meet the scientist whose ideas were stolen at least three times&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T06:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tiny scales in ancient lagoon may be the first fossil evidence of the moth-butterfly line</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tiny-scales-ancient-lagoon-may-be-first-fossil-evidence-moth-butterfly-line"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tiny-scales-ancient-lagoon-may-be-first-fossil-evidence-moth-butterfly-line</id>
		<updated>2018-01-15T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fancy liquid-sipper mouthparts might have evolved before the great burst of flower evolution</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Extending Christmas to fight the flu</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/15/extending-christmas-to-fight-the-flu/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9742</id>
		<updated>2018-01-15T10:15:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/2809961438_56d48f9969_z-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;School closure, a necessary break for both teachers and students, is also associated with mitigating influenza outbreaks. Purposely closing schools during outbreaks of influenza is not officially recommended by the World Health Organisation; however, this non-pharmaceutical intervention is well regarded as an approach in reducing the epidemic impact. A well-known example of this is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2334-14-207&quot;&gt;closure of schools during the swine flu epidemic&lt;/a&gt; in the UK, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De Luca &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;’s study considers the effect of regulated school holidays in interrupting influenza propagation by offering variety in social mixing and travel – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21176155&quot;&gt;two key determinants&lt;/a&gt; of influenza epidemic potency. The authors aimed to integrate social mixing and travel of children and adults during school/holiday periods into a spatial metapopulation that also utilised data based on demographics and infection dynamics. Focusing on the 2008/2009 influenza season in Belgium, the mathematical model was calibrated to the singular district of Brussels which showed accurate scalability to a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The authors observed how the growth of the number of new infections significantly slowed during the Christmas holidays whereas the fall and Easter holidays had little effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model was further parameterized with influenza-like-illness (ILI) data reported by the Belgian Scientific Institute of Public Health. Once the Belgian school calendar was applied, the authors tested a number of experimental scenarios. Different scheduled holidays were first removed and replaced with regular school/working weeks from the model to observe the effect on an epidemic’s timing and intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors observed how the growth of the number of new infections significantly slowed during the Christmas holidays whereas the fall and Easter holidays had little effect. The benefit of weekends in periodically slowing down the epidemic curve &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002251931200375X&quot;&gt;was also observed&lt;/a&gt;. Altering the contact and behaviour among groups of people over weekends and holidays is thought to alter epidemic dynamics, causing a smaller epidemic with less incidences. Altered mixing behaviour during weekends and holidays was found more influential on the spread of an epidemic than travel was in this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthering the observation that &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jid/article/215/5/732/2751325&quot;&gt;Christmas holidays can play a large role on epidemic impact&lt;/a&gt;, extension methods were tested. Adding a week of holiday before Christmas had no impact on the epidemics timing or severity, however, whilst extending the Christmas holidays could not delay the epidemic, it could reduce the severity as the number of ILIs decreased. Additional breaks beyond Christmas may also prove to have a mitigating impact, but the whole calendar must be considered as holidays throughout the year all affect the epidemic’s evolution differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis on a single season represents how the impact of regular school closures slow and mitigate influenza epidemics. However, the epidemic impact of school closure is heavily dependent on the closure timing and influenza season. The authors also noted that contacts and their changes throughout the calendar are likely to be country-specific. An improved understanding on the behavioural changes caused by an epidemic are required to further parameterize models for epidemic management which may be achieved by incorporating additional seasons and more specific age groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the impact that school closures can have on influenza may help manage future epidemics and attenuate pressure placed on public health services. These findings may be of relevant use to authorities considering reducing summer holidays to redistribute spare holidays throughout the year to manage the influenza season. The results from this study have helped shine light on previous studies performed throughout the world; therefore, it would be worthwhile to apply similar models in different countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/01/15/extending-christmas-to-fight-the-flu/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Extending Christmas to fight the flu&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edward Spofford</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-01-22T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Researchers say this 5-minute technique could help you fall asleep more quickly</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/15/researchers-say-this-5-minute-technique-could-help-you-fall-asleep-more-quickly/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33034</id>
		<updated>2018-01-15T09:06:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-498497602.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33037&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33037&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Teenage girl lying on bed in her room and studying. She is tired and book covering her face. Evening or night with beautiful yellow lights lightning the scenes.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1448386844&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;svetikd&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired of studying!&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tired of studying!&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-498497602.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-498497602.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-498497602.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/15/researchers-say-this-5-minute-technique-could-help-you-fall-asleep-more-quickly/tired-of-studying/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/01/gettyimages-498497602.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve had all day to worry, but your brain decides that the moment you rest your weary head upon your pillow is the precise instant it wants to start fretting. The result of course is that you feel wide awake and cannot sleep. Two possible solutions: (1) spend five minutes before lights out writing about everything you have done. This might give you a soothing sense of achievement. Or (2) spend five minutes writing a comprehensive to-do list. This could serve to off-load your worries, or perhaps it will only make them more salient? To find out which is the better strategy, a team led by Michael Scullin at Baylor University, invited 57 volunteers to their sleep lab and had half of them try technique 1 and half try technique 2. &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-47677-001&quot;&gt;Their findings&lt;/a&gt; are published in the latest issue of the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: General&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33034&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants, aged 18 to 30, attended the sleep lab at about 9pm on a weekday night. They filled out questionnaires about their usual sleep habits and underwent basic medical tests. Once in their sound-proofed room and wired up to equipment that uses brain waves to measure sleep objectively, they were told that lights out would be 10.30pm. Before they tried to sleep, half of the participants spent five minutes “writing about everything you have to remember to do tomorrow and over the next few days”. The others spent the same time writing about any activities they’d completed that day and over the previous few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key finding is that the participants in the to-do list condition fell asleep more quickly. They took about 15 minutes to fall asleep, on average, compared with 25 minutes for those in the “jobs already done” condition. Moreover, among those in the to-do list group, the more thorough and specific their list, the more quickly they fell asleep, which would seem to support a kind of off-loading explanation. Another interpretation is that busier people, who had more to write about, tended to fall asleep more quickly. But this is undermined by the fact that among the jobs-done group, those who wrote in more detail tended to take longer to fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Rather than journal about the day’s completed tasks or process tomorrow’s to-do list in one’s mind, the current experiment suggests that individuals spend five minutes near bedtime thoroughly writing a to-do list,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the experiment didn’t have a baseline no-intervention control group, so it’s possible that the shorter time-to-sleep of the to-do list writing intervention was actually a reflection of journaling about completed jobs making it harder to fall asleep. Also, note the current sample didn’t have any sleep problems. Scullin and his team say the next step is to conduct a longer-running randomised control trial of the to-do list intervention outside of the sleep lab, with people who do and don’t have sleep-onset insomnia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-47677-001&quot;&gt;The Effects of Bedtime Writing on Difficulty Falling Asleep:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-47677-001&quot;&gt; A Polysomnographic Study Comparing To-Do Lists and Completed Activity Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-01-26T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Transformational Work Over a Career: Breakthrough Prize in Life Sciences for PLOS Authors</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/Ayr13-5jOo0/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7965</id>
		<updated>2018-01-14T17:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Breakthrough2_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you measure lifetime achievement? It’s not by assessing individual works but by consideration and evaluation of consistent contributions to a discipline over time. Contributions may be independently substantial, but in science, a researcher’s impact is more often made through gradual insights that accrue meaning as a discipline advances. Over the course of a career, creative thinkers and leaders in science can significantly influence a field, and humanity more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recently established award provides one measure of lifetime achievement for life sciences—the Breakthrough Prize. Established in 2013, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Prize/2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Breakthrough Prize in Life Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; honors “transformative advances toward understanding living systems and extending human life.” The prize encourages celebration and recognition of “outstanding minds.” Those scientists who “think big, take risks and have made a significant impact on our lives” each receive $3 million for their work that provides fundamental and far-reaching understanding of biological mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Breakthrough Prize in Life Sciences is designed to bring public attention, financial reward and a bit of glamor to outstanding scientists who over the course of their careers have changed the way scientists think about basic principles. Through a central component of the award, the impact of honored scientists’ work is extended to a broader general audience. Recipients are invited to present public talks – with recorded lectures made &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Lectures&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;available to the public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – “allowing everyone to keep abreast of the latest developments in life sciences, guided by contemporary masters of the field,” according to the Breakthrough Prize website. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Breakthrough Prizes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are also awarded in fundamental physics and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, five scientists received life sciences prizes; collectively these creative thinkers have published 30 papers in PLOS journals (13 in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 16 in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; and one in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;), providing their work to the global community free of access and reuse restrictions. The 2018 Breakthrough Prizes in Life Sciences were awarded to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Laureates/2/L3823&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joanne Chory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, for pioneering work elucidating mechanisms by which plants “optimize their growth, development, and cellular structure to transform sunlight into chemical energy.” Chory has published &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plos.io/Chory_BTP2018&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;work with PLOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;on how the circadian clock coordinates plant growth through &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0060225&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;synchronized gene expression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, on growth patterning in the model plant system &lt;em&gt;Arabidopsis &lt;/em&gt;and a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0020258&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;novel approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to identify required gene regulatory elements, and on diurnal and clock-regulated transcription factors and their target &lt;em&gt;cis&lt;/em&gt;-regulatory elements in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0016907&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;additional plant models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The Chory team first published with PLOS in 2004.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7968&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7968 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;229&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Chori2-300x229.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0060225&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pbio.0060225&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Laureates/2/L3826&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kim Nasmyth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, for elucidating the “sophisticated mechanism that mediates the perilous separation of duplicated chromosomes during cell division and thereby prevents genetic diseases such as cancer.” Nasmyth’s work in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt; covers the influence of excess heterochromatin (highly packed DNA) segments and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1001962&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cohesin protein accumulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on sister chromatid separation, and that the protein &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0030086&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shugoshin protects centromeres&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; until chromosomes are ready to separate. He and colleagues from the Research Institute of Molecular Pathology, in Vienna, Austria, first published with PLOS in 2005.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7972&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7972 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Neysmith-150x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0030086&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pbio.0030086&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Laureates/2/L3827&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Don Cleveland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, for characterizing molecular mechanisms involved in the pathogenesis of inherited Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS), “including the role of glia in neurodegeneration, and for establishing antisense oligonucleotide therapy in animal models of ALS and Huntington disease.”&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://plos.io/Cleveland_BTP2018&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cleveland’s work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; using post-mortem human tissue samples and transgenic mice showed that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0002849&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mRNA oxidation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an early event associated with motor neuron deterioration in ALS, and possibly other neurological diseases. His work on the enzyme superoxide dismutase, responsible for breaking down toxic, charged oxygen molecules known as superoxide radicals, included assessing the therapeutic effect of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0042614&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;human fetal spinal neural stem cells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; grafted into the lumbar spine of transgenic rats presymptomatic for ALS. Cleveland and his many colleagues first published with PLOS (twice) in 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7971&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7971 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Cleveland-197x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;197&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0042614&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0042614&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two scientists, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Laureates/2/L3825&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kazutoshi Mori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of Kyoto University, Japan, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Laureates/2/L3824&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peter Walter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the University of California, San Francisco, received Breakthrough Prizes for their independent work on “elucidating the unfolded protein response, a cellular quality-control system that detects disease-causing unfolded proteins and directs cells to take corrective measures.” The unfolded protein response (UPR) is a phylogenetically conserved endoplasmic reticulum-to-nucleus signaling pathway that senses unfolded proteins early on in the biosynthetic process, and then transmits that information to the cell nucleus. This information stimulates a genetic transcription program designed to re-establish cellular homeostasis by increasing the intracellular machinery and processes that help proteins fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various cellular insults, writes Mori in his team’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0040374&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; article, “including exposure to pharmacological agents that perturb protein folding, genetic mutation of ER chaperones or chaperone substrates, viral infection, metabolic demands, and even normal differentiation and function of professional secretory cells” impact the UPR in similar and unique ways. His earlier work &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plos.io/Mori_BTP2018&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;published with PLOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; examined the differential influence of low-level, severe and chronic stress on UPR activation. More recently, Mori has extended his investigations to the development of a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0161486&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;high-throughput screening assay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that incorporates a molecular biosensor to identify small molecule activators of the endoplasmic reticulum stress response in malignant glioma cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7969&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7969 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Mori-300x206.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0040374&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pbio.0040374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since 2004, Walter has published &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plos.io/Walter_BTP2018&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;12 papers with PLOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; covering the role of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0040423&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;endoplasmic reticulum expansion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the UPR in yeast; a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0004170&quot;&gt;teasing out&lt;/a&gt; of the relationship between cell proliferation, cell death and protein folding in human embryonic kidney cell lines; and the importance of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1001735&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;targeting a key transcription factor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the cell membrane, to provide the appropriate cellular response to protein folding status in bacteria. Walter’s first two papers published in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;, presented as a series together with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.0020269&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Synopsis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, described amplitude adjustment signals for the UPR in yeast. Prior to this work, the UPR was thought to largely be a binary, on or off, function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7970&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7970 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/Walter-288x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;288&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0003528&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0003528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more than other prize recipients, Joanne Chory was surprised by her inclusion as an awardee, explaining to the &lt;em&gt;San Diego Union-Tribune&lt;/em&gt;, “this prize has been more associated with biomedical things.” The award may be a nod to the relevance of Chory’s current work to climate change. Those interested in the connection between mechanisms of sunlight and clock-regulated plant development to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salk.edu/news-release/salk-institutes-joanne-chory-awarded-prestigious-breakthrough-prize-life-sciences/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;global warming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; may find of interest the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/eco-climate-change&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ecological Impacts of Climate Change Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and newly launched &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/rtcc&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Responding to Climate Change Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International lifetime achievement awards are given in many fields, including &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sioe.org/sioe-awards&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldmusicawards.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.sif.it/activities/fermi_award&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;physical sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, among others. With support of founding sponsors Mark Zuckerberg, Priscilla Chan, Sergey Brin, Anne Wojcicki and Yuri Milner, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/09/2017-lasker-awards/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;life sciences&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;has another prize of its own, with a musical perk. This year’s awardees were honored at a gala hosted by Morgan Freeman with a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DWK5ebvtnbw&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;performance of “See You Again” by Wiz Khalifa and Nana Ou-Yang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DWK5ebvtnbw&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7975 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;174&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/01/music-300x174.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hero image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://breakthroughprize.org/Prize/2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;breakthroughprize.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/Ayr13-5jOo0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-01-16T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: A manuscript marriage proposal; a biotech company screw-up; “systematic failure” in run-up to vaccine trial</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/13/weekend-reads-manuscript-marriage-proposal-biotech-company-screw-systematic-failure-run-vaccine-trial/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53436</id>
		<updated>2018-01-13T14:12:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured “a concerning – largely unrecognised – threat to patient safety,” the loss of a grant following findings of misconduct in a controversial study, and a request that authors remove a reference for libel concerns. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A researcher has hidden a marriage proposal in a paper. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2018/01/13/weekend-reads-manuscript-marriage-proposal-biotech-company-screw-systematic-failure-run-vaccine-trial/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A manuscript marriage proposal; a biotech company screw-up; “systematic failure” in run-up to vaccine trial&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-01-20T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Spaceships could use blinking dead stars to chart their way</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spaceships-could-use-blinking-dead-stars-chart-their-way"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spaceships-could-use-blinking-dead-stars-chart-their-way</id>
		<updated>2018-01-12T22:15:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Timing signals from five pulsars allowed scientists to pinpoint an experiment’s place in space.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-01-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
