<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Trump’s proposed 2018 budget takes an ax to science research funding</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/trump-proposed-budget-science-research-funding"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/trump-proposed-budget-science-research-funding</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T21:26:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Administration would cut total federal research spending by about 17 percent, according to a preliminary estimate.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“There is an injustice in this article”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/there-is-an-injustice-in-this-article/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50255</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T17:30:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The editors of a plant biology journal have retracted a 2007 paper because of “an injustice.” According to the notice, the editors of Cytologia found evidence of “apparent figure manipulation,” and decided to retract the paper. This marks the 10th retraction for plant biologist Dibyendu Talukdar. Talukdar, who is first and corresponding author on the 2007 paper and listed at the University of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/there-is-an-injustice-in-this-article/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“There is an injustice in this article”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Running is contagious among those with the competitive bug</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/running-contagious-among-those-competitive-bug"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/running-contagious-among-those-competitive-bug</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Can behaviors really be contagious? Runners log more miles when their friends do — especially if they want to stay leader of the pack, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Paper with duplicated image “sequentially builds” on neuroscience work, authors argue</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/paper-duplicated-image-sequentially-builds-neuroscience-work-authors-argue/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50126</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T13:30:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A neurochemistry journal has retracted a paper from a group in China over a duplicated image. According to the notice, the authors used the same image in the two papers to represent different experimental conditions. The only distinguishing feature between the images: “apparent brightness changes.” The authors defended their actions, explaining that the research published in Journal of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/paper-duplicated-image-sequentially-builds-neuroscience-work-authors-argue/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paper with duplicated image “sequentially builds” on neuroscience work, authors argue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Magnetism disrupts winds on ‘hot Jupiter’ exoplanet</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetism-disrupts-winds-hot-jupiter-exoplanet"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetism-disrupts-winds-hot-jupiter-exoplanet</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Simulations of HAT-P 7b’s magnetic field give clues to why the exoplanet’s winds blow both east and west.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Is something rotten in the state of social psychology? Part Two: digging through the past</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/26/is-something-rotten-in-the-state-of-social-psychology-part-two-digging-through-the-past/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24126</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T10:10:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Victorian lifeboat men rowing to rescue a stricken ship&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24132&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24132&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;An illustration from \&amp;quot;The Family Friend\&amp;quot; published by S.W. Partridge &amp;amp; Co. (London, 1874). Lifeboat men rowing towards a wrecked ship in high seas.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Linda Steward&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Victorian lifeboat men rowing to rescue a stricken ship&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Victorian lifeboat men rowing to rescue a stricken ship&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-157585830.jpg?w=845?w=832&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-157585830.jpg?w=845?w=244&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-157585830.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1561,1921&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/26/is-something-rotten-in-the-state-of-social-psychology-part-two-digging-through-the-past/victorian-lifeboat-men-rowing-to-rescue-a-stricken-ship/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-157585830.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/qxaby&quot;&gt;in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/a&gt; has taken a hard look at psychology’s crisis of replication and research quality and we’re covering its findings in two parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/25/was-the-crisis-in-social-psychology-really-that-bad-have-things-improved-part-one-the-researchers-perspective/&quot;&gt;Part One, published yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, we reported the views of active research psychologists on the state of their field, as surveyed by Matt Motyl and his colleagues at the University of Illinois at Chicago. Researchers reported a cautious optimism: research practices hadn’t been as bad as feared, and are in any case improving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is their optimism warranted? After all, &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/349/6251/aac4716&quot;&gt;several high-profile&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//osf.io/ct89g/wiki/home/&quot;&gt;replication projects&lt;/a&gt; have found that, more often than not, re-running previously successful studies produces only null results. But defenders of the state of psychology argue that replications fail for many reasons, including defects in the reproduction and differences in samples, so the implications aren’t settled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get closer to the truth, Motyl’s team complemented their survey findings with a forensic analysis of published data, uncovering results that seem to bolster their optimistic position. In Part Two of our coverage, we look at these findings and why they’re already proving controversial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24126&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motyl and his colleagues used a relatively new type of analysis to assess the quality and honesty of the data found in over 500 previously published papers in social psychology. Their approach is technical, involving weirdly-named statistics conducted upon even more statistics, so it helps to use an analogy: Just as a vegetable garden produces a variety of tomatoes, some bigger than others, some misshapen, some puny and poor for eating, an honestly-conducted body of research should bear a range of fruit in the same way. True experimental effects shouldn’t always come out exactly the same: they should vary in size from experiment to experiment, including instances when the effect is too small to be statistically significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the sorts of things you can evaluate in a body of research – in this case with the &lt;i&gt;Test for Insufficient Variance,&lt;/i&gt; which Motyl’s study used alongside six other indices. When there were too many irregularities in the data, or bizarre regularity like identikit supermarket tomatoes, this suggested to Motyl and his colleagues that questionable research practices may have been used to make the weak results swell up to reach the desired appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, however, the study found that more often than not, the indices showed low levels of anomalies, suggesting research practices are more likely to be acceptable than questionable. This was the case for studies from 2003-4, before the crisis was fully acknowledged, and the researchers found an even better picture for more recent (2013-14) papers. The fruits of the research may have been tampered with from time to time, but there was no case that the entire enterprise was “rotten to the core”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This optimistic conclusion conflicts with similar analyses performed in the past, but this might be explained by the different approaches of collecting the data – of gathering the fruit, if you will. Past approaches automatically scraped articles for every instance of a statistic, such as every listed p-value. But this is like a bulldozer ripping out a corner of a garden and measuring everything that looks anything like a tomato, including stones and severed gnome-heads. To take just one example, articles will often list p-values for manipulation checks: confirmations that an experimental condition was set up correctly (did participants agree that the violent kung-fu clip was more violent than the video of grass growing?). But these aren’t tests to determine new scientific knowledge, rather – turning to another analogy – the equivalent of a chemist checking their equipment works before running an experiment. So Motyl’s team took a more nuanced approach, reading through every article and picking out by hand only the relevant statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, all is not rosy in the garden. At their Datacolada blog, “state of science” researchers Joseph Simmons, Leif Nelson, and Uri Simonsohn, have already responded to the new analysis and &lt;a href=&quot;http://datacolada.org/60&quot;&gt;they’re sceptical&lt;/a&gt;. Simmons and co first note the daunting scale of the new enterprise: to correctly identify 1800 relevant test statistics from 500 papers. In an online response, Motyl’s team &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/7jz3f&quot;&gt;agreed&lt;/a&gt; that yes, it was time consuming, and yes, it required a lot of hands: “there are reasons this paper has many authors: It really took a village,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Datacolada sampled some of the statistics that Motyl’s team used in their assessments and they argue that far too many of them were inappropriate, including data from manipulation checks that Motyl’s group had themselves categorised as &lt;i&gt;statistica non grata&lt;/i&gt;. To the Datacolada team, this renders the whole enterprise suspect: “We are in no position to say whether their conclusions are right or wrong. But neither are they.” In their response, Motyl’s team make some concessions, but they argue that some of the statistic selection comes down to difference of opinion, and defend both their overall  procedure, and the amount of coding errors they expect their study will contain. So….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So doing high-quality science isn’t straightforward. Neither is doing high-quality science on the quality of science, nor is gathering everything together to form high-quality conclusions. But if we care about the validity of the more sexy findings in psychology – the amazing powers of power poses to make you physically more confident, how you can hack your happiness simply by changing your face, and how even subtle social signals about age, race or gender can transform how we perform at tasks – we need to care about psychological science itself, how it’s working and how it isn’t. (By the way, those findings I just listed? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/16/ten-famous-psychology-findings-that-its-been-difficult-to-replicate/&quot;&gt;They’ve all struggled to replicate&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are surely ways to to improve the methods of this new study – perhaps not coincidentally, Datacolada’s Leif Nelson is running a similar project – but even if the new assessment does include some irrelevant statistics, it will likely be an advance on past analyses that included &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; irrelevant statistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So … the new insights have budged my position on the state of science a little: I’m still worried, but I can see a little more light among the dark. Motyl’s group make the case that social psychology isn’t ruined, that the garden isn’t totally contaminated. I hope so. But it’s not hope on its own that will move our field forward, but research, debate, and making sense of the evidence. After all, psychology is too good to give up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/qxaby&quot;&gt;The State of Social and Personality Science: Rotten to the Core, Not so Bad, Getting Better, or Getting Worse?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main image: An illustration from ‘The Family Friend’ published by S.W. Partridge &amp;amp; Co. (London, 1874). Lifeboat men rowing towards a wrecked ship in high seas. (via GettyImages.co.uk under licence)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8 of our PsychCrunch podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Can We Trust Psychological Studies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And our special feature: &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/16/ten-famous-psychology-findings-that-its-been-difficult-to-replicate/&quot;&gt;Ten Famous Psychology Findings That It’s Been Difficult To Replicate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24126/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24126/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24126&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">In the Belly of the Beast</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/26/in-the-belly-of-the-beast/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9019</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T08:39:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/sis-and-snake-bigger-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serpents are perhaps one of the most unique reptiles on the planet, both in form and function. They have adapted to movement without legs, hunting mechanisms range from venomous fangs to suffocation, and a metabolism that can quickly adapt between feast and prolonged famine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the metabolic changes that take place within serpentine metabolism have long fascinated scientists, who work towards understanding how the snake body could undergo such rapid changes without harming the animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Burmese python in particular is an excellent model for physiological studies since it is such a large snake (in the wild averaging just over twelve feet) with a sturdy build. Full grown adults can go months between feeding, but then consume an entire goat or pig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most notable changes that take place within the Burmese python before and after they feed occur within their organ systems, with major organs such as the heart, liver and kidneys increasing in mass by 40-100% two days after consuming a meal. On a cellular level, their metabolism skyrockets to a 44-fold increase, with more then 100-fold increase in plasma triglyceride content in their blood stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten to fourteen days after the python has consumed a meal, these same organs undergo atrophy and shrink back down to pre-meal sizes and metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a genomic perspective, transcriptional responses (as expected) are both rapid and massive in regards to both the magnitude of expression changes and in the number of genes with significant differential expression. Previous studies have indicated that these changes are likely a result of a conserved response to core signaling molecules, which in turn activate diverse, tissue-specific signaling cascades. However, the identity of these signaling molecules has not yet been discovered due to the sheer scale and abbreviated time frame within which these changes take place in the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audra Andrew and Blair Perry at the University of Texas, Arlington and colleagues have recently published &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3743-1?utm_content=buffer794ff&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; in which they analyzed the genomic changes that take place within the heart, liver, kidneys, and small intestine of the Burmese python before, during, and just after feeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest was the LXR/RXR activation pathway, PI3K/AKT, and mTOR signaling involved in upregulating the growth processes of organs, and the NRF2-mediated oxidative stress response pathways with regards to the stress response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study was conducted by taking groups of Burmese pythons, fasting them for 30 days, and then feeding them a meal equal to 25% of their body mass. Tissue sampling time points were 30 days post fasting, one day after being fed, and 4 days after being fed, and collected from the heart, liver, small intestine and kidney. The tissue samples were then run though NEB Next RNAseq to generate RNAseq libraries for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine pathway activation and regulatory molecule predictions, the authors annotated the full Burmese python transcription set with the orthologous human gene Ensembl identifiers. The program STEM was used to identify and visualize significant expression profiles for all genes within the samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once data on the full set of python genes was collected, the specific genetic effects over the time period were assessed, and changes in upregulation and regression were noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9028&quot; style=&quot;width: 510px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9028 size-full&quot; height=&quot;297&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/12864_2017_3743_Fig2_HTML.gif&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure 2A from Andrew et al. 2017. Summary of significantly differentially expressed genes for all four organs identified via regression analysis. This Venn diagram depicts the numbers of genes significantly differentially expressed across time points. Darker colors indicate a large number of genes and lighter colors indicate a smaller number of genes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every organ studied, the majority of differentially expressed genes showed immediate up or down regulation within 24 hours post feeding. Each of the four organs examined experienced regression towards fasting levels of expression by four days post fasting to widely different extents, indicating that growth changes are unique between organ systems. Of all genes in the genome, only a single gene was identified as significant in all four organs across all time points: coagulation factor X (F10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After mapping the python genes to human orthologs, Andrew and colleagues were able to associate over 70% of human genes within the mTOR and NRF2 stress response pathway.  Both of these biological pathways appear to be involved in every organ system response to feeding, suggesting human tissue is likely to have developed in the same manner. Notably, insulin signaling represents a key-regulation factor of the mTOR pathway, and the activation of NRF2 may play additional roles in growth response, as its blood plasma contains factors that have been shown in vitro to cause resistance to apoptosis in mammalian cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this scale of hypertrophy, hyperplasia and atrophy are impressive in snakes, it is not a unique phenomenon in the animal kingdom, as other classes of animals – notably fish and amphibians – as well as plants express varying levels of organ and tissue growth and regeneration. However, the use of mTOR and NRF2-mediated signaling is unique to the Burmese python in both phenotype and genotype expression patterns, particularly the use of multiple coordinated growth pathways in multiple tissue types, suggesting a possible future mechanism to facilitate future human growth and organ repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9024&quot; style=&quot;width: 2026px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9024 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/IMG_4575.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2016&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;BMC-series Editor Cecilia Devoto, and python.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/26/in-the-belly-of-the-beast/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;In the Belly of the Beast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Faye Nourollahi</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Gaslighting in the Medical Literature</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/2ANpI4AY2qM/gaslighting-in-medical-literature.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-3136124628347876017</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T03:00:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator tr_bq&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eVV_E56hbNM/WSJuoCHfUNI/AAAAAAAAMJo/XzXOWtUZWgomYZUoIwtU2aayKdsd10DEwCLcB/s1600/Gaslight%2Banimated%2Bgif.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eVV_E56hbNM/WSJuoCHfUNI/AAAAAAAAMJo/XzXOWtUZWgomYZUoIwtU2aayKdsd10DEwCLcB/s320/Gaslight%2Banimated%2Bgif.gif&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have you felt that your sense of reality has been challenged lately? That the word “truth” has no meaning any more? Does the existence of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ToLfQU2xmg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative facts&lt;/a&gt; make you question your own sanity? In modern usage, the term &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaslighting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;gaslighting&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; refers to “a form of psychological abuse  in which false information is presented to the victim with the intent  of making him/her doubt his/her own memory and perception”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaslighting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gaslighting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a form of manipulation  that seeks to sow seeds of doubt in a targeted individual or members of  a group, hoping to make targets question their own memory, perception,  and sanity. Using persistent denial, misdirection, contradiction, and lying, it attempts to destabilize the target and delegitimize the target's belief.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In December 2016, the amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/laurenduca&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lauren Duca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;wrote a widely shared piece for &lt;i&gt;Teen Vogue&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teenvogue.com/story/donald-trump-is-gaslighting-america&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump Is Gaslighting America&lt;/a&gt;. In it, she argued that Trump won the election by normalizing deception. Duca noted that the term &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaslighting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;gaslighting&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;  originated from the 1938 play &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gas_Light&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gas Light&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Hamilton, and explained it in this way:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&quot;Gas lighting&quot; is a buzzy name for a terrifying strategy currently being used to weaken and blind the American electorate. We are collectively being treated like Bella Manningham in the 1938 Victorian thriller from which the term &quot;gas light&quot; takes its name. In the play, Jack terrorizes his wife Bella into questioning her reality by blaming her for mischievously misplacing household items which he systematically hides. Doubting whether her perspective can be trusted, Bella clings to a single shred of evidence: the dimming of the gas lights that accompanies the late night execution of Jack’s trickery. The wavering flame is the one thing that holds her conviction in place as she wriggles free of her captor’s control.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gaslighting in the Medical Literature&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/4182427&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barton and Whitehead (1969)&lt;/a&gt; were the first to report cases where a patient's mental state was manipulated for material (or situational) gain, calling it the “Gas-Light Phenomenon”. If these incidents sound like something straight out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://noirwich.co.uk/2017/04/12/the-origins-of-domestic-noir/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;domestic noir&lt;/a&gt; or a TV crime drama, you'd be right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 1&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt; &lt;u&gt;48 year old mechanic, married for 10 years, with three children&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Mr. A. was admitted one evening to a psychiatric hospital as an emergency. His general practitioner, when asking for his admission, had said he was mentally ill and had attacked his wife. ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On admission the patient said he had felt tense and depressed for about six months and related this to his wife’s changed attitude towards him. He said she had become &quot;cold&quot;, and he thought she might have been seeing another man. He denied he had been violent and thought he had been sent into hospital because of his &quot;nerves&quot;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;His wife had concocted an elaborate tale of abuse, saying he had become “irritable, bad-tempered, and liable to unprovoked violent outbursts in which he sometimes hit her and once struck her with a hatchet.” She also claimed his memory was deteriorating, and she categorically denied having an affair. Mr. A was hospitalized for 12 days with no obvious physical or psychiatric disorder and left feeling more relaxed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, he returned to hospital two weeks later: “He said his wife had started taunting him, saying he was mad and should be in a mental hospital. His wife said that his mental condition had considerably worsened and that he had attacked her twice.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fortunately for Mr. A, his boss overheard a conversation between two men in the local tavern. One of the men was Mrs. A's lover, discussing how the two of them had plotted to get rid of Mr. A using the false claims of mental illness and abuse. The hospital staff confronted Mrs. A with her lies:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;She finally agreed that she had plotted with her boy-friend to get rid of her husband, but claimed she had been led on by him and now very much regretted her behaviour. Following some family counselling Mr. and Mrs. A. became reconciled and five years later were still living &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gone_Girl_(film)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Gone Girl&quot;&gt;happily together&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 2&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt; &lt;u&gt;45 year old pub owner married for 14 years&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mr. B was admitted based on his wife's story about her husband’s “heavy drinking, erratic behaviour, and aggressive outbursts.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;On admission to the unit Mr. B. gave a history of domestic difficulties and described mild symptoms of anxiety and depression. ...  He agreed that he was irritable but said that he had never been aggressive and did not acknowledge any of the common symptoms of alcoholism. ... recently ... his wife had lost interest in him and had started associating with younger men. She often stayed out all night, and when he asked her about this behaviour she told him not to be silly and accused him of being a drunk who should be put away.&lt;/blockquote&gt;A member of the staff eventually found out about Mrs. B's fabrication and her intent to get rid of her husband, keep the pub, and “then really start living.” Unlike the outcome of Case 1, Mr. B left his wife and was quite happy without her five years later.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 3&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt; &lt;u&gt;72 year old widow&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This case is unique, because it goes beyond mere mental manipulation. Mrs. C. was referred to a psychiatric hospital because of a &quot;confusional state&quot; and &quot;fecal incontinence&quot; that made her unfit for the old persons' home where she resided. She had moderate Parkinson's disease and slight dementia, but she was fairly well oriented and pleasant in demeanor. She stayed in the hospital for six weeks and showed no signs of fecal incontinence while there. And indeed it turned out that her incontinence had been cruelly induced by large doses of laxatives:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The lady running the home had been unable to develop a good relationship with Mrs. C. and considered &quot;she was a naughty old thing making life difficult for me, my staff, and other folk on purpose&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For some weeks before admission to hospital Mrs. C. had been receiving ’&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bisacodyl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dulcolax&lt;/a&gt;’ tablets one three times a day. This had produced the expected effect with occasional &quot;accidents&quot; due to Mrs. C.’s mobility difficulties. The evidence suggested that Mrs. C. was not wanted in the home and induced incontinence was used as a method of getting her removed to hospital.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 4&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt; Another example is an incident reported by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/588872&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lund and Gardiner (1977)&lt;/a&gt;, where the staff of the mental hospital conspired to keep a patient there so that one of them could live in her flat. The elderly woman had suffered from paranoid episodes in the past that were successfully treated with medication. But this time “they” were really out to get her:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Miss A., an 80-year-old retired professional lady&lt;/u&gt;, was first admitted to a mental hospital in connection with this incident under Section 31 of the Mental Health (Scotland) Act 1960, from her pleasant flat in a residential establishment. The admission notes stated that she had complained that there were people on the premises who had no business there, that they had spoken outside her door saying that they were going to throw her into the river and that she further believed that these people were 'after my flat'...&lt;/blockquote&gt;Miss A was shuttled in and out of hospital several times until the evil plot was finally foiled:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;She was admitted for the third time some four months later with a depressingly similar story. Her general practitioner had been called to the home where the patient had allegedly ' barricaded her room'; she had simply put a chair against the door. She was again admitted under an Emergency Order and once more settled down very rapidly, showing no sign of disturbed behaviour. She was generally pleasant and witty, showing some evidence of valuing her independence and mildly resenting the help of the nursing staff, which she regarded as unnecessary interference. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At this point, suspicion about the motives of the staff at the institution were aroused. Discreet inquiries revealed that the rooms which Miss A occupied had been earmarked for a proposed additional member of staff...&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[And the rental market has only gotten worse in the last 40 years!! So it's not surprising to see many stories emerging from trendy urban areas (and  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/legaladvice/comments/5a60w8/sc_landlord_refusing_repairs_gaslighting_creepy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;South Carolina&lt;/a&gt;). For starters, you can read these anecdotes of landlord gaslighting and harassment from tenants in &lt;a href=&quot;https://cityroom.blogs.nytimes.com/2008/01/24/ask-about-tenant-landlord-issues/comment-page-4/#comment-33881&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ask.metafilter.com/291082/Reality-check-re-slow-bathtub-drain-on-the-third-floor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rossdonnagentry.jennylens.com/city-attorney-ignoring-my-pleas-for-help-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Santa Monica&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expertlaw.com/forums/showthread.php?t=188848&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Case 5&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;–&lt;/span&gt; Let's conclude with one final report from the &lt;i&gt;Canadian Journal of Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/070674378202700310&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kutcher (1982)&lt;/a&gt; described the sad case of &lt;u&gt;Mrs. N, a 59 year old financially successful woman&lt;/u&gt; who was referred to a psychiatrist at her husband's insistence. Marital problems were clearly the source of her distress.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;About two years into the marriage she established Mr. N in a business as he had entered the relationship without a secure financial basis. She then noted he would stay away from home, be unavailable when she tried to contact him, tell her he was visiting with friends even though they denied any visits, and so forth. When she confronted him with these issues he denied any extramarital activity.  ...&lt;/blockquote&gt;Mr. N. wasn't terribly creative; his ruse was ripped from the pages of &lt;i&gt;Gaslight. &lt;/i&gt;An outside party described him as &quot;a 60 year old Cassanova who thinks he's 25.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Numerous friends often intimated that he was involved with another woman and Mrs. N eventually saw this for herself. When confronted, he denied it, then said it was all over and refused to discuss the matter further. He then complained about her &quot;saggy breasts&quot; and when she had surgery for reduction he ridiculed her.&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; He hid her jewelry and accused her of losing it, often changed times they were to meet without notifying her and berated her for being late; and told their acquaintances that she was &quot;going a little strange.&quot;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Unfortunately, Mrs. N's case was not a success story: “Currently she is still in therapy and as yet is unable to resolve the issue.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let's hope the U.S. can collectively (and individually) regain its grip on the truth so it will not suffer a similar fate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnote&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I think she's amazing for her persistence as a guiding voice on social media despite the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teenvogue.com/story/lauren-duca-internet-trolls-online-harassment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;grotesque harassment&lt;/a&gt; she's received.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;OK, gaslighting has jumped the shark &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/wkjxzjGkyE&quot;&gt;https://t.co/wkjxzjGkyE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;— Lauren Duca (@laurenduca) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/laurenduca/status/862126177221316612&quot;&gt;May 10, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Reading&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/on-the-origins-of-gaslighting&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;On the Origins of “Gaslighting”&lt;/a&gt; (by Rosemary Erickson Johnsen)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tressiemc.com/essays-2/a-few-notes-on-gaslighting/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Few Notes on Gaslighting&lt;/a&gt; (by Tressie McMillan Cottom)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Lancet+%28London%2C+England%29&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F4182427&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=The+gas-light+phenomenon.&amp;amp;rft.issn=0140-6736&amp;amp;rft.date=1969&amp;amp;rft.volume=1&amp;amp;rft.issue=7608&amp;amp;rft.spage=1258&amp;amp;rft.epage=60&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Barton+R&amp;amp;rft.au=Whitehead+JA&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Medicine%2CPsychology%2CPsychiatry&quot;&gt;Barton R, &amp;amp; Whitehead JA (1969). The gas-light phenomenon. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Lancet (London, England), 1&lt;/span&gt; (7608), 1258-60. PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/4182427&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;4182427&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Canadian+journal+of+psychiatry.+Revue+canadienne+de+psychiatrie&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F7093877&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=The+gaslight+syndrome.&amp;amp;rft.issn=0706-7437&amp;amp;rft.date=1982&amp;amp;rft.volume=27&amp;amp;rft.issue=3&amp;amp;rft.spage=224&amp;amp;rft.epage=7&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Kutcher+SP&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Medicine%2CPsychology%2CPsychiatry&quot;&gt;Kutcher SP (1982). The gaslight syndrome. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Canadian journal of psychiatry. Revue canadienne de psychiatrie, 27&lt;/span&gt; (3), 224-7 PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/7093877&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;7093877&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=The+British+journal+of+psychiatry+%3A+the+journal+of+mental+science&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F588872&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=The+gaslight+phenomenon--an+institutional+variant.&amp;amp;rft.issn=0007-1250&amp;amp;rft.date=1977&amp;amp;rft.volume=131&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=533&amp;amp;rft.epage=4&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Lund+CA&amp;amp;rft.au=Gardiner+AQ&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Medicine%2CPsychiatry&quot;&gt;Lund CA, &amp;amp; Gardiner AQ (1977). The gaslight phenomenon--an institutional variant. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The British journal of psychiatry : the journal of mental science, 131&lt;/span&gt;, 533-4. PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/588872&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;588872&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=The+British+journal+of+psychiatry+%3A+the+journal+of+mental+science&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F5043219&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=The+%22gaslight+phenomenon%22+reappears.+A+modification+of+the+Ganser+syndrome.&amp;amp;rft.issn=0007-1250&amp;amp;rft.date=1972&amp;amp;rft.volume=120&amp;amp;rft.issue=559&amp;amp;rft.spage=685&amp;amp;rft.epage=6&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Smith+CG&amp;amp;rft.au=Sinanan+K&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Medicine%2CPsychology%2CPsychiatry&quot;&gt;Smith CG, &amp;amp; Sinanan K (1972). The &quot;gaslight phenomenon&quot; reappears. A modification of the Ganser syndrome. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;The British journal of psychiatry : the journal of mental science, 120&lt;/span&gt; (559), 685-6 PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/5043219&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;5043219&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot; data-hveid=&quot;55&quot; data-ved=&quot;0ahUKEwioq5v8yovUAhUhi1QKHXXrAtsQ4EUINzAB&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; [although &lt;a href=&quot;http://bjp.rcpsych.org/content/122/568/367.3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Milo Tyndel (1973)&lt;/a&gt; pointed out those cases were nothing like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ganser_syndrome&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ganser syndrome&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;In today's episode of &quot;Gaslight&quot;... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/M70Zv5rPXe&quot;&gt;https://t.co/M70Zv5rPXe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;— Jon Cryer (@MrJonCryer) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MrJonCryer/status/866665014605656064&quot;&gt;May 22, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can watch the entire film for free at &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/Gaslight_201403&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;archive.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=2ANpI4AY2qM:R8-24srPCOg:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/2ANpI4AY2qM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T03:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Monument to peer review unveiled in Moscow</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Iq2Z72u1eTU/nature.2017.22060"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22060</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Cornerstone of modern science immortalized in concrete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22060&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Iq2Z72u1eTU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quirin Schiermeier</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Juno spacecraft reveals a more complex Jupiter</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/juno-spacecraft-reveals-more-complex-jupiter"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/juno-spacecraft-reveals-more-complex-jupiter</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T18:14:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 NASA’s Juno spacecraft has sent back unexpected details about Jupiter, giving scientists their first intimate look at the giant planet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Obscure brain region linked to feeding frenzy in mice</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/obscure-brain-region-linked-feeding-frenzy-mice"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/obscure-brain-region-linked-feeding-frenzy-mice</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Nerve cells in a little-studied part of the brain exert a powerful effect on eating, a mouse study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Deep heat may have spawned one of the world’s deadliest tsunamis</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-heat-may-have-spawned-one-worlds-deadliest-tsunamis"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-heat-may-have-spawned-one-worlds-deadliest-tsunamis</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The 2004 Indonesian quake was surprisingly strong because of dried-out, brittle minerals far below.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Would-be Johns Hopkins whistleblower loses appeal in case involving Nature retraction</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/25/johns-hopkins-whistleblower-loses-appeal-case-involving-nature-retraction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50191</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T15:50:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A former researcher at Johns Hopkins who voiced concerns about a now-retracted paper in Nature has lost another bid for whistleblower protection. Daniel Yuan, a longtime statistician for former Hopkins yeast geneticist Jef Boeke, was dismissed in 2011, after he’d spent years raising concerns about research coming out of the lab. Yuan’s criticisms, which continued […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/25/johns-hopkins-whistleblower-loses-appeal-case-involving-nature-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Would-be Johns Hopkins whistleblower loses appeal in case involving Nature retraction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal retracts nine papers in one day by author under investigation at the Weizmann Institute</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/25/journal-retracts-nine-papers-one-day-author-investigation-weizmann-institute/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50228</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T13:30:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;On April 27, the Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC) retracted nine papers by a researcher based in Israel, including some dating back to 2000. The reason: Image manipulation. Michal Neeman, vice president of The Weizmann Institute of Science, told us that the researcher, Rony Seger, is under investigation following an allegation of misconduct affecting papers in multiple […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/25/journal-retracts-nine-papers-one-day-author-investigation-weizmann-institute/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal retracts nine papers in one day by author under investigation at the Weizmann Institute&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Probability distributions for time durations</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/05/25/probability-distributions-for-time-durations.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-05-25:/2017/05/25/probability-distributions-for-time-durations.html</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T09:26:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;I will talk about probability distributions for time durations (not time series). I will cover some basic notions of probability theory, random variables and markov models and how these yield / are related to distributions for durations of events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 26/05/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rene te Boekhorst</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T09:26:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Was the “crisis” in social psychology really that bad? Have things improved? Part One: the researchers’ perspective</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/25/was-the-crisis-in-social-psychology-really-that-bad-have-things-improved-part-one-the-researchers-perspective/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24095</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T08:45:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Antique illustration of &quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24116&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24116&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;11&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Antique illustration of \&amp;quot;A nous! A nous!\&amp;quot; by Morlon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1450095537&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ilbusca&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;105&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Antique illustration of \&amp;quot;A nous! A nous!\&amp;quot; by Morlon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Antique illustration of “A nous! A nous!” by Morlon&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-501201158.jpg?w=845?w=661&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-501201158.jpg?w=845?w=194&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-501201158.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1391,2155&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/25/was-the-crisis-in-social-psychology-really-that-bad-have-things-improved-part-one-the-researchers-perspective/antique-illustration-of-a-nous-a-nous-by-morlon/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-501201158.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The field of social psychology is reeling from a series of crises that call into question the everyday scientific practices of its researchers. The fuse was lit by statistician John Ioannidis in 2005, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.0020124&quot;&gt;in a review&lt;/a&gt; that outlined why, thanks particularly to what are now termed “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/12/01/questionable-research-practices-are-rife-in-psychology-survey-suggests/&quot;&gt;questionable research practices&lt;/a&gt;” (QRPs), over half of all published research in social and medical sciences might be invalid. Kaboom. This shook a large swathe of science, but the fires continue to burn especially fiercely in the fields of social and personality psychology, which marshalled its response through &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/toc/ppsa/7/6&quot;&gt;a 2012 special issue in Perspectives on Psychological Science&lt;/a&gt; that brought these concerns fully out in the open, discussing &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/16/ten-famous-psychology-findings-that-its-been-difficult-to-replicate/&quot;&gt;replication failure&lt;/a&gt;, publication biases, and how to reshape incentives to improve the field. The fire flared up again in 2015 with the publication of Brian Nosek and the Open Science Collaboration’s high-profile attempt to replicate 100 studies in these fields, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/08/27/this-is-what-happened-when-psychologists-tried-to-replicate-100-previously-published-findings/&quot;&gt;which succeeded in only 36 per cent of cases&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, and to its credit, efforts to institute better safeguards like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cos.io/rr/&quot;&gt;registered reports&lt;/a&gt; have gathered pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how bad did things get, and have they really improved?&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/qxaby&quot;&gt;new article&lt;/a&gt; in pre-print at the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/i&gt; tries to tackle the issue from two angles: first by asking active researchers what they think of the past and present state of their field, and how they now go about conducting psychology experiments, and second by analysing features of published research to estimate the prevalence of broken practices more objectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper comes from a large group of authors at the University of Illinois at Chicago under the guidance of Linda Skitka, a distinguished social psychologist who participated in the creation of the journal &lt;i&gt;Social Psychological and Personality Science&lt;/i&gt; and who is on the editorial board of many more social psych journals, and led by Matt Motyl, a social and personality psychologist who has published with Nosek in the past, including on the issue of improving scientific practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology research is the air that we breathe at the Digest, making it crucial that we understand its quality. So in this two-part series, we’re going to explore the issues raised in the University of Illinois at Chicago paper, to see if we can make sense of the state of social psychology, beginning in this post with the findings from Motyl et al’s survey of approximately 1,200 social and personality psychologists, from graduate students to full professors, mainly from the US, Europe and Australasia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24095&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motyl’s team began by asking their participants about the state of the field now as opposed to 10 years ago. On average, participants believed that older research would only replicate in 40 per cent of cases – quite close to Nosek’s figure – but they believed that research being conducted now would have a better rate, about 50 per cent, and that generally the field was improving itself in response to the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motyl’s team also canvassed the respondents on a range of questionable research practices, sketchy behaviours like neglecting to report all the measures taken, or quietly dropping experimental conditions from your study. Thanks particularly to work by Joseph Simmons, Leif Nelson, and Uri Simonsohn, we understand just how much these practices compromise the assumptions of scientific significance testing, making it easy to produce false positive results even in the absence of fraudulent intent. In their words, QRPs are not wrong “in the way it’s wrong to jaywalk”, the way that researchers have often implicitly been encouraged to think of them, but “wrong the way it’s wrong to rob a bank.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous surveys of researchers’ own QRP usage have uncovered high levels of admissions, as if the field was rushing to the confession box to purge their sins. Here, Motyl’s team used finer-grained questioning to look at frequency (often a “yes” turned out to be “rarely” or “once”) and justification. In some cases, a researcher’s justification showed that they had misinterpreted the question and that they were actually expressing strong disapproval of the QRP – in fact, this seemed to be the case in virtually all “confessions” of data fabrication. In other cases, the context provided by a justification painted the particular research practice in a completely different light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, consider the seemingly dodgy decision to drop conditions from your study analysis. If your rationale is that the condition didn’t turn out to do what you want to do – in an emotion and memory study, your sad video didn’t produce a sad mood in participants, for instance – it’s actually more problematic to keep what is effectively a bogus condition in your analysis than it is to exclude it (ideally in a principled way according to a registered procedure). For the new survey, independent judges evaluated all the stated justifications, and felt they legitimised the “questionable” practices in 90 per cent of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovering these misunderstandings and justifiable practices littered through the QRP data led Motyl’s team to conclude that pre-explosion psychology practices aren’t as derelict as once feared, although the fact that 70 per cent respondents said they are now less likely to engage in many of these practices than ten years ago suggests that all was not entirely virtuous back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So not perfect, but getting better, is the take within the field: a cautious optimism compared to some dire pronouncements on the state of psychology. In Part  Two, we’ll look at the body of psychological research itself, to see if this optimism is justified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/preprints/psyarxiv/qxaby&quot;&gt;The State of Social and Personality Science: Rotten to the Core, Not so Bad, Getting Better, or Getting Worse?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main image: Antique illustration of ‘A nous! A nous!’ by Morlon (via GettyImages.co.uk under licence)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/26/is-something-rotten-in-the-state-of-social-psychology-part-two-digging-through-the-past/&quot;&gt;Part Two&lt;/a&gt; of our coverage. Also check out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8 of our PsychCrunch podcast: &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Can We Trust Psychological Studies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And our special feature: &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/16/ten-famous-psychology-findings-that-its-been-difficult-to-replicate/&quot;&gt;Ten Famous Psychology Findings That It’s Been Difficult To Replicate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24095/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24095/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24095&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">What can keep young people away from alcohol and cigarettes?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/25/what-can-keep-young-people-away-from-alcohol-and-cigarettes/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9030</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T07:53:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/beer-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Public Health England (PHE), alcohol is now the leading risk factor for ill-health, early mortality and disability among those aged 15 to 49 in England. It wants to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/health-matters-harmful-drinking-and-alcohol-dependence/health-matters-harmful-drinking-and-alcohol-dependence&quot;&gt;prevent and reduce&lt;/a&gt;” the harms caused by alcohol. It also has ambitions to create “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/health-matters-smoking-and-quitting-in-england/smoking-and-quitting-in-england&quot;&gt;a tobacco-free generation&lt;/a&gt;” by 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent figures from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://natcen.ac.uk/our-research/research/survey-of-smoking,-drinking-and-drug-use-among-young-people-in-england/&quot;&gt;Survey of Smoking, Drinking and Drug Use Among Young People in England&lt;/a&gt; show that around 90,000 children aged between 11 and 15 are regular smokers and 240,000 have drunk alcohol in the past week. These figures are the lowest they have been since the survey began in 1982.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-016-2847-x&quot;&gt;recent research published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by colleagues at UCL, shows that around one in seven 11 year-olds is drinking alcohol and that having peers who consume alcohol makes them four times more likely to drink that their peers who don’t. We also know that smokers start young, two thirds of them before the age of 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we wanted to examine more closely the sorts of things that might drive young people away from cigarettes and alcohol. In this way we hope to arm policy makers, health practitioners and those working directly with or caring for children and young people with information that can help with the development of clear policies and interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protective role&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focused on three factors thought to play a protective role in preventing young people from starting to smoke and drink. These were: their awareness of the harms, their well-being or happiness and how supportive their networks of friends and family were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information came from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.understandingsociety.ac.uk&quot;&gt;Understanding Societ&lt;/a&gt;y, a large UK survey, which, in addition to collecting a wide range of social and economic information from everyone in the household aged 16 and over, has a special self-completion questionnaire for 10-15 year olds. Our sample contained 1,729 boys and girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We examined answers at two time points (approximately a year apart) to questions about their smoking and drinking. With these two sets of information, we were able to see whether they had started but then stopped smoking or drinking, whether they were persistent users of cigarettes and alcohol, whether they had started between the first and second surveys (initiation) or whether they had not smoked or drunk alcohol at either point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children were also asked about how happy they were with different aspects of their lives, including how they were getting on at school, how they felt about their appearance, family and friends and life in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a scale of 1-4, the children were asked to rate how risky they thought different levels of smoking and drinking were. They were also asked how many supportive friends they had; friends they could confide in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harm awareness and happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly 70 per cent of the study participants described themselves as persistent non-users of alcohol and cigarettes, and around 13 per cent categorized themselves as persistent users. Persistent non-users scored highest on harm awareness and happiness tests compared to the other groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 8 per cent of the study group labelled themselves as ex-users and about 13 per cent had started using alcohol or cigarettes between the first and second time they completed the survey. Young people aged 10 to 12 were more likely to be in the persistent non-use group, whereas participants aged 13 and above were more likely to be in the persistent user and initiation groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were surprised that while, for most young people, knowledge of the potential and actual harms of alcohol and smoking was linked with them never drinking or smoking, for some it seemed to be associated with them starting to drink or smoke. It is possible that positive expectations from drinking alcohol or smoking cigarettes may, in some way, have overridden their awareness of what harm they could do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The happier the young person was, and more aware of the harms of alcohol and cigarettes, the more likely they were never to drink or smoke. Having supportive friends to confide in did not play a role in preventing adolescents from using alcohol or cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoting happiness and harms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems that promoting young people’s happiness and well-being and making them aware of the harms of smoking and drinking may be key to keeping them away from alcohol and cigarettes. In terms of possible timings for information and interventions, another takeaway from the study might be that working with children between the ages of 10 and 12, before they start trying cigarettes and alcohol, could be important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the information used in this study is self-reported, we need to interpret the findings with caution, but they do suggest that making adolescents aware of alcohol and smoking related harm can be helpful in preventing them from engaging in risky health behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleagues at the Centre are now getting to grips with the new age 14 data from the Millennium Cohort Study and, in collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mentoruk.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/a&gt;, a charity working on the ground in schools to tackle alcohol and drug abuse, are hoping to develop our growing body of evidence in this area that will help formulate policies and activities to make some of Public Health England’s ambitions around smoking and alcohol a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is also featured on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://childofourtimeblog.org.uk/2017/05/what-can-keep-yo%E2%80%A6l-and-cigarettes/&quot;&gt;Child of our Time&lt;/a&gt; blog, which reports on new research and evidence on children’s health and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What could keep young people away from alcohol and cigarettes? Findings from the UK Household Longitudinal Study &lt;/em&gt;is research by Noriko Cable, Maria Francisca Roman Mella and Yvonne Kelly and is published in BMC Public Health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/25/what-can-keep-young-people-away-from-alcohol-and-cigarettes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What can keep young people away from alcohol and cigarettes?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr Noriko Cable</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Putting ClinicalKey in doctors’ hands through Research4Life’s developing country access</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/putting-clinicalkey-in-doctors-hands-through-research4lifes-developing-country-access"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/putting-clinicalkey-in-doctors-hands-through-research4lifes-developing-country-access</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T06:30:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Medical search engine lets doctors and nurses find evidence-based answers while treating patients</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T11:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Jupiter’s secrets revealed by NASA probe</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/kIRnQsZ1dFg/nature.2017.22027"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22027</id>
		<updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A deep ammonia plume and a powerful magnetic field are among the many surprises uncovered by the Juno mission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22027&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22027&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/kIRnQsZ1dFg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New test may improve pancreatic cancer diagnoses</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-test-may-improve-pancreatic-cancer-diagnoses"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-test-may-improve-pancreatic-cancer-diagnoses</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T21:50:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Blood test that detects five tumor proteins may someday help doctors better screen for pancreatic cancer.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Publisher blames bad choice of reviewer for publication of hoax paper on penis as “social construct”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/publisher-blames-bad-choice-reviewer-publication-hoax-paper-penis-social-construct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50269</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T19:20:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Less than a week after publishing a much-discussed hoax paper, a scholarly publisher has acknowledged that it had chosen reviewers for the paper whose “expertise did not fully align with this subject matter.” The subject matter: that the penis should not be considered an anatomical organ, but more as a concept – “a gender-performative, highly fluid social […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/publisher-blames-bad-choice-reviewer-publication-hoax-paper-penis-social-construct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Publisher blames bad choice of reviewer for publication of hoax paper on penis as “social construct” &lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Willingham</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Zika epidemic began long before anyone noticed</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-epidemic-began-long-anyone-noticed"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-epidemic-began-long-anyone-noticed</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Zika spread undetected into Brazil and Florida, a genetic study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Beil</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Authors retract much-debated blockchain paper from F1000</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/authors-retract-much-debated-blockchain-paper-f1000/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50263</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T16:35:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The authors of a popular — and heavily debated — F1000Research paper proposing a method to prevent scientific misconduct have decided to retract it. The paper was initially criticized for allegedly plagiarizing from a graduate student’s blog — and revised to try to “rectify the overlap.” But according to F1000, it is now being retracted after an additional […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/authors-retract-much-debated-blockchain-paper-f1000/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors retract much-debated blockchain paper from F1000&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Unreliability of fMRI Emotional Biomarkers</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8806"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8806</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T14:21:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Brain responses to emotion stimuli are highly variable even within the same individual, and this could be a problem for researchers who seek to use these responses as biomarkers to help diagnose and treat disorders such as depression.

That's according to a new paper in Neuroimage, from University College London neuroscientists Camilla Nord and colleagues.



Nord et al. had 29 volunteers perform three tasks during fMRI scanning. All of the tasks involved pictures of emotional faces, which</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-05-24T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author retracts nanotechnology paper over doubts about key results</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/author-retracts-nanotechnology-paper-doubts-key-results/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49931</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T13:30:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The corresponding author of a 2015 nanotechnology paper has penned a lengthy — and revealing — retraction notice, explaining why he is not certain about the findings. In the notice, Chang Ming Li from the Institute for Clean Energy &amp;amp; Advanced Materials (ICEAM) at Southwest University in China, states that there is “insufficient evidence to conclusively” identify […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/24/author-retracts-nanotechnology-paper-doubts-key-results/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author retracts nanotechnology paper over doubts about key results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Petite parrots provide insight into early flight</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/petite-parrots-provide-insight-early-flight"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/petite-parrots-provide-insight-early-flight</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 High-speed video shows that tiny parrots direct their hops to use the least amount of energy necessary.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Drugs for reflux disease in infants may come with unintended consequences</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/drugs-reflux-disease-infants-may-come-unintended-consequences"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/drugs-reflux-disease-infants-may-come-unintended-consequences</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Infants prescribed proton-pump inhibitors for reflux disease may be at higher risk for broken bones later on.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Survey of US science classrooms suggests role models are vital for encouraging girls into engineering and computer science</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/24/science-classrooms-survey-suggests-role-models-vital-for-encouraging-girls-into-engineering-computer-science/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24045</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T09:25:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_24068&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;TechCrunch 10th Annual Crunches Awards&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24068&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24068&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Steve Jennings&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D3S&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SAN FRANCISCO, CA - FEBRUARY 06:  (L-R) Sarah Buhr, TechCrunch Writer and Marissa Mayer, Yahoo President &amp;amp; CEO attend the TechCrunch 10th Annual Crunchies Awards on February 6, 2017 in San Francisco, California.  (Photo by Steve Jennings\/Getty Images for TechCrunch)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1486415330&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;175&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;TechCrunch 10th Annual Crunches Awards&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;TechCrunch 10th Annual Crunches Awards&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-634118404.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-634118404.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-634118404.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,669&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/24/science-classrooms-survey-suggests-role-models-vital-for-encouraging-girls-into-engineering-computer-science/techcrunch-10th-annual-crunches-awards/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-634118404.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Sarah Buhr, TechCrunch Writer and Marissa Mayer, Yahoo President &amp;amp; CEO attend the TechCrunch 10th Annual Crunchies Awards on February 6, 2017 in San Francisco&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://sheffield.academia.edu/ElizabethKirkham&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Kirkham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you heard the riddle about the doctor? A father and his son are involved in a car accident and taken to different hospitals, the boy to a children’s hospital and the father to the general hospital. When the boy arrives at hospital, the doctor on call is shocked, saying “I can’t treat this boy, he’s my son!” The question is: who’s the doctor? The answer, as with many riddles, is obvious once you know it: the doctor is the boy’s mother. Years ago when I first heard this riddle, I was stumped, even though the only doctor I had contact with in my own life happened to be a woman. The very fact that this question works as a riddle is testament to the strength of negative stereotypes surrounding women’s scientific abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women who take degrees in Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics (STEM) subjects do just as well as their male colleagues, even though they are far outnumbered by them: in the UK, only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wisecampaign.org.uk/uploads/wise/files/WISE_UK_Statistics_2014.pdf&quot;&gt;14 per cent of engineering and technology students, and 17 per cent of computer science&lt;/a&gt; students are women. The picture is similar in the USA, where Catherine Riegle-Crumb and Karisma Morton carried out a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00329/full&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;, published recently in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, to investigate why the numbers are so low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24045&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers focused on the time of life when occupational ambitions begin to take shape: adolescence. Adolescence is also a time when, for better or worse, individuals become increasingly conscious of their peers’ opinions. In light of this, it stands to reason that teenagers’ decisions about their future could be influenced by the attitudes of those around them, both positively and negatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers first measured the science and gender-related attitudes of male and female students aged 13 to 14 in science classrooms across a number of schools. On average, just two per cent of girls believed that boys were better at science and 29 per cent of girls were very confident in their science ability, but 16 per cent of boys endorsed gender/STEM stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the researchers caught up with the same students a year later, and asked them to indicate which subjects they were likely to study at university. The findings differed markedly by STEM subject: of those intending to study biological or physical sciences, slightly more (52 per cent vs. 48 per cent) were girls, and for these subjects, neither the proportion of boys endorsing stereotypes nor the proportion of girls with high science confidence influenced girls’ intentions to pursue these subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, only 33 per cent of students intending to study computer science or engineering were girls. Crucially, girls’ intentions to study these subjects &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; influenced by their classroom environments, decreasing as the proportion of male classroom peers with stereotypical views increased, and increasing as the proportion of female peers who were very confident in their scientific ability increased. Boys’ intentions to study STEM subjects were not affected by these factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings suggest social attitudes swirling around the classroom are affecting girls’ scientific ambitions in important ways. But if we can’t eradicate gender stereotypes, what can we do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings give us an answer: provide girls with positive role models, whether these are female peers who are confident in their scientific abilities, or women scientists who can talk about their achievements and passion for their fields. Initiatives such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wisecampaign.org.uk/&quot;&gt;WISE campaign&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inspiringthefuture.org/volunteers/inspiring-women/&quot;&gt;Inspiring the Future&lt;/a&gt; facilitate opportunities for women to speak to young people about their own careers and areas of interest. And there is reason to be optimistic – the girls in this research were not deterred from studying biological or physical sciences, despite the presence of unhelpful stereotypes in their classrooms. With the right support and guidance, it may not be long before we can say the same about other STEM subjects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00329/full&quot;&gt;Gendered Expectations: Examining How Peers Shape Female Students’ Intent to Pursue STEM Fields&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main photo by Steve Jennings/Getty Images for TechCrunch, reproduced here under licence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Elizabeth Kirkham&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-24093&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24093&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1462040996&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Elizabeth Kirkham&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/elizabeth-kirkham.jpg?w=245&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/elizabeth-kirkham.jpg?w=245&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/elizabeth-kirkham.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;245,216&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/24/science-classrooms-survey-suggests-role-models-vital-for-encouraging-girls-into-engineering-computer-science/elizabeth-kirkham/&quot; height=&quot;132&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/elizabeth-kirkham.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=132&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://sheffield.academia.edu/ElizabethKirkham&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Kirkham&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://digest.bps.org.uk&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Elizabeth is a PhD student at the University of Sheffield, where she is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://levita-lab.group.shef.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Developmental Affective Neuroscience Lab&lt;/a&gt;. Her research uses EEG to examine the effects of childhood stress on the adult brain. Elizabeth has previously worked for the journal &lt;em&gt;eLife&lt;/em&gt; writing accessible summaries of scientific articles, and in 2014 she won first prize in the Access to Understanding science writing competition. She can be found on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EK_Neuro&quot;&gt;@EK_Neuro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24045/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24045/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24045&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Can parents help their kids get sufficient sleep? When and how they provide support makes all the difference.</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/24/can-parents-help-their-kids-get-sufficient-sleep-when-and-how-they-provide-support-makes-all-the-difference/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9015</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T08:51:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Child-Sleep-Blog-image-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rising rates of childhood overweight and obesity have brought physical activity, healthy eating, and sedentary behaviour to the forefront of public health discussions. Lingering in the background is the essential, yet often overlooked, behaviour: sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its influence on cognitive and physical development, lack of sleep continues to be implicated in the child obesity epidemic. Inadequate sleep increases the risk of child obesity, both independently and by negatively affecting children’s physical activity levels and hormones associated with obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lack of sleep continues to be implicated in the child obesity epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Canada, children’s sleep duration has been decreasing in recent decades, thus prompting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.participaction.com/sites/default/files/downloads/2016%20ParticipACTION%20Report%20Card%20-%20Full%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 ParticipACTION Report Card on Physical Activity for Children and Youth&lt;/a&gt; to ask, “Are Canadian kids too tired to move?” This key report also highlighted the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csep.ca/CMFiles/Guidelines/24hrGlines/Canadian24HourMovementGuidelines2016.pdf&quot;&gt;Canadian 24-Hour Movement Guidelines for Children and Youth&lt;/a&gt;, which reveal that a healthy 24 hours includes an uninterrupted, consistent 9 to 11 hours of sleep per night for those aged 5–13 years, and 8 to 10 hours per night for those aged 14–17 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-016-3245-0&quot;&gt;previous research&lt;/a&gt; on child physical activity, healthy eating, and screen time presented a framework for classifying parental support behaviours. Parents’ behaviours also play a key role in influencing the sleep patterns of children across a range of ages. For our current study, we explored the contribution of motivational (encouragement) and regulatory (rule enforcement) parental support behaviours for predicting whether or not children meet the aforementioned sleep guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data were collected by Public Health Ontario using Computer Assisted Telephone Interviews (CATI) of parents or guardians living in Ontario, Canada. Our analyses included description of the sample by demographic characteristics, parental support behaviours, and child sleep duration; as well as construction of two multivariable logistic regression models to predict whether or not parents reported their child was meeting sleep guidelines – one for weekday sleep and another for sleep on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that as children enter and progress through adolescence, the proportion of children meeting Canadian sleep guidelines decreases, as do the proportion of parents engaging in support behaviours for sleep. Taken together, this suggests that the time period when parents are less engaged, may actually be when their kids most need the support. (Parents of unruly, sleepy teenagers will rightfully contend that this is easier said than done). Nonetheless, given that around 94% of parents reported encouraging their child to go to bed at a specific time, and just over 84% reported enforcing bedtime rules, it is clear that parents are aware and trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study also revealed that parents who reported encouraging their child to go to bed at a specific time were less likely to have children meeting sleep guidelines on weekdays. While initially surprising, it is not unreasonable to speculate that encouragement may be a parent’s reaction to their child’s already-established poor sleep habits. In other words, this may be a “chicken or the egg” problem, in which parents’ encouragement doesn’t produce poor sleep habits, but rather, children’s’ poor sleep habits prompt parents to encourage them to get to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, on weekends, none of the parental support behaviors were found to contribute to children meeting sleep guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents who reported enforcing rules about their child’s bedtime were more likely to have their child meeting sleep guidelines on weekdays, which may reflect general parental expectations, bedtime structure, or the proactive nature of rule-setting. Unexpectedly, on weekends, none of the parental support behaviors were found to contribute to children meeting sleep guidelines. That is not to say that parents have no control over their kid’s sleep on weekends, but weekends are often viewed as “wildcard” days with less consistent bed/wake time, and more activities that may impede sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is evident that use and presence of screens in the bedroom can negatively affect children’s sleep; however, our study found that neither rules nor encouragement to limit screens in the bedroom had an effect on children getting sufficient sleep. To help make sense of this finding, consider the use of a family living room only a few decades ago, in which “screen time” (often a single television) could be easily measured and controlled by parents. Now consider present day screen time, in its many forms, representing a highly unstructured activity with no clear starting and end point. The smaller and more portable the device, the easier it is to use in the bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue that now, more than ever, parents face challenges to effectively supporting child healthy behaviours, due to the pervasiveness of electronic media. It will be important for future studies to focus on how parental support behaviours can be made most effective, and what can be modified in the home environment to support children getting a good nights sleep. Children—even more than our cell phones, laptops, and tablets—need to recharge, and parents are instrumental in helping them do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/24/can-parents-help-their-kids-get-sufficient-sleep-when-and-how-they-provide-support-makes-all-the-difference/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can parents help their kids get sufficient sleep? When and how they provide support makes all the difference.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Evelyn Pyper</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Colombian biologist cleared of criminal charges for posting another scientist’s thesis online</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/then4x3LsyM/nature.2017.22057"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22057</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Diego Gómez had faced up to eight years in jail in closely watched copyright case whose verdict has been appealed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22057&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22057&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/then4x3LsyM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michele  Catanzaro</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tissue-independent cancer drug gets fast-track approval from US regulator</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/d4KcuKELo5A/nature.2017.22054"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22054</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Treatment will be given on the basis of a tumour’s molecular markers, rather than its location in the body.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22054&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22054&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/d4KcuKELo5A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Heidi Ledford</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fleeting phase of planet formation discovered</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/q2NE2-oyGKM/nature.2017.22039"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22039</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;These celestial bodies coalesce into objects shaped like giant red blood cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22039&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22039&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/q2NE2-oyGKM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ramin Skibba</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fund to curb outbreaks and chronic disease on the chopping block</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/z6Ym-8h3YK4/nature.2017.21963"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21963</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention stands to lose 12% of its budget through proposed cuts in the American Health Care Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21963&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21963&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/z6Ym-8h3YK4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Maxmen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Medical microbots need better imaging and control</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EEle9r0fuxk/545406a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545406a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Mariana Medina-Sánchez and Oliver G. Schmidt set priorities for more realistic tests of tiny machines that could be used to diagnose and treat conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 406 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545406a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545406a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EEle9r0fuxk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariana Medina-Sánchez</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The best-kept secrets to winning grants</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/XDs47O1T25k/545399a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545399a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;With competition for research funding approaching an all-time high, experts reveal their top tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 399 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545399a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545399a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/XDs47O1T25k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kendall Powell</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Drop in cases of Zika threatens large-scale trials</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/wXFLd_vkI3U/545396a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545396a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Dwindling infection rate makes reliable data hard to gather.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 396 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545396a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545396a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/wXFLd_vkI3U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Declan Butler</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">China expands DNA data grab in troubled western region</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xf2ISMo5fKw/545395a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545395a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Alarms raised over suspected efforts to collect massive numbers of genetic samples from citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 395 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545395a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545395a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xf2ISMo5fKw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Cyranoski</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum computing, election pledges and a thief who made science history</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CxA8OwxAnhA/545390a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545390a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 19–25 May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 390 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545390a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545390a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CxA8OwxAnhA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Eighty-eight days till the next total eclipse of the Sun</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/zmrr3TFuN7k/545385b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545385b</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Nature  won’t repeat the mistake of its founding editor when this summer’s totality is visible in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 386 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/545385b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545385b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/zmrr3TFuN7k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cell imaging: An intracellular dance visualized</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/fUfqos_T5b8/nature22500"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22500</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The development of a microscopy technique that enables observation of the interactions between six types of organelle, in 3D and over time, holds promise for improving our understanding of intracellular processes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22500&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/fUfqos_T5b8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sang-Hee Shim</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Epidemiology: Molecular mapping of Zika spread</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/EgP_3Aipw1Q/nature22495"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22495</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Evolutionary trees constructed using both newly sequenced and previously available Zika virus genomes reveal how the recent outbreak arose in Brazil and spread across the Americas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22495&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22495&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/EgP_3Aipw1Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Worobey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Zika virus evolution and spread in the Americas</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/KJnK8TPpQYA/nature22402"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22402</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Although the recent Zika virus (ZIKV) epidemic in the Americas and its link to birth defects have attracted a great deal of attention, much remains unknown about ZIKV disease epidemiology and ZIKV evolution, in part owing to a lack of genomic data. Here we address this gap in knowledge by using multiple sequencing approaches to generate 110 ZIKV genomes from clinical and mosquito samples from 10 countries and territories, greatly expanding the observed viral genetic diversity from this outbreak. We analysed the timing and patterns of introductions into distinct geographic regions; our phylogenetic evidence suggests rapid expansion of the outbreak in Brazil and multiple introductions of outbreak strains into Puerto Rico, Honduras, Colombia, other Caribbean islands, and the continental United States. We find that ZIKV circulated undetected in multiple regions for many months before the first locally transmitted cases were confirmed, highlighting the importance of surveillance of viral infections. We identify mutations with possible functional implications for ZIKV biology and pathogenesis, as well as those that might be relevant to the effectiveness of diagnostic tests. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22402&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22402&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/KJnK8TPpQYA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Hayden C. Metsky</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Establishment and cryptic transmission of Zika virus in Brazil and the Americas</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/FnONXM0TvYs/nature22401"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22401</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Transmission of Zika virus (ZIKV) in the Americas was first confirmed in May 2015 in northeast Brazil. Brazil has had the highest number of reported ZIKV cases worldwide (more than 200,000 by 24 December 2016) and the most cases associated with microcephaly and other birth defects (2,366 confirmed by 31 December 2016). Since the initial detection of ZIKV in Brazil, more than 45 countries in the Americas have reported local ZIKV transmission, with 24 of these reporting severe ZIKV-associated disease. However, the origin and epidemic history of ZIKV in Brazil and the Americas remain poorly understood, despite the value of this information for interpreting observed trends in reported microcephaly. Here we address this issue by generating 54 complete or partial ZIKV genomes, mostly from Brazil, and reporting data generated by a mobile genomics laboratory that travelled across northeast Brazil in 2016. One sequence represents the earliest confirmed ZIKV infection in Brazil. Analyses of viral genomes with ecological and epidemiological data yield an estimate that ZIKV was present in northeast Brazil by February 2014 and is likely to have disseminated from there, nationally and internationally, before the first detection of ZIKV in the Americas. Estimated dates for the international spread of ZIKV from Brazil indicate the duration of pre-detection cryptic transmission in recipient regions. The role of northeast Brazil in the establishment of ZIKV in the Americas is further supported by geographic analysis of ZIKV transmission potential and by estimates of the basic reproduction number of the virus. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22401&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22401&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/FnONXM0TvYs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>N. R. Faria</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genomic epidemiology reveals multiple introductions of Zika virus into the United States</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/t3QfhYvHZmg/nature22400"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22400</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Zika virus (ZIKV) is causing an unprecedented epidemic linked to severe congenital abnormalities. In July 2016, mosquito-borne ZIKV transmission was reported in the continental United States; since then, hundreds of locally acquired infections have been reported in Florida. To gain insights into the timing, source, and likely route(s) of ZIKV introduction, we tracked the virus from its first detection in Florida by sequencing ZIKV genomes from infected patients and Aedes aegypti mosquitoes. We show that at least 4 introductions, but potentially as many as 40, contributed to the outbreak in Florida and that local transmission is likely to have started in the spring of 2016—several months before its initial detection. By analysing surveillance and genetic data, we show that ZIKV moved among transmission zones in Miami. Our analyses show that most introductions were linked to the Caribbean, a finding corroborated by the high incidence rates and traffic volumes from the region into the Miami area. Our study provides an understanding of how ZIKV initiates transmission in new regions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22400&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22400&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/t3QfhYvHZmg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nathan D. Grubaugh</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Leaf bacterial diversity mediates plant diversity and ecosystem function relationships</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/R1rC_tur0TI/nature22399"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22399</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Research on biodiversity and ecosystem functioning has demonstrated links between plant diversity and ecosystem functions such as productivity. At other trophic levels, the plant microbiome has been shown to influence host plant fitness and function, and host-associated microbes have been proposed to influence ecosystem function through their role in defining the extended phenotype of host organisms However, the importance of the plant microbiome for ecosystem function has not been quantified in the context of the known importance of plant diversity and traits. Here, using a tree biodiversity–ecosystem functioning experiment, we provide strong support for the hypothesis that leaf bacterial diversity is positively linked to ecosystem productivity, even after accounting for the role of plant diversity. Our results also show that host species identity, functional identity and functional diversity are the main determinants of leaf bacterial community structure and diversity. Our study provides evidence of a positive correlation between plant-associated microbial diversity and terrestrial ecosystem productivity, and a new mechanism by which models of biodiversity–ecosystem functioning relationships can be improved. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22399&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22399&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/R1rC_tur0TI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Isabelle Laforest-Lapointe</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ensemble cryo-EM elucidates the mechanism of translation fidelity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WmMATZS6FfE/nature22397"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22397</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Gene translation depends on accurate decoding of mRNA, the structural mechanism of which remains poorly understood. Ribosomes decode mRNA codons by selecting cognate aminoacyl-tRNAs delivered by elongation factor Tu (EF-Tu). Here we present high-resolution structural ensembles of ribosomes with cognate or near-cognate aminoacyl-tRNAs delivered by EF-Tu. Both cognate and near-cognate tRNA anticodons explore the aminoacyl-tRNA-binding site (A site) of an open 30S subunit, while inactive EF-Tu is separated from the 50S subunit. A transient conformation of decoding-centre nucleotide G530 stabilizes the cognate codon–anticodon helix, initiating step-wise ‘latching’ of the decoding centre. The resulting closure of the 30S subunit docks EF-Tu at the sarcin–ricin loop of the 50S subunit, activating EF-Tu for GTP hydrolysis and enabling accommodation of the aminoacyl-tRNA. By contrast, near-cognate complexes fail to induce the G530 latch, thus favouring open 30S pre-accommodation intermediates with inactive EF-Tu. This work reveals long-sought structural differences between the pre-accommodation of cognate and near-cognate tRNAs that elucidate the mechanism of accurate decoding. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22397&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22397&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WmMATZS6FfE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anna B. Loveland</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Therapeutic T cell engineering</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ZhbxYSEUTWM/nature22395"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22395</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Genetically engineered T cells are powerful new medicines, offering hope for curative responses in patients with cancer. Chimaeric antigen receptors (CARs) are a class of synthetic receptors that reprogram lymphocyte specificity and function. CARs targeting CD19 have demonstrated remarkable potency in B cell malignancies. Engineered T cells are applicable in principle to many cancers, pending further progress to identify suitable target antigens, overcome immunosuppressive tumour microenvironments, reduce toxicities, and prevent antigen escape. Advances in the selection of optimal T cells, genetic engineering, and cell manufacturing are poised to broaden T-cell-based therapies and foster new applications in infectious diseases and autoimmunity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 423 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22395&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22395&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ZhbxYSEUTWM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michel Sadelain</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cryo-EM structure of the activated GLP-1 receptor in complex with a G protein</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tWf60ycX2JQ/nature22394"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22394</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1) is a hormone with essential roles in regulating insulin secretion, carbohydrate metabolism and appetite. GLP-1 effects are mediated through binding to the GLP-1 receptor (GLP-1R), a class B G-protein-coupled receptor (GPCR) that signals primarily through the stimulatory G protein Gs. Class B GPCRs are important therapeutic targets; however, our understanding of their mechanism of action is limited by the lack of structural information on activated and full-length receptors. Here we report the cryo-electron microscopy structure of the peptide-activated GLP-1R–Gs complex at near atomic resolution. The peptide is clasped between the N-terminal domain and the transmembrane core of the receptor, and further stabilized by extracellular loops. Conformational changes in the transmembrane domain result in a sharp kink in the middle of transmembrane helix 6, which pivots its intracellular half outward to accommodate the α5-helix of the Ras-like domain of Gs. These results provide a structural framework for understanding class B GPCR activation through hormone binding. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22394&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22394&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tWf60ycX2JQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yan Zhang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Applying systems-level spectral imaging and analysis to reveal the organelle interactome</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ajqOBNp5mNE/nature22369"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22369</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The organization of the eukaryotic cell into discrete membrane-bound organelles allows for the separation of incompatible biochemical processes, but the activities of these organelles must be coordinated. For example, lipid metabolism is distributed between the endoplasmic reticulum for lipid synthesis, lipid droplets for storage and transport, mitochondria and peroxisomes for β-oxidation, and lysosomes for lipid hydrolysis and recycling. It is increasingly recognized that organelle contacts have a vital role in diverse cellular functions. However, the spatial and temporal organization of organelles within the cell remains poorly characterized, as fluorescence imaging approaches are limited in the number of different labels that can be distinguished in a single image. Here we present a systems-level analysis of the organelle interactome using a multispectral image acquisition method that overcomes the challenge of spectral overlap in the fluorescent protein palette. We used confocal and lattice light sheet instrumentation and an imaging informatics pipeline of five steps to achieve mapping of organelle numbers, volumes, speeds, positions and dynamic inter-organelle contacts in live cells from a monkey fibroblast cell line. We describe the frequency and locality of two-, three-, four- and five-way interactions among six different membrane-bound organelles (endoplasmic reticulum, Golgi, lysosome, peroxisome, mitochondria and lipid droplet) and show how these relationships change over time. We demonstrate that each organelle has a characteristic distribution and dispersion pattern in three-dimensional space and that there is a reproducible pattern of contacts among the six organelles, that is affected by microtubule and cell nutrient status. These live-cell confocal and lattice light sheet spectral imaging approaches are applicable to any cell system expressing multiple fluorescent probes, whether in normal conditions or when cells are exposed to disturbances such as drugs, pathogens or stress. This methodology thus offers a powerful descriptive tool and can be used to develop hypotheses about cellular organization and dynamics. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22369&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22369&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ajqOBNp5mNE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alex M. Valm</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Large conservation gains possible for global biodiversity facets</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Sau3iP0xY3s/nature22368"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22368</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Different facets of biodiversity other than species numbers are increasingly appreciated as critical for maintaining the function of ecosystems and their services to humans. While new international policy and assessment processes such as the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform on Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services (IPBES) recognize the importance of an increasingly global, quantitative and comprehensive approach to biodiversity protection, most insights are still focused on a single facet of biodiversity—species. Here we broaden the focus and provide an evaluation of how much of the world’s species, functional and phylogenetic diversity of birds and mammals is currently protected and the scope for improvement. We show that the large existing gaps in the coverage for each facet of diversity could be remedied by a slight expansion of protected areas: an additional 5% of the land has the potential to more than triple the protected range of species or phylogenetic or functional units. Further, the same areas are often priorities for multiple diversity facets and for both taxa. However, we find that the choice of conservation strategy has a fundamental effect on outcomes. It is more difficult (that is, requires more land) to maximize basic representation of the global biodiversity pool than to maximize local diversity. Overall, species and phylogenetic priorities are more similar to each other than they are to functional priorities, and priorities for the different bird biodiversity facets are more similar than those of mammals. Our work shows that large gains in biodiversity protection are possible, while also highlighting the need to explicitly link desired conservation objectives and biodiversity metrics. We provide a framework and quantitative tools to advance these goals for multi-faceted biodiversity conservation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22368&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22368&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Sau3iP0xY3s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura J. Pollock</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">CPS1 maintains pyrimidine pools and DNA synthesis in KRAS/LKB1-mutant lung cancer cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/XeftUkJ-cS8/nature22359"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22359</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Metabolic reprogramming by oncogenic signals promotes cancer initiation and progression. The oncogene KRAS and tumour suppressor STK11, which encodes the kinase LKB1, regulate metabolism and are frequently mutated in non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Concurrent occurrence of oncogenic KRAS and loss of LKB1 (KL) in cells specifies aggressive oncological behaviour. Here we show that human KL cells and tumours share metabolomic signatures of perturbed nitrogen handling. KL cells express the urea cycle enzyme carbamoyl phosphate synthetase-1 (CPS1), which produces carbamoyl phosphate in the mitochondria from ammonia and bicarbonate, initiating nitrogen disposal. Transcription of CPS1 is suppressed by LKB1 through AMPK, and CPS1 expression correlates inversely with LKB1 in human NSCLC. Silencing CPS1 in KL cells induces cell death and reduces tumour growth. Notably, cell death results from pyrimidine depletion rather than ammonia toxicity, as CPS1 enables an unconventional pathway of nitrogen flow from ammonia into pyrimidines. CPS1 loss reduces the pyrimidine to purine ratio, compromises S-phase progression and induces DNA-polymerase stalling and DNA damage. Exogenous pyrimidines reverse DNA damage and rescue growth. The data indicate that the KL oncological genotype imposes a metabolic vulnerability related to a dependence on a cross-compartmental pathway of pyrimidine metabolism in an aggressive subset of NSCLC. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22359&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22359&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/XeftUkJ-cS8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jiyeon Kim</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lymphatic endothelial S1P promotes mitochondrial function and survival in naive T cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Lfs83jWovkA/nature22352"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22352</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Effective adaptive immune responses require a large repertoire of naive T cells that migrate throughout the body, rapidly identifying almost any foreign peptide. Because the production of T cells declines with age, naive T cells must be long-lived. However, it remains unclear how naive T cells survive for years while constantly travelling. The chemoattractant sphingosine 1-phosphate (S1P) guides T cell circulation among secondary lymphoid organs, including spleen, lymph nodes and Peyer’s patches, where T cells search for antigens. The concentration of S1P is higher in circulatory fluids than in lymphoid organs, and the S1P1 receptor (S1P1R) directs the exit of T cells from the spleen into blood, and from lymph nodes and Peyer’s patches into lymph. Here we show that S1P is essential not only for the circulation of naive T cells, but also for their survival. Using transgenic mouse models, we demonstrate that lymphatic endothelial cells support the survival of T cells by secreting S1P via the transporter SPNS2, that this S1P signals through S1P1R on T cells, and that the requirement for S1P1R is independent of the established role of the receptor in guiding exit from lymph nodes. S1P signalling maintains the mitochondrial content of naive T cells, providing cells with the energy to continue their constant migration. The S1P signalling pathway is being targeted therapeutically to inhibit autoreactive T cell trafficking, and these findings suggest that it may be possible simultaneously to target autoreactive or malignant cell survival. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22352&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22352&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Lfs83jWovkA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alejandra Mendoza</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Blocking FSH induces thermogenic adipose tissue and reduces body fat</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/u_lC35T7BVk/nature22342"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22342</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Menopause is associated with bone loss and enhanced visceral adiposity. A polyclonal antibody that targets the β-subunit of the pituitary hormone follicle-stimulating hormone (Fsh) increases bone mass in mice. Here, we report that this antibody sharply reduces adipose tissue in wild-type mice, phenocopying genetic haploinsufficiency for the Fsh receptor gene Fshr. The antibody also causes profound beiging, increases cellular mitochondrial density, activates brown adipose tissue and enhances thermogenesis. These actions result from the specific binding of the antibody to the β-subunit of Fsh to block its action. Our studies uncover opportunities for simultaneously treating obesity and osteoporosis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22342&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22342&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/u_lC35T7BVk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peng Liu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Let me sleep when I die</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/vQXShbqWktE/545520a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545520a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Time to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 520 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545520a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545520a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/vQXShbqWktE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Wendy Nikel</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 &amp;amp; 100 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/_LlV2Pr-k_4/545419a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545419a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 419 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545419a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545419a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/_LlV2Pr-k_4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature Biological Sciences Research</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Medical research: Personalized test tracks cancer relapse</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/aovFwmSr2Ug/545417a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545417a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Genomic analysis of lung-tumour evolution has been used to create personalized blood tests that enable successful clinical monitoring for early signs of cancer relapse — a promising step on the road to precision medicine.  See Article    p.446&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 417 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545417a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545417a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/aovFwmSr2Ug&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alberto Bardelli</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Predatory journals: outwit with a safe list</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Cyvtrva36wM/545412d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412d</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 412 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545412d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Cyvtrva36wM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Henry Woo</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecular taxonomy: Species disconnected from DNA sequences</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/NX7PZvk3pZM/545412c"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412c</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 412 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545412c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/NX7PZvk3pZM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter Uetz</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cod stocks: Don't derail cod's comeback in Canada</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3hsSveOtzuY/545412b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412b</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 412 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545412b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3hsSveOtzuY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sherrylynn Rowe</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Impact factors: Is the Nature Index at odds with DORA?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/FmFRYYEAKp8/545412a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 412 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545412a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545412a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/FmFRYYEAKp8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ludo Waltman</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Books in brief</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oYfvz-eHjyk/545411a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545411a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 411 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545411a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545411a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oYfvz-eHjyk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Barbara Kiser</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Museums: The life and times of a curiosity-monger</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/IwzCpKvE5no/545410a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545410a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Henry Nicholls revels in a biography of Enlightenment collector and Royal Society president Hans Sloane.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 410 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545410a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545410a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/IwzCpKvE5no&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Henry Nicholls</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Astronomy: An all-American eclipse</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Cekb8WIkVnY/545409a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545409a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Jay Pasachoff enjoys four books heralding this summer's US total solar eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 545 409 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/545409a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/545409a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Cekb8WIkVnY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jay Pasachoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How a flamingo balances on one leg</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-flamingo-balances-one-leg"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-flamingo-balances-one-leg</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T23:59:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Flamingos’ built-in tricks for balance might have a thing or two to teach standing robots or prosthesis makers someday.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Using Discourse Analysis to Assess Cognitive Decline</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/tYYDadX2k1g/using-discourse-analysis-to-assess.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-6283119004927853198</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T23:49:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mT-NB1kp71M/WKlJKRrlx3I/AAAAAAAAMBk/qACWmxtPnfweLr2JF4poTAcEFOKaZRBEQCLcB/s1600/outline%2Bof%2BMCI.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mT-NB1kp71M/WKlJKRrlx3I/AAAAAAAAMBk/qACWmxtPnfweLr2JF4poTAcEFOKaZRBEQCLcB/s400/outline%2Bof%2BMCI.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673606685425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gauthier et al. (2005)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alzheimer's Disease (AD) and other dementias are progressive neurodegenerative conditions that unfold over time. Subtle symptoms such as forgetfulness and word finding problems may progress to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673606685425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mild cognitive impairment&lt;/a&gt; (MCI), and then escalate to full-blown dementia. Recent efforts to classify &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2881320/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Defining 'Prodromal' Alzheimer’s Disease, Frontotemporal Dementia, and Lewy Body Dementia: Are we there yet?&quot;&gt;prodromal states&lt;/a&gt; have included automated analysis of spontaneous speech, which loses complexity as the disease progresses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In one study, &lt;strike&gt;Frazier&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3233/JAD-150520&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fraser et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt; applied machine learning methods to speech transcripts and audio files from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.talkbank.org/DementiaBank/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DementiaBank&lt;/a&gt; database. The participants were 167 patients with probable AD and 97 controls. The authors considered a total of 370 linguistic features, and found that a subset of 35 was able to classify patients vs. controls with 82% accuracy.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; While an advance over previous studies, this is not yet useful for diagnostic purposes. Another limitation was the relatively short length of the speech samples.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using factor analysis, the researchers found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://alzheimersnewstoday.com/2015/12/15/alzheimers-disease-markers-found-speech-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;four dimensions of speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;were most indicative of dementia: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Semantic impairment&lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt; – &lt;/span&gt;using overly simple words&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acoustic impairment &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;e.g., speaking more  slowly &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syntactic impairment  &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;using less complex grammar &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Information impairment &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;not clearly identifying the main aspects  of a picture they were told to describe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Public figures who give repeated interviews leave a searchable record of spontaneous speech that can be analyzed for changes over time. Presidential press conferences provide another rich source of data for linguistic analysis. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25633673&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Berisha et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt; examined &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transcripts&lt;/a&gt; from the press conferences given by Ronald Reagan (1981-1989) and George H.W. Bush (1989-1993). We know that President Reagan received a formal diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease in 1994, five years after leaving office. And as far as we know, the elder Bush is still cognitively intact for his age (he's 92 now).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The quantified linguistic features included:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Number of unique words&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Non-specific nouns – e.g., &lt;i&gt;thing, something, anything&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filler words – &lt;i&gt;well, so, basically, actually, literally, um, ah&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low-imageability, high frequency verbs &lt;i&gt;– e.g., &lt;i&gt;get, give, go, have, do&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reagan showed a significant decline in the number of unique words over the course of his presidency, but Bush did not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-W3MMHZEZQqg/WKloZbS7jEI/AAAAAAAAMB4/oJKTD80k2o0HFZLiepXi0dVUEKS43k6YACLcB/s1600/unique%2Bwords_linked%2Bto%2BAD%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-W3MMHZEZQqg/WKloZbS7jEI/AAAAAAAAMB4/oJKTD80k2o0HFZLiepXi0dVUEKS43k6YACLcB/s400/unique%2Bwords_linked%2Bto%2BAD%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Likewise, Reagan showed a significant &lt;i&gt;increase&lt;/i&gt; in the use of non-specific nouns and fillers, but Bush did not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2r3dyRDBak/WKloZfPjJ4I/AAAAAAAAMB0/fbUHrn28BPgSlF1ZKIMXycTB1fMrDZN_wCLcB/s1600/non-specific%2Bnouns%2Band%2Bfillers%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2r3dyRDBak/WKloZfPjJ4I/AAAAAAAAMB0/fbUHrn28BPgSlF1ZKIMXycTB1fMrDZN_wCLcB/s400/non-specific%2Bnouns%2Band%2Bfillers%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are several caveats here. Reagan was 69 when he was elected, while Bush was 64. Reagan was president for eight years and Bush for only four years; yet Bush held over twice as many press conferences as Reagan. Nonetheless, the results are consistent with a decline in cognitive function (which is not uncommon when aging from 69 to 77). Can we can classify Reagan as having MCI on the basis of these results? I don't think so. We'd really need comparable data from a population of demographically matched elderly participants.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;President Donald Trump&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2017/02/16/remarks-president-trump-press-conference&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feb. 16 press conference&lt;/a&gt;, the public debate over whether President Trump is mentally unbalanced has intensified. Much of the current and past discussion has centered on the possibility of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narcissistic_personality_disorder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narcissistic Personality Disorder&lt;/a&gt; (NPD), as speculated in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/06/the-mind-of-donald-trump/480771/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vanityfair.com/news/2015/11/donald-trump-narcissism-therapists&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2017/feb/17/donald-trump-narcisissm-mentally-ill-personality?CMP=share_btn_tw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, Trump has many of these qualities (that predate his &lt;i&gt;actual&lt;/i&gt; grandiose status as POTUS): &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grandiosity with expectations of superior treatment from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixated on fantasies of power, success, intelligence, attractiveness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Self-perception of being unique, superior and associated with high-status people and institutions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Needing constant admiration from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sense of entitlement to special treatment and to obedience from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exploitative of others to achieve personal gain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unwilling to empathize with others' feelings, wishes, or needs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Intensely envious of others and the belief that others are equally envious of them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pompous and arrogant demeanor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;And we can call him &lt;b&gt;narcissistic&lt;/b&gt; in the generic sense of the word. But do we need to diagnose him with a quasi-psychiatric disorder, as in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/13/opinion/mental-health-professionals-warn-about-trump.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;NY Times&lt;/i&gt; letter&lt;/a&gt; signed by 35 mental health professionals?&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Mr. Trump’s speech and actions demonstrate an inability to tolerate views different from his own, leading to rage reactions. His words and behavior suggest a profound inability to empathize. Individuals with these traits distort reality to suit their psychological state, attacking facts and those who convey them (journalists, scientists).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a powerful leader, these attacks are likely to increase, as his personal myth of greatness appears to be confirmed. We believe that the grave emotional instability indicated by Mr. Trump’s speech and actions makes him incapable of serving safely as president.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Allen Frances, chair of the DSM-IV task force, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/14/opinion/an-eminent-psychiatrist-demurs-on-trumps-mental-state.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forcefully argued&lt;/a&gt; that Trump does not meet criteria for NPD, because he is not distressed by his behavior:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Mr. Trump causes severe distress rather than experiencing it and has  been richly rewarded, rather than punished, for his grandiosity,  self-absorption and lack of empathy. It is a stigmatizing insult to the  mentally ill (who are mostly well behaved and well meaning) to be lumped  with Mr. Trump (who is neither).&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Discourse Analysis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here I'll suggest a different approach: can we quantify age-related neurological change using spontaneous speech?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;This is probably my favorite part so far &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/n61y5I8UrN&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/n61y5I8UrN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;— Rachel Riederer (@readerer) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/readerer/status/832303185826033664&quot;&gt;February 16, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;“You know what uranium is, right?  It's this &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;thing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; called nuclear weapons  and other &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Like&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, lots of &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;done&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with uranium,  including some bad &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Nobody talks about that.  I didn't &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;do&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; anything&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for Russia.  I've &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;done&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;nothing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; for Russia.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the most egregious example in the one hour, 17 minute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ct0H_ndjavM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;train wreck&lt;/a&gt;. But there are other signs. He used the construction “very, very” 20 times. The word “thing” (and its variants) was uttered 102 times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Am I going to diagnose him with anything? Of course not. That's unethical!&lt;/b&gt; But I will say that since Mr. Trump has been a public figure for nearly 40 years, we can objectively analyze his spontaneous speech and quantify any changes over time. I must emphasize that there is no magical scale to use for classification or comparison purposes (at least not yet). We don't know what's normal age-related decline and what's pathological.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I suggest that the best corpus of spontaneous speech data is the collection of Trump interviews/conversations with David Letterman. I believe they're unscripted, and there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9-mWCMiytLi0RV53IHrGXA/search?query=donald+trump&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; of them on YouTube (I've linked to eight below). Letterman has aged too, so you might as well analyze his speech as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnotes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The authors performed... &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;...a 10-fold cross-validation procedure in which a unique 10% of the data (i.e., the ‘test set’) are used in each iteration for evaluation, and the remaining 90% (i.e., the ‘training set’) are used to select the most useful features (of the 370 available as described in “Features” above) and construct our models. The reported accuracy is an average across the 10 folds. In a given fold, data from any individual speaker can occur in the test set or the training set, but not both.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; A show-stopping limitation is that the two groups were not matched for age or education. The mean age was 71.8 for AD vs. 65.2 for controls, and years of education 12.5 vs. 14.1 yrs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://alzheimersnewstoday.com/2015/12/15/alzheimers-disease-markers-found-speech-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alzheimer’s Disease Markers Found in Speech Patterns&lt;/a&gt; (link via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aholdenj/status/824801091007115268&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@aholdenj&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;BTW, they're not supposed to diagnose non-patients, that's unethical.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Alzheimer%27s+Disease&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F25633673&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Tracking+discourse+complexity+preceding+Alzheimer%27s+disease+diagnosis%3A+a+case+study+comparing+the+press+conferences+of+Presidents+Ronald+Reagan+and+George+Herbert+Walker+Bush.&amp;amp;rft.issn=1387-2877&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=45&amp;amp;rft.issue=3&amp;amp;rft.spage=959&amp;amp;rft.epage=63&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Berisha+V&amp;amp;rft.au=Wang+S&amp;amp;rft.au=LaCross+A&amp;amp;rft.au=Liss+J&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CNeuroscience%2CCognitive+Psychology%2C+Language&quot;&gt;Berisha V, Wang S, LaCross A, &amp;amp; Liss J (2015). Tracking discourse complexity preceding Alzheimer's disease diagnosis: a case study comparing the press conferences of Presidents Ronald Reagan and George Herbert Walker Bush. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 45&lt;/span&gt; (3), 959-63 PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25633673&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;25633673&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Alzheimer%27s+Disease&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.3233%2FJAD-150520&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Linguistic+Features+Identify+Alzheimer%E2%80%99s+Disease+in+Narrative+Speech&amp;amp;rft.issn=13872877&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=49&amp;amp;rft.issue=2&amp;amp;rft.spage=407&amp;amp;rft.epage=422&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.medra.org%2Fservlet%2FaliasResolver%3Falias%3Diospress%26doi%3D10.3233%2FJAD-150520&amp;amp;rft.au=Fraser%2C+K.&amp;amp;rft.au=Meltzer%2C+J.&amp;amp;rft.au=Rudzicz%2C+F.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CNeuroscience%2CLanguage&quot;&gt;Fraser, K., Meltzer, J., &amp;amp; Rudzicz, F. (2015). Linguistic Features Identify Alzheimer’s Disease in Narrative Speech. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 49&lt;/span&gt; (2), 407-422 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3233/JAD-150520&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.3233/JAD-150520&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gs_citr&quot; id=&quot;gs_cit4&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Gauthier S, Reisberg B,  Zaudig M, Petersen RC, Ritchie K, Broich K, Belleville S, Brodaty H,  Bennett D, Chertkow H, Cummings JL. (2006). Mild cognitive impairment. &lt;i&gt;The  Lancet&lt;/i&gt;  367:1262-70.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=IEEE+International+Conference&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3A%2F10.1109%2FICMA.2005.1626789&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Automatic+detection+and+rating+of+dementia+of+Alzheimer+type+through+lexical+analysis+of+spontaneous+speech&amp;amp;rft.issn=&amp;amp;rft.date=2005&amp;amp;rft.volume=3&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=1569&amp;amp;rft.epage=1574&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fieeexplore.ieee.org%2Fdocument%2F1626789%2F&amp;amp;rft.au=Thomas%2C+C.%2C+Keselj%2C+V.%2C+Cercone%2C+N.%2C+Rockwood%2C+K.%2C+%26+Asp%2C+E.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Computer+Science+%2F+Engineering%2CLanguage&quot;&gt;Thomas, C., Keselj, V., Cercone, N., Rockwood, K., &amp;amp; Asp, E. (2005). Automatic detection and rating of dementia of Alzheimer type through lexical analysis of spontaneous speech. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;IEEE International Conference, 3&lt;/span&gt;, 1569-1574. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1626789/&quot;&gt;10.1109/ICMA.2005.1626789&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;ADDENDUM (May 23 2017):&lt;/b&gt; I updated some of the dead video links. Also, two new posts have appeared today: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2017/05/23/donald-trump-speaking-style-interviews/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trump wasn’t always so linguistically challenged. What could explain the change?&lt;/a&gt; (by Sharon Begley at STAT) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=32844&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump: Cognitive decline or TDS?&lt;/a&gt; (by Mark Liberman at Language Log).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Donald Trump on the David Letterman Show&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GmNN2MCJ-7U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;11-10-1988 Letterman Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cmG5bn-SN_A&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump Interview on Letterman Show (1997)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[corrected]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jH3svkMMfYk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump Interview on David Letterman Show (1998)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[corrected]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GKPC85KUSzk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman Show (2008-08-08)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[corrected]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PP8CO61hlgk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump talks business and banks on David Letterman Show (2009-02-18)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[dead link]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Z-pmh9ibo0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman Show (2010)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[corrected]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PR_SoJpWzOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman 17 October, 2013 Full Interview &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IPxmrXPycVg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman January 8th 2015 Full Interview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;[corrected]&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can find them all &lt;strike&gt;here&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYvDGDcbaSHkmPZf4fYxrZw/videos?sort=da&amp;amp;flow=grid&amp;amp;view=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;other Trump&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.org/details/trumparchive?&amp;amp;sort=date&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Trump Archive&lt;/a&gt; - over 900&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; televised speeches, interviews, debates, and other news broadcasts related to President Donald Trump. See post &lt;/span&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.archive.org/2017/01/05/internet-archives-trump-archive-launches-today/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYpsrstfx8o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump 1980 Interview (Brokaw)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ronald Reagan videos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dCl5FG9Kl7s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - 1/29/81&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ySHtDHrLJY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - 8/12/86 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n8gN-GxiRD8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iran/Contra Excerpt from 11/19/86&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n8gN-GxiRD8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - late Oct 1987&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/tYYDadX2k1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T03:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Reuters removes story on gender confirmation surgery because firm mistakenly released data</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/23/reuters-removes-story-gender-confirmation-surgery-firm-mistakenly-released-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50227</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T19:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Reuters has removed a story about gender confirmation surgery, saying it included problematic data. The public relations firm representing the American Society of Plastic Surgeons (ASPS) — which generated the data in the report  — took responsibility, saying it supplied Reuters with data the ASPS did not want released. Yesterday, Reuters pulled its version of a widely-reported story about […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/23/reuters-removes-story-gender-confirmation-surgery-firm-mistakenly-released-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Reuters removes story on gender confirmation surgery because firm mistakenly released data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Video blog: Microparticles may be breast cancer’s secret weapon to evade the immune system</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/23/video-blog-microparticles-may-breast-cancers-secret-weapon-evade-immune-system/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9017</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T16:06:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/23/video-blog-microparticles-may-breast-cancers-secret-weapon-evade-immune-system/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video blog: Microparticles may be breast cancer’s secret weapon to evade the immune system&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dafne Solera</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researchers mistakenly administer three-fold higher dose of anesthesia</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/23/researchers-mistakenly-administer-three-fold-higher-dose-anesthesia/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50073</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T13:30:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers have retracted a 2016 paper after discovering that they accidentally administered three times the reported dose of anesthesia to rats. In the Experimental Physiology paper, the authors set out to mathematically map how rats’ blood pressure changes under different conditions, which required the rats to be anesthetized. But their findings were called into question when […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/23/researchers-mistakenly-administer-three-fold-higher-dose-anesthesia/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researchers mistakenly administer three-fold higher dose of anesthesia&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">TRAPPIST-1’s seventh planet is a chilly world</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/trappist-1s-seventh-planet-chilly-world"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/trappist-1s-seventh-planet-chilly-world</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T13:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Follow-up observations of TRAPPIST-1 and its seven planets reveals details about the outermost one.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tool sharpens focus on Stone Age networking in the Middle East</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tool-sharpens-focus-stone-age-networking-middle-east"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tool-sharpens-focus-stone-age-networking-middle-east</id>
		<updated>2017-05-23T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Stone Age tool’s route to Syrian site covered at least 700 kilometers.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mouse sperm survive space to spawn</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mouse-sperm-survive-space-spawn"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mouse-sperm-survive-space-spawn</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T19:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sperm freeze-dried and sent into space for months of exposure to high levels of solar radiation later produced healthy baby mice.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Older adults may not benefit from taking statins</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/older-adults-may-not-benefit-taking-statins"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/older-adults-may-not-benefit-taking-statins</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T18:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Statins did not reduce heart attacks, coronary heart disease deaths or deaths from any cause in people age 65 and older, a new analysis finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">European fossils may belong to earliest known hominid</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/european-fossils-may-belong-earliest-known-hominid"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/european-fossils-may-belong-earliest-known-hominid</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T18:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 With new analyses of Graecopithecus fossils from Greece and Bulgaria, researchers argue for possible hominid origins in Europe, not Africa.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Ex-PhD candidate sues advisor, school: Colorado prof “poisoned the well” after research dispute</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/22/ex-phd-candidate-sues-advisor-school-colorado-prof-poisoned-well-research-dispute/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50182</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T15:35:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A former University of Colorado Boulder graduate student is suing his ex-advisor for defamation after being shooed out midway through his doctoral program. Robert Roscow says he had to leave CU Boulder’s department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology (EBIO) in the fall of 2016 with only a master’s degree after fish evolution researcher David Stock dropped […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/22/ex-phd-candidate-sues-advisor-school-colorado-prof-poisoned-well-research-dispute/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ex-PhD candidate sues advisor, school: Colorado prof “poisoned the well” after research dispute&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Sounding out the properties of DNA</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/22/sounding-out-the-properties-of-dna/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9009</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T15:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/DNA-music-notes-edited-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genomics researchers are all too used to seeing DNA sequences represented as long lists of A, T, C and Gs but could there be a better way to analyze this data? The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12859-017-1632-x&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; article by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.westernsydney.edu.au/staff_profiles/uws_profiles/doctor_mark_temple&quot;&gt;Dr Mark Temple&lt;/a&gt; of Western Sydney University suggests that representing DNA as musical notes could aid us in identifying stop and start codons and even help us to spot mutations that otherwise could prove much more difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound has been used in the past to help aid analysis; even as far back as 1948, Alan Turing’s computer used different sounds to help indicate the progress of software to the user. As the amount of available genomic data increases, researchers are increasingly seeking new ways to analyze and seek out unique features. Using sound to identify these features – in the same way that Turing’s machine used sound to identify progress – could provide a novel way of processing these large data sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9012&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DNA representation (Andy Leppard, Flickr CC)&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9012&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/DNA-representation-Andy-Leppard-Flickr-300x203.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;DNA representation (Andy Leppard, Flickr CC)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Temple developed six separate sonification algorithms that could each parse a DNA sequence and convert it into a musical score. Some of the algorithms worked by treating each nucleotide as an individual note, while others used di- or tri-nucleotide groups, the protein sequence itself, or the codon reading frames. The resulting musical notation can then be played in the same way as any conventional music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://static-content.springer.com/esm/art%3A10.1186%2Fs12859-017-1632-x/MediaObjects/12859_2017_1632_MOESM8_ESM.mp3&quot;&gt;Listen – track eight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://static-content.springer.com/esm/art%3A10.1186%2Fs12859-017-1632-x/MediaObjects/12859_2017_1632_MOESM12_ESM.mp3&quot;&gt;Listen – track twelve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach is particularly useful as it can highlight start and stop codons by using them to turn the music on or off, making those points in the DNA sequence abundantly clear. And this could be just the beginning of sound-based DNA analysis. As further research is carried out in this area, software could be developed that uses different sounds to represent features like binding sites, restriction endonucleases sites and SNPs. Today’s DNA sequence browsers may use conventional analysis tools but perhaps we will soon see sonification algorithms like these included as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while we may not see a DNA-based song topping iTunes, DNA sonification may open new avenues in DNA sequence analysis for researchers around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/22/sounding-out-the-properties-of-dna/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sounding out the properties of DNA&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Danielle Talbot</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">40 more ‘intelligence’ genes found</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/40-more-intelligence-genes-found"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/40-more-intelligence-genes-found</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A study of nearly 80,000 people turns up 40 genes that may have a role in making brains smarter.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">When misconduct occurs, how should journals and institutions work together?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/22/misconduct-occurs-journals-institutions-work-together/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50212</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T13:30:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When the World Conference on Research Integrity kicks off at the end of this month, one topic that will be on attendees’ minds is how journals and research institutions should collaborate when investigating the integrity of individual publications. That’s because this week, a group of stakeholders from institutions and the publishing world released draft guidelines […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/22/misconduct-occurs-journals-institutions-work-together/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When misconduct occurs, how should journals and institutions work together?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">New insights into an underlying influence for mitochondrial shaping</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/22/new-insights-underlying-influence-mitochondrial-shaping/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9003</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T12:43:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Drosophila-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As one of the wonders of the molecular world, the enzyme ATP synthase is responsible for the energy storage in most life forms. In the past, its own mechanisms surprised scientists when it was discovered that it functions like a machine; working in a ‘dual motor’ system and producing adenosine triphosphate (ATP) as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATP is used within cells as a coenzyme, and is said to be ‘the energy currency of life’. It plays a key role in the conversion of mitochondrial energy in mammals. As a chemical energy storing nucleotide, it releases its energy once broken down into Adenosine Diphosphate (ADP). This organic compound (ADP) influences the flow of energy across cells, and plays a key role in metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmccellbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12860-017-0132-1&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; recently published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmccellbiol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/a&gt;, led by Eric Sawyer, Elizabeth Brunner, and Karen Hales at Davidson College (NC, USA), new insights are presented for the role of ATP synthase in the fruit fly &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In scientific research, this genus has established itself as a reliable model to observe such processes. While analysing the testis of this species, it was found that the various subunits of ATP synthase contribute to the shaping of the Nebenkern – a mitochondrial formation within insect sperm. This structure resembles an onion-like form, due to mitochondria interlocking together after cell division has occurred. This spherical form has a complicated morphology made up of two masses that densely pack together as a result of mitochondrial fusion. Following this process, the two components of this structure re-organise, when they are unravelled and elongated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-9005 alignright&quot; height=&quot;207&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/microscope-300x198.jpg&quot; width=&quot;314&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The molecular mechanisms underlying these curious mitochondrial processes has been an area of growing research, as previously studied in a range of systems from yeast to neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this newly presented study, researchers are observing the process of spermatozoa production following cell division (spermatogenesis) in the &lt;em&gt;Drosophila&lt;/em&gt; species. This can act as a useful analogue, potentially helping us understand the molecular processes in other related systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to understanding its role across biological systems, comprehending the processes of ATP synthase is of direct importance to humans, as any defects in its processes can contribute to the development of neuromuscular disorders and various diseases (as the authors indicate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmccellbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12860-017-0132-1&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmccellbiol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Cell Biology&lt;/a&gt; presents the first piece of evidence which links tissue-specific ATP synthase subunits with tissue-specific mitochondrial shaping processes. These findings demonstrate the impact of cell processes on tissue morphogenesis, and contribute to the on-going research of ATP synthase’s influence on membrane conformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/22/new-insights-underlying-influence-mitochondrial-shaping/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;New insights into an underlying influence for mitochondrial shaping&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Clarissa Wright</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure of a pre-catalytic spliceosome</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/8EGeezc4ktw/nature22799"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22799</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Intron removal requires assembly of the spliceosome on pre-mRNA and extensive remodelling to form the spliceosome’s catalytic centre. Here we report the cryo-electron microscopy structure of the yeast pre-catalytic B complex spliceosome at near-atomic resolution. The mobile U2 snRNP associates with U4/U6.U5 tri-snRNP through U2/U6 helix II and an interface between U4/U6 di-snRNP and the U2 snRNP SF3b-containing domain, which also transiently contacts the helicase Brr2. The U2 snRNP 3’ region is flexibly attached to the SF3b-containing domain and protrudes over the concave surface of tri-snRNP, where the U1 snRNP may reside before its release from the pre-mRNA 5’-splice site. The U6 ACAGAGA sequence forms a hairpin which weakly tethers the 5’-splice site. B complex proteins Prp38, Snu23, and Spp381 bind the Prp8 N-terminal domain and stabilise U6 ACAGAGA stem–pre-mRNA and Brr2–U4 snRNA interactions. These results provide important insights into the events leading to active site formation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22799&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22799&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/8EGeezc4ktw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Clemens Plaschka</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The sunflower genome provides insights into oil metabolism, flowering and Asterid evolution</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ATqfqqU5M_k/nature22380"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22380</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The domesticated sunflower, Helianthus annuus L., is a global oil crop that has promise for climate change adaptation, because it can maintain stable yields across a wide variety of environmental conditions, including drought. Even greater resilience is achievable through the mining of resistance alleles from compatible wild sunflower relatives, including numerous extremophile species. Here we report a high-quality reference for the sunflower genome (3.6 gigabases), together with extensive transcriptomic data from vegetative and floral organs. The genome mostly consists of highly similar, related sequences and required single-molecule real-time sequencing technologies for successful assembly. Genome analyses enabled the reconstruction of the evolutionary history of the Asterids, further establishing the existence of a whole-genome triplication at the base of the Asterids II clade and a sunflower-specific whole-genome duplication around 29 million years ago. An integrative approach combining quantitative genetics, expression and diversity data permitted development of comprehensive gene networks for two major breeding traits, flowering time and oil metabolism, and revealed new candidate genes in these networks. We found that the genomic architecture of flowering time has been shaped by the most recent whole-genome duplication, which suggests that ancient paralogues can remain in the same regulatory networks for dozens of millions of years. This genome represents a cornerstone for future research programs aiming to exploit genetic diversity to improve biotic and abiotic stress resistance and oil production, while also considering agricultural constraints and human nutritional needs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22380&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22380&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ATqfqqU5M_k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Hélène Badouin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A neural circuit architecture for angular integration in Drosophila</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/vUCU6hvkT34/nature22343"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22343</id>
		<updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Many animals keep track of their angular heading over time while navigating through their environment. However, a neural-circuit architecture for computing heading has not been experimentally defined in any species. Here we describe a set of clockwise- and anticlockwise-shifting neurons in the Drosophila central complex whose wiring and physiology provide a means to rotate an angular heading estimate based on the fly’s angular velocity. We show that each class of shifting neurons exists in two subtypes, with spatiotemporal activity profiles that suggest different roles for each subtype at the start and end of tethered-walking turns. Shifting neurons are required for the heading system to properly track the fly’s heading in the dark, and stimulation of these neurons induces predictable shifts in the heading signal. The central features of this biological circuit are analogous to those of computational models proposed for head-direction cells in rodents and may shed light on how neural systems, in general, perform integration. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22343&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22343&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/vUCU6hvkT34&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jonathan Green</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">A Survey of Our Secret Lives</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8808"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8808</id>
		<updated>2017-05-21T11:55:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 What kinds of secrets does the average person keep? In a new paper, Columbia University researchers Michael L. Slepian and colleagues carried out a survey of secrets.



Slepian et al. developed a 'Common Secrets Questionnaire' (CSQ) and gave it to 600 participants recruited anonymously online. Participants were asked whether they'd ever had various secrets, at any point in their lives. The results are a monument to all our sins:

It turns out that extra-relational thoughts - meaning &quot;thou</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-05-24T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Position: Lecturer/Senior Lecturer in Computer Science (Machine Learning/Biocomputation)</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/05/20/open-position-lecturer-senior-lecturer-in-computer-science-machine-learning-biocomputation-1.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-05-20:/2017/05/20/open-position-lecturer-senior-lecturer-in-computer-science-machine-learning-biocomputation-1.html</id>
		<updated>2017-05-20T13:30:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Salary £32,004 to £48,327 per annum depending on qualifications and experience &lt;br /&gt;
Full time position working 37 hours per week (1.0 FTE) &lt;br /&gt;
Closing date 18 June 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a Lecturer or Senior Lecturer in the School of Computer Science, University of Hertfordshire. The successful candidate will be expected to contribute to the School's teaching and curriculum development activities, and to strengthen its research activities. We are looking to recruit specifically a computer scientist with background in machine learning or data science related to biocomputation (including computational neuroscience). By Data Science, we broadly mean the extraction of meaning from large quantities of data. The successful candidate will also have the flexibility to teach across mainstream topics in computer science. The School has an international reputation for teaching and research, with 58 academic staff, 20 adjunct lecturer staff, and 65 research students and postdoctoral research staff. With a history going back to 1958, the School teaches one of the largest cohorts of undergraduate students in the UK, and also delivers a thriving online computer science degree programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person appointed will be expected to contribute to learning and teaching relevant to core computer science topics, participate in curriculum review and development, design and develop new modules, and supervise student projects at all levels. The appointee will strengthen the research culture in the School by pursuing research as part of a larger research team, seeking external funding, publishing papers, supervising research students, and participating in commercial activity as appropriate. Preference will be given to candidates who can contribute to teaching and research in databases as outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applicants must hold a PhD (or equivalent) in a relevant subject, possess excellent communication skills in English and the ability to teach at undergraduate and postgraduate level. It is desirable that candidates have a track record of publication, external research funding, collaboration across disciplines, experience of different types of assessment and higher education quality assurance. They should also have the ability to play a role in the routine running of the School of Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications should be made through &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&lt;/a&gt; (reference 014050). Informal enquiries may be addressed to Dr Volker Steuber (Head of the Biocomputation Research Group, v.steuber AT herts.ac.uk) or Professor William Clocksin (Dean of School, w.clocksin AT herts.ac.uk). Please note that applications sent directly to these email addresses will not be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are committed to providing a supportive environment. The University offers a range of benefits including a pension scheme, professional development, family friendly policies, child care vouchers, a fee waiver of 50% for all children of staff under the age of 21 at the start of the course, discounted memberships at the Hertfordshire Sports Village and generous annual leave.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Volker Steuber</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T09:26:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: A hoax involving a “conceptual penis;” fake reagents;  plagiarism irony</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/20/weekend-reads-hoax-involving-conceptual-penis-fake-reagents-plagiarism-irony/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50206</id>
		<updated>2017-05-20T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a survey of researchers in China with an alarming result, and asked whether philosophy has a plagiarism problem. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: There’s a new paper hoax in town, this one involving the “conceptual penis as a social construct.” The authors, Peter Boghossian and James Lindsay, explain. (Skeptic) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/20/weekend-reads-hoax-involving-conceptual-penis-fake-reagents-plagiarism-irony/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A hoax involving a “conceptual penis;” fake reagents;  plagiarism irony&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T05:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Does the philosophy literature have a plagiarism problem?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/19/philosophy-literature-plagiarism-problem/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50133</id>
		<updated>2017-05-19T15:30:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Philosopher Michael Dougherty doesn’t take plagiarism sitting down. Over the years, the researcher at Ohio Dominican University has tipped us off to numerous instances of plagiarism he’s spotted. And it turns out, he’s done the same thing for publishers, as well. In a new paper in Metaphilosophy, Dougherty describes his experience contacting publishers over an […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/19/philosophy-literature-plagiarism-problem/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Does the philosophy literature have a plagiarism problem?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-24T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Denmark to institute sweeping changes in handling misconduct</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/19/denmark-institute-sweeping-changes-handling-misconduct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50055</id>
		<updated>2017-05-19T13:30:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;In six weeks, new policies for handling misconduct in Denmark will go into effect, which alter the definition of misconduct and establish clear policies for who handles such allegations. Starting July 1, research misconduct will be limited to how it’s typically defined elsewhere — fabrication, falsification, and plagiarism (the previous definition included serious breaches of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/19/denmark-institute-sweeping-changes-handling-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Denmark to institute sweeping changes in handling misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-24T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Even short-term opioid use can set people up for addiction risks</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/minor-injury-opioid-painkiller-addiction-risks"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/minor-injury-opioid-painkiller-addiction-risks</id>
		<updated>2017-05-19T13:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A study of opioid prescriptions for sprained ankles finds that patients prescribed 30 or more pills are more likely to seek refills.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Beil</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum tractor beam could tug atoms, molecules</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tractor-beam-could-tug-atoms-molecules"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tractor-beam-could-tug-atoms-molecules</id>
		<updated>2017-05-19T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The wavelike behavior of quantum particles could be harnessed to move atoms.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Music teachers and students fall for music-related neuromyths – German study</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/19/music-teachers-and-students-fall-for-music-related-neuromyths-german-study/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=23808</id>
		<updated>2017-05-19T08:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The left and right hemispheres of the brain.&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24033&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24033&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The left and right hemispheres of the brain. Hand drawn vector illustration.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mushroomstore&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The left and right hemispheres of the brain.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The left and right hemispheres of the brain.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-493909878.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-493909878.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-493909878.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/19/music-teachers-and-students-fall-for-music-related-neuromyths-german-study/the-left-and-right-hemispheres-of-the-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-493909878.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day neuroscience might revolutionise education, but for now the scientific findings most relevant to teaching and learning come from psychology. In fact, many popular claims about the brain and learning are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Great_Myths_of_the_Brain.html&quot;&gt;neuromyths&lt;/a&gt; – unsubstantiated or plain wrong ideas, such as that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-10-brain-myth-explained-in-60-seconds/&quot;&gt;we only use ten per cent of our brains&lt;/a&gt;, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-myths/201206/why-the-left-brain-right-brain-myth-will-probably-never-die&quot;&gt;some of us are left-brained, others right-brained&lt;/a&gt;, or that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2015/01/need-know-learning-styles-myth-two-minutes/&quot;&gt;we learn best when taught via our preferred “learning style”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately and often with the best of intentions, surveys have shown that a lot of teachers believe these myths (for instance, one &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00429/full&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; published in 2012 found that British and Dutch teachers believed around half of the 15 neuromyths they were tested on). Now &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00629/full&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; has focused on German music teachers and students to see how vulnerable they are to brain myths pertaining specifically to music. Although the participants showed some ability to distinguish between true facts and myths, they still endorsed around 40 per cent of the myths, especially those that contained neuroscientific jargon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-23808&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina Düvel and her colleagues at the Hanover Music Lab asked four experts in the fields of the neuroscience of music or the neuroscience of music education to agree on seven music-related brain facts, and seven music-related brain myths. Among the facts: the idea that music education can benefit language skills and that the anatomy of the brain can change in response to musical training. Among the myths: that right handers process music in the right hemisphere and that musical education boosts children’s intelligence. See box below for the full list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_23878&quot; style=&quot;width: 1019px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-05-10 at 15.01.07&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-23878&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;23878&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-05-10 at 15.01.07&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-10-at-15-01-07.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-10-at-15-01-07.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-10-at-15-01-07.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1019,554&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/19/music-teachers-and-students-fall-for-music-related-neuromyths-german-study/screen-shot-2017-05-10-at-15-01-07/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/screen-shot-2017-05-10-at-15-01-07.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;from Düvel et al, 2017 / &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers challenged 91 music teachers from a random selection of state schools in Germany and 125 students studying to be music teachers at German universities to read through a list of the 14 myths and facts presented in random order and identify which were scientifically substantiated and which unsubstantiated. To avoid raising undue suspicion, there was no mention of “neuromyths” in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although statistically speaking the participants were able to distinguish facts from myths better than if they’d simply been guessing, it remained the case that the teachers and students endorsed, on average, around 40 per cent of the myths, mistakenly believing them to be scientifically supported facts. The myths that contained neuroscientific jargon  (referencing “brain hemispheres” and “cognitive abilities”) were the most widely believed. On the plus side, the more books, magazines and websites that participants said they had read in relation to psychology and neuroscience, the less vulnerable they were to the myths (this is in contrast to the 2012 survey of school teachers where greater general knowledge about the brain correlated with more belief in neuromyths).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Düvel and her team said “the present study shows that there is a gap between the state of research in neuroscience related to music education and the knowledge of current and future music teachers about these findings and neuromyths”. This is worrying, they added, in the sense that time could be wasted on harmful, ineffective practices. The researchers concluded that perhaps “a lack of communication between scientists and music educators is to blame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00629/full&quot;&gt;Neuromyths in Music Education: Prevalence and Predictors of Misconceptions among Teachers and Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/23808/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/23808/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=23808&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Global access to quality health care has improved in the last two decades</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-access-quality-health-care-has-improved-last-two-decades"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-access-quality-health-care-has-improved-last-two-decades</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T22:53:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Health care quality and availability improved worldwide from 1990 to 2015, but the gap between countries with the lowest and highest levels of care widened.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_42190266851478=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hybrid protein offers malaria protection</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hybrid-protein-offers-malaria-protection"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hybrid-protein-offers-malaria-protection</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T18:19:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Rare hybrid protein that spans red blood cell membranes offers some protection against malaria.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rachel Ehrenberg</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3668</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Transplanted stem cells become eggs in sterile mice</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/transplanted-stem-cells-become-eggs-sterile-mice"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/transplanted-stem-cells-become-eggs-sterile-mice</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sterile mice that received transplanted egg-making stem cells were able to have healthy babies.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T05:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Positive psychology, expressive writing and the confidence cult – BPS 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/18/positive-psychology-expressive-writing-and-the-confidence-cult-bps-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8991</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T15:53:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/3420495837_07e4bd933f_z-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference boasted an impressive line-up of keynote speakers. The ‘father of’ positive psychology &lt;a href=&quot;https://ppc.sas.upenn.edu/people/martin-ep-seligman&quot;&gt;Martin Seligman&lt;/a&gt; (University of Pennsylvanna, USA) provided a fascinating summary of the ever growing field and discussed his updated theory of well-being, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.authentichappiness.sas.upenn.edu/learn&quot;&gt;PERMA&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;ositive emotion, &lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;ngagement, &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;elationships, &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;eaning and purpose, &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;ccomplishment). Helen Bevan (&lt;em&gt;Chief Transformation Officer, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theedge.nhsiq.nhs.uk/about/horizons-team/&quot;&gt;Horizons team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, NHS England) discussed her experience of ‘Leading change into the future’ – of particular interest was her experience of using social media and disease specific patient forums as platforms to aid healthcare transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8999&quot; style=&quot;width: 279px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rosalind Gill&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-8999&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/C_jMETlXYAEqlKPcropped-269x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;269&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Rosalind Gill&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.city.ac.uk/people/academics/rosalind-gill&quot;&gt;Rosaline Gill&lt;/a&gt; (City University London, UK) provided a stimulating critique of what she has termed the ‘confidence cult’ – the mindset that “whatever the problem, confidence is the solution”; she highlighted some of the key ways in which social questions of inequality are inappropriately portrayed as individual psychological issues, using pertinent examples from mainstream advertising to her illustrate the problem in relation to gender inequality. Last but not least, &lt;a href=&quot;http://liberalarts.utexas.edu/psychology/faculty/pennebak&quot;&gt;James W Pennebaker&lt;/a&gt; (University of Texas at Austin, USA) began the last keynote of the 2017 conference by discussing his early work exploring the links between emotion, language and health; which culminated in his finding that expressive writing interventions can improve both physical and mental health. He went on to focus on his current research studying how the use of everyday language reflects personality, with a particularly fascinating analysis of the linguistics of US presidential debates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8998&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;James W Pennebaker&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-8998&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/IMG_6547-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;James W Pennebaker&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Replication crisis averted? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerns that scientific results are often not reproducible is by no means limited to the field of psychology. However, when the scale of the problem in psychology was &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/349/6251/aac4716&quot;&gt;revealed by the Open Science Collaboration in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, rather than despair the psychology community has used its replication crisis as an opportunity to focus on improving research practices. In the vein of the ‘Replication and Reproducibility in Psychology event’ held in 2016 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2016/06/22/replication-reproducibility-psychology-debate-continues/&quot;&gt;summarized in this blog&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://medhealth.leeds.ac.uk/profile/1300/1026/daryl_o'connor&quot;&gt;Daryl O’Connor&lt;/a&gt; (Leeds University, UK) hosted a workshop designed to improve scientific practice, research methods and transparency. Using a series of elegant &lt;a href=&quot;https://lawsofthought.github.io/replication-crisis-demos/&quot;&gt;statistical demonstrations&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntu.ac.uk/staff-profiles/social-sciences/mark-andrews&quot;&gt;Mark Andrews&lt;/a&gt; (Nottingham Trent University, UK) highlighted the flaws in the current statistical system and the importance of conducting replicable, well powered, and statistically strong research. The discussion centered on possible solutions for improving reproducibility, including pre-registering studies and providing improved statistical inference training to undergraduates and early career researchers. We hope that &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/em&gt; can be part of the solution! &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/em&gt; has a policy of publishing all sound science, thus aiming to reduce the impact of publication bias that may currently exist within the field of psychology; we do not make editorial decisions on the basis of the interest of a study or its likely impact, and encourage submissions of replication studies and null results. We operate an open peer review model in order to increase transparency. In addition, we are now trialing &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/about/results-free-peer-review-for-authors&quot;&gt;Results-free review&lt;/a&gt;, a new model of peer review, where editors and reviewers are blinded to the results, focusing editorial decisions on the rationale and methods alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wellbeing and social inequalities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is well established that certain populations experience prejudice, discrimination and stigma, and have disparities in both physical and mental health. The psychological aspects of social inequalities in various ‘minority’ populations were a major focus of the conference. This included the ‘Sexuality and wellbeing’ session which kicked off the first day of the conference. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uea.ac.uk/medicine/people/profile/j-semlyen&quot;&gt;Joanna Semlyen&lt;/a&gt; discussed the importance of using population representative data to investigate inequalities in mental health, including her study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-016-0767-z&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry,&lt;/em&gt; which demonstrates that lesbian, gay and bisexual (LGB) populations are twice as likely to suffer from common mental disorders and/or low wellbeing, than heterosexual adults. Joanna discusses her work in more details in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2016/04/06/sexual-orientation-mental-health/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;. In the same symposium &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.york.ac.uk/sociology/our-staff/academic/celia-kitzinger/&quot;&gt;Celia Kitzinger&lt;/a&gt; highlighted the fact that despite the UK being ranked best in the world for end of life care, LGBT individuals face significant discrimination during this already difficult time. Another interesting discussion was found in the ‘Wellbeing in Dementia’ session; Linda Clare discussed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idealproject.org.uk/&quot;&gt;IDEAL project&lt;/a&gt;, which focuses on improving the quality of life of those living with dementia and Peter Mittler talked about his work to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dementiaallianceinternational.org/?s=peter+mittler&quot;&gt;improve the human rights of those living with dementia&lt;/a&gt;, following his own diagnosis of Alzheimer’s disease 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;brighton-pier-rgb&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-8992 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;197&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/brighton-pier-rgb-300x197.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social media psychology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is embedded in today’s society, with many people using some form of social media on a daily basis. Another big focus of the conference was the psychology of social media. &lt;a href=&quot;http://martingraff.com/&quot;&gt;Martin Graff&lt;/a&gt; presented his recent study examining how receiving ‘likes’ and other kinds of online validation influence the way people interact on social media; he demonstrated that personality and self-esteem are key factors in the individuals responses to online validation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/megan-davis-94aa5069/?ppe=1&quot;&gt;Megan Davis&lt;/a&gt; then demonstrated how the content of online messages can predict adverse dating experiences, suggesting that this can be used by online daters to take appropriate precautions when deciding to meet online communication partners face to face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/18/positive-psychology-expressive-writing-and-the-confidence-cult-bps-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Positive psychology, expressive writing and the confidence cult – BPS 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anna Clark</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal flags two more papers by diabetes researcher who sued to stop retractions (and now has 12)</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/18/journal-flags-two-papers-diabetes-researcher-sued-stop-retractions-now-12/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50145</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T15:30:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A diabetes journal has issued two notices of concern for papers co-authored by a researcher who took another publisher to court after it did the same thing — but ultimately lost. The notices are for two papers co-authored by Mario Saad — who, after losing his legal battle with the American Diabetes Association, has since […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/18/journal-flags-two-papers-diabetes-researcher-sued-stop-retractions-now-12/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal flags two more papers by diabetes researcher who sued to stop retractions (and now has 12)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-24T17:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Introduction to signal processing using FFT</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/05/18/introduction-to-signal-processing-using-fft.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-05-18:/2017/05/18/introduction-to-signal-processing-using-fft.html</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T14:41:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A Fourier Transform takes a signal (usually acoustic or any sequence of data) and finds the frequencies that are dominant in the signal.  For example: A pure middle 'C' note from piano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;loweralpha simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source separation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying emotions in voices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it's important for me as I am researching in emotion detection from speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FFT (Fast Fourier Transform) is a very efficient algorithm for computing the power spectrum (Fourier transform). The normal Fourier Transform is a O(N^2), whereas FFT is O( N log(N)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in this workshop I will show how FFT can be performed in real-time and I will show how human voices produce different power spectrum.  I will also let the audience see what their own vocal profile looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 19/05/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anuradha Sulane</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T09:26:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Four in 10 biomedical papers out of China are tainted by misconduct, says new survey</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/18/four-10-biomedical-papers-tainted-misconduct-chinese-scientists-say/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50142</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T13:30:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Chinese biomedical researchers estimate that 40% of research in their country has been affected in some way by misconduct, according to a new survey. The authors are quick to caution against putting too much stock in this figure due to the subjective nature of the survey, published in Science and Engineering Ethics. The estimates also […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/18/four-10-biomedical-papers-tainted-misconduct-chinese-scientists-say/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Four in 10 biomedical papers out of China are tainted by misconduct, says new survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Zastrow</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-23T23:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS Appoints Alison Mudditt Chief Executive Officer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/a2T1Oly6RUA/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7570</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T11:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2015/10/8-690x3201-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-7574&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/05/Alison-Mudditt_headshot-214x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;214&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS is pleased to announce the appointment of Alison Mudditt as its Chief Executive Officer, effective June 19, 2017.  For the past six years Mudditt served as Director of University of California Press (UC Press) where she ushered in new strategies to lead the company into the digital age, including the innovative journal and monograph Open Access programs Collabra and Luminos. Prior to UC Press, Mudditt was Executive Vice President at SAGE Publications, Inc., leading publishing programs across books, journals and digital platforms. Her 25 plus years in the publishing industry include leadership positions at Blackwell Publishers in Oxford, UK and Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Inc., in Philadelphia, US. Mudditt received her Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of Bath and her Master of Business Administration from The Open University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“PLOS is truly privileged to bring on board a person of Alison’s caliber whose extensive experience in and deep knowledge of academic publishing will invigorate a renewed focus on our mission—transforming research communication to better serve authors, readers and the public,” said Gary Ward, Chairman of the Board at PLOS. “Her history and accomplishments as a leader, coalition builder and strategic thinker for organizations experiencing change is impressive and will prove very valuable to PLOS in the years ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am delighted to join a like-minded publisher in PLOS, which fully embraces the Open Access principles that drive its mission,” said Mudditt. “PLOS’ long-held reputation as a change agent in this industry provides a tremendously gratifying challenge as we continue to push the boundaries of what is possible in scientific publishing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/a2T1Oly6RUA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-05-23T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, an Earth-based telescope spotted Saturn’s fourth ring</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-earth-based-telescope-spotted-saturns-fourth-ring"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-earth-based-telescope-spotted-saturns-fourth-ring</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists now rely on spacecraft to chart the intricate rings of the gas giant.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T05:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Do women really show their emotions more than men?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/18/do-women-really-show-their-emotions-more-than-men/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=23968</id>
		<updated>2017-05-18T08:00:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The collage of young man and woman face expressions&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-23978&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;23978&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The collage of surprised young men and women&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;master1305&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The collage of young man and woman face expressions&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The collage of young man and woman face expressions&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-511109622.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-511109622.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-511109622.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3900,1488&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/18/do-women-really-show-their-emotions-more-than-men/the-collage-of-young-man-and-woman-face-expressions/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-511109622.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a stereotype that has improved a little over the years but still persists: women are more emotionally expressive than men. Like Bridget Jones, we constantly reveal exactly how we’re feeling, while men, Mark Darcy-like, look on impassively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although prior evidence suggests that women &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/?&amp;amp;fa=main.doiLanding&amp;amp;doi=10.1037/0033-2909.129.2.305&quot;&gt;really do smile more often&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0173942&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt;, published in &lt;i&gt;PLOS One&lt;/i&gt;, has considered a greater variety of facial expressions, and it finds that the gender pattern is more complex, with some emotions displayed more by men than women. Arguably, this work helps to reveal not only differences in the emotional signals men and women send to others, but also differences in the emotions that we feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-23968&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel McDuff of Microsoft Research, Redmond, US and his team used a new automated facial coding technology to analyse the expressions of 2,106 people as they watched a series of 10 video adverts at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants were crowdsourced from France, Germany, China, the US and the UK. While they watched ads from their own countries on everything from confectionary to cars, their webcams streamed images of their faces to a remote server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women smiled more than the men, replicating the earlier research. They also engaged in more “inner brow raises”, an expression taken to indicate fear or sadness. But the men frowned more. Frowns are usually taken to be a show of anger, though the researchers noted that in this study, they might have reflected greater concentration, or confusion. There were no gender differences in some other expressions, including downturned mouths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an ongoing debate in psychology about the extent to which facial expressions, including smiles and frowns, actually reflect and match felt emotions. When you smile, is it always because you’re feeling happy? Or do you sometimes smile when you’re anxious? And just because you’re frowning, does it necessarily mean you’re mad – or you just want someone else to think you are?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But given work &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/?&amp;amp;fa=main.doiLanding&amp;amp;doi=10.1037/1528-3542.5.2.175&quot;&gt;suggesting there is a close association&lt;/a&gt; between emotions and facial expressions, an implication of the new results is that women are more prone to feeling happy and also more anxious (or at least more inclined to show these emotions), and that men are more likely to feel angry (or more confused…), which raises the question of why might this be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McDuff and his team suggested that at least part of the explanation could be down to the different social expectations and pressures placed on the genders. For example, there’s evidence that in many countries, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0022022104268387&quot;&gt;happiness is seen as more desirable for girls than boys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such an account would help explain why the size of the observed gender differences varied around the world, being the smallest in the UK, consistent with the idea that gender-related social expectations are less marked in some countries than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few other geographical differences: women in the US were the smiliest, while women in the UK and Germany frowned least. But the general data patterns in each of the five countries were the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One limitation with the study was the fact that volunteers knew they were being videoed, which might have influenced their reactions. But a major advantage was the use of rapid automated coding technology. This allowed for many more participants than would normally be practical in research on facial expressions, which are usually decoded by a researcher. Crowdsourcing volunteers and using computer-based decoding, as in this case, could open the way for many more mass-studies of emotion and behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0173942&quot;&gt;A large-scale analysis of sex differences in facial expressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/23968/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/23968/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=23968&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-05-26T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When it’s hot, plants become a surprisingly large source of air pollution</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-its-hot-plants-become-surprisingly-large-source-air-pollution"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-its-hot-plants-become-surprisingly-large-source-air-pollution</id>
		<updated>2017-05-17T21:33:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 During a heat wave, trees and shrubs can sharply raise ozone levels, a new study shows.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-05-25T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
