<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:53+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These spiders may have the world’s fastest body clocks</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T21:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Three orb-weaving spiders may have the shortest circadian clocks yet discovered among animals.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Simulating the universe using Einstein’s theory of gravity may solve cosmic puzzles</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T20:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Better simulating the dense parts of the universe could improve scientists’ view of how the universe evolves.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New camera on Palomar telescope will seek out supernovas, asteroids and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Zwicky Transient Facility at Palomar Observatory in California will seek supernovas, black holes and asteroids.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Puzzle of Multiple Personality Disorder</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/14/the-puzzle-of-multiple-personality-disorder/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23056</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T16:30:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/08/28/behind-the-masks-the-mysteries-of-dissociative-identity-disorder/&quot;&gt;Dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a&gt; (DID, commonly referred to as multiple personality disorder) is well known to the general public through multiple movies and books. However, the disease remains poorly understood and rather mysterious for the medical specialists. The definition of this disorder implies that a patient has at least two distinctive and relatively long-lasting identities (sometimes called “alters”) that manifest themselves in a person’s behavior. Their presence is accompanied by memory impairments that cannot be explained by usual forgetfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are no clear clinical criteria to help in the diagnostics. There is a whole range of dissociative disorders that range from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/22/improve-cognition-with-a-trip-down-memory-lane/&quot;&gt;daydreaming&lt;/a&gt; and lapses in attention to serious pathologies. The diagnostics rely on descriptive data rather than something measurable. This leads to lots of confusion, controversies, and inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the incidence of multiple personality disorder varied wildly. For a long time, the condition was considered among the rarest psychological disorders, with less than 100 cases described before 1944. The incidence of DID rose sharply in the 1970s–1980s, reaching 20,000 by the end of the century. In addition, this growth was accompanied by the increase in the number of alters reported in patients, from just one to 13–16 by the 1980s. These changes in the statistics might have been caused by increasing recognition of the disease symptoms among practitioners, but also led to the growing skepticism in the research community about the very existence of this distinct condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variability on the geographic distribution of this condition is substantial too: the disorder is diagnosed in the US much more frequently than anywhere else. The overwhelming majority of publications on this condition originate from North America, making some researchers believe that DID is a purely American disease confined to this continent. This further adds to the skepticism of many health practitioners: there are no reasons to believe that qualified specialists capable of recognizing this condition are vastly underrepresented in other developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is little clarity regarding what causes the disorder. The iatrogenic hypothesis suggests that DID can be a result of psychotherapeutic treatment, while the traumatogenic hypothesis states that the disease develops as a result of severe &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/09/15/coping-with-trauma-in-netflixs-unbreakable-kimmy-schmidt/&quot;&gt;trauma&lt;/a&gt;, usually in childhood. Some researchers believe that most cases of DID are pseudogenic, i.e., simulated. There is an opinion that many patients want to believe that they have the disorder, to explain the inconsistencies in their own behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence of DID is 5–9 times higher in females compared to males. Again, there is no agreement among specialists regarding what causes such a big gender difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential reasons for the sharp increase in the incidence of DID were examined in the scientific literature. Although there are many possible explanations for this phenomenon, the iatrogenic explanation appears to be the most substantiated. The unusually large number of diagnosis in the 1980s were clustered around a small number of practitioners, many of whom used &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/01/09/the-neurological-mechanisms-behind-hypnosis/&quot;&gt;hypnosis&lt;/a&gt; as a therapeutic tool. It is quite possible that under the influence of hypnosis the patients with a higher level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;suggestibility&lt;/a&gt; may start to believe that they are suffering from split personality disorder, and behave accordingly. The level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;hypnotisability&lt;/a&gt; of people with the diagnosis of DID is known to be the highest among any clinical population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the DID diagnosis numbers also correlated with the growing number of split personality cases in the criminal court cases. The defense on the basis of DID was rarely successful, as it was often assumed that the defenders simply pretend to have the disorder to avoid taking responsibility for their crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opinion exists that the manifestations of DID are simply the consequences of other disorders such as bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and borderline personality disorder. Many patients diagnosed with DID have previous history of these and other psychiatric conditions. Another theory suggests that the manifestations of DID are the consequences of trauma. There is plenty of clinical cases in support of this theory, but not so much statistical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it is well proven that people with DID are at higher risk of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/27/ketamine-for-rapid-treatment-of-depression/&quot;&gt;depression &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/10/back-to-school-suicides/&quot;&gt;suicide&lt;/a&gt;. The patients often suffer from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/24/how-does-post-traumatic-stress-disorder-change-the-brain/&quot;&gt;post-traumatic stress disorder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/22/from-abuse-to-addiction-the-withdrawal-period-makes-the-difference/&quot;&gt;substance abuse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/21/could-brain-stimulation-be-a-therapy-for-anorexia-nervosa/&quot;&gt;eating disorders&lt;/a&gt;. Such statistics are not uncommon in other psychiatric conditions, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, there is a shortage of proper neurological studies of this disorder. Nobody knows what exactly causes it and what kind of changes take place in the brains of patients diagnosed with this disease. The brain imaging data from patients with DID do not reveal any specific diagnostic patterns. Several studies demonstrated that the changes in personality state in the DID patients are associated with certain changes in the blood flow in the brain. There are also differences in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/12/17/exercise-to-keep-your-brain-healthy/&quot;&gt;brain blood flow&lt;/a&gt; patterns between patients with DID and healthy control subjects. It remains uncertain if these differences can be used in the diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of how real the majority of DID cases are is yet to be fully answered. In general, researchers agree that there are cases with very pronounced and obvious manifestations that would be rather hard to explain without invoking the concept of DID. However, when it comes to less severe cases, the diagnostic remains really problematic. This creates a problem for patients, as not knowing the specific diagnosis means the lack of clarity with treating the problem. Also, there is no consensus regarding how to treat the split personality disorder. Various psychotherapeutic and hypnotherapeutic techniques are currently used, but their efficacy remains unknown due to the absence of controlled randomised clinical trials. Clearly, there is a lot of room for further research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maldonado, JR; Spiegel D (2008) Dissociative disorders — Dissociative identity disorder (Multiple personality disorder). In Hales RE; Yudofsky SC; Gabbard GO; with foreword by Alan F. Schatzberg. The American Psychiatric Publishing textbook of psychiatry (5th ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinders AA (2008) Cross-examining dissociative identity disorder: Neuroimaging and etiology on trial. Neurocase. 14 (1): 44–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080%2F13554790801992768&quot;&gt;10.1080/13554790801992768&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris J (1996) Review-Essay: Dissociative Symptoms, Dissociative Disorders, and Cultural Psychiatry. Transcult Psychiatry. 33 (1): 55–68. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F136346159603300104&quot;&gt;10.1177/136346159603300104&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kihlstrom JF (2005) Dissociative disorders. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology. 1 (1): 227–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1146%2Fannurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&quot;&gt;10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atchison M, McFarlane AC (1994) A review of dissociation and dissociative disorders. The Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry. 28 (4): 591–9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3109%2F00048679409080782&quot;&gt;10.3109/00048679409080782&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piper A, Merskey H (2004) The persistence of folly: A critical examination of dissociative identity disorder. Part I. The excesses of an improbable concept. Canadian Journal of Psychiatry. &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt; (9): 592–600. PMID &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15503730&quot;&gt;15503730&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiegel D, Loewenstein RJ, Lewis-Fernández R, Sar V, Simeon D, Vermetten E, Cardeña E, Dell PF (2011) Dissociative disorders in DSM-5. Depression and Anxiety. 28 (9): 824–852. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002%2Fda.20874&quot;&gt;10.1002/da.20874&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52598</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T16:00:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Here’s a mystery: How did a nonexistent paper rack up hundreds of citations? Pieter Kroonenberg, an emeritus professor of statistics at Leiden University in The Netherlands, was puzzled when he tried to locate a paper about academic writing and discovered the article didn’t exist. In fact, the journal—Journal of Science Communications—also didn’t exist. Perhaps Kroonenberg’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52589</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T13:00:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last month, a colleague of emergency medicine doctor Daniel Waxman sent him some newly reported findings that took him by surprise. Waxman knew from the title of a press release about the recent paper — “Nearly Half of U.S. Medical Care Comes From Emergency Rooms” — that something was wrong. Immediately I said, that’s not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ancient spiral galaxy is 11 billion years old</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The most ancient spiral galaxy seen to date is 11 billion years old and could help reveal how galaxies sprout arms.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New blood pressure guidelines put half of U.S. adults in unhealthy range</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T00:01:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New hypertension guidelines broaden the range of those considered to have high blood pressure and emphasize lifestyle changes to combat the condition.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">China fires up next-generation neutron-science facility</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EUma8ce4MBU/nature.2017.22976"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976</id>
		<updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Beam generator puts country in elite company for doing experiments in materials science and other fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 284 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22976&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EUma8ce4MBU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Cyranoski</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Study shows how easy and effective it is for Facebook ads to target your personality</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/study-shows-how-easy-and-effective-it-is-for-facebook-ads-to-target-your-personality/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32433</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T20:00:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-20&quot; style=&quot;width: 2032px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-11-13 17.38.22.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32535&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32535&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-11-13 17.38.22&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2032,1818&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/study-shows-how-easy-and-effective-it-is-for-facebook-ads-to-target-your-personality/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examples of ads used in the study: (A) targeted at high and low extraversion users, (B) at high and low openness users. via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Matz et al, 2017 / Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, Facebook’s founding president Sean Parker admitted his concerns that by focusing on social validation, Facebook was designed to exploit “a vulnerability in human psychology”. Added to this, and amidst the current furore around fake news, imagine if adverts on Facebook could be adapted to target your personality, significantly increasing the odds that people like you will click on the ads and then buy the associated products. A timely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt; shows just how easy and effective it is to target web users according to their personality, a technique that the researchers call “psychological persuasion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32433&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, led by Sandra Matz at Columbia Business School, used data previously gathered via the myPersonality.org app. Millions of people took personality tests and agreed for the app to access their history of Likes on Facebook (for instance, whether they had “liked” Lady Gaga or the TV series Battlestar Galactica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a subsample of 65,000 users of the app, Matz and her team identified Likes which correlated strongly with scores on one of the main personality traits, but were neutral as regards the others. For example, they found that liking the US rapper Shwayze correlated with extraversion, but not with scores on the other main personality traits, and that liking Stargate SG1 correlated with introversion, but not the other traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an initial study, the researchers then created variations of a professional ad for a beauty product, either designed to appeal to extraverts (e.g. tagline: “Dance like no one’s watching (but they totally are)”, or to introverts (e.g. tagline: “Beauty doesn’t have to shout”). They then used Facebook’s marketing tool to target the two ads deliberately either at people likely to be introverted (because they had “liked” a page identified earlier as correlated with introversion) or likely to be extraverted (again, because they had liked one of the pages known to be liked more often by high scorers in extraversion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results from this ad campaign, which reached over three million users, were clear: when the ad design matched users’ personality, it was 1.54 times more likely to lead to a purchase of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second study was similar, but this time the researchers looked for Likes that correlated with low or high openness-to-experience, a trait that’s associated with creativity, aesthetic appreciation and a desire to try out new things. For instance, liking the BBC drama The Fall correlated with high openness whereas liking the Farm Town game correlated with low openness. The researchers then created versions of an ad for a crossword app designed to appeal to people with low or high openness-to-experience. In a campaign reaching over 84,000 users, when the ad design matched users’ personality, they were 1.38 times more likely to click the ad, and 1.31 times more likely to buy the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Matz and her team used their approach to target ads for a bubble shooting game at a subsample of Facebook users already signed up to similar games (such as FarmVille). The pattern of likes for this group showed they are likely more introverted than average. The researchers therefore compared an ad designed to appeal to introverts (tagline “Phew! Hard day? How about a puzzle to wind down with?”) with the app company’s standard advertising spiel (i.e. “Ready? FIRE! Grab the latest puzzle shooter now! Intense action and brain-bending puzzles!”). The ad designed to appeal to introverts was more 1.3 times more likely to be clicked on and 1.2 times more likely to be purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers said their results showed the “effectiveness of psychological targeting in the context of real-life digital mass persuasion; tailoring persuasive appeals to the psychological profiles of large groups of people allowed us to influence their actual behaviours and choices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Persuasive appeals that were matched to people’s extraversion or openness-to- experience level resulted in up to 40 per cent more clicks and up to 50 per cent more purchases than their mismatching or unpersonalized counterparts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They added that this approach could be used for good (for example, to boost the effectiveness of public health campaigns) or ill (imagine if online gambling companies started using these techniques).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads tailored to your personality could just be the start. As apps and tracking software become more sophisticated (especially via wearable devices), it may be possible to gather data in real-time about users’ current mood or emotional state and then tailor ads accordingly, both in terms of their content, but also their timing. “Hence, extrapolating from what one does to who one is likely just the first step in a continuous development of psychological mass persuasion,” Matz and her team concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Psychological targeting as an effective approach to digital mass persuasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Matz et al/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32433/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32433/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32433&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Philosophical critique exposes flaws in medical evidence hierarchies</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/critique-medical-evidence-hierarchies"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/critique-medical-evidence-hierarchies</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T19:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Rankings of research methods for validity of medical evidence suffer from logical flaws, an in-depth philosophical critique concludes.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Lord Howe stick insect is officially back from the dead</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lord-howe-stick-insect-extinction"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lord-howe-stick-insect-extinction</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T17:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New genomic sequencing confirms that stick insects discovered near Lord Howe Island are the assumed-extinct Lord Howe stick insect.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Science Exchange Scientific Provider Elion Labs Presenting New Research at the AAPS Annual Meeting</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/science-exchange-scientific-provider-elion-labs-presenting-new-research-at-the-aaps-annual-meeting/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1180</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T16:47:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Breakthrough in drug product particle analysis using machine learning&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Biopharma researchers can access Elion’s new services from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;scienceexchange.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elion-at-AAPSsmaller.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Science Exchange and Elion at AAPS&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1182&quot; height=&quot;188&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elion-at-AAPSsmaller-300x188.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, and LOUISVILLE, CO, November 13, 2017 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform for outsourced research and development, is proud to announce that Elion Labs, provider of analytical development and drug product characterization services, will present exciting new research at the 2017 AAPS (American Association of Pharmaceutical Scientists) Annual Meeting, the most comprehensive event for innovations in bioanalysis, formulation, and product characterization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Elion’s expertise has helped bring numerous clinical products to market. Their AAPS research poster presentation (Abstract M8003) introduces a novel method for drug product analysis, using machine learning and advanced image analysis to improve particle detection, enumeration, and classification. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Machine learning approaches open up exciting new possibilities for analyzing particles in biologics, and ultimately, for better analyzing a broad range of complex data sets,”  said John Gabrielson, Ph.D., CEO and Founding Partner of Elion Labs. “We hope that our research will help biopharmaceutical researchers develop safer, more effective drugs and deliver them to patients faster.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Elion and Science Exchange will exhibit at booth 2337 at AAPS, meeting drug discovery and development researchers and representatives of regulatory agencies seeking the latest, innovative services available for pharmaceutical analysis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We’re proud to participate in this year’s conference alongside Elion, who are true thought leaders in analytical research,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO and Co-Founder of Science Exchange. “And because they’re part of the Science Exchange network, biopharmaceutical researchers can access Elion’s technologies immediately under our pre-existing master service agreement that covers IP and confidentiality.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;More information about Elion Labs and their innovative services can be found at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/elion-labs&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com/labs/elion-labs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Elion Labs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elion Labs, based in Louisville, Colorado, USA, was founded to serve the analytical development and product characterization needs of the biopharmaceutical industry. Elion offers a variety of services, including analytical method development, qualification and validation; analytical characterization testing of biologics; formulation development; training in highly specialized analytical techniques; comprehensive data analysis including visualization and interpretation of complex data sets; technical and regulatory writing; and technical consulting. They are committed to providing all services with unmatched professionalism, quality, and speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Science Exchange&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange is the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research, providing an efficient procure-to-pay platform for ordering 6,000+ services from a network of more than 2,500 qualified scientific service providers, all with pre-established contracts in place that protect client intellectual property and confidentiality. The platform increases access to innovation and improves productivity, freeing scientists from administrative tasks and delays associated with sourcing, establishing and managing service provider contracts. Additionally, the Science Exchange enterprise program enables large R&amp;amp;D organizations to consolidate research outsourcing spend into a single strategic relationship, driving efficiency, improving transparency and oversight, and delivering cost savings. Since being founded in 2011, Science Exchange has raised more than $58 million from Norwest Venture Partners, Maverick Capital Ventures, Union Square Ventures, Collaborative Fund, Index Ventures, OATV, the YC Continuity Fund, and others. For more information, visit www.ScienceExchange.com. Follow the company on Twitter @ScienceExchange.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Lawyers call libel suit against journal and critic “lawless” but “well written”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/lawyers-call-libel-suit-journal-critic-lawless-well-written/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52575</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T16:10:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A $10 million defamation suit filed by a Stanford University professor against a critic and a journal may be an assault on free speech, according to one lawyer, but at least it’s “well written.” Kenneth White, a lawyer at Southern California firm Brown White &amp;amp; Osborn who frequently blogs about legal issues related to free […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/lawyers-call-libel-suit-journal-critic-lawless-well-written/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lawyers call libel suit against journal and critic “lawless” but “well written”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Dear peer reviewer, please read the methods section. Sincerely, everyone</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/caught-notice-dear-peer-reviewer-please-read-methods-section-sincerely-everyone/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52518</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T13:00:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Plasma contributes to the antimicrobial activity of whole blood against Mycobacterium tuberculosis What Caught Our Attention: A big peer review (and perhaps academic mentorship) fail.  These researchers used the wrong anticoagulant for their blood samples, leading them to believe that certain blood components were fighting microbes. The authors counted the number of colonies to show […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/caught-notice-dear-peer-reviewer-please-read-methods-section-sincerely-everyone/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Dear peer reviewer, please read the methods section. Sincerely, everyone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Joe Biden: “Your work will bring hope to millions of people”</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/joe-biden-your-work-will-bring-hope-to-millions-of-people"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/joe-biden-your-work-will-bring-hope-to-millions-of-people</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T12:41:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 At the UN, the former VP recognizes the Lancet Oncology Commission and Elsevier for their contributions to the Cancer Moonshot initiative</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cholera pandemics are fueled by globe-trotting bacterial strains</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cholera-pandemics-are-fueled-globe-trotting-bacterial-strains"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cholera-pandemics-are-fueled-globe-trotting-bacterial-strains</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 International cholera strains, rather than local ones, have caused raging epidemics, according to research that examined the bacteria’s DNA.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Very intelligent people make less effective leaders, according to their peers and subordinates</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/very-intelligent-people-make-less-effective-leaders-according-to-their-peers-and-subordinates/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32398</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T08:50:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32415&quot; style=&quot;width: 1847px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-473843606.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32415&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32415&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;businessman in suit with brain over head&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ismagilov&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;businessman with brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;businessman with brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1847,1624&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/very-intelligent-people-make-less-effective-leaders-according-to-their-peers-and-subordinates/businessman-with-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Leaders who stand intellectually apart and are prone to complex language may be less inspiring&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly intelligent people tend to make good progress in the workplace and are seen as fit for leadership roles: overall, smarter is usually associated with success. But if you examine the situation more closely, as does &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14279-001&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Applied Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, you find evidence that too much intelligence can harm leadership effectiveness. Too clever for your own good? Let’s look at the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32398&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Antonakis at the University of Lausanne and colleagues recruited 379 mid-level leaders (27 per cent women, average age 38) at private companies in 30 mainly European countries, working in areas ranging from banking and telecoms to hospitality and retail. Each participant completed a personality questionnaire and a well-validated measure of intelligence, the Wonderlic Personnel Test. Their average IQ was 111 (the average for the general population is 100), with a fairly even spread of scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also had access to third-party ratings of the participants’ leadership performance from eight people: either peers or subordinates of the leader, who rated them on the Multifactor Leadership Questionnaire, which explores the degree to which the leader demonstrates various leadership styles, some known to be useful (e.g. a “transformational style” which inspires, or an “instrumental” style that removes stumbling blocks), others detrimental (e.g. a passive, hands-off style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, women tended to employ better leadership styles, and to a lesser extent so did older leaders, but the bulk of the variance was accounted for by personality and intelligence. Like so much previous work, intelligence showed a positive linear relationship with leadership effectiveness, but this association flattened out and then reversed at an IQ of about 120. For leaders with higher intelligence than this, their scores in transformational and instrumental leadership were lower, on average, than less smart leaders; and beyond an IQ of 128, the association with less effective leadership was clear and statistically significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note is that Antonakis’ team also predicted that very high intelligence would correlate not only with less use of effective leadership methods, but also greater use of harmful leadership styles (such as laissez-faire leadership). The data didn’t bear this out. Very smart leaders weren’t falling prey to bad approaches, they were struggling to use the good ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of several recent psychological studies investigating how there can be “too much of a good thing”. For leaders, this can apply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//digest.bps.org.uk/2015/08/17/having-strong-political-skills-can-be-a-handicap-in-the-workplace/&quot;&gt;political skills&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/14/with-leader-charisma-its-possible-to-have-too-much-of-a-good-thing/&quot;&gt;charisma&lt;/a&gt;. Intelligence is perhaps more surprising, given its well-established association with positive outcomes. The new findings can’t tell us why very smart people seem to make poorer leaders, but it’s possible leaders who stand intellectually apart and are prone to complex language are less inspiring, and they may find it difficult to anticipate what will prove a challenge to others, and how to reduce tasks to an appropriate level of simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must remember, however, that the issue isn’t whether, on balance, intelligence benefits leadership – it does – but whether it does so at every level of increasing intelligence. Antonakis’ team also speculate that the levels at which a leader’s intelligence delivers diminishing or reversing returns may depend on the relative intelligence of their team members, so these results don’t necessarily tell us the optimal IQ for all leaders. But they do suggest that in a social world, even highly advantageous traits can come with some drawbacks. And they also give defensive managers an excuse for a poor performance review: “I’m too clever for these guys!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14279-001&quot;&gt;Can super smart leaders suffer from too much of a good thing? The curvilinear effect of intelligence on perceived leadership behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32398/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32398/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32398&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">World’s carbon emissions set to spike by 2% in 2017</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/snhc4pE7Lyw/nature.2017.22995"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22995</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Increased coal use in China appears to be driving the first increase in global greenhouse-gas output since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 283 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22995&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22995&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/snhc4pE7Lyw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Archaeologists say human-evolution study used stolen bone</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/s1GMt9lYXfQ/nature.2017.22984"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22984</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Bizarre tale of theft and suspicious packages casts doubt on claims for early-human occupation in northern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 279 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22984&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22984&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/s1GMt9lYXfQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ewen Callaway</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">High-jumping beetle inspires agile robots</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/IbXzFd13L-s/nature.2017.22981"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22981</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Machines could get themselves out of a sticky spot, thanks to an insect that can right itself without using its legs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22981&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/IbXzFd13L-s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lab mice's ancestral ‘Eve’ gets her genome sequenced</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/XopkqJ1aPF4/nature.2017.22974"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22974</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Effort aims to help scientists understand how generations of inbreeding have altered the genetics of research rodents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22974&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22974&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/XopkqJ1aPF4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sara Reardon</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A non-canonical Notch complex regulates adherens junctions and vascular barrier function</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/BJpT2Sv5AhU/nature24998"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24998</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The vascular barrier that separates blood from tissues is actively regulated by the endothelium and is essential for transport, inflammation, and haemostasis1. Haemodynamic shear stress plays a critical role in maintaining endothelial barrier function2, but how this occurs remains unknown. Here, using an engineered organotypic model of perfused microvessels and confirming in mouse models, we identify that activation of the Notch1 transmembrane receptor directly regulates vascular barrier function through a non-canonical, transcription independent signalling mechanism that drives adherens junction assembly. Shear stress triggers Dll4-dependent proteolytic activation of Notch1 to reveal the Notch1 transmembrane domain—the key domain that mediates barrier establishment. Expression of the Notch1 transmembrane domain is sufficient to rescue Notch1 knockout-induced defects in barrier function, and does so by catalysing the formation of a novel receptor complex in the plasma membrane consisting of VE-cadherin, the transmembrane protein tyrosine phosphatase LAR, and the Rac1 GEF Trio. This complex activates Rac1 to drive adherens junction assembly and establish barrier function. Canonical Notch transcriptional signalling is highly conserved throughout metazoans and is required for many processes in vascular development, including arterial-venous differentiation3, angiogenesis4, and remodelling5; here, we establish the existence of a previously unappreciated non-canonical cortical signalling pathway for Notch1 that regulates vascular barrier function, and thus provide a mechanism by which a single receptor might link transcriptional programs with adhesive and cytoskeletal remodelling. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24998&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24998&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/BJpT2Sv5AhU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>William J. Polacheck</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">IL11 is a crucial determinant of cardiovascular fibrosis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5Ik8RBw0SjU/nature24676"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24676</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Fibrosis is a final common pathology in cardiovascular disease1. In the heart, fibrosis causes mechanical and electrical dysfunction1,2 and in the kidney, it predicts the onset of renal failure3. Transforming growth factor β1 (TGFB1) is the principal pro-fibrotic factor4,5 but its inhibition is associated with side effects due to its pleiotropic roles6,7. We hypothesised that downstream effectors of TGFB1 in fibroblasts could be attractive therapeutic targets and lack upstream toxicities. Using integrated imaging-genomics analyses of primary human fibroblasts, we found that Interleukin 11 (IL11) upregulation is the dominant transcriptional response to TGFB1 exposure and required for its profibrotic effect. IL11 and its receptor (IL11RA) are expressed specifically in fibroblasts where they drive non-canonical, ERK-dependent autocrine signalling that is required for fibrogenic protein synthesis. In mice, fibroblast-specific Il11 transgene expression or Il11 injection causes heart and kidney fibrosis and organ failure whereas genetic deletion of Il11ra1 is protective against disease. Thus, inhibition of IL11 prevents fibroblast activation across organs and species in response to a range of important pro-fibrotic stimuli. These data reveal a central role of IL11 in fibrosis and we propose inhibition of IL11 as a new therapeutic strategy to treat fibrotic diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24676&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5Ik8RBw0SjU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sebastian Schafer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Jurassic gliding euharamiyidan mammal with an ear of five auditory bones</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/z5F4t1IpEpE/nature24483"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24483</id>
		<updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Gliding is a distinctive locomotion type that has been identified in only three mammal species from the Mesozoic era. Here we describe another Jurassic glider that belongs to the euharamiyidan mammals and shows hair details on its gliding membrane that are highly similar to those of extant gliding mammals. This species possesses a five-boned auditory apparatus consisting of the stapes, incus, malleus, ectotympanic and surangular, representing, to our knowledge, the earliest known definitive mammalian middle ear. The surangular has not been previously identified in any mammalian middle ear, and the morphology of each auditory bone differs from those of known mammals and their kin. We conclude that gliding locomotion was probably common in euharamiyidans, which lends support to idea that there was a major adaptive radiation of mammals in the mid-Jurassic period. The acquisition of the auditory bones in euharamiyidans was related to the formation of the dentary-squamosal jaw joint, which allows a posterior chewing movement, and must have evolved independently from the middle ear structures of monotremes and therian mammals. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24483&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24483&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/z5F4t1IpEpE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gang Han</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Publishing’s day of reckoning; an Impact Factor discount — on lunch; a prize for negative results</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/11/weekend-reads-publishings-day-reckoning-impact-factor-discount-lunch-prize-negative-results/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52571</id>
		<updated>2017-11-11T14:00:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured mass resignations from a journal’s editorial board, software that writes papers for you, and a retracted retraction. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Academic journal publishing is headed for a day of reckoning,” says librarian Patrick Burns. (The Conversation) A Beijing BBQ joint, named after The Lancet, is offering discounts to researchers who […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/11/weekend-reads-publishings-day-reckoning-impact-factor-discount-lunch-prize-negative-results/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Publishing’s day of reckoning; an Impact Factor discount — on lunch; a prize for negative results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why the wiggle in a crowd’s walk can put a wobble in a bridge</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-wiggle-crowds-walk-can-put-wobble-bridge"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-wiggle-crowds-walk-can-put-wobble-bridge</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T19:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New simulations can better predict when pedestrians cause a bridge to shimmy.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A journal retracted a paper when authors couldn’t pay. Then it retracted the retraction.</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-retracted-paper-authors-couldnt-pay-retracted-retraction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52561</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T15:53:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Oops. A plant journal recently retracted a 2017 paper, saying the authors couldn’t pay the page charges ($110/page). The notice has since disappeared, and the journal announced on Twitter Thursday it was issued in error. The paper is now intact on the journal’s site. This isn’t the first time the journal has withdrawn a statement […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-retracted-paper-authors-couldnt-pay-retracted-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A journal retracted a paper when authors couldn’t pay. Then it retracted the retraction.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum computers take a step forward with a 50-qubit prototype</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/quantum-computers-take-step-forward-50-qubit-prototype"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/quantum-computers-take-step-forward-50-qubit-prototype</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T14:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Race to build ever-more-powerful processors edges the technology closer to being able to best traditional machines.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal to assemble “senior editorial committee” to review paper that led to board resignations</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-assemble-senior-editorial-committee-review-paper-led-board-resignations/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52559</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T13:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Following heavy criticism of its decision to correct — instead of retract — a paper accused of plagiarism, Scientific Reports is adding an editor’s note to the paper and forming a committee to review the case. The 2016 paper in question has been accused of plagiarism by a researcher at Johns Hopkins, Michael Beer. Following […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-assemble-senior-editorial-committee-review-paper-led-board-resignations/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal to assemble “senior editorial committee” to review paper that led to board resignations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ancient European farmers and foragers hooked up big time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-european-farmers-and-foragers-hooked-big-time"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-european-farmers-and-foragers-hooked-big-time</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Interbreeding escalated in regionally distinct ways across Neolithic Europe.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">To (m)eat or not to (m)eat? Ethical dilemmas in food choice</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/10/to-meat-or-not-to-meat-ethical-dilemmas-in-food-choice/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9600</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T10:00:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/meat-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘You are what you eat’ – The concept that you need to eat good food in order to be fit and healthy has gained meaning on a wider scale. While good dietary choices boost one’s own health, they can also benefit the planet. Dietary guidelines often give quantitative recommendations for the intake of animal products; however, in light of increasing encouragement to eat less meat to lessen the effects of climate change, consumers have become more concerned by the environmental impacts associated with meat production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Flickr: Anders Steen Nilsen&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-9603 size-full&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/cows.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;Raising animals for food requires enormous amounts of land, food, energy, and water and causes animal suffering. According to a&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldwatch.org/files/pdf/Livestock%20and%20Climate%20Change.pdf&quot;&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; published by the Worldwatch Institute, a staggering 51% or more of global greenhouse gas emissions are caused by animal agriculture. Meat consumption in the European Union has reduced and stabilized at around 42m tons over the last 15 years, and with the number of gluten-free products available doubling every year in Europe and the US, there has been in an increase in the consumption of plant proteins from beans and lentils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong claims like ‘You can’t be a meat-eating environmentalist’ have spurred disputes between vegetarians and meat-eaters but more and more people are trying to make major changes to their diets. New labels such as ‘flexitarians’ (only eat meat sometimes) and ‘reducetarians’ (aim to eat less meat) are an indication of how different groups of people are making efforts to cut down on their meat consumption one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conscious customer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do consumers choose their foods when they have to consider dietary guidelines as well as the potential environmental impact of their purchasing behaviors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4875-6&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published yesterday in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the first to investigate potential dilemmas between health and environmental considerations when purchasing animal food. The authors of the study specifically look at the socio-demographic profiles of individuals reporting health and environmental dilemmas when purchasing meat, fish and dairy products, and compare the diet quality of individuals with and without dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cross-sectional study involves 22,936 subjects from the NutriNet-Santé cohort study. Volunteers were recruited via multimedia campaigns and completed a set of self-administered, web-based questionnaires assessing dietary intake, physical activity, anthropometric characteristics, lifestyle, socioeconomic conditions and health status. At inclusion and once a year thereafter, participants were invited to complete three non-consecutive 24-h dietary records, which were validated against urinary biomarkers. In order for a dilemma to be assessed, participants were asked to rate items on a 4-point Likert scale: strongly disagree/disagree/agree/strongly agree to statements including: “I purchase [meat/fish/dairy products] for health issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of the study show that around 10% of individuals are torn between health and environmental considerations when purchasing meat or fish, and this is the case for only 5% for dairy products. Older participants, women, and low income individuals are more likely to report facing this dilemma. Participants who report dilemmas for meat and dairy products consume less of these foods and have a better dietary quality overall. In addition, participants with a meat dilemma show better adherence to meat/fish/eggs guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability and the way forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9619 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/fruits.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;The results of this study indicate that having environmental concerns is not contradictory to adherence with nutritional guidelines. National dietary guidelines should therefore be adapted to take into account both health and environmental sustainability as we are already seeing in some countries, such as Germany, where dilemmas in food choice will probably be lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we cannot say with certainty that eating a vegetarian diet is any better for the environment, we do need to acknowledge and understand that there are trade-offs in what foods we choose to eat. For example, flying in green beans from Kenya to the UK may be seen as unsustainable due to air miles, but it also supports up to 1.5 million people in some of the poorest regions of Sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, if you are contributing to food waste, then your diet is unsustainable regardless of whether you are a vegan, vegetarian, or a meat eater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/10/to-meat-or-not-to-meat-ethical-dilemmas-in-food-choice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;To (m)eat or not to (m)eat? Ethical dilemmas in food choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Natalie Pafitis</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-11-12T00:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Moderate alcohol consumption improves foreign language skills</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/10/moderate-alcohol-consumption-improves-foreign-language-skills/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32378</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T09:07:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-32391 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32391&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845?w=480&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;480,270&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/10/moderate-alcohol-consumption-improves-foreign-language-skills/giphy-6/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcohol is not exactly known for its brain-boosting properties. In fact, it impairs all kinds of cognitive functioning, including working memory and the ability to ignore distractions. So it really should make it harder for someone to speak in a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as Fritz Renner of Maastricht University in the Netherlands, and colleagues, point out in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0269881117735687&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Psychopharmacology&lt;/i&gt;, “contrary to what would be expected based on theory, it is a widely held belief among bilingual speakers that alcohol consumption improves foreign language fluency, as is evident in anecdotal evidence from numerous discussions in social and popular media.” And in welcome news for holiday drinkers (not to mention language students) everywhere, it turns out that, at least at moderate levels, this belief seems to be right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32378&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the effect of alcohol on foreign language skills, Renner and his fellow researchers recruited 50 German students in their second year of an undergraduate degree in psychology at Maastricht University in the Netherlands. Maastricht is close to the German border and the university attracts many German students, all of whom must pass a Dutch language exam before they can attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, the students drank either 250ml of chilled water or 250ml of bitter lemon and enough vodka to generate a moderate blood alcohol concentration of about 0.04 per cent (the precise amount of vodka varied, according to gender and body weight). About 15 minutes after finishing the drink – by which time alcohol would have been absorbed into the bloodstream – the students were instructed to argue either for or against animal testing in Dutch, for two minutes. Two native Dutch speakers, who didn’t know which students had drunk what, rated the students’ language performance in terms of overall quality, understandability, vocabulary, pronunciation, word selection and fluency. Finally, the students completed an arithmetic task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renner and his colleagues predicted that while alcohol might increase the students’ &lt;i&gt;perceptions &lt;/i&gt;of how well they’d spoken in Dutch, they would in fact perform worse, based on the judges’ ratings, than the students who’d drunk water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn’t what they found. The vodka drinkers didn’t rate their own language performance any higher than the water-drinkers did. Neither did they do any worse on the arithmetic task. But they did receive better scores for their Dutch language skills, both overall and specifically for pronunciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why might this be? Some people feel nervous when speaking in a foreign language. It may be that the anxiety-reducing effects of a relatively small amount of alcohol improved their performance,  but this needs further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The findings of this study need replication in future studies, testing participants learning languages other than Dutch and varying the amount of alcohol that is consumed to further explore the effects of acute alcohol consumption on foreign language proficiency,” Renner and his fellow researchers concluded. At least, it shouldn’t be too tricky to find students willing to volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers noted in their paper, however, the amount of alcohol will be important in determining effects. The level in this study equated to a drink or two. As anyone who’s ever drunk more than that knows, at higher levels, slurring sets in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0269881117735687&quot;&gt;Dutch courage? Effects of acute alcohol consumption on self-ratings and observer ratings of foreign language skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32378/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32378/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32378&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Resurrected malaria strategy saves thousands of lives in Africa</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ANgkOvcKgmo/nature.2017.22982"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22982</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Pre-emptively treating kids for malaria is working, despite logistical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22982&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ANgkOvcKgmo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Maxmen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">South Africa tackles crime at sea with ship-spotting satellites</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1jrVcjODqAo/nature.2017.22977"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22977</id>
		<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Automated vessel-tracking system aims to spy poachers and smugglers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22977&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22977&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1jrVcjODqAo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Linda Nordling</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This talk is based on the article &quot;Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants&quot; by Bernd Noack; Research Director CNRS (Centre Nationnal de la Recherche Scientifique), LIMSI-CNRS, France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk Anuradha will summarise the article and attempt to explain some fundamental features of human speech.
In particular, she will show the range of frequencies typically used by men and women.
She will also explain the role of formants (concentration of energy at particular frequency) in speech communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vowels play an important part in the formation of words and how they are vocalised.
In fact, as will be shown much of the energy in human speech is used in the production of vowels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anuradha will also demonstrate how the human voice can be heard against the background of a full orchestra, even though the total sound from the orchestra is much louder than the singer (typically a soprano).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, she will show the relationship between distance and received speech level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 10/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anuradha Sulane</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This deep-sea fish uses weird eyes to see in dark and light</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T20:25:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The eyes of deep-sea fish called pearlsides contain cells that look like rods but act like cones.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Firing patterns in the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T19:20:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Julia will present the paper by Naud et al (2008) 'Firing patterns in the AdEx IF model'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article the authors explore the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model as a good tool to simulate large-scale spiking neuron networks.
They show that the AdEx model generates multiple firing patterns in response to the parameter values.
In order to describe the transition from one pattern to another, the phase diagrams are analysed in the article.
To further classify the firing patterns, the transient response to step current is studied.
The analytical solutions are given for continuous adaptation, initial bursting, regular bursting, tonic spiking and irregular spiking as a response to the constant current.
It is also concluded, that the network simulations of a large systems, such as thalamocortical, require the description of different neuron types.
Parameter sets for three neuron types are provided, but further work is needed to extend this to a larger number of neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full article could be found here: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Julia Goncharenko</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crested pigeons sound the alarm with their wings</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T18:28:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Crested pigeons have specialized feathers that signal danger when they flee from an apparent threat.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52537</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T15:57:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This week, we received a press release that caught our attention: A company is releasing software it claims will write manuscripts using researchers’ data.  The program, dubbed “Manuscript Writer,” uses artificial intelligence (AI) to generate papers, according to the company that created it, sciNote LLC. A spokesperson explained the software generates a first draft the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Honeybees fumble their way to blueberry pollination</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Blueberry flowers drive honeybees to grappling, even stomping a leg or two down a bloom throat, to reach pollen.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52531</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T13:37:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Carlo Croce, a cancer researcher who has faced numerous research misconduct allegations, recently accused a former lab member of misconduct. Although an institutional probe did not support that allegation, Croce’s efforts have led to a retraction. In November 2015, Croce and another cancer researcher at Ohio State University (OSU), Ramiro Garzon, contacted PLOS ONE, alleging […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Can evolutionary psychology and personality theory explain Trump’s popular appeal?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32297</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T12:30:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-632198430.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32369&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32369&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;WASHINGTON, DC - JANUARY 20:  U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on the West Front of the U.S. Capitol on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. In today's inauguration ceremony Donald J. Trump becomes the 45th president of the United States.  (Photo by Chip Somodevilla\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1484914722&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;840&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2500&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,683&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/donald-trump-is-sworn-in-as-45th-president-of-the-united-states/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago today, Donald J Trump, a man with no political or military experience, defied expectations, winning the election to become the 45th president of the United States. Nearly 63 million voted for him, including, and in spite of his reputation for sexism, over half of all white women. In an &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;open-access paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Evolutionary Studies in Imaginative Culture&lt;/em&gt;, Dan McAdams, one of the world’s leading experts in personality psychology, proposes an explanation for Trump’s popular appeal that is grounded in evolutionary psychology, personality theory and the social psychology of leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32297&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump encapsulates, and his personality is perfectly suited to, “dominance-oriented leadership”, McAdams explains, in contrast to “prestige leadership”, as exemplified by Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prestige leadership emerged more recently in our evolutionary history and is grounded in the cultural transmission of ideas and skills. Individuals who acquire expertise, and who have the ability to effectively organize other experts, are respected for their knowledge and wisdom and seen as legitimate leaders for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, dominant leadership is based on fear and power and dates farther back in our evolutionary past. To many Americans, Trump’s bombastic style and persona and proclamations have a “primal appeal”. Describing Trump as more “overtly aggressive” than any other political figure, “physically big and dynamic”, “insulting” and “egregiously self-promoting”, McAdams likens Trump’s “incendiary tweets” to the “charging displays” of an alpha male chimp, “designed to intimidate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to the dominance approach to leadership is the derogation of experts – Trump has previously stated he knows more than military generals and has no need for economists. Related to this is the espousal of an essentialist view that sees some individuals as inherently superior to others. Trump consistently boasts about his superior intelligence and abilities over others. He displays what social psychologists call “hubristic pride” – celebrating who he is (brilliant and powerful, in his view), rather than the work and effort he has invested (upon which “authentic pride” is based).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominant leader is especially appealing in a climate of fear. Trump has pushed this view – highlighting the dangers of outsiders, be they Mexican immigrants or Islamist terrorists, while also speaking of the economic “carnage” afflicting the country. Throughout his life, Trump has advocated a Hobbesian view of human culture. Even as long ago as 1981, he said “Man is the most vicious of all animals, and life is a series of battles ending in victory or defeat”. Against the enemies he invokes, and in these dangerous times, Trump “confidently assures Americans that he will deliver them from the chaos,” McAdams writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s personality is perfectly suited to this particular approach to leadership, McAdams observes. He has an unusual mix of extremely high extraversion, low agreeableness, and extreme narcissism. The first two traits contribute to his ability and willingness to forge opportunistic, short-term coalitions, but then to drop them as soon as they no longer fulfill his needs, just as alpha chimpanzees do with their potential rivals. Indeed, McAdams observes that “the case of Donald Trump shows how much humans turn out to be like chimps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Trump’s narcissism (and his essentialist view of ability and status) is likely appealing to voters who crave authoritarian rule – that is, submission to a strong leader, adherence to strict rules, and an aggressive, intolerant approach to outsiders and liberals (polls suggest authoritarianism has risen in the US over the last decade). A leader who believes confidently in, and frequently brags about, his own abilities, and strength and power, is highly appealing to these voters who have what social psychologists call a right-wing authoritarian attitude and social dominance orientation, meaning they believe strongly in the superiority of their own group over others, and who want a leader who endorses and represents this superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McAdams concludes by writing that he does not wish to dismiss or denigrate the many other explanations put forward for the rise of a man described by people from all political persuasions as “a serial liar, a sexual predator, a swindler, a narcissist, and a bully”. There are “many reasons” McAdams writes, [but] “the view advanced here is that Trump holds a deep and primal appeal for millions of Americans at this time in our history because of how effectively he channels the psychology of dominance – a way of thinking and feeling about leadership in groups that traces back many millions of years in human evolution, to our primate heritage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;The Appeal of the Primal Leader: Human Evolution and Donald J. Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32297&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">See these first-of-a-kind views of living human nerve cells</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A catalog of live brain cells reveals stunning diversity and intricate shapes, and may help scientists understand the abilities of the human brain.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How text mining is changing the way we tackle chronic disease</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T11:02:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers are working with Pathway Studio to design innovative treatments using simulations of complex diseases</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Physicists shrink plans for next major collider</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xmPIEmDBp1I/nature.2017.22983"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Large Hadron Collider’s failure to detect new particles beyond the Higgs has eroded the case for Japan’s proposed linear accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22983&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xmPIEmDBp1I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edwin Cartlidge</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">EPA OKs first living pest-control mosquito for use in United States</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T23:58:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Feds approve non-GM male tiger mosquitoes for sale as fake dads to suppress local pests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52498</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T19:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Nobel Prize Physiology 2017 (for their discoveries of molecular mechanisms controlling the circadian rhythm) is On Fiction as There Is No Molecular Mechanisms of Biological Clock Controlling the Circadian Rhythm. Circadian Rhythm Is Triggered and Controlled By Divine Mechanism (CCP – Time Mindness (TM) Real Biological Clock) in Life Sciences  What Caught Our Attention: This isn’t a retraction — rather, it’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists replaced 80 percent of a ‘butterfly’ boy’s skin</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T18:35:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 By correcting genes in stem cells and growing new skin in the lab, a new therapy repaired a genetic skin disease.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This star cheated death, exploding again and again</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The weirdest supernova ever has lasted more than three years, and may be the third outburst from the same star.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52505</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T16:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last week, a Swedish government funding agency announced 325 recipients of grants in Natural and Engineering Sciences. We don’t normally write about grant announcements, but we’re flagging this one because one recipient may be familiar to our readers. It is Peter Eklöv of Uppsala University, a co-author of a now-retracted Science paper about the potential […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">Is a thermostat conscious?</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/is-a-thermostat-conscious/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1464</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T14:23:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;A theory of consciousness initially proposed by David Chalmers (in his book the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Conscious-Mind-Search-Fundamental-Philosophy/dp/0195117891&quot;&gt;Conscious Mind&lt;/a&gt;) is that consciousness (or experience) is a property of information processing systems. It is an additional property, not logically implied by physical laws; a new law of nature. The theory was later formalized by Giulio Tononi into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_information_theory&quot;&gt;Integrated Information Theory&lt;/a&gt;, based on Shannon’s mathematical concept of information. One important feature of this theory is it is a radical form of panpsychism: it assigns consciousness (to different degrees) to virtually anything in the world, including a thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bewitched experiment of thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/modern-panpsychism-about-the-integrated-information-theory-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;I have criticized IIT previously&lt;/a&gt; on the grounds that it fails to define in a sensible way what makes a conscious subject (eg a subsystem of a conscious entity would be another conscious entity, so for example your brain would produce an infinite number of minds). But here I want to comment specifically on the example of the thermostat. It is an interesting example &lt;a href=&quot;https://annakaharris.com/chalmers/&quot;&gt;brought up by Chalmers in his book&lt;/a&gt;. The reasoning is as follows: a human brain is conscious; a mouse brain is probably conscious, but with a somewhat lower degree (for example, no self-consciousness). As we go down the scale of information-processing systems, the system might be less and less conscious, but why would it be that there is a definite threshold for consciousness? Why would a billion neurons be conscious but not a million? Why would a million neurons be conscious but not one thousand? And how about just one neuron? How about a thermostat? A thermostat is an elementary information-processing system with just two states, so maybe, Chalmers argue, the thermostat has a very elementary form of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To claim that a thermostat is conscious defies intuition, but I would not follow Searle on insisting that the theory must be wrong because it assigns consciousness to things that we wouldn’t intuitively think are conscious. As I argued in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/the-substrate-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, to claim that biology tells us that only brains are conscious is to use circular arguments. We don’t know whether anything else than a brain is conscious, and since consciousness is subjective, to decide whether anything is conscious is going to involve some theoretical aspects. Nonetheless, I am skeptical that a thermostat is conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to examine the Bewitched experiment of thought. In the TV series Bewitched, Samantha the housewife twitches her nose and everyone freezes except her. Then she twitches her nose and everyone unfreezes, without noticing that anything happened. For them, time has effectively stopped. The question is: was anyone experiencing anything during that time? To me, it is clear that no one can experience anything if time is frozen. In fact, that whole time has not existed at all for the conscious subject. It follows that a substrate with a fixed state (e.g. hot/cold) cannot experience anything, because time is effectively frozen for that substrate. Experience requires a flow of time, a change in structure through time. I leave it open whether the interaction of the thermostat with the room might produce experience for that coupled system (see below for some further thoughts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is “information”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my view, the fallacy in the initial reasoning is to put the thermostat and the brain in the same scale. That scale is the set of information-processing systems. But as I have argued before (mostly following Gibson’s arguments), &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xix-does-the-brain-process-information/&quot;&gt;it is misleading to see the brain an information-processing system&lt;/a&gt;. The brain can only be seen to transform information of one kind into information of another kind by an external observer, because the very concept of information is something that makes sense to a cognitive/perceptual system. The notion of information used by IIT is Shannon information, a notion from communication theory. This is an extrinsic notion of information: for example, neural activity is informative about objects in the world in the sense that properties of those objects can be inferred from neural activity. But this is totally unhelpful to understand how the brain, which only ever gets to deal with neural signals and not things in the world, sees the world (see this argument in more detail in my paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/07/31/168237&quot;&gt;Is coding a relevant metaphor for the brain?&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s clarify with a concrete case: does the thermostat perceive temperature? The thermostat can be in different states depending on temperature, but from its perspective, there is no temperature. There are changes in state that seems to be unrelated to anything else (there is literally nothing else for the thermostat). One could replace the temperature sensor with some other sensor, or with a random number generator, and there would be literally no functional change in the thermostat itself. Only an external observer can link the thermostat’s state with temperature, so the thermostat cannot possibly be conscious of temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, Shannon’s notion of information is inappropriate to understand consciousness. Instead of extracting information in the sense of communication theory, what the brain might do is build models of sensory (sensorimotor) signals from its subjective perspective, in the same way as scientists make models of the world with observations (=sensory signals) and experiments (=actions). But this intrinsic notion of information, which corresponds eg to laws of physics, is crucially not what Shannon’s notion of information is. And it is also not the kind of information that a thermostat is dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inappropriate notion of information leads to what in my view is a rather absurd quantitative scale of consciousness, according to which entities are more or less conscious along a graded scale (phi). Differences in consciousness are qualitative, not quantitative: there is dreaming, being awake, being self-conscious or not, etc. These are not different numbers. This odd analog scale arises because Shannon information is counted in bits. But information in the sense of knowledge (science) is not counted in bits; there are different kinds of knowledge, they have different structure, relations between them etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subjective physics of a thermostat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let us not throw away Chalmers’ interesting experiment of thought just now. Let us ask, following Chalmers: what does it feel like to be a thermostat? We will examine it not with Shannon’s unhelpful notion of information but with what I called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;subjective physics&lt;/a&gt;”: the laws that govern sensory signals and their relations to actions, from the perspective of the subject. This will define my world from a functional viewpoint. Let’s say I am a conscious thermostat; a homunculus inside the thermostat. All I can observe is a binary signal. Then there is a binary action that I can make, which for an external observer corresponds to turning on the heat. What kind of world does that make to me? Let’s say I’m a scientist homunculus, what kind of laws about the world can I infer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m a conventional thermostat, then the action will be automatically triggered when the signal is in a given state (“cold”). After some time, the binary signal will switch and so will the action. So in fact there is an identity between signal and action, which means that all I really observe is just the one binary signal, switching on and off, probably with some kind of periodicity. This is the world I might experience, as a homunculus inside the thermostat (note that to experience the periodicity requires memory, which a normal thermostat doesn’t have). In a way, I’m a “locked-in” thermostat: I can make observations, but I cannot freely act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that I am not locked-in and have a little more free will, so I can decide whether to act (heat) or not. If I can, then my world is a little bit more interesting: my action can trigger a switch of the binary signal, after some latency (again requiring some memory), and then when I stop, the binary signal switches back, after a time that depends on how much time my previous action lasted. So here I have a world that is much more structured, with relatively complex laws which in a way defines the concept of “temperature” from the perspective of the thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if a thermostat were conscious, then we have a rough idea of the kind of world it might experience (although not how it feels like), and even in this elementary example, you can’t measure these experiences in bits - let alone the fact that a thermostat is not conscious anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>admin</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52488</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T13:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When examining the roles of conflicts of interest in academic publishing, most research focuses on transparency around the payments authors receive. But what about journal editors? According to a new Peer J preprint, two-thirds of editors at prominent journals received some type of industry payment over the last few years – which, at many journals, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A 30-minute lesson in the malleability of personality has long-term benefits for anxious, depressed teenagers</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32165</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T12:24:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-155427885.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32264&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32264&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This series aims to portrait tattooed people in their professional and private lives.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;alvarez&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2000,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/portrait-of-a-tattooed-person/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many effective psychological therapies to help teenagers with depression, anxiety or other mental health problems. Unfortunately, for various reasons, most teenagers never get access to a professional therapist. To overcome this problem, some researchers are exploring the potential of brief, “single-session” interventions that can be delivered cheaply and easily to many at-risk teenagers outside of a clinical context. In &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, Jessica Schleider and John Weisz at Harvard University &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;present extremely promising results&lt;/a&gt; from their trial of a 30-minute computer session teaching depressed and anxious teenagers that personality is malleable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32165&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible, the participating teenagers needed to have problematic anxiety and/or depression. Ninety-six teenagers took part, aged 12 to 15, mostly White American. Forty-eight of them were assigned to the 20-to-30-minute session about the malleability of personality. The others, who had the same baseline symptom levels, acted as controls and spent an equal amount of time in a computer-based session of “supportive therapy” learning about emotions and how it’s helpful to talk about them. The idea was this would match the experience of being enrolled in the personality change session in all ways except for the all-important content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personality session was self-administered on computer and taught the teenagers about neuroplasticity and the idea that behaviours arise from thoughts and feelings in their brains, and that brains are always changing. They heard from older youths saying they believe people can change, and from others saying how they’d used belief in our capacity for change (a “growth mindset”) to cope with problems like embarrassment or rejection. The teenagers learned strategies for applying these principles to themselves and they wrote notes to younger children about the malleability of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary message of the intervention, the researchers said, is that “personal attributes are malleable if we systematically – and with appropriate supports – act to change them. Essentially it reinforces beliefs in &lt;em&gt;behavioral&lt;/em&gt; control over the kinds of people we are can can become.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the teens completed a series of psychological measures before and immediately after whichever session they took part in, and then they took the same measures again three, six, and nine-months later. Their parents also completed some of the same measures about their child. To avoid their own expectations affecting the results, the researchers were kept unaware of which teens were in which condition until the end of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promising findings include that the teens in the personality change session showed more rapid declines in depression, and nine months later their depression scores had declined more than the control participants’ scores (33 per cent fewer of them now had clinically severe levels of depression, compared with 11 per cent fewer among the control group). These benefits were mirrored in parents’ ratings of their children’s depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results for anxiety weren’t as good, but still showed promise – the personality change intervention led to greater declines in symptoms at nine months based on parents’ reports, although not based on the teenagers’ self-reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hoped, compared with the controls, the teenagers in the personality change intervention reported a stronger increase in their belief that your personality is something you can change. Further clues as to how the personality change intervention helped the teenagers come from measures of their belief in their ability to deal with adversity by controlling their own behavior (e.g. whether they agreed with statements like “I can be popular with kids my age, if I really try”; “I can do well on tests if I try really hard”) and their own emotions (e.g. “I can usually find something good to like, even in a bad situation” or ““When I have a problem that I can’t change, I can do something to take my mind off it.”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the follow-up period, the teens in the personality change intervention showed larger increases in their sense of control over their own behavior, as compared with the control participants (there was no difference in their sense of control over their emotions). This makes sense given the personality intervention’s focus on behavioral control as a means to influence our personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleider and Weisz said their “mindset” intervention teaching that personality is malleable is “highly cost-effective and scalable”, meaning it could be delivered to all new pupils arriving at a secondary school, for example. They added “these are the first findings we know of suggesting that a 30-minute, self-administered program may help reduce depression, and to a lesser degree, anxiety, in high-symptom and high-risk youths.” They believe the intervention may have such strong and enduring effects because it focuses on “‘keystone beliefs’ of high developmental relevance to adolescents”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage is that for any teens who end up in therapy, the brief personality change session could help lay the groundwork in terms of motivation and helpful beliefs about personal control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the results are encouraging, larger trials are needed, the researchers noted, including with teenagers from more ethnically diverse and less affluent backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;A single-session growth mindset intervention for adolescent anxiety and depression: 9-month outcomes of a randomized trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Psych_Writer/status/818794319385690113&quot;&gt;currently writing a book about personality change&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32165&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Human study supports theory on why dengue can be worse the next time around</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The amount of dengue antibodies leftover in the blood may up the chances of a severe second dengue infection, a study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Q&amp;amp;A: German pharma start-up leader on the importance of knowledge in a fast-changing industry</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T09:24:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Till Erdmann, Managing Director Myelo Therapeutics, on the challenges for young businesses in healthcare and how to tackle them</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How to increase your grant success rates with insights, discovery and decisions</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T08:37:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier’s VP of Academic and Government Strategic Alliances examines the challenges of research funding – and introduces a new solution</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Face it: Sheep are just like us when it comes to recognizing people</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:09:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sheep trained to recognize celebrity faces demonstrate that the animals have face-recognition capabilities similar to humans and other primates.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_14559625241659735=0.5361658477394641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">UK government appoints next chief scientific adviser</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/O3Ylql2RgSw/nature.2017.22956"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22956</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A former pharmaceutical boss will help navigate the UK’s exit from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 282 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22956&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22956&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/O3Ylql2RgSw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The catalogue that made metrics, and changed science</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6mV2dBaf2NE/551163a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551163a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As new ways emerge to assess research, Alex Csiszar recalls how the first one transformed the practice and place of science in society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 163 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551163a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551163a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6mV2dBaf2NE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alex Csiszar</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Four ethical priorities for neurotechnologies and AI</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/A5H-Jeo28uM/551159a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551159a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and brain–computer interfaces must respect and preserve people's privacy, identity, agency and equality, say Rafael Yuste, Sara Goering and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 159 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551159a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551159a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/A5H-Jeo28uM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rafael Yuste</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The bitter battle over the world’s most popular insecticides</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/y1H1Dfi1b0s/551156a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551156a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As regulators consider a ban on neonicotinoids, debate rages over the harm they cause to bees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 156 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551156a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551156a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/y1H1Dfi1b0s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Cressey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dark-matter hunt fails to find the elusive particles</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Z0791HB-KBA/551153a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551153a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Physicists begin to embrace alternative explanations for the missing material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551153a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551153a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Z0791HB-KBA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rohingya refugees, Bulgarian protests and a prize for negative results</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3nMPj_0gx2U/551146a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551146a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 3–9 November 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 146 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551146a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551146a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3nMPj_0gx2U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Grant recipients can still give objective advice</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oNHGz7KGPgM/551142a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551142a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The US environment agency should not ban researchers it funds from its advisory boards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551142a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551142a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oNHGz7KGPgM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Too many academics study the same people</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/FQ9aHM9zyLg/551141b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141b</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers should recognize communities that feel over-researched and under-rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 141 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551141b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/FQ9aHM9zyLg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Skin regeneration with insights</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_xxO-kIw2-o/551141a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A feat in stem-cell therapy highlights what can be achieved when basic and clinical research combine to advance biological understanding and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 141 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551141a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_xxO-kIw2-o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Gene therapy: Transgenic stem cells replace skin</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/X-lqwYnUihg/nature24753"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24753</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The treatment of a patient affected by an incurable genetic skin disease demonstrates the efficacy, feasibility and safety of replacing almost the whole skin using genetically corrected stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24753&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24753&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/X-lqwYnUihg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariaceleste Aragona</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Astrocytic neuroligins control astrocyte morphogenesis and synaptogenesis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WqIv855oAf8/nature24638"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24638</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Astrocytes are complex glial cells with numerous fine cellular processes that infiltrate the neuropil and interact with synapses. The mechanisms that control the establishment of astrocyte morphology are unknown, and it is unclear whether impairing astrocytic infiltration of the neuropil alters synaptic connectivity. Here we show that astrocyte morphogenesis in the mouse cortex depends on direct contact with neuronal processes and occurs in parallel with the growth and activity of synaptic circuits. The neuroligin family cell adhesion proteins NL1, NL2, and NL3, which are expressed by cortical astrocytes, control astrocyte morphogenesis through interactions with neuronal neurexins. Furthermore, in the absence of astrocytic NL2, the formation and function of cortical excitatory synapses are diminished, whereas inhibitory synaptic function is enhanced. Our findings highlight a previously undescribed mechanism of action for neuroligins and link astrocyte morphogenesis to synaptogenesis. Because neuroligin mutations have been implicated in various neurological disorders, these findings also point towards an astrocyte-based mechanism of neural pathology. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 192 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24638&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WqIv855oAf8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff A. Stogsdill</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fully integrated silicon probes for high-density recording of neural activity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/fi-MLl9S27I/nature24636"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24636</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Sensory, motor and cognitive operations involve the coordinated action of large neuronal populations across multiple brain regions in both superficial and deep structures. Existing extracellular probes record neural activity with excellent spatial and temporal (sub-millisecond) resolution, but from only a few dozen neurons per shank. Optical Ca2+ imaging offers more coverage but lacks the temporal resolution needed to distinguish individual spikes reliably and does not measure local field potentials. Until now, no technology compatible with use in unrestrained animals has combined high spatiotemporal resolution with large volume coverage. Here we design, fabricate and test a new silicon probe known as Neuropixels to meet this need. Each probe has 384 recording channels that can programmably address 960 complementary metal–oxide–semiconductor (CMOS) processing-compatible low-impedance TiN sites that tile a single 10-mm long, 70 × 20-μm cross-section shank. The 6 × 9-mm probe base is fabricated with the shank on a single chip. Voltage signals are filtered, amplified, multiplexed and digitized on the base, allowing the direct transmission of noise-free digital data from the probe. The combination of dense recording sites and high channel count yielded well-isolated spiking activity from hundreds of neurons per probe implanted in mice and rats. Using two probes, more than 700 well-isolated single neurons were recorded simultaneously from five brain structures in an awake mouse. The fully integrated functionality and small size of Neuropixels probes allowed large populations of neurons from several brain structures to be recorded in freely moving animals. This combination of high-performance electrode technology and scalable chip fabrication methods opens a path towards recording of brain-wide neural activity during behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 232 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24636&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24636&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/fi-MLl9S27I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>James J. Jun</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ultra-selective looming detection from radial motion opponency</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/pma6qLrOVNY/nature24626"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24626</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Nervous systems combine lower-level sensory signals to detect higher-order stimulus features critical to survival, such as the visual looming motion created by an imminent collision or approaching predator. Looming-sensitive neurons have been identified in diverse animal species. Different large-scale visual features such as looming often share local cues, which means loom-detecting neurons face the challenge of rejecting confounding stimuli. Here we report the discovery of an ultra-selective looming detecting neuron, lobula plate/lobula columnar, type II (LPLC2) in Drosophila, and show how its selectivity is established by radial motion opponency. In the fly visual system, directionally selective small-field neurons called T4 and T5 form a spatial map in the lobula plate, where they each terminate in one of four retinotopic layers, such that each layer responds to motion in a different cardinal direction. Single-cell anatomical analysis reveals that each arm of the LPLC2 cross-shaped primary dendrites ramifies in one of these layers and extends along that layer’s preferred motion direction. In vivo calcium imaging demonstrates that, as their shape predicts, individual LPLC2 neurons respond strongly to outward motion emanating from the centre of the neuron’s receptive field. Each dendritic arm also receives local inhibitory inputs directionally selective for inward motion opposing the excitation. This radial motion opponency generates a balance of excitation and inhibition that makes LPLC2 non-responsive to related patterns of motion such as contraction, wide-field rotation or luminance change. As a population, LPLC2 neurons densely cover visual space and terminate onto the giant fibre descending neurons, which drive the jump muscle motor neuron to trigger an escape take off. Our findings provide a mechanistic description of the selective feature detection that flies use to discern and escape looming threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 237 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24626&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24626&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/pma6qLrOVNY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nathan C. Klapoetke</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure and assembly of the Ebola virus nucleocapsid</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/f0xxw1BINHI/nature24490"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24490</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ebola and Marburg viruses are filoviruses: filamentous, enveloped viruses that cause haemorrhagic fever. Filoviruses are within the order Mononegavirales, which also includes rabies virus, measles virus, and respiratory syncytial virus. Mononegaviruses have non-segmented, single-stranded negative-sense RNA genomes that are encapsidated by nucleoprotein and other viral proteins to form a helical nucleocapsid. The nucleocapsid acts as a scaffold for virus assembly and as a template for genome transcription and replication. Insights into nucleoprotein–nucleoprotein interactions have been derived from structural studies of oligomerized, RNA-encapsidating nucleoprotein, and cryo-electron microscopy of nucleocapsid or nucleocapsid-like structures. There have been no high-resolution reconstructions of complete mononegavirus nucleocapsids. Here we apply cryo-electron tomography and subtomogram averaging to determine the structure of Ebola virus nucleocapsid within intact viruses and recombinant nucleocapsid-like assemblies. These structures reveal the identity and arrangement of the nucleocapsid components, and suggest that the formation of an extended α-helix from the disordered carboxy-terminal region of nucleoprotein-core links nucleoprotein oligomerization, nucleocapsid condensation, RNA encapsidation, and accessory protein recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24490&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24490&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/f0xxw1BINHI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>William Wan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A single-cell survey of the small intestinal epithelium</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MVaQv3dg3tI/nature24489"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24489</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Intestinal epithelial cells absorb nutrients, respond to microbes, function as a barrier and help to coordinate immune responses. Here we report profiling of 53,193 individual epithelial cells from the small intestine and organoids of mice, which enabled the identification and characterization of previously unknown subtypes of intestinal epithelial cell and their gene signatures. We found unexpected diversity in hormone-secreting enteroendocrine cells and constructed the taxonomy of newly identified subtypes, and distinguished between two subtypes of tuft cell, one of which expresses the epithelial cytokine Tslp and the pan-immune marker CD45, which was not previously associated with non-haematopoietic cells. We also characterized the ways in which cell-intrinsic states and the proportions of different cell types respond to bacterial and helminth infections: Salmonella infection caused an increase in the abundance of Paneth cells and enterocytes, and broad activation of an antimicrobial program; Heligmosomoides polygyrus caused an increase in the abundance of goblet and tuft cells. Our survey highlights previously unidentified markers and programs, associates sensory molecules with cell types, and uncovers principles of gut homeostasis and response to pathogens. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24489&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24489&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MVaQv3dg3tI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Adam L. Haber</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Regeneration of the entire human epidermis using transgenic stem cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/SRXKhF2JIAw/nature24487"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24487</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Junctional epidermolysis bullosa (JEB) is a severe and often lethal genetic disease caused by mutations in genes encoding the basement membrane component laminin-332. Surviving patients with JEB develop chronic wounds to the skin and mucosa, which impair their quality of life and lead to skin cancer. Here we show that autologous transgenic keratinocyte cultures regenerated an entire, fully functional epidermis on a seven-year-old child suffering from a devastating, life-threatening form of JEB. The proviral integration pattern was maintained in vivo and epidermal renewal did not cause any clonal selection. Clonal tracing showed that the human epidermis is sustained not by equipotent progenitors, but by a limited number of long-lived stem cells, detected as holoclones, that can extensively self-renew in vitro and in vivo and produce progenitors that replenish terminally differentiated keratinocytes. This study provides a blueprint that can be applied to other stem cell-mediated combined ex vivo cell and gene therapies. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24487&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24487&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/SRXKhF2JIAw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tobias Hirsch</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A ubiquitin-dependent signalling axis specific for ALKBH-mediated DNA dealkylation repair</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/_5xuJLZMxk8/nature24484"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24484</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 DNA repair is essential to prevent the cytotoxic or mutagenic effects of various types of DNA lesions, which are sensed by distinct pathways to recruit repair factors specific to the damage type. Although biochemical mechanisms for repairing several forms of genomic insults are well understood, the upstream signalling pathways that trigger repair are established for only certain types of damage, such as double-stranded breaks and interstrand crosslinks. Understanding the upstream signalling events that mediate recognition and repair of DNA alkylation damage is particularly important, since alkylation chemotherapy is one of the most widely used systemic modalities for cancer treatment and because environmental chemicals may trigger DNA alkylation. Here we demonstrate that human cells have a previously unrecognized signalling mechanism for sensing damage induced by alkylation. We find that the alkylation repair complex ASCC (activating signal cointegrator complex) relocalizes to distinct nuclear foci specifically upon exposure of cells to alkylating agents. These foci associate with alkylated nucleotides, and coincide spatially with elongating RNA polymerase II and splicing components. Proper recruitment of the repair complex requires recognition of K63-linked polyubiquitin by the CUE (coupling of ubiquitin conjugation to ER degradation) domain of the subunit ASCC2. Loss of this subunit impedes alkylation adduct repair kinetics and increases sensitivity to alkylating agents, but not other forms of DNA damage. We identify RING finger protein 113A (RNF113A) as the E3 ligase responsible for upstream ubiquitin signalling in the ASCC pathway. Cells from patients with X-linked trichothiodystrophy, which harbour a mutation in RNF113A, are defective in ASCC foci formation and are hypersensitive to alkylating agents. Together, our work reveals a previously unrecognized ubiquitin-dependent pathway induced specifically to repair alkylation damage, shedding light on the molecular mechanism of X-linked trichothiodystrophy. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24484&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/_5xuJLZMxk8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Joshua R. Brickner</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Parallel palaeogenomic transects reveal complex genetic history of early European farmers</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tXosyiVuYOk/nature24476"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24476</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ancient DNA studies have established that Neolithic European populations were descended from Anatolian migrants who received a limited amount of admixture from resident hunter-gatherers. Many open questions remain, however, about the spatial and temporal dynamics of population interactions and admixture during the Neolithic period. Here we investigate the population dynamics of Neolithization across Europe using a high-resolution genome-wide ancient DNA dataset with a total of 180 samples, of which 130 are newly reported here, from the Neolithic and Chalcolithic periods of Hungary (6000–2900 bc, n = 100), Germany (5500–3000 bc, n = 42) and Spain (5500–2200 bc, n = 38). We find that genetic diversity was shaped predominantly by local processes, with varied sources and proportions of hunter-gatherer ancestry among the three regions and through time. Admixture between groups with different ancestry profiles was pervasive and resulted in observable population transformation across almost all cultural transitions. Our results shed new light on the ways in which gene flow reshaped European populations throughout the Neolithic period and demonstrate the potential of time-series-based sampling and modelling approaches to elucidate multiple dimensions of historical population interactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24476&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24476&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tXosyiVuYOk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Lipson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A neoantigen fitness model predicts tumour response to checkpoint blockade immunotherapy</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gwCTz9AgNOw/nature24473"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24473</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Checkpoint blockade immunotherapies enable the host immune system to recognize and destroy tumour cells. Their clinical activity has been correlated with activated T-cell recognition of neoantigens, which are tumour-specific, mutated peptides presented on the surface of cancer cells. Here we present a fitness model for tumours based on immune interactions of neoantigens that predicts response to immunotherapy. Two main factors determine neoantigen fitness: the likelihood of neoantigen presentation by the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) and subsequent recognition by T cells. We estimate these components using the relative MHC binding affinity of each neoantigen to its wild type and a nonlinear dependence on sequence similarity of neoantigens to known antigens. To describe the evolution of a heterogeneous tumour, we evaluate its fitness as a weighted effect of dominant neoantigens in the subclones of the tumour. Our model predicts survival in anti-CTLA-4-treated patients with melanoma and anti-PD-1-treated patients with lung cancer. Importantly, low-fitness neoantigens identified by our method may be leveraged for developing novel immunotherapies. By using an immune fitness model to study immunotherapy, we reveal broad similarities between the evolution of tumours and rapidly evolving pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24473&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24473&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gwCTz9AgNOw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Marta Łuksza</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genetic variation in glia–neuron signalling modulates ageing rate</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tUF9CiN1FwI/nature24463"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24463</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The rate of behavioural decline in the ageing population is remarkably variable among individuals. Despite the considerable interest in studying natural variation in ageing rate to identify factors that control healthy ageing, no such factor has yet been found. Here we report a genetic basis for variation in ageing rates in Caenorhabditis elegans. We find that C. elegans isolates show diverse lifespan and age-related declines in virility, pharyngeal pumping, and locomotion. DNA polymorphisms in a novel peptide-coding gene, named regulatory-gene-for-behavioural-ageing-1 (rgba-1), and the neuropeptide receptor gene npr-28 influence the rate of age-related decline of worm mating behaviour; these two genes might have been subjected to recent selective sweeps. Glia-derived RGBA-1 activates NPR-28 signalling, which acts in serotonergic and dopaminergic neurons to accelerate behavioural deterioration. This signalling involves the SIR-2.1-dependent activation of the mitochondrial unfolded protein response, a pathway that modulates ageing. Thus, natural variation in neuropeptide-mediated glia–neuron signalling modulates the rate of ageing in C. elegans. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 198 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24463&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24463&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tUF9CiN1FwI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jiang-An Yin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Identification of unique neoantigen qualities in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/HW2E_H4heFY/nature24462"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24462</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma is a lethal cancer with fewer than 7% of patients surviving past 5 years. T-cell immunity has been linked to the exceptional outcome of the few long-term survivors, yet the relevant antigens remain unknown. Here we use genetic, immunohistochemical and transcriptional immunoprofiling, computational biophysics, and functional assays to identify T-cell antigens in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer. Using whole-exome sequencing and in silico neoantigen prediction, we found that tumours with both the highest neoantigen number and the most abundant CD8+ T-cell infiltrates, but neither alone, stratified patients with the longest survival. Investigating the specific neoantigen qualities promoting T-cell activation in long-term survivors, we discovered that these individuals were enriched in neoantigen qualities defined by a fitness model, and neoantigens in the tumour antigen MUC16 (also known as CA125). A neoantigen quality fitness model conferring greater immunogenicity to neoantigens with differential presentation and homology to infectious disease-derived peptides identified long-term survivors in two independent datasets, whereas a neoantigen quantity model ascribing greater immunogenicity to increasing neoantigen number alone did not. We detected intratumoural and lasting circulating T-cell reactivity to both high-quality and MUC16 neoantigens in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer, including clones with specificity to both high-quality neoantigens and predicted cross-reactive microbial epitopes, consistent with neoantigen molecular mimicry. Notably, we observed selective loss of high-quality and MUC16 neoantigenic clones on metastatic progression, suggesting neoantigen immunoediting. Our results identify neoantigens with unique qualities as T-cell targets in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. More broadly, we identify neoantigen quality as a biomarker for immunogenic tumours that may guide the application of immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24462&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24462&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/HW2E_H4heFY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Vinod P. Balachandran</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inflammation-induced IgA+ cells dismantle anti-liver cancer immunity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/6sK2Bc0IpX0/nature24302"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24302</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The role of adaptive immunity in early cancer development is controversial. Here we show that chronic inflammation and fibrosis in humans and mice with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease is accompanied by accumulation of liver-resident immunoglobulin-A-producing (IgA+) cells. These cells also express programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) and interleukin-10, and directly suppress liver cytotoxic CD8+ T lymphocytes, which prevent emergence of hepatocellular carcinoma and express a limited repertoire of T-cell receptors against tumour-associated antigens. Whereas CD8+ T-cell ablation accelerates hepatocellular carcinoma, genetic or pharmacological interference with IgA+ cell generation attenuates liver carcinogenesis and induces cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-mediated regression of established hepatocellular carcinoma. These findings establish the importance of inflammation-induced suppression of cytotoxic CD8+ T-lymphocyte activation as a tumour-promoting mechanism. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24302&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24302&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/6sK2Bc0IpX0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shabnam Shalapour</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dynamics of P-type ATPase transport revealed by single-molecule FRET</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/rHJ4SHZjOWY/nature24296"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24296</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Phosphorylation-type (P-type) ATPases are ubiquitous primary transporters that pump cations across cell membranes through the formation and breakdown of a phosphoenzyme intermediate. Structural investigations suggest that the transport mechanism is defined by conformational changes in the cytoplasmic domains of the protein that are allosterically coupled to transmembrane helices so as to expose ion binding sites to alternate sides of the membrane. Here, we have used single-molecule fluorescence resonance energy transfer to directly observe conformational changes associated with the functional transitions in the Listeria monocytogenes Ca2+-ATPase (LMCA1), an orthologue of eukaryotic Ca2+-ATPases. We identify key intermediates with no known crystal structures and show that Ca2+ efflux by LMCA1 is rate-limited by phosphoenzyme formation. The transport process involves reversible steps and an irreversible step that follows release of ADP and extracellular release of Ca2+. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24296&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/rHJ4SHZjOWY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mateusz Dyla</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BCAT1 restricts αKG levels in AML stem cells leading to IDHmut-like DNA hypermethylation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/GDDi0cdk-XQ/nature24294"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24294</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The branched-chain amino acid (BCAA) pathway and high levels of BCAA transaminase 1 (BCAT1) have recently been associated with aggressiveness in several cancer entities. However, the mechanistic role of BCAT1 in this process remains largely uncertain. Here, by performing high-resolution proteomic analysis of human acute myeloid leukaemia (AML) stem-cell and non-stem-cell populations, we find the BCAA pathway enriched and BCAT1 protein and transcripts overexpressed in leukaemia stem cells. We show that BCAT1, which transfers α-amino groups from BCAAs to α-ketoglutarate (αKG), is a critical regulator of intracellular αKG homeostasis. Further to its role in the tricarboxylic acid cycle, αKG is an essential cofactor for αKG-dependent dioxygenases such as Egl-9 family hypoxia inducible factor 1 (EGLN1) and the ten-eleven translocation (TET) family of DNA demethylases. Knockdown of BCAT1 in leukaemia cells caused accumulation of αKG, leading to EGLN1-mediated HIF1α protein degradation. This resulted in a growth and survival defect and abrogated leukaemia-initiating potential. By contrast, overexpression of BCAT1 in leukaemia cells decreased intracellular αKG levels and caused DNA hypermethylation through altered TET activity. AML with high levels of BCAT1 (BCAT1high) displayed a DNA hypermethylation phenotype similar to cases carrying a mutant isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDHmut), in which TET2 is inhibited by the oncometabolite 2-hydroxyglutarate. High levels of BCAT1 strongly correlate with shorter overall survival in IDHWTTET2WT, but not IDHmut or TET2mut AML. Gene sets characteristic for IDHmut AML were enriched in samples from patients with an IDHWTTET2WTBCAT1high status. BCAT1high AML showed robust enrichment for leukaemia stem-cell signatures, and paired sample analysis showed a significant increase in BCAT1 levels upon disease relapse. In summary, by limiting intracellular αKG, BCAT1 links BCAA catabolism to HIF1α stability and regulation of the epigenomic landscape, mimicking the effects of IDH mutations. Our results suggest the BCAA–BCAT1–αKG pathway as a therapeutic target to compromise leukaemia stem-cell function in patients with IDHWTTET2WT AML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24294&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24294&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/GDDi0cdk-XQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Simon Raffel</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neurobiology: A genetic cause of age-related decline</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/2N7m_3huZ10/551179a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551179a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Genetic variation in a neuropeptide signalling pathway regulates age-related declines in health in nematode worms. This discovery points to a mechanism that influences individual differences in ageing.  See Article    p.198&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 179 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551179a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551179a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/2N7m_3huZ10&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Patrick T. McGrath</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brain technology: Neurons recorded en masse</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tRvyn1rkY5g/551172a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551172a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A silicon probe that is inserted into the mouse brain can precisely measure the activity of about 200 individual neurons simultaneously. This tool should improve our ability to study functional neuronal circuitry.  See Letter    p.232&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 172 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551172a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551172a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tRvyn1rkY5g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edward M. Callaway</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Books in brief</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ldr6NzoCcQg/551167a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551167a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 167 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551167a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551167a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ldr6NzoCcQg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew Robinson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Polar exploration: The forgotten journey</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/f51Jjfob5J8/551166a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551166a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Huw Lewis-Jones revisits a pioneering, ill-fated expedition to map the Arctic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 166 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551166a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551166a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/f51Jjfob5J8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Huw Lewis-Jones</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">NASA wants your help naming New Horizons’ next destination</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/nasa-wants-your-help-naming-new-horizons-next-destination"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/nasa-wants-your-help-naming-new-horizons-next-destination</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T19:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 NASA’s New Horizons mission team is asking the public to vote on a nickname for the spacecraft’s next destination.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mike Denison</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Let most babies eat food containing peanuts. Really.</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-peanuts-allergy-guidelines"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-peanuts-allergy-guidelines</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Pediatricians are not yet peanut-savvy when it comes to convincing parents to feed babies food containing peanuts, a new survey suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T18:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Opioid Epidemic Resource Center</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/opioid-epidemic-resource-center"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/opioid-epidemic-resource-center</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T16:46:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Free access to research, data, analyses and other resources — updated 8 November 2017</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-13T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">17 Johns Hopkins researchers resign in protest from ed board at Nature journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/17-johns-hopkins-researchers-resign-protest-ed-board-nature-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52494</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T16:02:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;More than a dozen members of the editorial board at Scientific Reports have resigned after the journal decided not to retract a 2016 paper that a researcher claims plagiarized his work. As of this morning, 19 people — mostly researchers based at Johns Hopkins — had stepped down from the board, according to Hopkins researcher […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/17-johns-hopkins-researchers-resign-protest-ed-board-nature-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;17 Johns Hopkins researchers resign in protest from ed board at Nature journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-11T18:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researchers ask to retract cancer paper five days after it’s flagged by journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/researchers-ask-retract-cancer-paper-five-days-flagged-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52480</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T13:00:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers from the University of Kansas asked to retract their paper only days after the journal issued an expression of concern related to some of the images. The retraction notice marks the close of an episode that started in June, but it doesn’t provide much closure: Figures in the paper apparently do not match primary […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/researchers-ask-retract-cancer-paper-five-days-flagged-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researchers ask to retract cancer paper five days after it’s flagged by journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-11T18:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Contrary to stereotypes, study of hedge fund managers finds psychopaths make poor investors</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/07/contrary-to-stereotypes-study-of-hedge-fund-managers-finds-psychopaths-make-poor-investors/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32141</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T10:18:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-457803795.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32157&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32157&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cindy Ord&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NEW YORK, NY - DECEMBER 18:  A view of atmosphere at the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences Official Academy Members screening of 'The Wolf Of Wall Street' at the Academy Theater at Lighthouse International on December 18, 2013 in New York City.  (Photo by Cindy Ord\/Getty Images for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1387405599&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2013 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;40&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Academy Of Motion Picture Arts And Sciences Hosts An Official Academy Members Screening Of The Wolf Of Wall Street&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The Academy Of Motion Picture Arts And Sciences Hosts An Official Academy Members Screening Of The Wolf Of Wall Street&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,2147&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/07/contrary-to-stereotypes-study-of-hedge-fund-managers-finds-psychopaths-make-poor-investors/the-academy-of-motion-picture-arts-and-sciences-hosts-an-official-academy-members-screening-of-the-wolf-of-wall-street/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a psychopath who’s good with numbers, you could make the perfect hedge fund manager. Your lack of empathy will allow you to capitalise blithely on the financial losses of others, while your ability to stomach high-risk, but potentially high-return, options will send your fund value soaring…. Well, that’s the story that’s been painted by popular media, folk wisdom and Wall Street insiders alike. The problem, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0146167217733080&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/i&gt;, is that hedge fund managers with psychopathic tendencies actually make &lt;i&gt;less&lt;/i&gt; money for their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32141&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dacher Keltner at the University of California, Berkeley, and his colleagues analysed videos of semi-structured interviews with 101 hedge fund managers, whose firms each managed between US$40 million and US$1 trillion in assets. This money generally came from institutional investors, such as insurance companies and public and private pension funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos had been recorded between 2005 and 2015 by an investment advisory firm, to act as a marketing tool, and to give existing clients market updates. They followed a set format with the interviewer asking questions like, “What is your outlook on opportunities in the current market?” and “What is your philosophy on risk management?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers were looking for non-verbal evidence in the hedge fund managers’ replies of the so-called Dark Triad personality traits of narcissism, Machiavellianism and psychopathy. Erratic emotional expression, for example, was taken as a signal of psychopathy. A dominant positioning of the jaw and posture were among the signals of Machiavellianism. Flashy clothes, coy looks, and excessive use of “I” rather than “We”, were among the indicators of narcissism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keltner and his colleagues also analysed the financial performance of each manager’s so-called “flagship fund” – usually the largest fund offered by the company, and the one considered to most reflect the individual manager’s investment process – during the ten-year period that the videos were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machiavellianism had no bearing on performance. Narcissistic hedge fund managers had to make riskier decisions to make the same returns over a given period compared with a less narcissistic manager; as far as an investor is concerned, this would manifest as greater volatility in the value of their investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to psychopathic tendencies, however, the results were more clear cut. For managers who displayed psychopathic tendencies at a level of one standard deviation above the mean, an investment of US$1 million earned US$1,161,694 (15 per cent) &lt;i&gt;less&lt;/i&gt; over the course of ten years, on average, compared with a manager who ranked average for psychopathy. More extreme psychopathy led to even weaker returns. For example, the same US$1 million investment by a manager who rated two standard deviations above the mean for psychopathy earned 30 per cent less, on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that the Dark Triad traits have been investigated in the context of hedge fund performance, and unfortunately the study doesn’t reveal the reasons for the counterintuitive results. It may be that, while the individual managers led the hedge funds, innovative ideas from team members are important for effective financial investing – and the more bullying style of managers with more psychopathic traits could have stifled this kind of creative, collaborative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the findings suggest that investors would be wise to avoid managers with psychopathic and narcissistic tendencies, there are some limitations to be mindful of. The financial data were from a period that included the Global Financial Crisis and the researchers can’t rule out the possibility that Dark Triad traits may be advantageous in other, less financially disastrous, contexts. Also the non-verbal coding procedure – although it’s a valid measure according to earlier research – provides only a rather coarse indication of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that the results tally with another &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797615611922&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; (on which Dacher Keltner was also a co-author), that found US senators with psychopathic tendencies received less support for bills they had proposed. “These two studies, clear examples of real-world performance, cast doubts upon the efficacy of a Dark Triad-based approach to wielding power,” Keltner and his team concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0146167217733080&quot;&gt;Hedge Fund Managers With Psychopathic Tendencies Make for Worse Investors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Photo by Cindy Ord/Getty Images for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32141/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32141/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32141&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pirate paper website Sci-Hub dealt another blow by US courts</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yvjU6ZDjMjM/nature.2017.22971"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22971</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;American Chemical Society wins lawsuit against the site, and could seek to block access to the portal in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22971&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22971&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yvjU6ZDjMjM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quirin Schiermeier</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Predicting Suicide: Return of a Scandal (Part 1)</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9228"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9228</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T20:19:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 I recently decided to revisit a 2014 case that regular readers might remember.



Back in 2014, I posted about a terrible piece of statistical 'spin' that somehow made it into the peer-reviewed Journal of Psychiatric Research. The offending authors, led by Swedish psychiatrist Lars H. Thorell, had run a study to determine whether an electrodermal hyporeactivity test was able to predict suicide and suicidal behaviour in depressed inpatients.



Now, the standard way to evaluate the perfor</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crocs take a bite out of claims of ancient stone-tool use</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crocs-take-bite-out-claims-ancient-stone-tool-use"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crocs-take-bite-out-claims-ancient-stone-tool-use</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T20:16:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Reptiles with big bites complicate claims of Stone Age butchery.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS Channels Provide Opportunity for Discovery, Exploration and Contextual Insights</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/-tKIbmRxVKQ/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7839</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:31:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/11/flag_channels_opt2-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, the new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; joined existing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veterans Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Source Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Channels in providing distinct and cohesive scholarly homes for research communities. These innovative forums increase the visibility of curated, quality research and reliable news and commentary, bridging a gap in relevance that contributes to public misunderstanding of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Channels Program launched with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veterans Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (VDRR), and as Veterans Day in the US approaches it’s an opportunity to take a moment to relay the channels origin story, highlight the latest content and re-introduce the editors behind this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“It is imperative that scientists and consumers explore novel and innovative strategies to share research findings. Towards this end, as an editor of the PLOS Channel for Veterans Disability and Rehabilitation Research, I look forward to highlighting research aimed at helping Veterans with disability and/or chronic illness increase function and participation in daily life.”—Lisa Brenner, VDRR Channel Editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those intimately involved with the generation, use or reuse of research, channels provide a central information source for the latest developments, whether published in PLOS journals or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Beyond Traditional Journal and Editorial Boundaries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As global forums for research, news and discussion, all PLOS Channels deliver a similar contemporary layout for easy navigation and reading, developed with feedback from multiple audiences in mind: basic and clinical scientists, policymakers, science journalists, educators, students and patients. The Featured Research section pulls from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0179912&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and other &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jcm.asm.org/content/55/10/3057&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; article &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openhardware.metajnl.com/articles/10.5334/joh.4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A Related Content section contains news, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dspo.mil/Conference/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;occasional events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and journal commentary that speak &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/indias-ambitious-new-plan-to-conquer-tb-needs-cash-and-commitment-84821&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;directly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and with integrity to the channel topic. Although not peer reviewed, web articles and commentary in the Related Content section are selected by channel editors for the reliability of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/13/health/tuberculosis-treatment-drugs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, relevance to the topic and when possible, to provide broad perspective on global issues from local journalists. PLOS hopes the mix of quality peer-reviewed research and exploratory journalistic content will help bridge current knowledge and communication gaps between scientists and the lay public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel editors, selected either from existing PLOS Editorial Board members or recruited together with the channel focus, are an integral component of any given channel. Their expertise and ability to bring in supplementary material through commentary, blogs, news and more helps research communities and the public stay up to date with the latest advances, research trends and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/08/23/world/middleeast/yemen-cholera-humanitarian-crisis.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;societal impact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of work in the field of focus. To highlight their foundational work and dedication to this innovative effort in science communication, these editors are profiled at the bottom of the respective channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stories of Channel Origins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels originate either from community demand or engaged editors or partners. VDRR provides a new home for the community formerly served by the Journal of Rehabilitation Research &amp;amp; Development (JRRD), no longer published by the US Department of Veterans Affairs. VDRR offers international researchers and practitioners a dedicated online space to share and read state-of-the-art research, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=2914&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and resources to assist Veterans with chronic illness and disabilities worldwide. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/the-veteran-disability-rehabilitation-research-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the four editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Channels and Collections blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; exemplify the academic strength, community knowledge and dedication to science and medicine this position provides for each channel. The channel was proposed by Dr. Soumya Swaminathan during her tenure as Secretary, Department of Health Research, Ministry of Health &amp;amp; Family Welfare, Government of India, and Director General of the Indian Council of Medical Research. In October, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/icmr-chief-soumya-swaminathan-appointed-who-deputy-director-general/article19792489.ece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Swaminathan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was appointed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/dg/leadership-team/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Deputy Director-General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the World Health Organization in Geneva, the second-highest position at the health agency. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/plos-tuberculosis-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet both TB Channel editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born as the PLOS Open Source Toolkit: Hardware Collection, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Source Toolkit Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; builds on the success of the Collection and now includes peer-reviewed and web articles addressing software and its &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appropedia.org/Open-source_mobile_water_quality_testing_platform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The dedication of this community to all aspects of open source in advancing science and medicine was a determining factor in transitioning this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to a PLOS Channel. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/the-open-source-toolkit-meet-the-channel-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the two editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recently launched Cholera Channel was proposed by Dr. Andrew Azman, Deputy Editor of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; he is joined as a channel editor by international experts in global health and infectious disease. Those engaged in the fight against cholera include academics, healthcare workers, policymakers, patients and civil society—all sharing a vision that collective action can stop cholera transmission and end cholera deaths through strengthened international collaboration and improved coordination. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2017/10/12/plos-cholera-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the four editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Speaking of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Supporting this community, until now with no specialist journal or centralized publication venue for their work, is key to PLOS Channels’ mission to serve as resources for research communities.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Current Editor’s Picks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Channel showcases an Editor’s Pick, updated regularly, to bring the latest research front and center to readers. On the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VDRR Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the latest Editor’s Pick covers a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185613&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study for early screening of Parkinson’s disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; using voicing tasks and text-dependent speech options, published in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focus on research that demonstrates an &lt;em&gt;in vitro &lt;/em&gt;diagnostic test commonly used to accurately detect &lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; complex and rifampin resistance in high-incidence TB settings &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0186139&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;performs comparably&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in low TB-incidence settings. Editors of the Open Source Toolkit Channel chose to feature a &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt; Community Page describing a tool for ethomics, the high-throughput approach to behavioral studies. “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.2003026&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethoscopes: An open platform for high-throughput ethomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” originated as a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/08/05/113647.article-info&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprint on bioRxiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and describes open source software and hardware solutions for monitoring animal behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; highlights “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0183100&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Identification of burden hotspots and risk factors for cholera in India: An observational study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” describing disease hotspots and risk factors for transmission. Using district-level data from the Integrated Disease Surveillance Program, the authors offer their open research results to policymakers for development of a cholera prevention and control roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From epidemiological studies using existing census data to translational research and innovations for behavioral studies of experimental model organisms, these diverse choices highlight channel editors’ broad perspective in curating content of interest for their scholarly communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Focus on Cholera: PLOS’ Newest Channel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While universal access to safe water and appropriate sanitation is the key to cholera prevention, global progress towards these goals has been slow. The disease remains a global public health threat, with ongoing risk factors that include poor sanitation, lack of enough clean drinking water and poverty. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; features articles on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185041&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;applied&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006838&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;basic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;research related to the global fight against this disease and spans a range of topics with application to cholera prevention and control, including computational studies exploring the dynamics and spread of cholera; epidemiologic studies and translational science. Also covered is applied field research on the efficacy, effectiveness and impact of cholera control programs such as water and sanitation interventions and oral cholera vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS aspires to put &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/04/where-next-for-plos-working-together-to-make-waves-in-scientific-communication/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;researchers back at the center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of science communication, working in the best interests of all stakeholders—for the benefit of science and the public. Innovations such as the Channels Program, with collaboration from like-minded organizations, push the boundaries of scientific publishing beyond traditional journal, publisher and editorial constraints. Additional channels are currently in planning; bookmark &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://channels.plos.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or your Channel of interest and check back every two weeks for the latest research, news and developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/-tKIbmRxVKQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Senior NOAA appointee calls for retraction of paper on illegal fishing</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/senior-noaa-appointee-calls-retraction-paper-illegal-fishing/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52472</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:00:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A top US official at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who was recently appointed by President Donald Trump, has called for the retraction of a paper that suggests the country exports a significant amount of illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing. The paper, published July 6 in Marine Policy, estimated that in 2015 approximately one-fifth […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/senior-noaa-appointee-calls-retraction-paper-illegal-fishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Senior NOAA appointee calls for retraction of paper on illegal fishing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-11T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A sandy core may have kept Enceladus’ ocean warm</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enceladus-core-water-ocean-saturn"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enceladus-core-water-ocean-saturn</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Friction in Enceladus’ porous core could help heat its ocean enough to keep it liquid for billions of years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-14T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are early interventions effective?</title>
		<link href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/06/are-early-interventions-effective/"/>
		<id>http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=552</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T14:55:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Early years interventions can seem a particularly powerful way to forestall developmental difficulties. The wide-ranging evidence that early cognitive and behavioural difficulties can predict lifelong outcomes&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn1&quot; name=&quot;_ednref1&quot;&gt;[i]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn2&quot; name=&quot;_ednref2&quot;&gt;[ii]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes it seem obvious that if a child is struggling, intervening earlier is better. This has led to considerable interest in intervening within the first few years of a child’s life, and the temptation to seek out earlier indicators of children’s cognitive development and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;However, there are several challenges with choosing effective early interventions. First, reliably identifying which children will require support is a substantial challenge. This is particularly evident in the case of language development. Children’s language is a rich area for research on early intervention, for several reasons: it provides a window onto learning at school entry, and weak language at school entry is a risk factor for poor educational, social and emotional outcomes in subsequent years. There is also a clear socio-economic gradient in children’s language abilities, in which children from lower socio-economic backgrounds tend to have weaker language skills than their peers before they start school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;blog_image2&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-587 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;587&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;blog_image2&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195?w=324&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;324,251&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/06/are-early-interventions-effective/blog_image2/&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195&quot; width=&quot;252&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(But is the story really so simple?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Despite this, children’s language abilities are highly variable and volatile before they are 4-5 years old, which makes the early identification of children who may be in need of intervention non-trivial. This is demonstrated by several studies showing that whilst children’s early vocabulary around 2 years of age &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; predict their later vocabulary and reading skills at school entry, this predictive power is very small. Only about 10-20%&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn3&quot; name=&quot;_ednref3&quot;&gt;[iii]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn4&quot; name=&quot;_ednref4&quot;&gt;[iv]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of the variation in children’s abilities at school is typically predicted by their early language skills, which indicates that there are multiple other factors that shape children’s outcomes. This also suggests that finding a sufficiently sensitive marker of early difficulties is challenging because of how much a child’s abilities can shift and develop over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;This relates to the second challenge: early interventions can struggle to have sustained impacts unless intervention is ongoing. A good example of this comes from a recent study by McGillion and colleagues (2017). The researchers were interested in whether a caregiver intervention to promote talking with their 11-month old child would lead to changes in both parenting approach and children’s language development. Caregivers from a range of socio-economic backgrounds were randomly assigned to one of two conditions: watching a short video about talking with their child, or a control video about dental hygiene. One month later the caregivers in the language video condition talked more with their children than those in the control video condition. This fed into vocabulary improvement in the low socio-economic group: children in the intervention condition had higher vocabularies at 15 and 18 months compared to children in the control condition. However, at 24 months these benefits had disappeared, and there was no effect of the intervention on children’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;These findings demonstrate several important points about early interventions. Interventions &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; have a positive impact: in this case a brief, low-intensity video intervention was able to positively change caregiver behaviour, and this may have helped gains in children’s vocabulary a few months later. However, these effects were not sustained over time: they had faded by the time children were 2 years old. This shows how critical longer-term follow-ups are in intervention studies to understand whether benefits are long lasting. Moreover, this result reminds us that without ongoing support it is difficult for early gains in one area of cognition to offset other challenges children might face. The promise of early interventions means there can be an assumption that they will permanently shift a child’s trajectory. In reality this is often not the case, and initial gains may often require ongoing support to have real long-term effects for children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;It is important to therefore strike a balance between the promises and limitations of early interventions. Whilst endeavouring to find the right areas to target is undoubtedly valuable, the challenge of finding reliable indicators of difficulties early in a child’s life might mean searching for stable predictors at later ages (e.g. from school entry) may be a more fruitful approach&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn5&quot; name=&quot;_ednref5&quot;&gt;[v]&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, long-term follow-ups to interventions may be key to understanding the extent to which they are effective. The challenge of early interventions is that development is complex and shaped by multiple factors. Working within these constraints may help us better identify and help children in need of ongoing support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt; This newest article was contributed by our beloved lab member Erin Hawkins. Erin’s research focuses on understanding the mechanisms and interventions of developmental difficulties in children.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;[i] Caspi et al. (2016). Childhood forecast of a small segment of the population with large economic burden. &lt;em&gt;Nature Human Behaviour, &lt;/em&gt;doi:10.1038/s41562-016-0005&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref2&quot; name=&quot;_edn2&quot;&gt;[ii]&lt;/a&gt; The Allen Report (2011). Early Intervention: The Next Steps. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/284086/early-intervention-next-steps2.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/284086/early-intervention-next-steps2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref3&quot; name=&quot;_edn3&quot;&gt;[iii]&lt;/a&gt; Duff, Reen, Plunkett, &amp;amp; Nation (2015). Do infant vocabulary skills predict school-age language and literacy outcomes? &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, &lt;/em&gt;doi:10.1111/jcpp.12378.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref4&quot; name=&quot;_edn4&quot;&gt;[iv]&lt;/a&gt; McGillion, Pine, Herbert &amp;amp; Matthews. (2017). A randomised controlled trial to test the effect of promoting caregiver contingent talk on language development in infants from diverse socioeconomic status backgrounds. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1111/jcpp.12725&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref5&quot; name=&quot;_edn5&quot;&gt;[v]&lt;/a&gt; Norbury, C. (2015). Editorial: Early intervention in response to language delays – is there a danger of putting too many eggs in the wrong basket? &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1111/jcpp.12446&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For further reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Succinct reviews of the evidence and cost effectiveness of different kinds of early years interventions, by the Education Endowment Foundation: &lt;a href=&quot;https://educationendowmentfoundation.org.uk/evidence-summaries/early-years-toolkit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://educationendowmentfoundation.org.uk/evidence-summaries/early-years-toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Early Intervention Foundation has practical reports on the effectiveness of various interventions: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eif.org.uk/publication/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.eif.org.uk/publication/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This report provides a case study of the ‘London effect’ in attainment gaps: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/321969/London_Schools_-_FINAL.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/321969/London_Schools_-_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/552/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/552/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=552&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>mengyaz</name>
			<uri>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T16:01:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The deactivation effect: What 15 minutes device-free solitude does to your emotions</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/06/the-deactivation-effect-what-15-minutes-device-free-solitude-does-to-your-emotions/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32021</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T13:56:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-493659014.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32132&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32132&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter on the beach at sunset&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;AntonioGuillem&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/06/the-deactivation-effect-what-15-minutes-device-free-solitude-does-to-your-emotions/lonely-woman-watching-sunset-alone-in-winter/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology research has tended to portray solitude as an unpleasant experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ac.els-cdn.com/027322979090008R/1-s2.0-027322979090008R-main.pdf?_tid=37436a9e-c2f8-11e7-890f-00000aacb35d&amp;amp;acdnat=1509975879_39d803157dfe7b76706a2d52e725d31e&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-6494.1978.tb00191.x/abstract&quot;&gt;conducted&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s and 1990s suggested a clear pattern: people usually felt less happy when alone as compared with having company. More recently, researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/03/is-it-the-darkness-within-some-people-would-rather-shock-themselves-with-electricity-than-spend-time-with-their-own-thoughts/&quot;&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; that their volunteers preferred to give themselves mild electric shocks than sit in silence with their own thoughts. However, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0146167217733073&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;, a research team led by They-vy Nguyen at the University of Rochester explains the shortcomings in this earlier research and presents a more nuanced picture, showing how 15 minutes solitude can have beneficial effects on our emotions. Their results suggest that if you want to lower the intensity of your emotions, positive and negative, time spent alone may be just the ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32021&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research from the 70s and 90s measured emotion on a scale from positive to negative, overlooking the possibility that our positive and negative emotions can fluctuate independently, and that both positive and negative emotions can be either high arousal (such as excitement or anger) or low arousal (such as calmness and loneliness). Meanwhile, the electric shock research involved volunteers being instructed that they must actively think, which may have been aversive as compared with simply being in solitude without more specific instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their new paper, Nguyen’s team first asked 75 student participants to spend 15 minutes sitting alone in a comfortable chair at the psych lab, away from their digital devices and without engaging in any activity. For comparison, 39 other students spent the same time chatting with a research assistant. Before and after this 15 minute period, all the students completed a questionnaire measuring their “high arousal” positive and negative emotions (examples being excited, interested, scared, distressed). The results were clear: the participants in the solitude condition, but not the comparison group, showed reductions in their positive and negative emotions – what the researchers described as a “deactivation effect”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A follow-up study with more students found the same deactivating effect of 15 minutes of solitude on high arousal emotions, but also added in a measure of low-arousal positive and negative emotions (such as calm, relaxed, sad, lonely) and found that these were increased by time alone. It seems solitude doesn’t have a simple emotional effect that can be caricatured as good or bad; rather, it changes the intensity of our inner experience, both positive and negative: accentuating low-key emotions, while dialling down our stronger feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same pattern was found for a comparison group who spent the time alone reading a moderately interesting article rather than in their own thoughts, suggesting that complete mental disengagement from an external task is not necessary for solitude to have its emotional effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you think about when you’re alone surely has some bearing on the emotional effects of solitude: the researchers investigated this in another study, as well as looking into whether it matters whether you choose the tone of your thoughts or follow someone else’s instructions. Choosing the content of one’s own thoughts, rather than following instructions, was preferable in terms of reducing high arousal negative emotions and boosting low arousal positive ones. However, it’s also true that time alone with positive thoughts – whether by choice or through following instructions – was advantageous, as compared with having neutral thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the researchers asked 157 students to keep an evening diary for two weeks to track their emotions. Half the students were instructed to spend 15 minutes in device-free solitude daily during the first week; the other half of the students did this in the second week. Again, the de-activation effect was observed: the week that the students spent time in solitude, they tended to show reduced high arousal positive and negative emotions. There was also an apparent deactivation spill-over into the second week for those who completed the solitude exercises in the first week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth clarifying that these findings pertain to relatively brief moments of solitude as distinct from prolonged loneliness, which is known to be associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/11/12/loneliness-is-a-disease-that-changes-the-brains-structure-and-function/&quot;&gt;a host of unwelcome physical and psychological effects&lt;/a&gt;. Also, bear in mind the current findings could vary across cultures and with older volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nguyen and her colleagues said more research needs to be done, but that the “take-home message is that there are benefits and detriments of solitude.” They added their studies suggest “that people can use solitude, or other variations on being alone, to regulate their affective states, becoming quiet after excitement, calm after an angry episode, or centred and peaceful when desired.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new results may also be seen as a complement to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/05/researchers-say-dont-worry-what-other-people-think-going-out-on-your-own-can-be-fun/&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published two years ago that made the case that people generally enjoy going out on their own in public more than they think they will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0146167217733073&quot;&gt;Solitude as an Approach to Affective Self-Regulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32021/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32021/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32021&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-15T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
