<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:35+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Carlo Croce, Ohio State researcher facing misconduct allegations, suing New York Times for defamation</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/carlo-croce-ohio-state-researcher-facing-misconduct-allegations-suing-new-york-times-defamation/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51737</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T22:39:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Carlo Croce, a cancer researcher at The Ohio State University who has faced numerous allegations of research misconduct, has filed a lawsuit against the New York Times, claiming the newspaper defamed him in a March 8 story. Croce filed the civil suit May 10, in the US District Court for the Southern District of Ohio, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/carlo-croce-ohio-state-researcher-facing-misconduct-allegations-suing-new-york-times-defamation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, Ohio State researcher facing misconduct allegations, suing New York Times for defamation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sugars in breast milk may fight harmful bacteria directly</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/sugars-breast-milk-may-fight-harmful-bacteria-directly"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/sugars-breast-milk-may-fight-harmful-bacteria-directly</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T20:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A small study finds that the sugars present in some women’s breast milk may fight potentially harmful bacteria.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author who previously claimed plagiarism was a mistake earns new erratum</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/author-previously-claimed-plagiarism-mistake-earns-new-erratum/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51703</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T15:18:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A biotechnology journal has corrected a 2006 paper after discovering duplication and plagiarism. This offense is the second we know of for the corresponding author, Uttam Chand Banerjee, in the same journal, Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology. Last year, Banerjee—who works at National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) in Mohali, Punjab, India—had a 14-year-old review […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/author-previously-claimed-plagiarism-mistake-earns-new-erratum/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author who previously claimed plagiarism was a mistake earns new erratum&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Air pollution takes a toll on solar energy</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/air-pollution-takes-toll-solar-energy"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/air-pollution-takes-toll-solar-energy</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Dust and other tiny air pollutants can reduce solar energy output by as much as 25 percent in parts of the world.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Behind the Image: bad day for a bumblebee</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/behind-image-bad-day-bumblebee/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9381</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T12:11:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9424&quot; height=&quot;3505&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;5258&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your profession?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a researcher at the Ethology unit, University of Valencia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What type of research are you involved in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research line combines experimental and phylogenetic approaches and encompasses both ecological and evolutionary studies focused on investigating those traits employed by animals to engage in social and sexual interactions and their role in lineages diversification and species adaptations. Specifically, I am currently investigating at the University of Valencia (at Pau Carazo´s Lab) the mechanisms inherent to sexual conflict and the ecological factors that modulate this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you become interested in this area of research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been interested in the process and mechanism underlying animal ecology and evolution and thus, my way has moved forward progressively, building this interesting framework of study in which I am involved in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you become interested in photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life cannot be understood without animals and hence, the best way to “capture” them and wear them always with you is with photography. They will be with you in photography forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where and how was this photo taken? Why were you there at the time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken while I was walking with my dog in Valencia. I often observe snails, grasshoppers, lizards, and that time I could see that special interaction among three animals. I went to my house to take the camera and took several photos of what was happening in this interesting interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you explain a bit more about the image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In field work, you often see, with luck and effort, spiders hunting or even eating their prey. However, this case was special because a third protagonist appeared in the scene. This small fly was parasitizing the bee while it was being eaten by the spider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about this scene particularly interested you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this scene reflects life from 3 different perspectives and show how complex are animal interactions. It shows mimicry with the crab spider, it shows the dangers underlying pollination for bees, it shows three different positions on the trophic web (predators, prey and parasites) and finally, the image highlights how connected are many animals in a dynamic in which the loss of some of them in a hypothetical region could trigger crucial consequences for other species in that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/behind-image-bad-day-bumblebee/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Behind the Image: bad day for a bumblebee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Francesca Martin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“We would now catch” this conflict of interest: Hindawi journal retracts two papers</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/now-catch-conflict-interest-hindawi-journal-retracts-two-papers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51656</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T12:00:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A computer science journal has retracted two papers, after discovering “a conflict of interest between the handling editor and one of the authors.” Matt Hodgkinson, head of research integrity at Hindawi Limited, which publishes the journal Scientific World Journal, told us that the conflict of interest stemmed from the fact that Zheng Xu, an author […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/now-catch-conflict-interest-hindawi-journal-retracts-two-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“We would now catch” this conflict of interest: Hindawi journal retracts two papers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Debates on whether science is broken don’t fit in tweets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/debates-whether-science-broken-dont-fit-tweets"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/debates-whether-science-broken-dont-fit-tweets</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Amid debates over whether science is broken, many experts are proposing repairs.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Can technology help global suicide prevention?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/can-technology-help-global-suicide-prevention/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9484</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T09:20:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/National-Suicide-Prevention-Jared-Keener-Flickr-CC-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization estimates that over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs398/en/&quot;&gt;800,000 people die by suicide each year&lt;/a&gt; – that is one person every 40 seconds! But for every suicide, there are many more people who attempt suicide, and many individuals who are impacted by the suicide of a loved one. Suicide is not restricted by age, gender, nationality or income; it occurs throughout the lifespan and in 2015, was the second leading cause of death among 15–29-year-olds. A prior suicide attempt is the single most important risk factor for suicide in the general population, and whilst people with mental health conditions are at higher risk of suicide, many suicides occur spontaneously in response to life events or crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suicide is a serious public health concern and is preventable. In 2014, the World Health Organization published “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/mental_health/suicide-prevention/world_report_2014/en/&quot;&gt;Preventing suicide: a global imperative&lt;/a&gt;”, it’s first global report to increase awareness of suicide and suicide attempts, and to make suicide prevention a global public health priority. Suicide is a complex issue and therefore effective suicide prevention efforts require multiple constituents. One critical component to suicide prevention is the early identification of those in need, to ensure that they receive appropriate care and support; this is where the social support provided by communities and loved ones can be so vital to a vulnerable individual seeking mental health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to appropriate mental health care, when and where it is needed, is vital for the prevention of suicide. In some countries mental health care may be harder to access due to geographical or financial restraints. However, even in countries where access to care is ready available many who experience suicidal ideation do not seek help. A number of barriers may prevent those experiencing suicidal ideation from seeking treatment; suicide and mental illness are still heavily stigmatized in many communities, and some groups of the general population are less likely to seek help than others, including young people and men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9486&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9486&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Dropbox-Johan-Larsson-Flickt-CC-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Johan Larsson, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing global reliance on technology allows for opportunities to improve mental health care provision; the potential for those who cannot, or choose not to, access traditional ‘face-to-face’ healthcare to be reached by digital methods is possible. To date, this has taken many forms – from doctor-patient consultations via video calling, to the development of sophisticated online and mobile telephone applications. Research examining the effectiveness of digital or eHealth interventions for both preventative treatment and follow-up care is rapidly expanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A  systematic review and meta-analysis, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://monash.edu/research/explore/en/persons/katrina-witt%289a5e2239-c431-43cb-aa45-cb74096b4056%29.html&quot;&gt;Katrina Witt&lt;/a&gt; and colleagues from Monash University, Australia, examined the effectiveness of digital interventions for the self-management of suicidal ideation or self-harm. The researchers analyzed data from 14 published studies including a total of 3,356 participants. Most of the studies included evaluated online interventions, but two examined mobile phone applications that were designed for people suffering from depression/suicidal-ideation to self-manage their symptoms. The researchers found that despite limitations with many of the published studies design, there is some evidence that digital interventions may be associated with reductions in suicidal ideation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another systematic review and meta-analysis, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.unsw.edu.au/people/mr-mark-deady&quot;&gt;Mark Deady&lt;/a&gt; and colleagues from the University of New South Wales and the Black Dog Institute (Australia), &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1473-1&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, evaluated the effectiveness of eHealth interventions for the prevention of depression and anxiety. The researchers analyzed data from 10 published randomized controlled trials, including a total of 4,522 participants. The studies included evaluated online and mobile phone applications, but also other intervention methods such as those using email and/or text messaging to provide support. The review suggests that a range of eHealth intervention programs produce small, but positive, effects on symptom reduction for anxiety and depression in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both of these reviews the intervention programs were developed by psychologists/psychiatrists using aspects of cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), and were found to be beneficial compared with control conditions. However, it should be emphasized that in all studies there is lack of long-term follow up data, and it is therefore unclear whether these interventions may translate to reduced suicide attempts, depression and anxiety in the longer term. The small numbers of studies in both reviews indicate the continuing need to rigorously evaluate the effectiveness of eHealth interventions; despite the ever increase number of digital programs and apps available that are designed to improve and promote mental wellbeing, a clear distinction needs to be made between those designed with a basis in evidence based medicine, such as the studies analyzed here, and those that are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eHealth and digital interventions have the potential to reach more people with fewer resources than face-to face care, and may be useful in breaking down some of the current barriers that prevent those in need from accessing mental health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9488 size-full aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;141&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/2017_wspd_banner_english.png&quot; width=&quot;701&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find out more about suicide prevention please see &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry’s&lt;/em&gt; dedicated section ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/sections/causes-treatment-and-prevention-of-suicide&quot;&gt;Causes, treatment and prevention of suicide&lt;/a&gt;‘.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/can-technology-help-global-suicide-prevention/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can technology help global suicide prevention?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anna Clark</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Learning more about yourself could help you better understand others</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29764</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T08:57:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29767&quot; style=&quot;width: 1624px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-501651483.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29767&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29767&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A woman is looking into the mirror asking herself \&amp;quot;Who am I?\&amp;quot;. In her face there is a big question mark to bring ones consciousness into question. Vector illustration.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PeterHermesFurian&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mirror Who Am I Woman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mirror Who Am I Woman&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845?w=264&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1624,1846&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/mirror-who-am-i-woman-3/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The intervention used in this research was based on the Internal Family Systems model that sees an individual’s personality as made up of different sub-personalities&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariannecezza.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Marianne Cezza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As social creatures, accurately recognising and understanding the mental states of others (their intentions, knowledge, beliefs, etc.) is crucial to our social bonds and interactions. In fact, in today’s multi-cultural world and strongly divided political climate, this skill – known as Theory of Mind – is perhaps more important than ever. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s41465-017-0023-6&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cognitive Enhancement&lt;/i&gt; proposes that an effective way to develop our Theory of Mind lies in learning to better understand ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29764&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne Böckler and colleagues, based at the Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences in Leipzig, recruited 141 participants to take part in a three-month long contemplative training course that teaches people to take the perspective of the different aspects of their own personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before they started, the participants completed a test of their Theory of Mind: they watched short video clips of people describing autobiographical events, then answered a questionnaire about the storyteller’s intentions, thoughts and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the participants were taught to identify and label six ‘inner parts’ or sub-personalities within themselves, for example ‘the caring part’, ‘the inner happy child’, ‘the vulnerable part’. They could modify or add to this list at any time during the training course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course itself consisted of two key components that the participants practised daily for thirty minutes, and at a two-hour guided weekly training sessions. The first component was an ‘observing-thoughts’ meditation, in which participants observed their thoughts objectively,  de-identified from them (i.e. observed them in a detached way), then classified the thoughts into categories of me/other, past/future or positive/negative. The second component was a perspective-taking exercise which participants conducted in pairs, alternating between the role of speaker and listener. The speaker recounted an event from their day from the perspective of one of their randomly selected inner parts. Aware of the speaker’s various inner parts, the listener had to guess which one was talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These perspective-taking exercises and the concept of ‘inner parts’ are based on the Internal Family Systems (IFS) model; an approach used in psychotherapy. The model sees an individual’s personality as made up of different sub-personalities, each with its own set of behaviours, cognitions and affects.  The current study is part of a larger research project which draws from the model’s principles, successfully implemented in a therapeutic setting (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23950186&quot;&gt;with rheumatoid arthritis patients&lt;/a&gt;), and applies them to a non-clinical, healthy, adult population with the aim of improving mental well-being and social intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, the participants in the current study identified 11 inner parts to their personalities, of which 44 per cent were labelled by independent judges as negative traits and 56 per cent were positive traits. The researchers organised the participants’ different personality parts into related trait types according to the IFS model, the most common being: Protectors (12 per cent), Managers and Pleasure Parts (both 11 per cent), Inner Critics (9 per cent), and Vulnerable Parts (8 per cent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the training course the participants re-took the same Theory of Mind test that they’d taken at the start of the study. Improvement in Theory of Mind was correlated with the number of different inner personality parts identified – the more facets the participants were able to recognise within themselves, the better they seemed to become at understanding others. This is reflected in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2gDnXvv&quot;&gt;neuroimaging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2wCOd20&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, where the processes of perspective-taking of the self and others utilise shared neural mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the correlation between number of parts of self identified and improvement in Theory of Mind was even stronger in those who identified more negative parts. The researchers propose that this supports the theory that people are naturally resistant to looking for negative aspects of their personality, therefore those who do are thought to be working more profoundly to better understand themselves. In addition to the result of a better understanding of the mental states of others, this deeper work also improves psychological wellbeing, as it is widely acknowledged in clinical psychology that accepting negative emotions is beneficial to mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of identifying the different aspects of our personalities is to understand that through them one can view a single situation through a handful of different outlooks; we learn to see the self as multifaceted and can detach and de-identify from one sole personal perspective. Consequently, we’ll also be more open to the different points of view of others, and less likely to assume that a person’s perspective remains consistent across different life situations. It’s likely this increased interpersonal understanding will in turn encourage greater respect and compassion for others, facilitate communication and reduce the ostracism and stigmatisation of groups with alternative outlooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems a little soul searching is required to better understand the people around us. Why not have a go at reflecting on your own psyche, and see what you can recognise in others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s41465-017-0023-6&quot;&gt;Know Thy Selves: Learning to Understand Oneself Increases the Ability to Understand Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-29769&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29769&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=380&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=112&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;380,508&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=112&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;112&quot; /&gt;Written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariannecezza.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Marianne Cezza&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@maricezza&quot;&gt;@maricezza&lt;/a&gt;) for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Marianne studied psychology at the University of York, where she was editor of the psychology department’s magazine. She now works as a freelance writer and blogger specialising in psychology, neuroscience and mental well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29764/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29764/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29764&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">Tip for new PIs : always do administrative work at the last minute, or later</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/tip-for-new-pis-always-do-administrative-work-at-the-last-minute-or-later/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1446</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T07:19:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;This is a tip that has taken me years to really grasp, and I still haven't fully internalized it. I don't like to work at the last minute. If I have something to do and I don't do it, then it stays in the back of my mind until I do it. So, especially if it's some boring task like administrative work, I like to get rid of it as soon as possible. That's a mistake. I'm speaking of my experience in France, so maybe it doesn't apply so much elsewhere. The reason it's a mistake is that what you are required to do changes all the time, so the latest you do it, the least work you will have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every new politician seems to want to add a new layer of bureaucracy, independently of their political origin, so the amount of administrative work you are required to do as a scientist keeps growing, and it doesn't seem to converge. But setting up new rules and reglementations in a complex bureaucratic monster is not easy, so the monster often outputs nonsensical forms and requirements. One example in France is the evaluation of labs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hceres.fr/&quot;&gt;HCERES&lt;/a&gt;), whose role is unclear and changing. The amount of redundancy and the absurdity of some requirements is abysmal. For example, you are required to fill a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SWOT_analysis&quot;&gt;SWOT diagram&lt;/a&gt;, to select and list 20 % of all your « outputs », but also to list each one of them in another form, etc. Because many of the requirements are vague and nonsensical, any organization that deals with them will take some time to converge to a clear set of rules issued to the labs. I have written my evaluation document about 4 times because of the changing instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another recent example is the new evaluation system set up by INSERM (national medical research institution). Someone there (external consulting company ?) apparently decided that having an online CV with fields to fill instead of uploading a text would be more convenient. So for example you have to insert, one by one in web forms, the list of all journals for which you have reviewed in your entire career, and how many papers you have reviewed for each of them. You need to insert the list of all students you have supervised in you entire carrier, with names and exact dates, etc, all one by one in separate fields. Imagine that for senior PIs. Guess what : one week before deadline, the requirement of filling that CV was lifted for most scientists because of many complaints (a bit too late for most of them, including me). About a quarter of them still have to, but the message says that the format of the CV will change next year since it was not good, so all the work will basically be for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is my conclusion and tip : bureaucracy is nonsense and don't assume otherwise ; just set yourself some time on the deadline to do the required work, whatever it might become at that time (and it might disappear).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>romain</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T11:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">South Korean researchers lobby government to lift human-embryo restrictions</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0-4Doaca2_M/nature.2017.22585"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22585</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Regulations are deterring research that could lead to disease treatments, say scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22585&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22585&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0-4Doaca2_M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Zastrow</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers respond to Nature’s Editorial on historical monuments</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y7b_MW2XJgQ/nature.2017.22584"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22584</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22584&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22584&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y7b_MW2XJgQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Geneticists pan paper that claims to predict a person's face from their DNA</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/DLKxNScNA_s/nature.2017.22580"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22580</id>
		<updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Reviewers and a co-author of a paper by genomics entrepreneur Craig Venter claim that it misrepresents the risks of public access to genome data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22580&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22580&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/DLKxNScNA_s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sara Reardon</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pluto’s pits, ridges and famous plain get official names</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/pluto-pits-ridges-plain-get-official-names"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/pluto-pits-ridges-plain-get-official-names</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T22:05:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 From Adlivun to Voyager, the International Astronomical Union officially names 14 surface features on the dwarf planet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When a fungus invades the lungs, immune cells can tell it to self-destruct</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-fungus-invades-lungs-immune-cells-can-tell-it-self-destruct"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-fungus-invades-lungs-immune-cells-can-tell-it-self-destruct</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T21:01:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Immune system resists fungal infection by directing spores to their death.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brain chemical lost in Parkinson’s may contribute to its own demise</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-chemical-lost-parkinsons-may-contribute-its-own-demise"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-chemical-lost-parkinsons-may-contribute-its-own-demise</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T18:12:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A dangerous form of the chemical messenger dopamine causes cellular mayhem in the very nerve cells that make it.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why bats crash into windows</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/why-bats-crash-windows"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/why-bats-crash-windows</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Smooth, vertical surfaces may be blind spots for bats and cause some animals to face-plant, study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">UCSF, VA investigations find “clear evidence” of misconduct in cancer papers</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/ucsf-va-investigations-find-clear-evidence-misconduct-cancer-papers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51707</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T15:00:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the University of California, San Francisco and the San Francisco Veterans Administration Medical Center teamed up to write a letter. Addressed to the editorial office at the American Association of Cancer Research (AACR), the letter, parts of which have been published in a retraction notice, contained information concerning two papers on genetic […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/ucsf-va-investigations-find-clear-evidence-misconduct-cancer-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;UCSF, VA investigations find “clear evidence” of misconduct in cancer papers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Woolly rhinos may have grown strange extra ribs before going extinct</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/woolly-rhinos-extra-ribs-extinct"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/woolly-rhinos-extra-ribs-extinct</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ribs attached to neck bones could have signaled trouble for woolly rhinos, a new study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Dos and Don’ts of PhD supervision</title>
		<link href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/09/07/the-dos-and-donts-of-phd-supervision/"/>
		<id>http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=544</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T14:53:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Myself and Sue Fletcher-Watson (you know, the fabulously clever one…) have been putting our minds to a series of blog posts, attempting to help the fledgling academic get to grips with some of their new professional duties.  This week it is a real classic – how to supervise a PhD student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;download&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-547 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;547&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;download&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192?w=341&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;341,148&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/09/07/the-dos-and-donts-of-phd-supervision/download/&quot; height=&quot;192&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a good supervisor is not easy, and tricky relationships between students and supervisors are all too common (you may have direct experience yourself). Understanding and mutually agreeing upon the role of the student and the supervisor is a crucial starting point. Establishing these expectations is an important early step and will make navigating the PhD easier for all concerned. With a shared idea of where you are both starting from, and where you want to get to, together you can chart the path forward.  Hopefully these DOs and DON’Ts will help you get off on the right foot as a PhD supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing your intellectual contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO challenge their thinking…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good PhD supervisor should question their student’s decision making – some part of your supervision meetings should be viva-like. Why are you doing this? How does this method answer this question? What do these data mean? Make sure your student understands what you’re doing and why – be explicit that you expect them to defend their interpretation of the literature / research plans NOT adhere to yours. It is important that they don’t feel that this is a test, with just one right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When questioning your student, strike a balance between exploring alternatives, and making forward progress. Probing assumptions is important but don’t become a pedant; you need to recognise when is the time to question the fundamentals, and when is the time to move the debate on to the next decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T make decisions for them…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help students determine the next decision to be made (“&lt;em&gt;now that we have selected our measures we need to consider what analysis framework we will use&lt;/em&gt;”) and also the parameters that constrain this decision… but remember that it is not your place to make the decisions for them. Flagging the consequences of the various choices is an excellent way to bring your experience to bear, without eclipsing the student. You may wish to highlight budget constraints, discuss the likely recruitment rate, or consider the consequences of a chosen data type in terms of analysis time and required skills. Help them see how each decision feeds back. Sue recently worked with a student to move from research question, to methods, to power calculation, to ideal sample size, and then – finding that the project budget was inadequate to support the sample target – back to RQ again. It’s tough for a student to have to re-visit earlier decisions but important to consider all the relevant factors before committing to data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who’s in charge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO give them project management responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Sue and Duncan run fortnightly lab group meetings with all their students and this is highly recommended as a way to check in and ensure no student gets left hanging. But don’t make the mistake of becoming your student’s project manager. Whether you prefer frequent informal check-ins or more formal supervisions that are spaced apart, your student should be in charge of monitoring actual progress against plans, and recording decisions. For formal meetings, they can provide an agenda, attachments and minutes, assigning action points to you and other supervisors, and chasing these if needed. They should monitor the budget, and develop excellent version control and data management skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This achieves a number of different goals simultaneously. First, it gives your student a chance to learn the generic project management skills which will be essential if they continue in an academic career, and useful if they leave academia too. Second, it helps to reinforce the sense that this is &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; project, since power and responsibility go hand in hand. Finally, it means that your role in the project is as an intellectual contributor, shaping and challenging the research, rather than wasting your skills and time on bureaucratic tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T make them a lackey to serve your professional goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate students are not cheap research assistants. They are highly talented early career researchers with independent funding (in the majority of cases) that has been awarded to them on merit. They have chosen to place their graduate research project in your lab. They are not there to conduct &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; research or write &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; papers. In any case, attempting this approach is self-defeating. Students soon realise that they are being taken advantage of, especially when they chat with friends in other labs. When students become unhappy and the trust in their supervisor breaks down, the whole process can become ineffective for everyone concerned. As the supervisor you are there to help and guide their project… not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be really challenging when graduate projects are embedded within a larger funded project. How do you balance the commitment you’ve made to the funder alongside the need for students to have sufficient ownership? Firstly, think carefully about whether your project really lends itself to a graduate student. Highly specified and rigid projects need great research assistants rather than graduate students. Secondly, build in sufficient scope for individual projects and analyses, for example by collecting flexible data types (e.g. parent-child play samples) which invite novel analyses, and make sure that students are aware of any constraints before they start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are they here to learn?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO provide opportunities to learn skills which extend beyond the project goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A successful graduate project is not just measured in terms of thesis or papers, but in the professional skills acquired and whether these help them launch a career in whichever direction they choose. This will mean allowing your students to learn skills necessary for their research, but also giving them broader opportunities: formal training courses, giving and hearing talks, visiting other labs or attending conferences. This is all to be encouraged, though be careful that it happens alongside research progress, rather than as a displacement activity. Towards the end of the PhD, as the student prepares to fly the nest, these activities can be an important way of building the connections that are necessary to be part of a scientific community and make the next step in their career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T expect them to achieve technical marvels without support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All too often supervisors see exciting new analyses in papers or in talks and want to bring those skills to their lab. But remember, if you cannot teach the students to do something, then who will? Duncan still &lt;em&gt;tries&lt;/em&gt; to get his hands dirty with the code (and is humoured in this effort by his lab members), but often manages to underestimate how difficult some technical steps can be. Meanwhile, Sue is coming to terms with the fact that she will never fully understand R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you recommend new technical analyses, or development of innovative stimuli, then make sure you fully understand what you are asking of your student – allow sufficient time for this and provide appropriate support. When thinking of co-supervisors, don’t always go for the bigwig you are trying to cosy up to… often a more junior member of staff whose technical skills are up-to-date would be far more useful to your student. Also try and create a lab culture with good peer support. Just as ‘&lt;em&gt;it takes a village to raise a child’&lt;/em&gt;, so “&lt;em&gt;it takes a lab to supervise a PhD student&lt;/em&gt;”. Proper peer support mechanisms, shared problem solving and an open lab culture are important ingredients for giving students the proper support they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being reasonable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO set clear expectations             &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one of any PhD should be to create a project timeline.  Sue normally recommends a detailed 6-month plan alongside a sketched 3-year plan, both of which should be updated about quarterly. For a study which is broken down into a series of short experiments, a different model might be better. Whatever planning system you adopt, you should work with your student to set realistic deadlines for specific tasks, assuming a full time 9-5 working day and no more, and adhere to these. Model best practice by providing timely feedback at an appropriate level of detail – remember, you can give too much as well as too little feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think carefully about what sort of outputs to ask for – make them reasonable and appropriate to the task. You might want propose a lengthy piece of writing in the first six months, to demonstrate that your student has grasped the literature and can pull it together coherently to make a case for their chosen research.  But, depending on the project, it might also be a good idea to get them to contrast some differing theoretical models in a mini-presentation to your lab, create a table summarising key methodological details and findings from previous work, or publish a web page to prioritise community engagement with the project topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T forget their mental health and work-life balance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhD students might have recently moved from another country or city – they may be tackling cultural differences at work and socially. Simultaneous life changes often happen at the same time as a PhD – meeting a life partner, marriage, children. Your students might be living in rented and shared accommodation, with all the stresses that can bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your students go home at a reasonable hour.  If you must work outside office hours be clear you don’t expect the same from them. Remind them to take a holiday – especially if they have had a period of working hard (e.g. meeting a deadline, collecting data at weekends). Ensure that information about the University support services are available prominently in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to take into account their personal lives when you are discussing project progress. Being honest about your own personal situation (without over-sharing) creates an environment where it is OK to talk about stuff happening outside the office. Looking after your students’ mental health doesn’t mean being soft, or turning a blind eye to missed deadlines or poor quality work – it means being proactive and taking action when you can see things aren’t going well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about the research??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning another blog in the future about MSc and undergrad supervision which might address some other questions more closely tied to the research itself – how to design an encapsulated, realistic but also worthwhile piece of research, and how to structure this over time. But the success (or otherwise) of a PhD hangs on a lot more than just having a great idea and delivering it on time. We hope this post will help readers to reflect on their personal management style and think about how that impacts their students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, be humble. Be supportive. Be a good supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/544/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/544/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=544&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>duncanastle</name>
			<uri>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Did the author of a now-retracted article bribe a critic to silence him?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/author-now-retracted-article-bribe-critic-silence/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51449</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T12:00:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Authors react in a variety of ways to criticism of their work. Some stonewall, some grit their teeth but make corrections, and others thank their critics. But what about bribery? After an economist alerted a journal and government agency to potential problems with a 2015 paper, he says the first author tried to bribe him […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/author-now-retracted-article-bribe-critic-silence/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Did the author of a now-retracted article bribe a critic to silence him?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Megan Scudellari</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Guiding addiction treatment from the front lines</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/guiding-addiction-treatment-from-the-front-lines"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/guiding-addiction-treatment-from-the-front-lines</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T11:29:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier’s Dr. Leslie Dye on recognizing addiction — and using technology to get health professionals the information they need at the point of care</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, West Germany embraced nuclear power</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-west-germany-embraced-nuclear-power"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-west-germany-embraced-nuclear-power</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In 1967, Germany gave nuclear power a try. Today, the country is trading nukes for renewables.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Elsevier supports TOP Guidelines in ongoing efforts to ensure research quality and transparency</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-supports-top-guidelines-in-ongoing-efforts-to-ensure-research-quality-and-transparency"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-supports-top-guidelines-in-ongoing-efforts-to-ensure-research-quality-and-transparency</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T09:53:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier’s new journal data guidelines promote the exchange and integrity of scientific research</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Highlights of the BMC-series: August 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/07/highlights-bmc-series-august-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9490</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T09:43:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Family Practice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0650-0&quot;&gt;Managing diagnostic uncertainty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic uncertainty is one of the biggest predictors of diagnostic error. When coming across diagnostic uncertainty, physicians can respond in multiple ways including cognitive, emotional and ethical reactions. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0650-0&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Family Practice &lt;/em&gt;determined how primary care physicians deal with diagnostic uncertainty in cognitive, emotional, and ethical domains. These responses included behaviors such as reaching out to supportive colleagues, seeking out further training, anxiety due to diagnostic uncertainty, and whether or not to disclose diagnostic uncertainty to patients. Diagnostic uncertainty can have implications for the doctor, patient, and healthcare system in general and the authors further discuss how doctors can better manage their responses to diagnostic uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Psychiatry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;Mobile applications for suicidal ideation self-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of online and mobile telephone applications (‘apps’) have been increasingly used to treat psychological disorders, especially for populations that have limited resources and are remotely located. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, Witt and colleagues searched the exhisting literature to determine the effectivenss of apps for the self-management of suicidal ideation and self-harm. The use of apps offers some promise for reducing suicidal ideation although there did not seem to be any beneficial impact on suicide attempts or self-harm. Furthermore, the adherence to these programs was poor. The authors discuss the limitations and variability of the existing literature and argue for more well designed studies to determine whether the use of apps for suicidal ideation and self-harm can be productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Physiology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcphysiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12899-017-0033-8&quot;&gt;Androgen receptors in developing heart cells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Androgens have been shown to be involved in the sex differences in cardiovascular diseases. Androgen receptors in cardiac muscle cells called myocytes could help explain this association. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcphysiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12899-017-0033-8&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Physiology&lt;/em&gt;, the authors examined the expression of androgen receptors on cardiac myocytes while also looking at alpha and beta myosin heavy chain genes and atrial natriuretic peptide genes. The authors looked at the hearts of male and female mice prenatally and early postnatally.  Androgen receptors were found in cardiac myocytes during heart development prenatally and during heart maturation postnatally.  Androgen receptors were found primarily in the cardiac myocytes nuclei compared to surrounding cells and were found more in atria compared to ventricles postnatally. These findings indicate that androgen receptors are involved in heart development pre- and post-natally but interestingly the lack of sex difference suggests that sex differences in cardiovascular diseases may not be related to the developing heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image(s) of the month:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0138-8&quot;&gt;The winners of the 2017 &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Image competition 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the fifth year &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; held its astounding image competition.  Ecologists from all over the world submitted their photographs to showcase their research. The &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology &lt;/em&gt;editorial board, along with special guest judge Chris Darimont, had the pleasure to vote on the photographs based on the image and the story behind it. This year’s winning image was by Ana Carolina Lima who took a picture of giant South American turtles (&lt;em&gt;Podocatemias expansa&lt;/em&gt;) which was admired for its “…rare, multi-layered perspective from above”.  In contrast to the lively image of the winner, the first runner-up photograph entitled “Two Towers” pictures the stark Antarctic landscape.  Winners were selected for each section of &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; including a special Editor’s pick. Meanwhile 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; place went to the image below, entitled ‘Connections’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0138-8&quot;&gt;Read the announcement editorial&lt;/a&gt; to see all the winners, along with a number of excellent highly commended entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9424&quot; style=&quot;width: 5268px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9424&quot; height=&quot;3505&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;5258&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Second runner-up&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Roberto García-Roa &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Psychology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0198-8&quot;&gt;Methods for word learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several techniques to learn new words which can include recall, reproduction, and restudy. These techniques have been shown to be beneficial when learning written words. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0198-8&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/em&gt; by Krishnan and colleagues, which went through &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/about/results-free-peer-review-for-authors&quot;&gt;Results-free Review&lt;/a&gt; process, aimed to determine the effects of three different word learning techniques when participants are taught words that are presented to them verbally instead of in written form. Participants went through a task in which they learned pseudowords presented verbally and learned these words through a cued recall, reproduction, and restudy method of learning. It was hypothesized that cued recall practice would lead to better retention in the long term.  In contrast to the hypothesis, cued recall training did not provide better retention of newly learned words in the long term compared to the forms of learning new words. This suggests that how people learn words presented verbally differs from how they learn written words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Geriatrics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-017-0578-1&quot;&gt;Changes in physical activity in older people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than 10% of the population in the UK over 75 years of age reach the recommended amount of physical activity. Unfortunately, this information is primarily collected through subjective questionnaires thereby risking accuracy. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-017-0578-1&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Geriatrics&lt;/em&gt; the authors surveyed a population of almost 600 community dwelling people over the age of 65. Various questionnaires were used to assess health, subjective norms, coping planning and social support, anxiety, and depression.  Subjects were then fitted with an accelerometer on their waist to measure physical activity. The lack of a satisfactory social network, older age, lower self-reported physical functioning and diabetes all independently predicted lower objectively measured physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/07/highlights-bmc-series-august-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC-series: August 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ben Ragen</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How short-term increases in testosterone change men’s thinking style</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/07/how-short-term-increases-in-testosterone-change-mens-thinking-style/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29735</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T09:08:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29753&quot; style=&quot;width: 1522px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-91016858.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29753&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29753&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MaryLB&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845?w=791&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845?w=232&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1522,1970&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/07/how-short-term-increases-in-testosterone-change-mens-thinking-style/retro-profile-of-a-man-with-gears-in-brain-ii/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Competitive situations or the presence of attractive potential mates can lead to the short-term testosterone increases that were the focus of the new research&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hot-headed “macho man”, who acts first and thinks later, has long been popular in movies.  Now there’s psychological evidence to support it. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617709592&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/i&gt; finds that a short-term rise in testosterone – as might occur when in the presence of an attractive potential mate, or during competition – shifts the way men think, encouraging them to rely on quick, intuitive, and generally less accurate, judgements, rather than engaging in careful, more deliberate thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29735&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the biggest investigation of the effects of testosterone on human behaviour to date, a team from Caltech, the University of Pennsylvania, Western University and the ZRT Laboratory in Oregon, recruited 243 men, mostly college students. The men rubbed a gel that they were told either contained testosterone or was a placebo over their shoulders, upper arms and chest. Four-and-a-half hours later – enough time for their testosterone levels to peak – they embarked on a series of tests (saliva samples taken from the men through the study confirmed that testosterone levels were indeed higher in the group that applied the gel that contained testosterone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most critical test, in terms of the study aims, was the three-item Cognitive Reflection Test, which evaluates a person’s ability to override quick and intuitive, but likely incorrect, judgements through deliberate, careful thought. The volunteers were told that they’d be paid $1 for each correct answer, with a bonus of $2 for three correct answers, and they could take as long as they liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example from the test: &lt;i&gt;A bat and a ball cost $1.10 in total. The bat costs $1.00 more than the ball. How much does the ball cost? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier work has found that, when presented with this question, most people go with their first thought, and answer, incorrectly, 10 cents – even though it is straightforward to check the answer, which would show that 10 cents is wrong. With a little deliberation, it’s not too difficult for most people to work out the right answer*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that the men who’d received testosterone performed significantly worse on this test. Overall, they came up with 20 per cent fewer correct answers than the men who’d received the placebo. What’s more, when volunteers who’d received testosterone gave correct answers, they tended to do this more slowly than the volunteers who’d got the placebo. While the team didn’t measure individual volunteers’ testosterone levels, based on previous work on the dose used (100 mg of topical 1 per cent testosterone), they were probably at around the level that young men experience during real-world competition, the researchers say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tasks also included an arithmetic test, and those who’d got the testosterone did as well as the others. The researchers take this to show that it was the men’s ability to reflect on their first impulses that was affected by the testosterone dose, rather than their level of engagement in the study, their motivation or their arithmetic skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our results demonstrate a clear and robust causal effect of testosterone on human cognition and decision making,” the researchers write. “The influence of testosterone on the Cognitive Reflection Test, alongside its lack of effect on the arithmetic control task, suggests that testosterone decreases … the probability of engaging in slow and effortful cognitive processes but keeps the capacity to perform them intact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context will determine whether this is bad news or not. Rapid intuitive responses could be beneficial for increasing the chance of having sex or succeeding at a physical challenge, the researchers observe. But they could be detrimental in the workplace – or an exam room. Is this an argument, then, for gender separation in classrooms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volunteers were all male, so the study tells us nothing about the effects of testosterone on thinking in women (who also produce the hormone, but at lower levels). And the study doesn’t identify what might mediate the greater reliance on intuitive decision-making with raised testosterone – over-confidence, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Male testosterone levels gradually fall with age, and some older men use testosterone ‘replacement’ gels, often at the dose used in this study, or inject the hormone. “Western society has been experiencing an exogenous testosterone ‘shock’ over the past decade from a rapidly growing testosterone-replacement-therapy industry,” the researchers write, in a final note. “The possibility that this widely prescribed treatment has unknown deleterious influences on specific aspects of decision making should be investigated further and taken into account by users, physicians and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More work is now needed to explore the effects of testosterone supplements in older men (whose levels are lower to start with), as well as to better understand how testosterone levels fluctuate naturally in day to day life – and so the likely effects on cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617709592&quot;&gt;Single-Dose Testosterone Administration Impairs Cognitive Reflection in Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*The bat costs $1.05 and the ball costs 5 cents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29735/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29735/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29735&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bats slam into buildings because they can't 'see' them</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3_5ZonPOZ40/nature.2017.22583"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22583</id>
		<updated>2017-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Smooth, vertical structures such as steel and glass buildings appear invisible to bats' echolocation system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22583&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22583&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3_5ZonPOZ40&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruno Martin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pollen hitches a ride on bees in all the right spots</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollen-hitches-ride-bees-all-right-spots"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollen-hitches-ride-bees-all-right-spots</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Flower reproduction depends on the pollen that collects in hard-to-reach spots on bees, a new study shows.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers were curious about rogue planets, exomoons and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-were-curious-about-rogue-planets-exomoons-and-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-were-curious-about-rogue-planets-exomoons-and-more</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T17:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers had questions about rogue planets, human arrival in Australia, and exomoons.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Learning is a ubiquitous, mysterious phenomenon</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/learning-ubiquitous-mysterious-phenomenon"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/learning-ubiquitous-mysterious-phenomenon</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T17:15:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill talks about the science of learning and how our brains process new knowledge.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Predatory journals: Not just a problem in developing world countries, says new Nature paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/predatory-journals-not-just-developing-world-countries-says-new-nature-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51688</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T17:00:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;“Common wisdom,” according to the authors of a new piece in Nature, “assumes that the hazard of predatory publishing is restricted mainly to the developing world.” But the authors of the new paper, led by David Moher of the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, found that more than half — 57% — of the 2,000 articles […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/predatory-journals-not-just-developing-world-countries-says-new-nature-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Predatory journals: Not just a problem in developing world countries, says new Nature paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Machines are getting schooled on fairness</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/machines-are-getting-schooled-fairness"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/machines-are-getting-schooled-fairness</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Machine-learning programs are introducing biases that may harm job seekers, loan applicants and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">One In Four US Children Exposed To Weapon Violence: Helping Kids Cope with Trauma</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/06/one-in-four-children-exposed-to-weapon-violence-helping-kids-cope-with-trauma/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22663</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T15:25:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;An important study published in &lt;em&gt;Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; indicated that over 17.5 million (or 1 in 4) school-aged children in the United States have been exposed to weapon violence in their lifetime, as either witnesses or victims. The results also suggest that more than 2 million (1 in 33) children have been directly assaulted with lethal weapons, including guns and knives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data was collected as part of the National Survey of Children’s Exposure to Violence. The sample (N = 4114) was a nationally represented survey conducted in 2011 of children (51% boys, 56.7% Caucasian, 18.8% Latino, 15.1% Black, and 9.4 Another Non-Latino Race) between the ages of two and seventeen years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the authors, children’s exposure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/02/19/human-aggression-and-violence-a-necessary-evil/&quot;&gt;violence&lt;/a&gt; is a primary national healthcare crisis, even greater than pediatric diabetes or cancer. The American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; suggests an even higher concern, stating that gun violence is the second leading cause of death for children in the United States. Data from the National Center for Health Statistics&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; supports these concerns, indicating that firearms are in the top 10 leading causes of injury deaths for children as young as 1 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brady Campaign&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; also reports staggering statistics, including a daily average of 40 children and teens being shot and surviving, American children being killed by gun violence 11 times more often than children in other high-income countries, and the incidence of over 160 school shootings since the Sandy Hook mass shooting in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical, psychological, and economic cost of these statistics are profound, but frequently neglected or unknown. It is estimated that homicide- and assault-related injuries cost the US $16 million annually.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Being a victim, a victim of multiple incidents (poly-victim), or even a witness of violence results in significant levels of symptoms of trauma, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/08/new-target-in-brain-for-treating-depression-the-bmp-pathway/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, anxiety, anger, and aggression in youth.&lt;sup&gt;1,5&lt;/sup&gt; The authors report that children exposed to lethal weapon violence, such as a knife or gun crime, were significantly more likely to report these symptoms than children who had not been exposed to such weapon violence, even after taking into consideration and removing the variables of physical abuse, sexual abuse, and neglect that are also associated with trauma symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that research indicates that witnessing violence is also a significant risk factor, and is often more frightening to children.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Moreover, high lethality risk weapon violence is a greater contributing factor to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/24/how-does-post-traumatic-stress-disorder-change-the-brain/&quot;&gt;trauma symptoms&lt;/a&gt;, even more than that of multiple victimization incidents.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence, prevalence, and research indicate that weapon violence is frighteningly high in the United States, and a substantial number of children may be at risk for significant &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/03/18/the-trauma-inflicted-by-child-sex-predators/&quot;&gt;mental health issues&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, program development and implementation focused on intervention and prevention related to the consequences of weapon violence are sparse and often unavailable to communities who need it most. It is imperative that we focus our resources on what is being defined by experts as a “national youth crisis” in delivering cost-effective, immediate, and community-based mental health programs to children exposed to weapon violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it may take years to diminish the prevalence of weapon violence in the US, simple therapeutic tools may be the first step for immediate intervention. One such resource is a new book, &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go? Helping Children Cope With A Traumatic Death&lt;/em&gt; that can serve as an excellent first step in the journey of healing. &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go? &lt;/em&gt;is a children’s picture book for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;therapeutic coping&lt;/a&gt; that is to be read by an adult to a young child (3–8 years) who has witnessed or survived a traumatic death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the book is to facilitate the child’s processing and coping with the fear, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/07/03/coping-with-grief-and-loss-the-five-stages/&quot;&gt;loss&lt;/a&gt;, and confusion associated with the trauma in developmentally appropriate and safe ways. Thorough guides for adults and child-based interventions are provided at the beginning and end of the book. The book is versatile and can be utilized for incidents of gun violence, other-weapon violence, terrorist attacks, car accidents, and plane crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents, teachers, pediatricians, ER doctors, counselors, and social workers in schools, shelters, community clinics, and hospitals, who are the first to observe socio-emotional and physical symptoms in children, can use &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go?&lt;/em&gt; as a first step assessment and intervention tool. The professionals on the front lines working with affected children need to be proactive in asking children about their exposure to weapon violence, and this book can serve as a helpful resource in the process. The play-based interventions at the end of the book are also an effective guide for parents and professionals on how to explore, shift, and reassure young children’s trauma, anxiety, and loss to more adaptive functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental health professionals need to begin to develop and deliver intervention and prevention programs in schools, clinics, and shelters for the staggering number of children and teenagers exposed to lethal weapon violence. Teachers and healthcare professionals can play a critical role in identifying victims of violence and making appropriate referrals. Establishing and implementing standardized screenings for exposure to lethal weapon violence for children and teenagers as part of a general well-visit exam at the pediatrician’s, as well as in all schools, Head Starts, ERs, and shelters may further allow us to intervene at the early stages of symptom presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we well know, violence begets violence. Early intervention is prevention, and if one in four American children are being directly exposed to weapon violence, we need to step in now to break the intergenerational cycle of violence and the emerging mental health crisis related to trauma and weapon violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitchell, K., Hamby S., Turner, H., Shattuck, A., and Jones, M. (2015). Weapons involvement in the victimization of children. Pediatrics, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt; (1), 10-17. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2014-3966&quot;&gt;10.1542/peds.2014-3966&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Pediatrics (2013). Retrieved from http://bit.ly/2wxZSiY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Center for Health Statistics, National Vital Statistics System. 10 Leading causes of injury deaths by age group highlighting violent-related injury deaths. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/injury/wisqars/pdf/10LCID_Violence_Related_Injury_Deaths_2010-a.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brady Campaign. Retrieved from http://bit.ly/1Rhqfts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, H.A., Shattuck, A., Hamby S, and Finkelhor, D. (2013). Community disorder, victimization exposure, and mental health in a national sample of youth. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, &lt;em&gt;54&lt;/em&gt; (2), 258-275. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1177/0022146513479384&quot;&gt;10.1177/0022146513479384&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamby S., Finkelhor D., and Turner H. (2013). Perpetrator and victim gender patterns for 21 forms of youth victimization in the National Survey of Children’s Exposure to Violence. Violence and Victims, &lt;em&gt;28 &lt;/em&gt;(6), 915–939. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00067&quot;&gt;10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00067&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/kellepics-4893063/&quot;&gt;kellepics&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>AMaker</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-06T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Data fabrication by ex-Harvard researcher takes down paper on Huntington’s disease</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/data-fabrication-ex-harvard-researcher-takes-paper-huntingtons-disease/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51671</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T12:00:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher at Harvard Medical School and Massachusetts General Hospital is retracting a paper due to “inappropriate manipulation and fabrication of data” by the first author. According to the retraction notice, published Aug. 22, corresponding author Marian DiFiglia is retracting the paper because the alleged misconduct by the first author, Antonio Valencia: led to an […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/data-fabrication-ex-harvard-researcher-takes-paper-huntingtons-disease/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Data fabrication by ex-Harvard researcher takes down paper on Huntington’s disease&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The results from a slew of experiments are in: Dark matter remains elusive</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/results-slew-experiments-are-dark-matter-remains-elusive"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/results-slew-experiments-are-dark-matter-remains-elusive</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists continue the search for particles that make up the universe’s missing matter.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rising temperatures threaten heat-tolerant aardvarks</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-temperatures-threaten-heat-tolerant-aardvarks"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-temperatures-threaten-heat-tolerant-aardvarks</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Aardvarks may get a roundabout hit from climate change — less food.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Researchers asked these British mothers which personality traits they would most wish for their babies – extraversion came out on top</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29622</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T10:23:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-587877026.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29725&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29725&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 6D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A happy mother kisses her baby's feet while she is lying down. The baby is looking up at her wearing a white baby grow.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1470912399&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SolStock&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Affectionate Mother&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Affectionate Mother&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/affectionate-mother/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Ambitious and self-disciplined or affable and fun-loving? If you could choose the personality profile for your children, what would you prioritise? Researchers at Goldsmiths, University of London, put this question to 142 British mothers with a baby aged 0 to 12 months. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865&quot;&gt;Reporting their findings in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Rachel Latham and Sophie von Stumm say there was a clear preference among the mothers for most of all wanting their infants to grow up to be extraverted, especially friendly and cheerful, more so than conscientious or intelligent, even though these latter attributes are more likely to contribute to a healthy, successful life. To the researchers’ knowledge this is the first time mothers’ wishes for their children’s personalities has been studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29622&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latham and von Stumm told the mothers (average age 33) the six personality facets that make up each of the Big Five personality traits (Extraversion, Conscientiousness, Neuroticism, Agreeableness, Openness to Experience). For each trait, the mothers were asked to say which facet they would most like their child to have. See the results below, showing how often each facet was chosen as the most preferred for each trait:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29698&quot; style=&quot;width: 2800px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-06 11.01.48.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29698&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29698&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-06 11.01.48&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2800,2380&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865#f0005&quot;&gt;Latham and von Stumm, 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, the mothers were asked to place their chosen five facets (one from each trait) in order of most to least important for their child to have, and to also place intelligence in its appropriate place in this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than half the mothers chose a facet of Extraversion as the most important overall, followed by 20 per cent choosing a facet of Agreeableness, such as being moral or trustworthy, as most important. An Openness facet was chosen as most important by just under 10 per cent of mothers, with intelligence or a facet of Conscientiousness, such as achievement-striving, not far behind at 9 to 10 per cent. Mothers’ choices didn’t vary with the sex of their child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latham and von Stumm point out that the high priority that mothers placed on Extraversion and the relatively low priority given to Conscientiousness and Intelligence contrasts sharply with the research literature on which traits are most important to positive and negative life outcomes. For instance, people who are more intelligent and Conscientious tend to live longer, healthier lives and do better in their careers and relationships. By contrast, although Extraversion correlates with being happier, it is also associated with negative outcomes such as drink and drug problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the research doesn’t speak to why mothers prioritised the traits that they did. “It is possible that mothers’ preference for extraversion is the result of a cohort effect, whereby the current zeitgeist, rather than the mothers themselves, values and encourages extraversion,” Latham and von Stumm speculated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see follow-up research on this question – for instance, how might mothers’ wishes for their children vary cross-culturally. And what about fathers’ wishes? The researchers speculated that perhaps fathers would place a higher value on traits that promote achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study contains an odd anomaly. Four of the five Big Five personality traits were presented in such a way that having more of any of the related facets would be an obviously welcome thing – such as being more friendly (a facet of Extraversion), having more imagination (Openness), being more self-disciplined (Conscientious). However, in terms of a person’s emotionality, the researchers presented the relevant trait as a negative: as Neuroticism rather than as Emotional Stability, its positive polar opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s little wonder then than zero mothers chose a facet of Neuroticism (such as self-consciousness or vulnerability) as the facet they would most like their child to have. Of course, if this trait had been framed as Emotional Stability (with positive facets, such as relaxed and not easily embarrassed), it’s possible many mothers would have placed a high priority on this trait. In fact, past research has shown that when young adults around the world are asked how they would most like to change their personality, most of them say that increasing their Emotional Stability (or reducing Neuroticism) is the change they would most like to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last, related point. Introverts may notice that the facets of Extraversion were all worded in a way biased in favour of the extroverted end of this personality dimension. It’s easy to imagine the results would have been different with some word changes to make the introverted end of this trait more appealing, such as listing “is content to spend time alone” and “happy to take it easy” as facets of Introversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865#f0005&quot;&gt;Mothers want extraversion over conscientiousness or intelligence for their children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and his next book &lt;em&gt;Personology &lt;/em&gt;(due 2019) is on the science of personality change. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29622/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29622/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29622&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Researchers riled by lack of detail in Brexit science plans</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/t8OBuN9VUV8/nature.2017.22566"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22566</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;UK government document fails to extinguish concerns over funding and migration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22566&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22566&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/t8OBuN9VUV8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Cressey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Massive genetic study shows how humans are evolving</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3dfBJ2GQjic/nature.2017.22565"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22565</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Analysis of 215,000 people's DNA suggests variants that shorten life are being selected against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22565&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22565&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3dfBJ2GQjic&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruno Martin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bacterial 'aphrodisiac' sends single-celled organism into mating frenzy</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/B20mXw3oXG4/nature.2017.22549"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22549</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers surprised to observe bacterial protein triggering a switch from asexual to sexual behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22549&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/B20mXw3oXG4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruno  Martin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Germany must go back to its low-carbon future</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rYn5vpowqhU/549026a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549026a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Once a world leader in renewables, the nation will miss all of its environmental goals unless the next government realigns its energy policies, warns Claudia Kemfert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 26 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549026a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549026a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rYn5vpowqhU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Claudia Kemfert</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Stop this waste of people, animals and money</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yJ5FdgsqOlg/549023a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549023a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Predatory journals have shoddy reporting and include papers from wealthy nations, find David Moher, Larissa Shamseer, Kelly Cobey and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549023a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549023a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yJ5FdgsqOlg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Moher</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The secret to Germany’s scientific excellence</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4KXb-leqrWI/549018a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549018a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;With a national election this month, Germany proves that foresight and stability can power research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 18 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549018a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549018a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4KXb-leqrWI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abbott</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">North Korea's nuclear test, cash for Italy's scientists and Zika-vaccine pause</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EWKXArtPEHY/549010a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549010a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 1–7 September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 10 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549010a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549010a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EWKXArtPEHY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Illegitimate journals scam even senior scientists</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/unYzndNfZxs/549007a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549007a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Kelly Cobey has seen a litany of researchers preyed on by predatory journals — and has ideas on how to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 7 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549007a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549007a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/unYzndNfZxs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kelly Cobey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Merkel deserves another term as German chancellor</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/aTDw5ucWOQ4/549005a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549005a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The former physicist shows a welcome immunity to the mood of anti-science resentment that has infected some democracies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 5 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549005a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549005a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/aTDw5ucWOQ4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Palmitoylation-dependent activation of MC1R prevents melanomagenesis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tf2Nw-2YK28/nature23887"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23887</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The melanocortin-1 receptor (MC1R), a G-protein-coupled receptor, has a crucial role in human and mouse pigmentation. Activation of MC1R in melanocytes by α-melanocyte-stimulating hormone (α-MSH) stimulates cAMP signalling and melanin production and enhances DNA repair after ultraviolet irradiation. Individuals carrying MC1R variants, especially those associated with red hair colour, fair skin and poor tanning ability (denoted as RHC variants), are associated with higher risk of melanoma. However, how MC1R activity is modulated by ultraviolet irradiation, why individuals with red hair are more prone to developing melanoma, and whether the activity of RHC variants might be restored for therapeutic benefit are unknown. Here we demonstrate a potential MC1R-targeted intervention strategy in mice to rescue loss-of-function MC1R in MC1R RHC variants for therapeutic benefit by activating MC1R protein palmitoylation. MC1R palmitoylation, primarily mediated by the protein-acyl transferase ZDHHC13, is essential for activating MC1R signalling, which triggers increased pigmentation, ultraviolet-B-induced G1-like cell cycle arrest and control of senescence and melanomagenesis in vitro and in vivo. Using C57BL/6J-Mc1re/eJ mice, in which endogenous MC1R is prematurely terminated, expressing Mc1r RHC variants, we show that pharmacological activation of palmitoylation rescues the defects of Mc1r RHC variants and prevents melanomagenesis. The results highlight a central role for MC1R palmitoylation in pigmentation and protection against melanoma. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23887&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23887&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tf2Nw-2YK28&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shuyang Chen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">m6A modulates haematopoietic stem and progenitor cell specification</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/p9FyrIb-Coo/nature23883"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23883</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 N6-methyladenosine (m6A) has been identified as the most abundant modification on eukaryote messenger RNA (mRNA). Although the rapid development of high-throughput sequencing technologies has enabled insight into the biological functions of m6A modification, the function of m6A during vertebrate embryogenesis remains poorly understood. Here we show that m6A determines cell fate during the endothelial-to-haematopoietic transition (EHT) to specify the earliest haematopoietic stem/progenitor cells (HSPCs) during zebrafish embryogenesis. m6A-specific methylated RNA immunoprecipitation combined with high-throughput sequencing (MeRIP–seq) and m6A individual-nucleotide-resolution cross-linking and immunoprecipitation with sequencing (miCLIP–seq) analyses reveal conserved features on zebrafish m6A methylome and preferential distribution of m6A peaks near the stop codon with a consensus RRACH motif. In mettl3-deficient embryos, levels of m6A are significantly decreased and emergence of HSPCs is blocked. Mechanistically, we identify that the delayed YTHDF2-mediated mRNA decay of the arterial endothelial genes notch1a and rhoca contributes to this deleterious effect. The continuous activation of Notch signalling in arterial endothelial cells of mettl3-deficient embryos blocks EHT, thereby repressing the generation of the earliest HSPCs. Furthermore, knockdown of Mettl3 in mice confers a similar phenotype. Collectively, our findings demonstrate the critical function of m6A modification in the fate determination of HSPCs during vertebrate embryogenesis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23883&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23883&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/p9FyrIb-Coo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chunxia Zhang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Polycomb-like proteins link the PRC2 complex to CpG islands</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/E7Eowlfqbuo/nature23881"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23881</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The Polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) mainly mediates transcriptional repression and has essential roles in various biological processes including the maintenance of cell identity and proper differentiation. Polycomb-like (PCL) proteins, such as PHF1, MTF2 and PHF19, are PRC2-associated factors that form sub-complexes with PRC2 core components, and have been proposed to modulate the enzymatic activity of PRC2 or the recruitment of PRC2 to specific genomic loci. Mammalian PRC2-binding sites are enriched in CG content, which correlates with CpG islands that display a low level of DNA methylation. However, the mechanism of PRC2 recruitment to CpG islands is not fully understood. Here we solve the crystal structures of the N-terminal domains of PHF1 and MTF2 with bound CpG-containing DNAs in the presence of H3K36me3-containing histone peptides. We show that the extended homologous regions of both proteins fold into a winged-helix structure, which specifically binds to the unmethylated CpG motif but in a completely different manner from the canonical winged-helix DNA recognition motif. We also show that the PCL extended homologous domains are required for efficient recruitment of PRC2 to CpG island-containing promoters in mouse embryonic stem cells. Our research provides the first, to our knowledge, direct evidence to demonstrate that PCL proteins are crucial for PRC2 recruitment to CpG islands, and further clarifies the roles of these proteins in transcriptional regulation in vivo. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23881&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/E7Eowlfqbuo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Haojie Li</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Competing memories of mitogen and p53 signalling control cell-cycle entry</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/qSQ5T4rhHu8/nature23880"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23880</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Regulation of cell proliferation is necessary for immune responses, tissue repair, and upkeep of organ function to maintain human health. When proliferating cells complete mitosis, a fraction of newly born daughter cells immediately enter the next cell cycle, while the remaining cells in the same population exit to a transient or persistent quiescent state. Whether this choice between two cell-cycle pathways is due to natural variability in mitogen signalling or other underlying causes is unknown. Here we show that human cells make this fundamental cell-cycle entry or exit decision based on competing memories of variable mitogen and stress signals. Rather than erasing their signalling history at cell-cycle checkpoints before mitosis, mother cells transmit DNA damage-induced p53 protein and mitogen-induced cyclin D1 (CCND1) mRNA to newly born daughter cells. After mitosis, the transferred CCND1 mRNA and p53 protein induce variable expression of cyclin D1 and the CDK inhibitor p21 that almost exclusively determines cell-cycle commitment in daughter cells. We find that stoichiometric inhibition of cyclin D1–CDK4 activity by p21 controls the retinoblastoma (Rb) and E2F transcription program in an ultrasensitive manner. Thus, daughter cells control the proliferation–quiescence decision by converting the memories of variable mitogen and stress signals into a competition between cyclin D1 and p21 expression. We propose a cell-cycle control principle based on natural variation, memory and competition that maximizes the health of growing cell populations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23880&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23880&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/qSQ5T4rhHu8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Hee Won Yang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The neuropeptide neuromedin U stimulates innate lymphoid cells and type 2 inflammation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jYZx1HglNDQ/nature23676"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23676</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The type 2 cytokines interleukin (IL)-4, IL-5, IL-9 and IL-13 have important roles in stimulating innate and adaptive immune responses that are required for resistance to helminth infection, promotion of allergic inflammation, metabolic homeostasis and tissue repair. Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) produce type 2 cytokines, and although advances have been made in understanding the cytokine milieu that promotes ILC2 responses, how ILC2 responses are regulated by other stimuli remains poorly understood. Here we demonstrate that ILC2s in the mouse gastrointestinal tract co-localize with cholinergic neurons that express the neuropeptide neuromedin U (NMU). In contrast to other haematopoietic cells, ILC2s selectively express the NMU receptor 1 (NMUR1). In vitro stimulation of ILC2s with NMU induced rapid cell activation, proliferation, and secretion of the type 2 cytokines IL-5, IL-9 and IL-13 that was dependent on cell-intrinsic expression of NMUR1 and Gαq protein. In vivo administration of NMU triggered potent type 2 cytokine responses characterized by ILC2 activation, proliferation and eosinophil recruitment that was associated with accelerated expulsion of the gastrointestinal nematode Nippostrongylus brasiliensis or induction of lung inflammation. Conversely, worm burden was higher in Nmur1−/− mice than in control mice. Furthermore, use of gene-deficient mice and adoptive cell transfer experiments revealed that ILC2s were necessary and sufficient to mount NMU-elicited type 2 cytokine responses. Together, these data indicate that the NMU–NMUR1 neuronal signalling circuit provides a selective mechanism through which the enteric nervous system and innate immune system integrate to promote rapid type 2 cytokine responses that can induce anti-microbial, inflammatory and tissue-protective type 2 responses at mucosal sites. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23676&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jYZx1HglNDQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christoph S. N. Klose</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structural basis of MsbA-mediated lipopolysaccharide transport</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ix3bppkVzaw/nature23649"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23649</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in the outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria is critical for the assembly of their cell envelopes. LPS synthesized in the cytoplasmic leaflet of the inner membrane is flipped to the periplasmic leaflet by MsbA, an ATP-binding cassette transporter. Despite substantial efforts, the structural mechanisms underlying MsbA-driven LPS flipping remain elusive. Here we use single-particle cryo-electron microscopy to elucidate the structures of lipid-nanodisc-embedded MsbA in three functional states. The 4.2 Å-resolution structure of the transmembrane domains of nucleotide-free MsbA reveals that LPS binds deep inside MsbA at the height of the periplasmic leaflet, establishing extensive hydrophilic and hydrophobic interactions with MsbA. Two sub-nanometre-resolution structures of MsbA with ADP-vanadate and ADP reveal an unprecedented closed and an inward-facing conformation, respectively. Our study uncovers the structural basis for LPS recognition, delineates the conformational transitions of MsbA to flip LPS, and paves the way for structural characterization of other lipid flippases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23649&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23649&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ix3bppkVzaw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Wei Mi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cell signalling: Red alert about lipid's role in skin cancer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/XumbpYRZtp0/nature23550"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23550</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Some versions of the MC1R protein are associated with red hair and an increased risk of developing a skin cancer called melanoma. It emerges that a lipid that binds MC1R might provide a target to reduce this risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23550&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23550&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/XumbpYRZtp0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ian J. Jackson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cell biology: The persistence of memory</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/LfkPrIp7lZ8/nature23549"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23549</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Live imaging reveals that whether or not a daughter cell proliferates is influenced by two molecular factors inherited from its mother, providing insight into how the behaviour of a newly born cell can be predetermined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23549&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/LfkPrIp7lZ8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Katarzyna M. Kedziora</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Leukaemia: Vitamin C regulates stem cells and cancer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/E44QHoPFeZA/nature23548"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23548</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;It emerges that high levels of vitamin C in blood-forming stem cells influence the number and function of the cells and affect the development of leukaemia, through binding to a tumour-suppressor protein, Tet2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23548&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23548&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/E44QHoPFeZA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter G. Miller</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neuronal regulation of type 2 innate lymphoid cells via neuromedin U</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/15555gY4WQY/nature23469"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23469</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) regulate inflammation, tissue repair and metabolic homeostasis, and are activated by host-derived cytokines and alarmins. Discrete subsets of immune cells integrate nervous system cues, but it remains unclear whether neuron-derived signals control ILC2s. Here we show that neuromedin U (NMU) in mice is a fast and potent regulator of type 2 innate immunity in the context of a functional neuron–ILC2 unit. We found that ILC2s selectively express neuromedin U receptor 1 (Nmur1), and mucosal neurons express NMU. Cell-autonomous activation of ILC2s with NMU resulted in immediate and strong NMUR1-dependent production of innate inflammatory and tissue repair cytokines. NMU controls ILC2s downstream of extracellular signal-regulated kinase and calcium-influx-dependent activation of both calcineurin and nuclear factor of activated T cells (NFAT). NMU treatment in vivo resulted in immediate protective type 2 responses. Accordingly, ILC2-autonomous ablation of Nmur1 led to impaired type 2 responses and poor control of worm infection. Notably, mucosal neurons were found adjacent to ILC2s, and these neurons directly sensed worm products and alarmins to induce NMU and to control innate type 2 cytokines. Our work reveals that neuron–ILC2 cell units confer immediate tissue protection through coordinated neuroimmune sensory responses. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23469&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23469&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/15555gY4WQY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Vânia Cardoso</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A right-handed signalling pathway drives heart looping in vertebrates</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MAMKqUtNmzA/nature23454"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23454</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Most animals show external bilateral symmetry, which hinders the observation of multiple internal left–right (L/R) asymmetries that are fundamental to organ packaging and function. In vertebrates, left identity is mediated by the left-specific Nodal–Pitx2 axis that is repressed on the right-hand side by the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) inducer Snail1 (refs 3, 4). Despite some existing evidence, it remains unclear whether an equivalent instructive pathway provides right-hand-specific information to the embryo. Here we show that, in zebrafish, BMP mediates the L/R asymmetric activation of another EMT inducer, Prrx1a, in the lateral plate mesoderm with higher levels on the right. Prrx1a drives L/R differential cell movements towards the midline, leading to a leftward displacement of the cardiac posterior pole through an actomyosin-dependent mechanism. Downregulation of Prrx1a prevents heart looping and leads to mesocardia. Two parallel and mutually repressed pathways, respectively driven by Nodal and BMP on the left and right lateral plate mesoderm, converge on the asymmetric activation of the transcription factors Pitx2 and Prrx1, which integrate left and right information to govern heart morphogenesis. This mechanism is conserved in the chicken embryo, and in the mouse SNAIL1 acts in a similar manner to Prrx1a in zebrafish and PRRX1 in the chick. Thus, a differential L/R EMT produces asymmetric cell movements and forces, more prominent from the right, that drive heart laterality in vertebrates. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 86 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23454&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MAMKqUtNmzA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Oscar H. Ocaña</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Alice in Peaceland</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/9MDSLvpeL14/549124a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549124a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;One more nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 124 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549124a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549124a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/9MDSLvpeL14&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Natalia Theodoridou</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecular biology: Rhino gives voice to silent chromatin</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4LARF4WF7jQ/549038a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549038a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Flies use master lists of DNA sequences from transposons to identify and silence these virus-like, genomic parasites. How the lists themselves escape the fate of their transposon targets has now been solved.  See Letter    p.54&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 38 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549038a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549038a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4LARF4WF7jQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Phillip D. Zamore</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Maryam Mirzakhani (1977–2017)</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MQg_2q-eiBM/549032a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549032a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Pioneering mathematician and winner of the Fields Medal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 32 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549032a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549032a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MQg_2q-eiBM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kasra Rafi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tribute to Daedalus: Fertile mind that led to unexpected places</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/fgEl6nm_3Gg/549031d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031d</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 31 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549031d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/fgEl6nm_3Gg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Martyn Poliakoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Biomedical literature: Testers wanted for article search tool</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/8oEUmDWY6Dc/549031c"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031c</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 31 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549031c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/8oEUmDWY6Dc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter Brown</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Herbarium collections: Venezuela's botanic heritage in jeopardy</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hESj90O_6os/549031b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031b</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 31 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549031b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hESj90O_6os&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Juan Núñez-Farfán</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum gravity: Quantum effects in the gravitational field</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/iLsHw0Dbc1A/549031a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 31 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549031a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549031a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/iLsHw0Dbc1A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sabine Hossenfelder</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Books in brief</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/fp9CLkj7ACI/549029a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549029a</id>
		<updated>2017-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 29 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549029a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549029a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/fp9CLkj7ACI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Barbara Kiser</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Zika could one day help combat deadly brain cancer</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-could-one-day-help-combat-deadly-brain-cancer"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-could-one-day-help-combat-deadly-brain-cancer</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T20:54:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Zika virus targets cells that cause glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer, studies in human cells and mice show.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Authors retract Science paper after investigation reveals manipulated images</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/authors-retract-science-paper-investigation-reveals-manipulated-images/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51680</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T18:48:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers at a prominent Japanese university have retracted a 2015 paper in Science, after an investigation uncovered image falsification and fabrication. Last September, the University of Tokyo began an investigation of seven papers from the lab of cell biologist Yoshinori Watanabe after receiving anonymous allegations. In May 2017, the university determined that five papers contained falsified […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/authors-retract-science-paper-investigation-reveals-manipulated-images/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors retract Science paper after investigation reveals manipulated images&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Amid legal battle, psych journal issuing caution about torture paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/amid-legal-battle-psych-journal-issuing-caution-torture-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51666</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T15:42:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A psychology journal plans to issue an editor’s note about a controversial paper exploring what the author called “the biggest scandal to hit” the American Psychological Association (APA) in years. The note cautions readers that the subject of the paper, published in the SAGE journal Teaching of Psychology, is part of a pending lawsuit, and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/amid-legal-battle-psych-journal-issuing-caution-torture-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Amid legal battle, psych journal issuing caution about torture paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Learning takes brain acrobatics</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-flexibility-learning"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-flexibility-learning</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T15:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Brains that learn best seem able to reconfigure themselves on the fly, a new line of research suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Data and efficiency in science and medicine</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/data-and-efficiency-in-science-and-medicine"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/data-and-efficiency-in-science-and-medicine</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T13:39:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 September's theme explores how professionals are using smart technology to make data-driven decisions</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Scientifically misleading errors” prompt authors to withdraw paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/scientifically-misleading-errors-prompt-authors-withdraw-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51621</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T12:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A group of authors have withdrawn a paper after revealing a litany of issues to the journal that published it. Among those issues were “scientifically misleading errors,” “insufficient” validation, and a disagreement between the researchers on whether it should have been published at all. “Optimal DNA structure of reverse-hairpin beacons for label-free and positive surface […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/scientifically-misleading-errors-prompt-authors-withdraw-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Scientifically misleading errors” prompt authors to withdraw paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Teaching methods go from lab to classroom</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teaching-methods-go-lab-classroom"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teaching-methods-go-lab-classroom</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Cognitive researchers are finding ways to help young students to hold on to all the knowledge and skills they need to succeed in school.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Gaidos</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">People may have lived in Brazil more than 20,000 years ago</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/stone-age-people-brazil-20000-years-ago"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/stone-age-people-brazil-20000-years-ago</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Stone Age humans left behind clues of their presence at a remote Brazilian rock shelter.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Increase the meaningfulness of your work by considering how it helps others</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/05/increase-the-meaningfulness-of-your-work-by-considering-how-it-helps-others/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29538</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T08:41:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29613&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-638601948.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29613&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29613&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark IV&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mid adult African American businesswoman and mid adult Caucasian businessman discuss project strategy. The woman is gesturing while talking with business partner.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1484587546&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Steve Debenport&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;80&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;320&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Diverse male and female business partners discuss strategy&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Diverse male and female business partners discuss strategy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/05/increase-the-meaningfulness-of-your-work-by-considering-how-it-helps-others/diverse-male-and-female-business-partners-discuss-strategy/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;You will be happier and more productive in your work if you find it meaningful&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we find our work meaningful and worthwhile, we are more likely to enjoy it, to be more productive, and feel committed to our employers and satisfied with our jobs. For obvious reasons, then, work psychologists have been trying to find out what factors contribute to people finding more meaning in their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top of the list is what they call “task significance”, which in plain English means believing that the work you do is of benefit to others. However, to date, most of the evidence for the importance of task significance has been correlational – workers who see how their work is beneficial to others are more likely to find it meaningful, but that doesn’t mean that task significance is causing the feelings of meaningfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Blake Allan at Purdue University has provided some of the first longitudinal evidence that seeing our work as benefiting others really does lead to an increase in our finding it meaningful. “These results are important both for the wellbeing of individual workers and as a potential avenue to increase productivity,” he concludes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300702&quot;&gt;in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vocational Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29538&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake contacted thousands of alumni of a university in Midwestern USA and asked them to complete a survey about their job, and then to complete it again three and six months later. Over 600 of them were in work and completed the survey at all three time points: just over half were female; they ranged in age from 22 to 82; and they were in a range of jobs, the most commonly cited titles being director, engineer, manager, teacher, professor and admin assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each survey point, the participants rated their agreement with four statements about the “task significance” of their work, such as “My job provides opportunities to substantially improve the welfare of others,” and “A lot of others can be positively affected by how well my job gets done”. They also rated their agreement with six statements about how meaningful they find their work to be, such as: “The work I do on this job is very important to me”; “My job activities are personally meaningful to me”; and “The work I do on this job is worthwhile”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater belief in task significance at an earlier time point tended to be followed by increasing ratings of work meaningfulness three months’ later, and this was true regardless of previous meaningfulness levels, and whatever the participants’ age, gender or social class. The reverse was not true: finding work to be more meaningful at an earlier time point wasn’t associated with seeing it as more beneficial to others at later survey points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new data complement another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28493738&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; by the same researcher in which he experimentally manipulated participants to experience greater task significance (for instance by having them complete a task that they were told would benefit of others versus being told it would benefit themselves). He found that those told it would benefit others found the work more meaningful as compared with those doing it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, Blake said it seems that “perceiving one’s work as improving the welfare of others leads to the perception that it is personally meaningful, important and valuable.” He added that employers might therefore be able to help workers to find their work more meaningful by helping them make contact with the people who benefit from their work, by increasing the influence of their work on others, or “creating a prosocial climate in the workplace”. Also, he suggests we can help ourselves find our work more meaningful, for example by setting aside time each week to help others in our work, or writing about times we’ve helped others through our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weakness of the new study is that the sample was predominantly made up of White people of higher social class. Although social class didn’t moderate the longitudinal link between task significance and finding work meaningful in the current data this may be because there wasn’t a wide enough range of social class in the sample. “Therefore, future studies should replicate the current findings and re-test social class as a moderator with more representative sample,” Blake said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300702&quot;&gt;Task significance and meaningful work: A longitudinal study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29538/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29538/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29538&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Hold the phone! Cell phone use while pregnant not linked to child neurodevelopment problems</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/05/hold-the-phone-cell-phone-use-while-pregnant-not-linked-to-child-neurodevelopment-problems/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9481</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T08:20:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/pexels-photo-261628-140x110.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cell phone use and exposure to weak radio frequency electromagnetic fields (EMF-RF) has been a public health concern for several years. Specific concerns on whether using your cell phone while pregnant can harm your fetus are mainly due to their extensive use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the widespread uncertainty among the public that EMF-RFs from cell phones might harm the developing brain of the fetus, the evidence from animal experiments and from previous epidemiological studies with mothers and children are inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find answers, we studied the association between maternal cell phone use during pregnancy and child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years. We included around 45,000 mothers and their children from all over Norway who are participants of a large birth cohort study, the Norwegian Mother and Child Study (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fhi.no/en/studies/moba&quot;&gt;MoBa study&lt;/a&gt;). This is the largest study worldwide that follows families from pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The child’s neurodevelopment was assessed by questionnaires answered by the parents. These are frequently used questionnaires in epidemiological studies, with questions like: “When you ask you child to point at his/her eyes, nose, hair, etc. does he/she point correctly on at least seven parts of the body?” and “Can your child catch a large ball with both hands?”. In addition, we used language development as an outcome because in previous studies we found this parameter to be sensitive to exposure to neurotoxicants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found no evidence of a harmful effect of the mother using her cell phone during pregnancy on her child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found no evidence of a harmful effect of the mother using her cell phone during pregnancy on her child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years. Further to this, we even found that the more the mother was using her cell phone during pregnancy the better language and motor skills her child had at 3 years of age. We observed no associations when the child was 5 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160412016307383?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;in another study&lt;/a&gt; that included mothers and children from five birth cohorts, including MoBa, the authors found that cell phone use during pregnancy was related to a higher risk for the child to have hyperactivity/inattention problems at 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personality, parenting style and other factors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, high cell phone use for the Norwegian women was related to a lower risk of emotional problems at 5 years. As in our study, the interpretation of such results is unclear. Mainly due to the small RF-EMF exposure that reached the fetus when the mother is using the phone while pregnant and due to other unmeasured factors that can “mask” the findings, such as maternal depression or anxiety, parenting style and maternal personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assumed that extrovert women would talk more (using their cell phones more) and this can help their child to advance their communication skills. The “International Personality Item Pool” questionnaire assessed the mother’s extrovert personality. Even after taking into account maternal extroversion, cell phone use in pregnancy was not found to be harmful for the child’s neurodevelopment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that a social and family background that is beneficial for the child’s language and motor skills development, rather than parental cell phone use in itself, might cause the observed effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A changing world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still large gaps of knowledge on the effects of EMF-RF exposure to human health. By the time our study was conducted cell phone use was widespread. During the recruitment period (2001 – 2009), cell phone use increased from 68% to 99%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell-phone technology has changed tremendously since 2009, with the major milestone of smart phone use. Smart phones and other smart devices have completely changed the way we use cell phones, including frequency of use, type of use and starting age of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we cannot be absolutely sure if we could observe the same results if the study was conducted now and had included the widespread use of smart phones, the physical exposure to EMF-RF has not changed that much and we believe that our results also have validity for the present situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/05/hold-the-phone-cell-phone-use-while-pregnant-not-linked-to-child-neurodevelopment-problems/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hold the phone! Cell phone use while pregnant not linked to child neurodevelopment problems&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jan Alexander &amp;#38; Eleni Papadopoulou</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Survival and Grief</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/6zHVZ3ydy90/survival-and-grief.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-7182136031378450444</id>
		<updated>2017-09-05T00:15:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-faz_UDhTFlY/Wa3PJy06ceI/AAAAAAAAMPo/LCvpLx_4rj0MSWwvOG3-V6V_qVCqvLfnwCLcBGAs/s1600/house%2Bin%2Bdobson.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;226&quot; data-original-width=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-faz_UDhTFlY/Wa3PJy06ceI/AAAAAAAAMPo/LCvpLx_4rj0MSWwvOG3-V6V_qVCqvLfnwCLcBGAs/s1600/house%2Bin%2Bdobson.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is no transcendent moment of growth or meaning in watching a childhood friend die of cancer. There is no learning experience that will somehow make me stronger. Only horror, helplessness, loss, and grief. I am deriving no spiritual uplift from this experience, only depression and despair. If someone wants to talk to me about post-traumatic growth, I will spray paint their car.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Others disagree with me, I'm sure of it. For religious reasons. And I will respect their beliefs. There is no point in being a skeptical asshole to a grieving family.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The most important point here is that dying patients should not have to suffer this much. I wrote about this and related issues seven years ago, as my father was dying of cancer.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2010/08/ketamine-for-depression-yay-or-neigh.html&quot;&gt;Ketamine for Depression: Yay or Neigh?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2010/09/limbaughpalin-death-panels-extend-life.html&quot;&gt;Limbaugh/Palin &quot;death panels&quot; extend the lives of terminally ill patients&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2010/12/2009-lie-of-year-redux-palins-so-called.html&quot;&gt;2009 Lie of the Year Redux: Palin's so-called Death Panels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2013/09/update-on-ketamine-in-palliative-care.html&quot;&gt;Update on Ketamine in Palliative Care Settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had more of a voice back then. Today I feel hopeless about the state of the world and my ability to have any impact on it. But I will try to keep my happy memories alive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yHRRE8CzCWc/Wa3e6LkTSRI/AAAAAAAAMP4/1JKAbORXa3MEl7Qu3arREsajXW72j5fTQCLcBGAs/s1600/carrowinds.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;244&quot; data-original-width=&quot;227&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yHRRE8CzCWc/Wa3e6LkTSRI/AAAAAAAAMP4/1JKAbORXa3MEl7Qu3arREsajXW72j5fTQCLcBGAs/s1600/carrowinds.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I love you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;RIP.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=6zHVZ3ydy90:63MCs7_Y8yk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/6zHVZ3ydy90&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T20:58:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Laws of Attraction: A Neurology and Psychology Expert Explains</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/04/the-laws-of-attraction-a-neurology-and-psychology-expert-explains/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22849</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T15:25:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why you could be crazy attracted to some people but not to others even if they are objectively very attractive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attraction is a multifaceted part of life that is both simple and complex. Certain aspects, such as becoming instantly attracted to a good-looking person are simple, while other aspects, such as sharing a stimulating conversation or enjoying the same types of interests, are much more complex. Interestingly, taking a closer look at biology provides several answers that can help us better understand the laws of attraction. There are a number of studies that explain how science is strongly related to attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What does science have to say about the laws of attraction?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinical research shows that factors such as physical features, natural body scent, and sharing similar traits all help promote attraction. Research specifically shows that people tend to view more attractive (e.g., physically handsome or beautiful) individuals as more sociable, interesting, sensitive, kind, outgoing, and modest [Dion, Wang]. Therefore, physical appearance promotes attraction to a new partner in a lot of cases. However, body language also plays a role in attraction and approachability. One particular study showed that moderately attractive women who displayed bodily gestures such as smiling, flicking the hair, and quick glances to gain attention, were approached more often by potential partners than more attractive women who did not display any of these types of gestures [Moore].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to natural body scent, research shows that women who breathe in a testosterone-like substance in male sweat, called androstadienone, feel more attracted to men they may not have otherwise been attracted to [Saxton]. After breathing in this substance for at least 15 minutes, a woman may feel more aroused, happy, and attentive to the man she is interacting with. This initial level of attraction can help facilitate a deeper conversation and connection that may lead to a new relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both men and women, pheromones create the body’s natural scent and also stimulate attraction. More specifically, there are genes that produce pheromones that give each individual a special scent. These particular genes also generally encourage individuals who are distinctly different to become attracted to each other’s scent in order to strengthen the DNA of future generations for partners who have children together [Chaix].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partners who share similar interests experience positive and rewarding interactions that further encourage individuals to want to stay in a relationship [Byrne]. This means that even though factors such as attractiveness, body scent, and body language may stimulate the initial attraction between two people, persistent attraction also involves discovering that you share common interests with your new partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How should this come into play when looking for a partner?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the laws of attraction are a complex science that facilitates a wonderful and often lasting bond between two compatible individuals. For individuals who are ready to start a new relationship, it is important to remember to keep an open mind and try not to focus solely on a person’s physical appearance. There is nothing wrong with wanting a beautiful or handsome partner, but if that is the main factor you focus on when you are trying to meet someone new you may miss an opportunity to build a strong relationship with an extraordinary individual. In addition, presenting a kind, warm, amiable, and easy-going personality to people that you meet, helps potential partners find you more attractive. Research actually shows that having a positive, pleasant personality increases perceived facial attractiveness [Zhang].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if your first impression of someone is not exactly what you expected, consider giving yourself a little more time to get to know the person before you make a relationship decision. Sometimes nervousness can prevent individuals from being themselves, especially during first dates. Lastly, make sure that finding a new partner does not take up all of your private time. Focus on enjoying your favorite activities and spending time with your friends or loved ones. This will help you remain happy, healthy, and ready to meet that special someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Byrne, D., &amp;amp; Nelson, D. (1965). Attraction as a linear function of proportion of positive reinforcements. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 1(6), 659-663. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1037/h0022073&quot;&gt;10.1037/h0022073&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaix R, Cao C, Donnelly P. (2008). Is mate choice in humans MHC-dependent? PLoS Genet, 12;4(9):e1000184. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1000184&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pgen.1000184&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dion, K., Berscheid, E., &amp;amp; Walster, E. (1972). What is beautiful is good. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 24(3), 285-290. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1037/h0033731&quot;&gt;10.1037/h0033731&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore MM. Nonverbal courtship patterns in women: Context and consequences. Ethology and Sociobiology. 1985;6(4):237-247. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/0162-3095(85)90016-0&quot;&gt;10.1016/0162-3095(85)90016-0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saxton TK, Lyndon A, Little AC, Roberts SC. (2008). Evidence that androstadienone, a putative human chemosignal, modulates women’s attributions of men’s attractiveness. Horm Behav, 54(5):597-601. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.yhbeh.2008.06.001&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.yhbeh.2008.06.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang J, Xia T, Xu L, Ru T, Mo C, Wang TT, Mo L. (2015). What is beautiful brings out what is good in you: The effect of facial attractiveness on individuals’ honesty. Int J Psychol. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1002/ijop.12218&quot;&gt;10.1002/ijop.12218&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang Y, Kong F, Zhong Y, Kou H. (2014). Personality manipulations: Do they modulate facial attractiveness ratings? Personality and Individual Differences, 70:80-84. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.paid.2014.06.033&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.paid.2014.06.033&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/StockSnap-894430/&quot;&gt;StockSnap&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Takeesha Roland-Jenkins, MS</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-06T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Spiritual convictions and group identities inspire terrorist acts, study finds</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/isis-spiritual-convictions-group-identities-terrorist-acts"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/isis-spiritual-convictions-group-identities-terrorist-acts</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sacred values and becoming one with comrades fuels terrorist acts, a report finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Watching box sets with your partner can benefit your relationship, claim researchers</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/04/watching-box-sets-with-your-partner-can-benefit-your-relationship-claim-researchers/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29472</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T12:27:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-813666252.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29527&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29527&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6.3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D300S&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LOS ANGELES, CA - JULY 12:  A general view of atmosphere at the Premiere of HBO's 'Game Of Thrones' Season 7 at Walt Disney Concert Hall on July 12, 2017 in Los Angeles, California.  (Photo by Barry King\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1499888577&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Barry King&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;18&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Premiere Of HBO's \&amp;quot;Game Of Thrones\&amp;quot; Season 7 - Arrivals&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Premiere Of HBO’s “Game Of Thrones” Season 7 – Arrivals&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-813666252.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-813666252.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-813666252.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,705&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/04/watching-box-sets-with-your-partner-can-benefit-your-relationship-claim-researchers/premiere-of-hbos-game-of-thrones-season-7-arrivals/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-813666252.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I were ridiculously excited about watching the recent season finale of &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; together – we’d watched all the previous 66 episodes together too, and the characters almost feel a part of our lives. Spending our time this way has always seemed like a guilty pleasure, but a team of psychologists led by Sarah Gomillion at the University of Aberdeen say that couples’ shared enjoyment of TV, movies and books can help foster feelings of closeness and a shared social identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They add that the benefits of consuming films and TV together may be especially apparent for couples who lack a shared world of real friends and family members, with the fictional characters serving a surrogate role. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0265407516660388&quot;&gt;Writing in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personal and Social Relationships&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Gomillion and her colleagues said “Humans have created shared social experiences through narrative and performance long before the advent of modern media. Our findings support the growing evidence that like other forms of narrative, contemporary media benefits people by providing a rich, psychologically meaningful social world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29472&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers asked 259 students in an exclusive romantic relationship (the average length was 16 months) to fill out questionnaires about the quality of their relationship, how many friends they shared with their partner, and how much time they spent watching TV shows or films, or reading books, together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants who said they shared more friends with their partner tended to rate their relationship more positively, as did those who said they spent more time consuming TV, films and/or books together, although the latter association was weaker. However, among the participants who said they shared few friends with their partner, sharing media together was strongly associated with rating the relationship more positively, including scoring it higher for interdependence, closeness and being more confident in it. This last association remained statistically significant even after controlling for overall time spent together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the researchers asked 128 more student participants in an exclusive relationship to either spend time thinking about the friends they shared with their partner or to think about all the friends they did not share. The participants also rated how much they are into films, TV and books. Finally, they said how motivated they were to share media together with their partner, and they rated the quality of their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants into TV and other media and who were primed to think about their lack of shared real-world friends tended to say they were more interested in consuming more media together with their partner, as if sensing intuitively that this would be beneficial. Also, the more they wanted to share media with their partner, the higher they tended to rate the quality of their relationship, raising the possibility that merely contemplating watching TV and movies together was enough to foster increased feelings of closeness, although the current data can’t prove this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, much as would like these new results to justifying sharing TV box sets with my wife, the new evidence for it being beneficial is weak, being entirely correlational in nature. The researchers acknowledged as much – “A critical next step for future research is to explore the potential benefits of media for relationships by directly manipulating sharing media with a partner,” they concluded, also adding that it remains a possibility that excessively sharing media together “may actually undermine relationships by isolating partners from their real-world social networks and limiting opportunities to share other types of social experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0265407516660388&quot;&gt;Let’s stay home and watch TV The benefits of shared media use for close relationships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: The Premiere of HBO’s ‘Game Of Thrones’ Season 7 at Walt Disney Concert Hall on July 2017 in Los Angeles (Photo by Barry King/Getty Images).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29472/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29472/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29472&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Elsevier shutters earth science journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/04/elsevier-shutters-earth-science-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51572</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T12:00:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Elsevier will close GeoResJ, a journal that published work on climate change, among other subjects, after five years of publication. According to a statement on the journal’s site: GeoResJ will be discontinued from January 2018 and is closed to new submissions. We would like to express our sincere thanks to the authors, referees, editors and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/04/elsevier-shutters-earth-science-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Elsevier shutters earth science journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Associative properties of structural plasticity based on firing rate homeostasis in a balanced recurrent network of spiking neurons</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/09/04/associative-properties-of-structural-plasticity-based-on-firing-rate-homeostasis-in-a-balanced-recurrent-network-of-spiking-neurons.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-09-04:/2017/09/04/associative-properties-of-structural-plasticity-based-on-firing-rate-homeostasis-in-a-balanced-recurrent-network-of-spiking-neurons.html</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T10:21:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Ankur Sinha's discusses the paper, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1706.02912&quot;&gt;'Associative properties of structural plasticity based on firing rate homeostasis in a balanced recurrent network of spiking neurons (Gallinaro and Stefan (arxiv pre-print: 2017)'&lt;/a&gt;. The abstract is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebbian and homeostatic plasticity have been studied extensively in the past, both experimentally and theoretically, but many aspects of their interaction remain to be elucidated. Hebbian plasticity is thought to shape neuronal connectivity during development and learning, whereas homeostatic plasticity would stabilize network activity. Here we investigate another aspect of this interaction, which is whether Hebbian associative properties can also emerge as a network effect from a plasticity rule based on homeostatic principles on the neuronal level. The maturation of cortical networks during sensory experience is an ideal case to explore this question. Excitatory neurons in the visual cortex of rodents have been shown to connect preferentially to neurons that respond to similar visual features. Since this connectivity bias is not existent at the time of eye opening, but only after some weeks of visual experience, it has been suggested that plastic mechanisms are responsible for the changes taking place during sensory stimulation. We consider a structural plasticity rule driven by a homeostasis of firing rate in a recurrent network of leaky integrate-and-fire (LIF) neurons exposed to external input that is modulated by the orientation of a visual stimulus. Our results show that feature specific connectivity, similar to what has been experimentally observed in rodent visual cortex, can emerge out of a random balanced network of LIF neurons with a plasticity rule that is not explicitly dependent on correlations between pre- and postsynaptic neuronal activity. The synaptic association of neurons responding to similar stimulus features occurs as a side-effect of controlling the activity of individual neurons. The experience dependent structural changes that are triggered by simulation are long lasting and decay only slowly when the neurons are exposed again to non modulated external input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 08/09/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ankur Sinha</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-09-04T10:21:43+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Grape Notes in an Orchestra of Fruit Flavors</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/04/grape-notes-in-an-orchestra-of-fruit-flavors/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9396</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T07:30:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/fruit-plate-1271943_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The grape flavor in your cough medicine makes it go down easier. Grape soda tastes the way it does because of the same sweet molecule.  That familiar gooey-sticky-sweet sensation has an interesting origin in food chemistry, and now we’re unraveling its genetic basis as a naturally-occurring contributor to the flavors of fruits, even fruits that we don’t think of as grape tasting-  like strawberries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The familiar “grape” notes in foods are imparted by a compound called methyl anthranilate (MA).  It was first synthesized and used as an artificial grape flavor, and is the familiar component of fruity drinks, perfumes and other common consumer products.  It is the flavor of purple. It also is a bird repellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The familiar “grape” notes in foods are imparted by a compound called methyl anthranilate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methyl anthranilate is also found naturally in many fruits as they ripen.  It is the conspicuous flavor signature of Concord grapes (&lt;em&gt;Vitis labrusca&lt;/em&gt;).   In other fruits MA plays a supporting role as one small note in the orchestra of compounds that emanate from fruit at the first stage of digestion—mechanical disruption in the mouth.  Sugars and acids lay out a foundation of sensation to the tongue, and a constellation of volatilized compounds migrate up behind the palate to the olfactory receptors where they trigger nerve impulses that reassemble the sensory experience in the brain milliseconds later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MA is just one part of a mind-brain connection that triggers thoughts of summer, desserts and enjoying healthy snacks.  This is why the flavors of fruits are so important—and if scientists can make them taste better, it might help inspire healthier choices for consumers and better profits for growers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But flavors have not always been a priority in modern varieties. Breeders did a stellar job selecting varieties that could withstand disease, and produce high yields of large fruits that could be shipped across a continent and arrive in reasonable shape.  Over decades, intensive annual selection of fruits like strawberries led to erosion of sensory quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, MA is present in wild strawberries and has been completely lost from just about all modern varieties. It exists only in a few older varieties and some new ones specifically bred for the grape aroma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our laboratory is interested in identifying the genes required for synthesis of important flavor volatiles so that they can be re-introduced to new varieties for the very first time. If we identify the genes required for the synthesis, it enables the development of DNA signatures that could hasten the breeding process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Plant Biology&lt;/em&gt; by Pillet&lt;em&gt; et al&lt;/em&gt;. started with a sophisticated approach to find associated genes, and identified the gene catalyzing the final step in MA synthesis.  The work married genomics, genetics, gene expression analyses, and strawberries poked with syringes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First an MA-producing cultivar was crossed with a non-producer.  Their progeny were found to segregate for the aroma compound; some offspring had it, others didn’t.  Fruit from each resulting plant were analyzed for a snapshot of active genes (as inferred from RNA levels) that corresponded with the presence of MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9397 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;256&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/foltepic-300x172.jpg&quot; width=&quot;446&quot; /&gt;Then all of the sequences of expressed genes from MA producers were combined into a list. All of the genes expressed in non-MA producers were combined into a separate list.  The two lists were compared computationally, and only five genes were obviously turned on in the producers and not in the non-producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of them encodes an enzyme known as a methyltransferase.  A methyltransferase transfers methyl groups, and methyl anthranilate has “methyl” right in the name.  Essentially what this candidate enzyme might do is grab anthranilate and attach a methyl to it, making methyl anthranilate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hypothesis was tested in several ways.  First, we turned off the gene in MA-producing fruits using a process called RNA interference.  The fruit is literally injected with bacteria that transfer a backwards copy of the gene to the cells.  This new reverse genetic information suppresses the methyltransferase gene.  When we did this, the fruits did not produce MA.  That’s pretty strong evidence that the gene is driving synthesis.  When our methyltransferase gene is turned off, the fruits did not produce MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second test was to produce the enzyme in bacteria, purify it, and determine if the synthesized enzyme could take a methyl donor compound, strip off the methyl group, and move it onto an anthranilate molecule to make methyl anthranilate.  It didn’t work.  There are lots of technical reasons for such failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if bacteria made the enzyme internally and were fed anthranilate in the culture medium, they could produce methyl anthranilate.  In another test we took frozen fruit powders and reconstituted them into a chemical soup containing anthranilate and a methyl donor.  They also were able to synthesize the grape aroma from the component parts!   When any of the components were left out, the fruit powders did not produce the MA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work we used genomics and genetics approaches to identify a candidate gene that might perform the last step in MA synthesis.  If the gene was turned off, no MA was detected.  The corresponding enzyme could manufacture MA from its component parts in bacteria, and we could cold generate MA when we fed the right precursors to strawberry fruit components.  These data together make a compelling argument that the methyltransferase was indeed the correct gene in the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this work we used genomics and genetics approaches to identify a candidate gene that might perform the last step in MA synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step was to identify traceable differences in the gene between MA producers and non-producers.  A part of the control region of the gene can be amplified in producers, but not non-produces.  This DNA sequence can serve as a “molecular marker”.  Now anyone wanting to breed strawberries for high levels of MA should test their plants first for the active version of the gene.  The progeny will have a higher likelihood of being MA producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot more to the story of MA in strawberry.  The study also showed how the levels are dependent on environmental conditions and stage of fruit ripening.  This is good news because it means there are more genes that contribute to the process, so the hunt continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, the identification of genes contributing to individual flavor notes will allow plant breeders to combine genetics and get and get all of them into one great farmable strawberry.  The resulting flavorful berries will reclaim the lost sensory excitement of heirloom varieties, once again reunited in elite strawberries compatible with modern production demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/04/grape-notes-in-an-orchestra-of-fruit-flavors/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Grape Notes in an Orchestra of Fruit Flavors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Professor Kevin M. Folta</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How type II CRISPR–Cas establish immunity through Cas1–Cas2-mediated spacer integration</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/f7MbvF2Um7Q/nature24020"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24020</id>
		<updated>2017-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 CRISPR (clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats) and the nearby cas (CRISPR-associated) operon establish an RNA-based adaptive immunity system in prokaryotes1–5. Molecular memory is created when a short foreign DNA-derived prespacer is integrated into the CRISPR array as a new spacer6–9. Whereas the RNA-guided CRISPR interference mechanism varies widely among CRISPR-Cas systems, the spacer integration mechanism is essentially identical7–9. The conserved Cas1 and Cas2 proteins form an integrase complex consisting two distal Cas1 dimers bridged by a Cas2 dimer in the middle6,10. The prespacer is bound by Cas1-Cas2 as a dual forked DNA, and the terminal 3’-OH of each 3’-overhang serves as an attacking nucleophile during integration11–14. Importantly, the prespacer is preferentially integrated into the leader-proximal region of the CRISPR array1,7,10,15, guided by the leader sequence and a pair of inverted repeats (IRs) inside the CRISPR repeat7,15–20. Spacer integration in the most well-studied Escherichia coli Type I-E CRISPR system further relies on the bacterial Integration Host Factor (IHF)21,22. In Type II-A CRISPR, however, Cas1-Cas2 alone integrates spacer efficiently in vitro18; other Cas proteins (Cas9 and Csn2) play accessory roles in prespacer biogenesis17,23. Focusing on the Enterococcus faecalis Type II-A system24, here we report four structure snapshots of Cas1-Cas2 during spacer integration. EfaCas1-Cas2 selectively binds to a splayed 30-bp prespacer bearing 4-nt 3’-overhangs. Three molecular events take place upon encountering a target: Cas1-Cas2/prespacer first searches for half-sites stochastically, then preferentially interacts with the leader-side CRISPR repeat and catalyzes a nucleophilic attack that connects one strand of the leader-proximal repeat to the prespacer 3’-overhang. Recognition of the spacer half-site requires DNA bending and leads to full integration. We derive a mechanistic framework explaining the stepwise spacer integration process and the leader-proximal preference. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24020&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/f7MbvF2Um7Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yibei Xiao</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">North America’s largest recorded earthquake helped confirm plate tectonics</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/north-americas-largest-recorded-earthquake-helped-confirm-plate-tectonics"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/north-americas-largest-recorded-earthquake-helped-confirm-plate-tectonics</id>
		<updated>2017-09-03T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Henry Fountain’s 'The Great Quake' mixes drama and science to tell the story of the 1964 Alaska earthquake.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Publishing too much?; CRISPR doubts; Pharma in predatory journals</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/02/weekend-reads-3/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51659</id>
		<updated>2017-09-02T14:26:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of a paper from Yale on ketamine and depression, a retraction for Carlo Croce, and a discussion of when a citation may not be enough. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A researcher published 77 papers in a year. Should that be a red flag? (Soumya Chatterjee, The News […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/02/weekend-reads-3/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Publishing too much?; CRISPR doubts; Pharma in predatory journals&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rings of Uranus reveal secrets of the planet’s moon Cressida</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/uranus-moon-cressida"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/uranus-moon-cressida</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 By studying variations in the rings of Uranus, researchers have determined the mass and density of the planet’s moon Cressida.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=6641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T11:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How deep water surfaces around Antarctica</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oceans-deep-water-map-antarctica"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oceans-deep-water-map-antarctica</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New 3-D maps trace the pathway that deep water takes to the surface of the Southern Ocean.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=6641</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T11:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This sea snake looks like a banana and hunts like a Slinky</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-snake-looks-banana-and-hunts-slinky"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-snake-looks-banana-and-hunts-slinky</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newly identified sea snake subspecies is known to live in a single gulf off the Pacific coast of Costa Rica.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Microglia: a New Cellular Target for Alzheimer’s Research</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/01/microglia-a-new-cellular-target-for-alzheimers-research/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22771</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T15:25:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Those who follow the developments in the treatment of Alzheimer’s disease are very well aware that the majority of treatments currently under development target, directly or indirectly, amyloid-beta protein and its derivatives. So far, unfortunately, this strategy brought nothing in terms of effective treatments. However, there are many different molecular participants involved in the development of the disease. It looks very likely that with a heavy focus on amyloid-beta, other potential avenues for therapeutic interventions have been overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Basics of amyloid theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/04/24/targeting-alzheimers-new-unorthodox-approaches/&quot;&gt;Alzheimer’s disease&lt;/a&gt; is a chronic neurodegenerative disease characterized by progressive dementia, the most common form of dementia worldwide, and may affect more than 5 million people in the US alone. Neuropathological hallmarks of Alzheimer’s disease include a build-up of toxic protein aggregates in the brain, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/19/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-disease/&quot;&gt;amyloid-beta&lt;/a&gt; plaques and tau tangles. In addition, Alzheimer’s disease is characterized by a loss neurons, as well as the synapses that are the points of contact for communication between neurons. Loss of synapses has been linked to cognitive decline in Alzheimer’s disease and other neurodegenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers have tested different genes that may be contributing to disease risk. The first few genes discovered encode proteins that are involved in the production of amyloid and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/02/25/development-of-alzheimers-disease-is-tau-protein-to-blame/&quot;&gt;tau protein&lt;/a&gt; aggregates. Taken together, these findings have led to a prominent theory, where aggregation of toxic amyloid and/or tau proteins in the brain triggers Alzheimer’s disease—the so-called ‘amyloid cascade theory’ of Alzheimer’s disease. The theory is that accumulation of these toxic proteins triggers a cerebral cascade that is harmful to neurons and synapses, leading to progressive cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amyloid cascade theory has been a major focus of research into the pathophysiology of Alzheimer’s disease and has guided the development of potential new treatments. While pharmacotherapies that target these proteins have proven to be effective at reducing amyloid burden, they have failed to improve cognitive functioning in clinical trials. Therefore, there are no effective treatments for Alzheimer’s disease to-date. Recent research has provided new avenues into additional potential causes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/03/26/metabolic-syndrome-and-cognitive-decline/&quot;&gt;cognitive decline&lt;/a&gt; in Alzheimer’s disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Microglia: the brain’s scavengers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent large-scale genetic studies have found that genes that are associated with risk for Alzheimer’s disease are highly expressed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/04/12/microglia-part-1-definitions-and-developmental-progression/&quot;&gt;microglia&lt;/a&gt;. These results imply a potential role for microglia in Alzheimer’s disease pathophysiology. As the name implies, &lt;em&gt;micro&lt;/em&gt;glia are tiny glial cells, the support cells in the brain. Glial cells outnumber neurons by a ratio of nearly 4 to 1. Microglial cells act as the resident immune cells in the brain and play a unique role in neuroprotection and maintenance of homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microglia have been called the brain’s ‘scavenger cells’ because once activated, these cells can engulf cellular debris via a process known as ‘phagocytosis’. Therefore, microglia may protect nerve cells from damage by efficiently clearing potentially toxic protein aggregates, such as excess amyloid-beta. This clearing function has made microglia a promising target for Alzheimer’s disease treatments that are aimed at reducing amyloid protein load in the brain. During development, microglia also play a key role in removing excess synapses, a naturally-occurring process referred to as ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/03/31/how-to-recharge-the-batteries-in-our-brain/&quot;&gt;synaptic pruning&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A potential role for microglia in neurodegeneration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although microglia play a key role in neuroprotection and homeostasis in the brain, their potential role in Alzheimer’s disease is unclear. Microglia have been thought to contribute to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/27/body-mass-inflammation-and-cognition-what-is-the-strongest-link/&quot;&gt;inflammation&lt;/a&gt; in response to disease neuropathology and may indirectly harm neurons and synapses by causing an increase in proinflammatory cytokines (e.g., interleukin-6 and tumor necrosis factor). However, a new study suggests that microglia may have a more direct role in neurodegeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent research demonstrates that when microglia become activated, they can remove toxic protein aggregates associated with Alzheimer’s disease, but importantly, also remove &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/03/rna-storage-in-neurons-contributes-to-brain-plasticity/&quot;&gt;synapses&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, the process of synapse removal during development appears to be aberrantly reactivated, which may help to explain the link between amyloid burden and synapse loss in Alzheimer’s disease. This finding is important because it sheds new light on the reasons why drugs that have been effective at reducing protein load have not been effective at slowing cognitive decline. Dysfunctional microglia may therefore contribute directly to neurodegeneration in Alzheimer’s disease by removing synapses and enhancing cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors of this study caused microglia to become more active by turning off the gene that encodes the protein TDP-43 in microglial cells. TDP-43 is a DNA-RNA binding protein that regulates microglial phagocytosis, and when removed, the microglia become dysfunctional and remove amyloid protein as well as synapses. Interestingly, TDP-43 has been previously investigated for its potential central role in other neurodegenerative disease, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/09/26/celiac-disease-and-amyotrophic-lateral-sclerosis-is-there-a-link/&quot;&gt;amyotrophic lateral sclerosis &lt;/a&gt;(ALS) and frontotemporal lobar degeneration (FTLD-U). In ALS, TDP-43 may contribute to neurodegeneration by increasing mitochondrial dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A potential role for TDP-43 in Alzheimer’s disease, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/21/huntingtons-disease-a-high-tech-solution/&quot;&gt;Huntington’s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/04/21/new-developments-in-treating-parkinsons-disease/&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s&lt;/a&gt; disease, has only been the topic of investigation more recently. It was hypothesized that TDP-43 may contribute to mitochondrial dysfunction in Alzheimer’s disease or the production of amyloid plaques. Recent results unveil a new role for TDP-43 in Alzheimer’s disease pathophysiology, via microglial-induced pathological synaptic pruning. This may be critically important for early cognitive decline in Alzheimer’s, in that up-regulation of microglial phagocytosis in response to detection of excess protein aggregates may lead to removal of synapses, which in turn, causes cognitive decline. These findings are consistent with post-mortem studies of patients with Alzheimer’s disease, where TDP-43 levels are associated with the trajectory of cognitive decline (particularly episodic memory decline) and dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings are important because they provide evidence for a potential role of microglia in the pathogenesis of Alzheimer’s disease. They also raise important questions about the mechanisms involved in microglia-induced pathological synaptic pruning. Understanding these mechanisms could lead to the development of new treatments for Alzheimer’s disease that aim to retain the protein clearing action of microglia while preventing the pathological removal of synapses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chang, X. L., Tan, M. S., Tan, L. &amp;amp; Yu, J. T. The Role Of Tdp-43 In Alzheimer’s Disease. 2016. &lt;em&gt;Mol Neurobiol, &lt;/em&gt;53, 3349-3359. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-015-9264-5&quot;&gt;10.1007/s12035-015-9264-5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardy, J. A. &amp;amp; Higgins, G. A. 1992. Alzheimer’s Disease: The Amyloid Cascade Hypothesis.&lt;em&gt; Science, &lt;/em&gt;256, 184-185. PMID: 1566067&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kettenmann, H., Hanisch Uk Fau – Noda, M., Noda M Fau – Verkhratsky, A. &amp;amp; Verkhratsky, A. Physiology Of Microglia. 2011. &lt;em&gt;Physiol Rev&lt;/em&gt;, 91, 461-553. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.00011.2010&quot;&gt;10.1152/physrev.00011.2010&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paolicelli, R. C., Jawaid, A., Henstridge, C. M., Valeri, A., Merlini, M., Robinson, J. L., Lee, E. B., Rose, J., Appel, S., Lee, V. M. Y., Trojanowski, J. Q., Spires-Jones, T., Schulz, P. E. &amp;amp; Rajendran, L. 2017. Tdp-43 Depletion In Microglia Promotes Amyloid Clearance But Also Induces Synapse Loss. &lt;em&gt;Neuron,&lt;/em&gt; 95&lt;strong&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; 297-308.E6. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.05.037&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neuron.2017.05.037&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson, R. S., Yu L Fau – Trojanowski, J. Q., Trojanowski Jq Fau – Chen, E.-Y., Chen Ey Fau – Boyle, P. A., Boyle Pa Fau – Bennett, D. A., Bennett Da Fau – Schneider, J. A. &amp;amp; Schneider, J. A. 2013. Tdp-43 Pathology, Cognitive Decline, And Dementia In Old Age. &lt;em&gt;JAMA Neurol&lt;/em&gt;, 70, 1418-1424. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3961&quot;&gt;10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3961&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-06T17:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Minuscule jitters may hint at quantum collapse mechanism</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/minuscule-jitters-may-hint-quantum-collapse-mechanism"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/minuscule-jitters-may-hint-quantum-collapse-mechanism</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T15:05:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Vibrations of a tiny cantilever could help reveal why quantum rules fail on large scales.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Bogus affiliation scuttles paper on Atlantic currents</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/01/bogus-affiliation-scuttles-paper-atlantic-currents/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51634</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T15:00:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;An oceanography journal has retracted a 2017 paper by a group of researchers in China after learning from a reader that one of the authors had a bogus affiliation in the United States. The paper, “Southward migrations of the Atlantic Equatorial Currents during the Younger Dryas,” appeared in early spring in Limnology and Oceanography, a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/01/bogus-affiliation-scuttles-paper-atlantic-currents/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bogus affiliation scuttles paper on Atlantic currents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Fueling an engineer’s need to know</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/fueling-an-engineers-need-to-know"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/fueling-an-engineers-need-to-know</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T13:20:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Petroleum engineers are using Knovel to create safer and more environmentally friendly extraction processes</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Behind the Image: Towers of Jewels</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/01/behind-image-towers-jewels/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9378</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T13:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Landscape-winner-Las-Cañadas-del-Teide-by-Harry-Seijmonsbergen-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your profession?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an earth scientist (Physical Geographer) working at the University of Amsterdam, Institute for Biodiversity and Ecosystem Dynamics, in the Theoretical Computational Geo-Ecology (TCE) Group. I am responsible for remote sensing and Geographical Information Systems (GIS) courses, but also geological and geomorphological field work, a great combination!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What type of research are you involved in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I studied Physical Geography at the University of Amsterdam. During my Ph.D. research, I developed methods for the evaluation of natural hazards based on detailed geomorphological mapping. Currently, my research is part of the Theoretical Computational Geo-Ecology group at the University of Amsterdam and is focusing on the functioning of Geo-Ecosystems by analyzing the 3D structure of both the landscape and the vegetation cover using air-born and terrestrial LiDAR-based (Lase Detection and ranging) high resolution elevation data as well as geodiversity mapping at multiple scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, my research is part of the Theoretical Computational Geo-Ecology group at the University of Amsterdam and is focusing on the functioning of Geo-Ecosystems by analyzing the 3D structure of both the landscape and the vegetation cover using air-born and terrestrial LiDAR-based (Lase Detection and ranging) high resolution elevation data as well as geodiversity mapping at multiple scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you become interested in this area of research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a huge environmental knowledge gap between (landscape) ecological sciences and environmental sciences (geology, geomorphology) at fine scales, and over large extents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of remote sensing data such as LiDAR and very high-resolution air-photos, (collected by airborne platforms or unmanned airborne vehicles – UAVs, drones) can overcome this knowledge gap. For that, intensive cloud computing facilities are necessary (see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esciencecenter.nl/project/eecolidar&quot;&gt;https://www.esciencecenter.nl/project/eecolidar&lt;/a&gt;, in which I am involved).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you become interested in photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my profession, for a long time I relied on the interpretation of satellite imagery and all kinds of aerial photographs (panchromatic, Infrared, multi- and hyperspectral). Synergy of such images and field photo’s generated an immense source of understanding, information, and insight into the functioning of ecosystems. For educational purposes, for research and for just fun it is a visual time capsule because monitoring of landscapes is a prerequisite to learn from the past and be able to make scenarios for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where and how was this photo taken?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo was taken May 5th, 2016 (12.04 hr) at approximately 2075m altitude in ‘Las Cañadas del Teide’ on Tenerife island, Spain. Camera: Sony DSC-W110.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why were you there at the time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I combined a short 1 week vacation on Tenerife in May with the preparation for a fieldwork course – Vulnerability Assessment of Geo-ecosystems” – that I coordinate in September / October for students earth Science and Future Planet Ecosystem Science, in order to see the landscape during the flowering season and to have a detailed view on micro-habitats. Each year these students spent two weeks on Tenerife to learn about abiotic and biotic systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you explain a bit more about the image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we see is a micro-habitat on the north-facing caldera slopes at 2100m altitude in ‘Las Cañadas del Teide’ on Tenerife island, Spain. Shown here are a rare mixture of the Canary pine (Pinus canariensis) and the flowering endemic Teide bugloss (Echium wildpretii), amongst other plants, such as the rosallilo de cumbre (Pterocephalus lasiospermus). The unique geological environment and geomorphological development created a specific micro-habitat, perfectly suitable for both the Canary pine trees invading from outside the caldera depression and the Echium wildpretii, a rare species fully adapted to survive in this harsh terrain.&lt;br /&gt;
The micro-habitat is formed by coarse rock fall deposits, piling up at the foot of the &amp;gt;3 million years old basaltic cliffs, creating local scree slopes. Locally, fine-grained sub-horizontal soil patches, form behind larger fallen blocks, as the result of fine-scale surface runoff and sediment transport and deposition, which, in combination with mechanical and chemical weathering, release sufficient nutrients from the basaltic parent material to sustain this unique vegetation cover. Signs of a forest fire, especially on the pine trees, emphasize the vulnerability and dynamic nature of this ecologically fragile (micro-)ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about this scene particularly interested you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relation between active geomorphological processes, invasion of and competition between plants in a harsh environment is amazing. The patch dynamics within larger ecological zones is striking, the vulnerability, but also the resilience of this fragile ecosystem is exceptional. And of course, it is simply beautiful scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/01/behind-image-towers-jewels/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Behind the Image: Towers of Jewels&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Francesca Martin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PNAS retracts paper linked to ex-Ohio State researcher who had chemistry PhD revoked</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/01/pnas-retracts-paper-linked-ex-ohio-state-researcher-chemistry-phd-revoked/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51645</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T12:00:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers from The Ohio State University and The Scripps Research Institute are retracting a 2013 paper in Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences after they uncovered data irregularities. The retraction notice for “Somatic hypermutation maintains antibody thermodynamic stability during affinity maturation,” will appear online on Sept. 5. The paper purported to find clues about […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/01/pnas-retracts-paper-linked-ex-ohio-state-researcher-chemistry-phd-revoked/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PNAS retracts paper linked to ex-Ohio State researcher who had chemistry PhD revoked&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-06T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Smell wars: are worms manipulating each others’ reproduction through the power of smell?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/01/smell-wars-are-worms-manipulating-each-others-reproduction-through-the-power-of-smell/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9462</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T10:00:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/C-elegans-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only now is it becoming clear that these animals have a complex and fascinating sensory biology&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shakespeare tells us that “If music be the food of love, play on” – well for some animals it’s not music but smell. Many animals famously attract mates using chemical smells – called pheromones – typically secreted in sweat and urine. An intriguing example of this smelly communication is being slowly uncovered in the often unnoticed world of mouldy apples and rotten plant detritus, the home of the nematode roundworm, &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt;. By peering into the natural biology of these places, we’re finding that these worms live in a complex world where smells carry detailed information about worms – their sex, how well fed they are, perhaps their genetics. These places are filled with public information broadcasts, but all done by smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; worm has long been some scientists’ favourite system for the study of genetics and developmental biology. But only now is it becoming clear that these animals have a complex and fascinating sensory biology. It has long been known that in poor quality, crowded environments worms may be found as a non-feeding, long lived form called a dauer larva – something almost akin to hibernation. Immature larval worms may, instead of continuing to grow towards adulthood, choose to developmentally arrest as a dauer larva. A pheromone produced by worms is used by individuals to decide whether or not to become a dauer larva.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the 2000s, the chemical composition of the pheromone has been discovered, showing that it’s a complex modular system of hundreds of different pheromone molecules. Despite &lt;em&gt;C. elegans &lt;/em&gt;having a limited repertoire of sensory neurons, worms are able to distinguish among chemically similar pheromone molecules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9479&quot; style=&quot;width: 3274px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9479&quot; height=&quot;2448&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/worm-etching.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3264&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Drypoint etching of &lt;em&gt;C.elegans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Barney Wharam&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the dauer larva decision, it’s becoming increasingly clear that this pheromone also affects a diverse set of other worm behaviours, including mate attraction, social aggregation, repulsion, and ageing. In our &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-017-1033-9&quot;&gt;recent &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology &lt;/em&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; we show how pheromone alters worm reproduction and development. Specifically, when worms sense pheromone, they accelerate their reproduction, growth and development rates. This means that a worm’s olfaction is having significant effects on its biology, and so probably its fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worms may be using pheromone-based signals to trick each other&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also looked at worms from different genetic backgrounds – and this is when it starts to get really weird. We found that worms differ in the potency of their pheromone, measured as the effects that it has on other worms. Genetically different worms live together in the same locations, where their pheromones seem to have different effects on each other’s reproduction. When coupled with our previous work, showing a similar diversity of pheromone effects on larval arrest, the idea of a smell-based war among worms seems ever more real. Our bigger idea is that co-existing, but genetically different, worms may be using pheromone-based signals to trick each other into arresting as dauer when they shouldn’t, or into reproducing when they otherwise wouldn’t, all as ways to compete with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To properly understand the true biological functions of this system of smells and behaviours we need to use whole new approaches to studying these worms, particularly studying them in the wild, rather than in the lab. If smell is indeed the food of love for these creatures then we can gain a fascinating insight into the minutiae of their personal lives, their biology, and their evolution by decoding their secret language of smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/01/smell-wars-are-worms-manipulating-each-others-reproduction-through-the-power-of-smell/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Smell wars: are worms manipulating each others’ reproduction through the power of smell?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Barney Wharam</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Believing widely doubted conspiracy theories satisfies some people’s need to feel special</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/01/believing-widely-doubted-conspiracy-theories-makes-some-people-feel-special/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29442</id>
		<updated>2017-09-01T08:58:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29451&quot; style=&quot;width: 3008px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-157287478.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29451&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29451&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;9&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D70&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Slightly. A young man wearing a tinfoil hat and watching a fuzzy old TV set. Probably seeing aliens.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1192558515&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Trevor Hunt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Paranoid&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Paranoid&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-157287478.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-157287478.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-157287478.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3008,2000&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/01/believing-widely-doubted-conspiracy-theories-makes-some-people-feel-special/paranoid/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-157287478.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;For conspiracy theorists, the more obscure a theory, the more appealing it becomes, satisfying their “need for uniqueness”&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simoxenham&quot;&gt;Simon Oxenham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelenting faith in the face of insurmountable contradictory evidence is a trait of believers in conspiracy theories that has long confounded researchers. For instance, past &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/23/the-backfire-effect-correcting-false-beliefs-about-vaccines-can-be-surprisingly-counterproductive/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has demonstrated how attempting to use evidence to sway believers of anti-vaccine conspiracy theories can backfire, increasing their certainty in the conspiracy. Could it also be the case that knowing that most people doubt a conspiracy actually makes believing in it more appealing, by fostering in the believer a sense of being somehow special? This question was &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ejsp.2265/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;explored&lt;/a&gt; recently in the &lt;i&gt;European Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/i&gt; by Roland Imhoff and Pia Karoline Lamberty at Johannes Gutenberg University in Mainz, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29442&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers first asked a sample of 238 US participants recruited via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk survey website to complete a self-reported “Need For Uniqueness” scale (they rated their agreement with items like “being distinctive is extremely important to me”) and a Conspiracy Mentality scale (e.g. “Most people do not see how much our lives are determined by plots hatched in secret.”) before indicating whether or not they believed in a list of 99 conspiracy theories &lt;a href=&quot;http://rationalwiki.org&quot;&gt;circulating online&lt;/a&gt;. Endorsement of the different conspiracy theories was highly correlated: belief in one conspiracy theory meant beliefs in others would be more likely. Participants’ self-reported Need For Uniqueness also correlated with their stronger endorsement of the conspiracy beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second study replicated this finding with a further 465 Mechanical Turk participants based in the US, but this time half the sample read a list of the five most well known conspiracy theories and the five least known ones, whereas the other half of the group read the five most popular conspiracy theories and the five least popular. Again, self-reported Need For Uniqueness correlated with stronger agreement with the various conspiracy theories. It’s not clear from these findings whether need for uniqueness was really driving greater conspiracy endorsement so the researchers devised a third experiment to test this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, the conspiracy theory that featured in this final experiment was entirely made-up by the researchers. This content warning may seem excessive but as the results show, it really is necessary. The conspiracy theory was about smoke detectors and the claim was that they produce dangerous hypersound. The researchers led half of 290 participants on Amazon’s Mechanical Turk to believe that this was a popular conspiracy theory in Germany where it was alleged to be believed by 81 per cent of Germans. The rest of the participants were led to believe that the theory was doubted by 81 per cent of Germans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While information about the popularity of the theory didn’t affect participants overall, it did impact those who said that they tended to endorse a lot of conspiracy theories. Among these conspiracy-prone participants, their belief in the made-up smoke detector conspiracy was enhanced on average when the conspiracy was framed as a &lt;i&gt;minority&lt;/i&gt; opinion. Just as people are known to stop liking a band as soon as it becomes popular or “mainstream”, it appears conspiracy theorists can behave in a very similar fashion upon learning about the next big new conspiracy theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final, unforeseen and particularly astounding finding emerged only after the participants had been debriefed. A full 25 per cent of the sample continued to retain beliefs in the made-up smoke detector conspiracy even after they had been told that the theory was false and had been made up by the researchers for the sole purpose of the study. Supporting the researchers’ conclusion further, this continued belief in the made-up conspiracy theory was correlated with the participants’ self-reported Need For Uniqueness. Taken together, the findings provide convincing evidence that some people are motivated to agree with conspiracy theories with an aura of exclusiveness. To them it may not matter in the slightest that their views are in the minority, to the contrary this knowledge could actually amplify their beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can dangerous conspiracy theories be tackled? By coincidence, another &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jasp.12453/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;recent paper&lt;/a&gt;, this one authored by Daniel Jolley at Staffordshire University and Karen Douglas at the University of Kent, attempted to solve this problem. Focusing on anti-vaccine conspiracy theories, the researchers found that exactly like the role of vaccines themselves, prevention is better than cure. They showed 267 participants recruited via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk conspiracy theories and anti-conspiracy arguments in different orders. Participants’ intentions to vaccinate were greater when the they were “inoculated” with anti-conspiracy arguments prior to reading the conspiracy theories, as compared with reading the same anti-conspiracy arguments after reading conspiracy theories. The research supports &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1529100612451018&quot;&gt;the observation&lt;/a&gt; by Stephan Lewandowsky, and his colleagues that misinformation is “sticky” – it can be incredibly difficult to counter. The new findings suggest that popular conspiracy theories may be best dealt with through early education that debunks dangerous conspiracy beliefs before they have the opportunity to take hold in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ejsp.2265/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;Too special to be duped: Need for uniqueness motivates conspiracy beliefs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jasp.12453/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;Prevention is better than cure: Addressing anti-vaccine conspiracy theories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;simon-head-shot&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-29463 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29463&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;simon-head-shot&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/simon-head-shot.png?w=845?w=150&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/simon-head-shot.png?w=845?w=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/simon-head-shot.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;150,84&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/01/believing-widely-doubted-conspiracy-theories-makes-some-people-feel-special/simon-head-shot-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/simon-head-shot.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;Post written by Simon Oxenham for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Simon covers psychology and neuroscience critically in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/article-type/brain-scanner/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brain Scanner&lt;/a&gt; column at &lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt;. Follow @simoxenham on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simoxenham&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Neurobonkers/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/+NeuroBonkers&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/Neurobonkers&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; or on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedburner.google.com/fb/a/mailverify?uri=Neurobonkers&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29442/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29442/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29442&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-09-08T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tiny quantum storage device fits on a chip</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tiny-quantum-storage-device-fits-chip"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tiny-quantum-storage-device-fits-chip</id>
		<updated>2017-08-31T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Photon information processing on nanoscale could enable future communication networks.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal flags four papers by researcher in Spain over figure issues noted on PubPeer</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/31/journal-flags-four-papers-researcher-spain-figure-issues-noted-pubpeer/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51640</id>
		<updated>2017-08-31T15:00:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A journal has issued expression of concerns (EOCs) for four papers after a concerned reader notified the editors of issues in several figures. According to the EOCs, the Journal of Cell Science (JCS) discussed the concerns with the corresponding author, José Ignacio Rodriguez-Crespo, and subsequently notified his institution, Complutense University of Madrid. Last year, all […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/31/journal-flags-four-papers-researcher-spain-figure-issues-noted-pubpeer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal flags four papers by researcher in Spain over figure issues noted on PubPeer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-09-06T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Elsevier’s Houston-based teams impacted by Hurricane Harvey</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elseviers-houston-based-teams-impacted-by-hurricane-harvey"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elseviers-houston-based-teams-impacted-by-hurricane-harvey</id>
		<updated>2017-08-31T14:59:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Employees in Gulf Coast region urged to focus on safety; Houston-based HESI business has temporarily shifted operations to other locations to ensure continuity of service to customers</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fiery re-creations show how Neandertals could have easily made tar</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fiery-re-creations-show-how-neandertals-could-have-easily-made-tar"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fiery-re-creations-show-how-neandertals-could-have-easily-made-tar</id>
		<updated>2017-08-31T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Neandertals could have made tar with simple methods and materials on hand, new experiments show.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-09-07T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
