<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How gut bacteria may affect anxiety</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-gut-bacteria-may-affect-anxiety"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-gut-bacteria-may-affect-anxiety</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T19:20:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Microbes may tamper with the production of tiny molecules in brain regions that help control anxiety.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Sugar: sweet, tempting but dangerous</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/qYHqbwQ4tjI/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19425</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T17:06:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/sugar-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only a really small fraction of us gets through a normal day without adding sugar to its standard meal. Just think about it for a second… Soft drinks, candies, cakes, cookies, pies, fruit drinks, desserts and milk products (ice cream, sweetened yogurt), even pasta…we are submerged by sugar-enriched food. Although obesity is undoubtedly a complex and a multifactorial metabolic disorder, increased sugar intake is considered one of the fundamental and principal factors of the current worldwide obesity epidemic.&lt;br /&gt;
A compelling body of evidence strongly suggests that high-sugar consumption results in profound neural alterations in critical brain regions involved in reinforcement and determining incentive salience of palatable food. In fact, the rewarding properties of sugar can modulate the activity of the brain reward system, the same neural pathway which is activated by drugs such as cocaine and amphetamine. The mesolimbic reward circuit is a collection of highly interconnected brain nuclei including the nucleus accumbens (NAc), the ventral tegmental area (VTA) and the amygdala that encodes emotional states such as anticipation of reward and motivation. Long-term consumption of highly palatable food can cause maladaptive modifications within the brain reward pathway. Modified cell morphology, altered synaptic plasticity and imbalanced neuronal homeostasis have been described following consumption of palatable food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermittent access to sugar alters the amygdala &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among several brain regions, the basolateral amygdala (BLA), a specific nucleus of the amygdaloid complex, is known to influence reward learning and the association with adaptive, goal-directed and emotional behaviors. The BLA receives dopaminergic input from the VTA and sends glutamatergic projections to the medium spiny neurons in the NAc, a key structure of the mesolimbic reward circuit. In a recent study published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0183063&quot;&gt;PLOS One&lt;/a&gt;, Shariff and colleagues (Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia) decided to examine the effect of short- and long-term binge-like sucrose consumption on the morphology of the BLA principal neurons using an intermittent-access two-bottle choice paradigm. Two bottles, one containing water and the second one containing 5% (w/v) sucrose, were presented simultaneously to the animals using a binge-access protocol. Surprisingly, the authors found that the total spine densities of BLA principal cells were not affected by binge-like consumption of sucrose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the authors sought to investigate whether sugar consumption was able to alter the general structure of the dendritic components of the BLA principal neurons. “&lt;em&gt;Given that BLA principal cell apical dendrites receive distal glutamatergic inputs that play a pivotal role in the formation of emotional and associative memories, it is interesting to note that our study revealed significant restructuring of apical distal branches&lt;/em&gt;”, point out Dr. Bartlett, the senior author of the paper. In fact, decreased dendritic arbor length of principal neurons from the basolateral amygdala was detected in both short- and long-term sucrose consuming rats, thus suggesting a structural remodeling of BLA circuits. However, “&lt;em&gt;whether long-term sucrose induced reductions in dendritic length and branching of BLA principal neurons (…) are associated with reductions in their excitatory activity and neuronal output is an interesting possibility that warrants further investigation&lt;/em&gt;”, report the authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sugar and drugs of abuse &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same laboratory has previously reported that sugar consumption triggers a reduction of total dendritic length and an increase in distal spine density in the medium spiny neurons of the nucleus accumbens (&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnbeh.2016.00054/full&quot;&gt;Klenowski et al., 2016&lt;/a&gt;). This kind of cellular and morphological hallmarks have been also observed in response to chronic exposure to drugs of abuse such as alcohol, cocaine and amphetamines. Interestingly, different studies have also shown that not only drugs of abuse but also a high-fat diet attenuates dendritic spine density as well as decreased inhibitory synaptic transmission in the prefrontal cortex, a key region intricately involved with processing reward and motivation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26983815&quot;&gt;Dingess et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28042870&quot;&gt;Thompson et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;). “&lt;em&gt;Taken together&lt;/em&gt;”, report the authors, “&lt;em&gt;this suggests the possibility of overlapping neural pathways for drugs of abuse and certain foods types&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must be pointed out that comparing sugar to drugs of abuse is a simplistic short-cut. Indeed, natural rewards (sugar) and drugs of abuse (cocaine, amphetamine, etc) may share some common neuronal features, but the big picture is much more complex. In fact, it is also noteworthy that exposure to various drugs of abuse as well as various types of stress can cause an increase in distal spine density in the BLA principal neurons. This difference between sugar- and drug-induced structural modifications may indicate that both rewards (sugar vs drugs) may impact different aspects of the neuronal homeostasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future studies are definitely needed to fully elucidate the mechanisms underlying food reward, thus hopefully leading to a better understanding of food-related maladaptive behaviors such as obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit Reese Wilson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rwilson04/4277351227/&quot;&gt;flickr.com &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Peppe-BW&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-17882 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/10/Peppe-BW-238x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;117&quot; /&gt;Giuseppe Gangarossa &lt;/b&gt;received his PhD in Biomedical Sciences, specialty Neuroscience, from the University of Bologna. He has been a visiting fellow at the Karolinska Institutet (Sotckholm, Sweden), the French Inserm (Montpellier, France) and the Collège de France (Paris, France). Giuseppe is currently Assistant Professor of Physiology at the University Paris Diderot. His main research topic is dopamine-related brain disorders. You can follow him on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peppeganga?lang=en&quot;&gt;@PeppeGanga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/qYHqbwQ4tjI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Giuseppe Gangarossa</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The tenure-track: The first months</title>
		<link href="http://blog.ketyov.com/2014/11/the-tenure-track-first-months.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545.post-5840141993085725798</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T16:30:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Apparently people read this blog and have noticed I’ve not updated in a few months. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/2kk7is/science_ama_series_we_are_neuroscience_professors/clmaqqz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;People are all like&lt;/a&gt;, “hey man, what happened to your bloviating?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here’s the (shocking!) gist: moving to a new city, starting a faculty job, writing a book, having a second child, and creating a new class from scratch has been somewhat time consuming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My burgeoning lab has just been renovated.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WNP0xPrVA-M/VGThChZT0HI/AAAAAAAAGiM/xxIPNpWXWS8/s1600/voytek_lab_reno.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-WNP0xPrVA-M/VGThChZT0HI/AAAAAAAAGiM/xxIPNpWXWS8/s1600/voytek_lab_reno.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Voytek lab: pre-renovation (L) and post-renovation (R)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;I’ve got one post-doc (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.robotpuggle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Erik Peterson&lt;/a&gt;) working with me, two PhD students with two more rotating, and one more post-doc joining in early 2015. I’m the diversity chair for Cognitive Science and a diversity committee member for neuroscience (positions I take very seriously and is a topic near and dear to my heart). I’m constantly busy playing catch up, trying to finish up my post-doctoral research while also trying to establish my scientific independence and build my own lab.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Where does that leave me now that I’m a few months in?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mentorship is difficult, and I’m trying to do well by my trainees. As a mentor there’s a balance between giving guidance and providing freedom, and I’m still learning that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I (very amicably and somewhat sadly!) resigned my position as data scientist at Uber, mostly because I was too busy and, between my family, my lab, and Uber, something had to give and it wasn’t going to be my family or my lab. So my nearly four-year-long side career in helping build out a multi-billion dollar multi-national company has come to an end (and I could write a whole book about that, probably).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That decision lead me to reassess life and career choices yet again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recently gave a talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedxsandiego.com/events/2014-chain-reaction/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TEDxSanDiego&lt;/a&gt; about failure, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ketyov.com/2014/03/the-passion-trap.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“passion trap”&lt;/a&gt;, and the narratives we tell ourselves. We love a good narrative, and for the past 10 years my personal narrative has been one of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ketyov.com/2013/11/laziness-and-being-academic-batman.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;failed student&lt;/a&gt; reformed as a neuroscientist. That’s mostly the narrative I’ve shared here on this blog. But I want to make sure I’m not getting caught up in my own narrative and that I don’t pigeonhole myself into a particular way of thinking.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Uber thing was partially an attempt at pushing myself outside of my comfort zone and away from my neuroscience narrative. Same with writing the zombie book (&lt;i&gt;Do Zombies Dream of Undead Sheep?&lt;/i&gt; now available for sale &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Zombies-Dream-Undead-Sheep-Neuroscientific/dp/0691157286/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; or as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audible.com/pd/Science-Technology/Do-Zombies-Dream-of-Undead-Sheep-Audiobook/B00PG1W4ZC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;audiobook on Audible&lt;/a&gt; BUY IT NOW). In fact, when I’m presented with a new opportunity, one of the major factors in my decision making is, “how weird/novel is this opportunity?”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I’ve made several deviations in my career but I keep coming back to neuroscience research. I’m just a few months into the tenure-track, and while it’s been a hell of a thing, I have little doubt that I’ve made the right choice. While I’m working a lot, I’m still able to hold evenings and weekends as protected family time, with most weekends spent with my kids at musea, the beach, the zoo, and so on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, this is all just a bunch of words to put down on here to excuse my absence so I can get back to writing other stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vlOD0G2bD6k/VGTjHw8gIBI/AAAAAAAAGiY/KcKYD3Xrxqg/s1600/voytek_g_beach.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vlOD0G2bD6k/VGTjHw8gIBI/AAAAAAAAGiY/KcKYD3Xrxqg/s1600/voytek_g_beach.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bradley Voytek</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://blog.ketyov.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Oscillatory Thoughts</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Thoughts of a Neuroscientist</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/5648062351012720545/posts/default"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T16:30:44+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Carlo Croce, OSU cancer researcher under investigation, retracts paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/29/carlo-croce-osu-cancer-researcher-investigation-retracts-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51596</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T15:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher whose work has come under repeated scrutiny has retracted a 2008 paper for “errors that occurred in the construction” of various figures. Carlo Croce, the corresponding author of the newly retracted paper, has been dogged by misconduct accusations for years — as recently described in the New York Times. His employer, The Ohio […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/29/carlo-croce-osu-cancer-researcher-investigation-retracts-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, OSU cancer researcher under investigation, retracts paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How science has fed stereotypes about women</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-science-has-fed-stereotypes-about-women"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-science-has-fed-stereotypes-about-women</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new book, Inferior, shows how biased research branded women as inferior and aims to set the record straight.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erika Engelhaupt</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">When is a citation not enough?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/29/citation-not-enough/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51589</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T12:00:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last year, Boris Ratnikov was reading a paper and saw a familiar image. He quickly realized: The image was from a 2012 paper he’d written, but wasn’t cited. The 2016 Cell Metabolism paper he was reading had copied a figure from his 2012 PLOS ONE paper without referencing it.  In September 2016, Ratnikov, who is […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/29/citation-not-enough/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When is a citation not enough?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bones reveal what it was like to grow up dodo</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bones-reveal-what-it-was-grow-dodo"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bones-reveal-what-it-was-grow-dodo</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists take a first look at the inside of dodo bones.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Tensions in Scientific Culture Contribute to Reproducibility Challenges</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/E2fBYJ8ZTC4/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7696</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T05:01:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/08/tug-of-war-960x393px-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Once a system is running a certain way it’s hard to change course.”&lt;/em&gt;—Richard Harris, award-winning science correspondent for National Public Radio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists, publishers, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/nova/next/body/reproducibility-explainer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;journalists&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and the public talk of the problem of reproducibility in experimental science. There are committees, symposia, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stm.sciencemag.org/content/8/341/341ps12.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;peer-reviewed articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, blogs and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mbio.asm.org/content/7/6/e01902-16.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;opinion pieces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; documenting the issue and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.2001438&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;exploring remedies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the challenge of reproducibility. NPR science correspondent Richard Harris takes this societal challenge one step further in his book with a title that in no uncertain terms calls attention to the root cause of the reproducibility challenge—&lt;em&gt;Rigor Mortis: How Sloppy Science Creates Worthless Cures, Crushes Hope and Wastes Billions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-7697&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/08/Richard-Harris-headshot-227x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;197&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS interviewed Harris about the lack of rigor in experimental research that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2017/04/06/522262881/how-flawed-science-is-undermining-good-medicine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;he describes in his book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and from a discussion that covered materials standards, publishing fewer papers with greater confidence, text and data mining and the cultural shift required to improve the rigor in science, one unifying theme emerged—tension. Tension between evaluation and culture, hands-on training and coursework, between making work public and ensuring its reliability, and between responsible reporting and satisfying the needs of a news organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These lines of tension contribute to the current structural rigidity in the culture of science that, according to Harris, make scientific rigor a difficult challenge to address. As he delved into biomedical sciences in 2014 after nearly a decade reporting on climate change and the environment, Harris took a broad look at the state of the research enterprise and asked, what are the consequences of limited funds on the structural influences supporting the current state of academic biomedical research?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Evaluation and Culture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest obstacles influencing rigor, according to Harris, are the “underlying cultural issues” that confront science. He cites the financial crunch, career pressures and the hyper competitiveness of science, particularly in biomedical sciences, as examples. These are, he thinks, also the hardest problems to solve. “Even if you poured huge amounts of new money into biomedical research this problem would not go away quickly. It’s changing a mindset.” Fundamentally the “incentives are misaligned,” says Harris, to reward numbers of papers and how many of them are published in high profile journals, rather than “careful work where one is highly confident in results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Hands-on Training and Coursework&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the point of experimental responsibility, Harris’ book follows a path of practical recommendations to improve scientific rigor, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve experimental design and provide methods training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validate cell lines, antibodies, gene constructs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply appropriate statistical analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disclose experimental and analytical methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his research for the book, Harris was quite surprised to find out how little formal training there is in experimental methodology, particularly in biomedical research. He did note, however, that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/notice-files/NOT-GM-16-109.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NIH is now funding attempts to develop curriculum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, following an unsuccessful search to find the best training courses in the country to replicate. There is “huge room for improvement” in this area, he says, but how to integrate this into a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://loop.nigms.nih.gov/tag/rigor-and-reproducibility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;training program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;? Changing a system that’s already in place to accommodate that is difficult, especially without reward and recognition for faculty teaching those courses. “Should it start more robustly at the end of the undergrad career?” One potential solution discussed during the interview is for post-docs to teach these courses to incoming graduate students, as part of a summer or first-quarter orientation program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Making Work Public and Ensuring Reliability&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps can be taken to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/346/6216/1452.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;improve the situation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, researchers with grants from the National Institutes of Health are required to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/notice-files/NOT-OD-16-011.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;authenticate the cell lines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; used in their work. “There’s no simple solution to be imposed from top down, it needs to also work bottom up,” says Harris when considering what key additional recommendations the community might consider. “&lt;strong&gt;Young scientists are more open to sharing and that leads to transparency, that helps solve some of the issues.”&lt;/strong&gt; It’s not a silver bullet but it improves things if people can put their data out there, he says. Increased &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002506&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sharing and transparency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; addresses a number of these issues, and “to the extent that the culture of the young scientist is open to that, that’s great. Although it’s hard for them to change the culture, but over time this can help.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “more nimble publication system might encourage scientists to publish confirmatory or negative results,” Harris writes. When asked specifically about the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005473&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;role of preprints&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/scicomm/2017/08/14/science-connected-accessible-science-communication/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alternative forms of science communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, he acknowledges that experiments in openness and transparency are interesting although it’s unclear how successful they will be. Will that additional literature be less reliable, he wonders? “It’s the job of the entire community, not simply the scientist who makes a claim, to figure out what’s right and what’s wrong,” he says, when discussing the viable options of prepublication sharing of work and use of blogs and commenting as forums for peer review. However, as a science journalist, he ponders: “Do we want more literature out there or do we want more strict checks and less literature? Personally, I would like to see less literature, have people &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/113/34/9384.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spend more time thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; about what they’re doing and being sure they’re right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Responsible Reporting and News Flow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science journalists can help the issue of scientific rigor, acknowledges Harris. “They should step back from doing the story of the day&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;It takes more time to think about things from a broader perspective, but that’s more important than ever.” Science journalists must find a balance between that and satisfying the needs of their news organizations. Even an award-winning science journalist like Harris admits that he needs to think differently about how he does his job on a day to day basis. “Look at what’s published and fits into the broader trend and context of similar results, and what it means elsewhere,” these are results that should be the focus of science journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Easing the Tug of War&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that many institutions now evaluate candidates for jobs and promotions based on a set limit of publications, chosen by the author to best represent their contributions to science. Additional efforts to broaden evaluation within the constraints of the existing scientific culture include recognition and credit for reagent validation, peer review activities and training others on experimental responsibility. Dedicating &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/young-talented-and-fed-up-scientists-tell-their-stories-1.20872&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more time to thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and less time to drafting and revising manuscripts may not the working philosophy of many labs or the culture of science, but it’s an issue getting attention and was expressed as a concern by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2015/10/new-nih-biosketch-brings-opportunity-change/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;leaders&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;of the organization &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rescuingbiomedicalresearch.org/the-problem/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rescuing Biomedical Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a stake in the current structure of the scientific enterprise, says Harris, from journals caring about impact factors [&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/research-assessment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS de-emphasizes journal impact factors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;] to deans making sure scientists draw in funding and overhead for their institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The biomedical research enterprise is driven by economics; economic systems are much harder to change and that should be something the overall enterprise should be thinking about—how to rethink that.” &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harris believes clinical medicine in the 1990s experienced similar cultural stresses, but &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://directorsblog.nih.gov/2016/09/16/clinical-trials-sharing-of-data-and-living-up-to-our-end-of-the-bargain/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ClinicalTrials.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a web-based resource from the National Library of Medicine that provides public access to information about clinical studies and the availability of experimental drugs, got people “passed some of these issues without making them rethink their place in the scientific universe.” Hopefully academic biomedical research can do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;****************&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Harris, science correspondent for National Public Radio (NPR) received the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aaas.org/news/winners-named-2010-aaas-kavli-science-journalism-awards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2010 Kavli Science Journalism Award&lt;/a&gt; from the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://showcase.casw.org/the-envelope-please/diving-deep-oil-spill/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reporting on BP’s Deepwater Horizon oil spill&lt;/a&gt; in the Gulf of Mexico. He also received the award in 1988 and 1995. He currently covers biomedical sciences with a focus on investigative stories and recently completed an eight-part series examining the stresses on biomedical research in the US caused by fluctuating funding levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tug of War Image Credit: falco; pixabay.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/E2fBYJ8ZTC4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Legal threat exposes gaps in climate-change planning</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6o9FgPyg3r0/548508a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548508a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Australian lawsuit highlights how difficult it is to turn global warming data into useful advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 508 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548508a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548508a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6o9FgPyg3r0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nicky Phillips</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Europe’s X-ray laser fires up</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/wPygF3jpOng/548507a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548507a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;High-speed shooter will help scientists to make molecular movies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 507 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548507a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548507a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/wPygF3jpOng&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Philip Ball</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Keep on marching for science education</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PGNKmn-8SIs/548501a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548501a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists might have made a difference, had they protested against laws that now threaten what can be taught in our classrooms, argues Brandon Haught.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 501 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548501a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548501a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PGNKmn-8SIs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Brandon Haught</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Extreme weather events are the new normal</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/vEGSnXR1sng/548499b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548499b</id>
		<updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Hurricane Harvey highlights the struggle to apply climate science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 499 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548499b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548499b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/vEGSnXR1sng&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ancient mud documents the legacy of Rome’s lead pipes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/ancient-mud-documents-legacy-rome-lead-pipes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/ancient-mud-documents-legacy-rome-lead-pipes</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T20:36:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers used lead levels in Rome’s ancient harbors to track lead pipe use and urbanization.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 136 Why Reading Science Matters</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-136-why-reading-science-matters"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/398785774fe71468be014c269d7bdca6</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T18:06:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Brain Science 136&lt;/em&gt; we discuss &quot;Language at the Speed of Sight: How We Read, Why So Many Can’t, and What Can Be Done About It&quot; by Mark Seidenberg. We consider the disturbing gap between our scientific knowledge of reading and current education practices in the US.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This episode will provide the listener with some important basics about how reading changes our brains and what is known about how children learn to read. Learning to read is not as automatic as learning to talk and when problems arise, early intervention is essential.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also consider some of the fascinating differences between written languages and how they reflect underlying differences between spoken languages. Plus---- Why speed reading is as myth!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Check out the free &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com/iphone-apps/&quot;&gt;Brain Science Mobile app&lt;/a&gt; for extra content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Send feedback to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&quot;&gt;brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For more references and episode transcripts please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&quot;&gt;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T20:37:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecules face the big chill</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/molecules-face-big-chill"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/molecules-face-big-chill</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T16:41:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have cooled molecules below a previously impassable limit.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Gut-Brain Connection and Enterochromaffin cells</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/08/28/the-gut-brain-connection-and-enterochromaffin-cells/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22769</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T15:25:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Our gut feeling rarely lets us down, although we know very little about how it happens. As science discovers more about the connection between the gut and brain, the role of the little-known and rare enterochromaffin (EC) cells becomes central to our understanding of how the brain and gut communicate. We have all felt butterflies or that wrenching feeling in our stomach when we are &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/20/the-brain-gut-axis-part-3-the-gut-microbiota-in-disease/&quot;&gt;anxious&lt;/a&gt;, and we also know that long term anxiety and depression often leads to various disorders of the gastrointestinal (GI) tract. We have known for some time about that our mental state can affect the gut, and what we are discovering now with the help of modern research is how gut health affects the brain and general well-being. These days, it seems that what has been missing from this cyclic relationship is our understanding of EC cell functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Basic features of the gut-brain axis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fully appreciate the role of EC cells, we have to delve into some basic underlying concepts and facts. Our gut has more neurons than our spine or peripheral nervous system—that is why it is also known as &lt;em&gt;the second brain&lt;/em&gt;. These neurons have various functions, like controlling gut motility, protecting against irritants (through increased motility or vomiting), and many other still to be understood functionalities. These gut neurons mostly work independently from the brain, but when required, they send information and get feedback from the brain, thus functioning as a closed loop often called the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/19/the-brain-gut-axis-part-2-brain-gut-microbiota-communication/&quot;&gt;gut-brain axis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EC cells play a vital part in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/18/the-brain-gut-axis-part-1-a-paradigm-shift-in-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;gut-brain axis&lt;/a&gt;. These cells have receptors that are always listening to various activities in the gut and sending feedback to the brain and other neurons of the gut through chemical messengers or hormones. Although EC cells have functional similarities to glands, they are spread all over the digestive tract, and they form about one percent of the gut epithelium. Although one percent may sound small, EC cells secrete more than 30 kinds of hormones and neurotransmitters (this number will likely increase as more are identified). In fact, they secrete more than 90% of the body’s serotonin, a neurotransmitter well-known for its role in various mental states, including mental disorders like depression and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it is well understood that the communication between the brain and gut is double-sided, forming a loop. Thus, mental distress causes gut disorders, and gut disorders may influence mental states. Moreover, EC cells have a critical role in this entire axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brain and GI disorders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress is known not only to cause GI disorders, but it also makes the symptoms worse. Stress and psychological factors change the movement of the GI tract, worsen inflammatory processes, and even increase susceptibility to various infections. In all of these processes, EC cells play a crucial role. The release of serotonin from EC cells is the key mechanism for controlling the motility of the gut. They can be stimulated due to local irritation, as well as through nerve supply, especially the vagus nerve. Therefore psychological therapy has a special place in treating functional GI diseases, along with pharmaceutical therapy. EC cells are highly sensitive to the effect various chemical compounds like detergents and spices. They have been demonstrated to even have olfactory receptors—yes, the same receptors that are present in our nose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Gut and brain disorders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the effect of mental stress on GI function has been known for ages, in recent times there has been increased interest in better understanding the influence of gut health on the brain. This became particularly important after research demonstrated that EC cells not only have an indirect influence on nerves through &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/04/phobias-part-ii-new-social-anxiety-treatments-mdma-testosterone-less-serotonin/&quot;&gt;serotonin&lt;/a&gt;, they also seem to have direct links with neurons. Thus, EC cells appear to be directly connected to the brain. This means that changes in the gut are transmitted to the brain in milliseconds, and not in seconds or minutes as previously thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fact gains further importance, considering that the vagus nerve (the main nerve connecting the brain and GI) has more afferent fibers (those sending a signal to the brain) than efferent fibers (those sending a signal from the brain to organs). These afferent fibers cause feelings like nausea when you eat the wrong kind of food. The role of these vagal signals from the GI to the brain and their relationship with other aspects of health are being investigated, like arousal, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/10/26/understanding-chronic-fatigue-syndrome/&quot;&gt;fatigue&lt;/a&gt;, and poor regulation of body temperature, and may become the target of future therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Treatment strategies targeting the gut-brain axis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many drugs for mental distress like depression have been used effectively to treat gut disorders. Inflammatory bowel syndrome (IBS) is one of the most prevalent of such disorders. Some researchers even call it a “mental disorder of the gut”. Selective serotonin uptake inhibitors (SSRIs) have shown increasingly important roles in the management of this disorder. SSRIs help to control overactive EC cells. The role of SSRIs is not limited to the treatment of IBS. Their role is being studied in various functional diseases of the GI, in controlling nausea, diarrhoea, constipation, vomiting, and many other disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, the same SSRIs that are used to treat mental health issues are being used to deal with GI problems. However, many clinical researchers are studying non-absorbable serotonergic agents for GI disturbances. Further studies are being done to target &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/06/11/serotonin-and-behavior/&quot;&gt;tryptophan hydroxylase&lt;/a&gt;, a precursor for the synthesis of serotonin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role of EC cells in gut functioning is being investigated in depth to better understand and treat disorders of the brain like dementia, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/06/preventing-alzheimers-disease-interview-with-dean-sherzai-of-cedars-sinai/&quot;&gt;Alzheimer’s disease&lt;/a&gt;, Parkinsonism, and autism. As we learn more about EC cells, we might be able to treat many medical illnesses more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrews, P.L.R., Sanger, G.J., 2002. Abdominal vagal afferent neurones: an important target for the treatment of gastrointestinal dysfunction. Curr. Opin. Pharmacol. 2, 650–656. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/S1471-4892(02)00227-8&quot;&gt;10.1016/S1471-4892(02)00227-8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bellono, N.W., Bayrer, J.R., Leitch, D.B., Castro, J., Zhang, C., O’Donnell, T.A., Brierley, S.M., Ingraham, H.A., Julius, D., 2017. Enterochromaffin Cells Are Gut Chemosensors that Couple to Sensory Neural Pathways. Cell 170, 185–198.e16. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2017.05.034&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.cell.2017.05.034&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braun, T., Voland, P., Kunz, L., Prinz, C., Gratzl, M., 2007. Enterochromaffin Cells of the Human Gut: Sensors for Spices and Odorants. Gastroenterology 132, 1890–1901. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2007.02.036&quot;&gt;10.1053/j.gastro.2007.02.036&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunlop, S.P., Jenkins, D., Neal, K.R., Spiller, R.C., 2003. Relative importance of enterochromaffin cell hyperplasia, anxiety, and depression in postinfectious IBS. Gastroenterology 125, 1651–1659. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2003.09.028&quot;&gt;10.1053/j.gastro.2003.09.028&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mawe, G.M., Hoffman, J.M., 2013. Serotonin signalling in the gut—functions, dysfunctions and therapeutic targets. Nat. Rev. Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 10, 473–486. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nrgastro.2013.105&quot;&gt;10.1038/nrgastro.2013.105&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/slon_dot_pics-5203613/&quot;&gt;slon_dot_pics&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Ketamine-depression paper retracted following investigation at Yale</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/28/ketamine-depression-paper-retracted-following-investigation-yale/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51575</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T15:00:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A psychiatry journal has retracted a 2011 paper exploring the use of ketamine to treat patients with severe depression following an investigation at Yale University. According to the retraction notice, Yale determined that the paper, published in the International Journal of Neuropsychopharmacology, did not accurately describe the research. But the study’s lead author, Gregory Larkin, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/28/ketamine-depression-paper-retracted-following-investigation-yale/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ketamine-depression paper retracted following investigation at Yale&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How horses lost their toes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-horses-lost-their-toes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-horses-lost-their-toes</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fossils reveal that as horses evolved to have fewer toes, they also got stronger and faster.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Underwood</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Case closed? Fired Pfizer researcher slated for seven retractions</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/28/case-closed-fired-pfizer-researcher-slated-seven-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51541</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T12:13:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Pfizer has discovered two additional papers that merit retraction from the lab of a former employee. One of the papers, published in Clinical Cancer Research, was retracted earlier this month. Last year, Pfizer requested retractions of five papers from the lab of breast cancer researcher Min-Jean Yin, who was fired after an investigation revealed image duplication. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/28/case-closed-fired-pfizer-researcher-slated-seven-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Case closed? Fired Pfizer researcher slated for seven retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists create the most cubic form of ice crystals yet</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-create-most-cubic-form-ice-crystals-yet"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-create-most-cubic-form-ice-crystals-yet</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ice has taken on a strange structure, with its water molecules arranged in nearly perfect cubes.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">5 reasons to pay attention to machine learning</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/5-reasons-to-pay-attention-to-machine-learning"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/5-reasons-to-pay-attention-to-machine-learning</id>
		<updated>2017-08-28T10:16:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 How natural language processing and automation are transforming science and medicine</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The &quot;Unbearable Emptiness&quot; of Science on Twitter?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9080"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9080</id>
		<updated>2017-08-27T20:59:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The discussion of scientific papers on Twitter is largely dominated by spam bots, paid content promoters, and &quot;monomaniacs&quot; obsessed with a single issue. That's according to researchers Nicolas Robinson-Garcia and colleagues in a new paper called &quot;The unbearable emptiness of tweeting—about journal articles.&quot;



To reach their bleak conclusion, Robinson-Garcia et al. read 8,206 tweets. Tweets were included if they contained a link to a peer-reviewed paper in the field of dentristy and den</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Death Dive to Saturn’ celebrates the Cassini probe’s accomplishments</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/death-dive-saturn-celebrates-cassini-probes-accomplishments"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/death-dive-saturn-celebrates-cassini-probes-accomplishments</id>
		<updated>2017-08-27T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new documentary, “Death Dive to Saturn,” takes a look back at the Cassini spacecraft’s 13 years at Saturn and what to expect from its final days.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christopher Crockett</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: An NIH grant scam; are calls for retraction useful?; how to end honorary authorship</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/26/weekend-reads-nih-grant-scam-calls-retraction-useful-end-honorary-authorship/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51568</id>
		<updated>2017-08-26T13:50:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the revocation of a PhD, a questionable way to boost university rankings, and a look at what editors should do when a researcher known to have committed misconduct submits a new manuscript. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: For scientists whose grants are rejected by the U.S. National Institutes of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/26/weekend-reads-nih-grant-scam-calls-retraction-useful-end-honorary-authorship/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: An NIH grant scam; are calls for retraction useful?; how to end honorary authorship&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dinosaurs' spiky armour may have been status symbol</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_JAcLrn9sCo/nature.2017.22511"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22511</id>
		<updated>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Soft-tissue patterns on a well-preserved fossil suggest that elaborate spines helped dinosaurs to attract mates and communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22511&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22511&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_JAcLrn9sCo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Traci Watson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Eteplirsen: A Curious Scientific Controversy</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9065"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9065</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T19:30:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In April 2016, an FDA committee voted not to recommend acceptance of eteplirsen, a drug designed to treat muscular dystrophy. In September, however, the FDA did approve the drug, following a heated internal debate.



This wasn't the end of the story, however. What followed was an unusual scientific controversy that played out in the peer-reviewed literature, discussed in a Retraction Watch post this week.



Following the approval of eteplirsen, Ellis Unger and Robert Califf wrote a let</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rumors swirl that LIGO snagged gravitational waves from a neutron star collision</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rumors-swirl-ligo-snagged-gravitational-waves-neutron-star-collision"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rumors-swirl-ligo-snagged-gravitational-waves-neutron-star-collision</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T19:14:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Telescopes seem to be following up on a potential gravitational wave sighting.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">If you’re 35 or younger, your genes can predict whether the flu vaccine will work</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-youre-35-or-younger-your-genes-can-predict-whether-flu-vaccine-will-work"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-youre-35-or-younger-your-genes-can-predict-whether-flu-vaccine-will-work</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T18:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A set of nine genes predicted an effective response to the flu vaccine in young people, no matter the strains.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Wild yeasts are brewing up batches of trendy beers</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/wild-yeasts-are-brewing-batches-trendy-beers"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/wild-yeasts-are-brewing-batches-trendy-beers</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T16:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Wild beer studies are teaching scientists and brewers about the tropical fruit smell and sour taste of success.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Publisher flags paper on same-sex parenting after neo-Nazi group cites it</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/25/publisher-flags-paper-sex-parenting-neo-nazi-group-cites/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51558</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T15:53:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A publisher has issued an expression of concern (EoC) about a study that claimed children with same-sex parents were at greater risk of depression and abuse, after posters using statistics from the paper to support a homophobic message appeared in Australia and the US. On Aug. 21, several news websites reported that these posters were […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/25/publisher-flags-paper-sex-parenting-neo-nazi-group-cites/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Publisher flags paper on same-sex parenting after neo-Nazi group cites it&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Soda Drinks, Sugary or Not, are Damaging to the Brain</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/08/25/soda-drinks-sugary-or-not-are-damaging-to-the-brain/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22763</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T15:40:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;People who consume more than one diet soda a day are nearly three times more likely to develop dementia or stroke. Surprisingly, no such association was found for sugared drinks. These are the latest findings from a study published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Stroke&lt;/em&gt; on the 20th of April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study comprised of more than 4000 participants enrolled in the Framingham Heart Study Offspring Cohort. Dietary intake of sugared drinks and artificially sweetened drinks were recorded at 3 different time points over 10 years. Participants were followed up for another 10 years and were observed for the development of stroke or &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/14/prevention-is-the-best-medicine-for-dementia/&quot;&gt;dementia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the association between artificial sweeteners and the risk of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/20/can-stroke-be-prevented-by-lifestyle-changes/&quot;&gt;stroke&lt;/a&gt; or dementia were not influenced by potentially confounding factors, such as age, gender, smoking status, physical activity levels, and total calorie intake. Despite this, the researchers concluded that pre-existing &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/19/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-disease/&quot;&gt;diabetes&lt;/a&gt; or hypertension may be partially to blame for the correlation between artificial sweeteners and dementia. However, it is unclear if patients with these conditions could in fact be consuming more artificial sweeteners in an attempt to reduce sugar intake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the abovementioned study fuels emerging concerns that artificial sweeteners may not be the ‘safe alternative’ to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;sugar&lt;/a&gt;. As the first study to associate diet sodas to dementia, it underscores the potential harm that artificial sweeteners may have on the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moderate amounts of glucose are important for ensuring proper brain function. As the only source of energy for brain cells, glucose is responsible for powering neurons and for producing neurotransmitters that are vital for neuron to neuron signalling in the brain. Brain cells that support and maintain the neurons, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/02/03/the-many-emerging-roles-of-astrocytes/&quot;&gt;astrocytes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/04/12/microglia-part-1-definitions-and-developmental-progression/&quot;&gt;microglia&lt;/a&gt;, also depend on glucose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurons are exquisitely sensitive to drops in glucose levels. Epileptic syndromes have been ascribed to neurons that are deficient for a protein called glucose transporter type 1 (GLUT1), rendering brain cells unable to draw up glucose from the blood. Neurological conditions such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/26/nurturing-the-brain-part-11-magnesium/&quot;&gt;migraines&lt;/a&gt;, strokes, and traumatic brain injury all have a component of altered glucose metabolism in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the coin, too much of a good thing is never a good idea. Excessive sugar intake induces a myriad of diseases, such as type 2 diabetes mellitus, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/03/26/metabolic-syndrome-and-cognitive-decline/&quot;&gt;metabolic syndrome&lt;/a&gt;, dental problems, and many others. According to the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey from 2011–2014, half of all adults in the U.S. drank at least one sugary beverage a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is behind our seemingly innate attraction to sweetness? The concept of ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;sugar addiction&lt;/a&gt;’ has stemmed from observing binging, withdrawal, and craving-like behavior in rats that were exposed to sugar. The current theory holds that intermittent, excessive sugar consumption causes altered neurochemical transmissions (one of them being a large release of the neurotransmitter dopamine) in the nucleus accumbens, the brain’s feelgood center. These brain changes are strikingly similar to those that occur in response to addictive drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excess amounts of sugar may also predispose us to developing brain diseases. Another study, which also utilized the data from the Framingham Heart Study Offspring cohort, discovered that people who drank two sugary drinks a day had lower total brain volume, smaller hippocampal volumes (an area of the brain responsible for forming &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/12/11/using-magnets-on-the-brain-to-bring-back-memories/&quot;&gt;memories&lt;/a&gt;), and poorer memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given mankind’s insatiable appetite for sugar, artificial sweeteners were introduced to help the masses limit their sugar intake. Also known as low calorie sweeteners, FDA-approved artificial sweeteners include aspartame, neotame, acesulfame-K, sucralose, and saccharin. Low calorie sweeteners can be up to 13,000 times sweeter than regular sugar but with a fraction of the calories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, evidence has sprung up rebutting the perceived beneficial health effects of artificial sweeteners. A large systemic review of 37 studies on these sweeteners revealed that increased intake actually resulted in increased weight and waist circumference, as well as higher occurrences of type 2 diabetes, obesity, metabolic syndrome, hypertension, and heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, artificial sweeteners and regular sugar act differently on the brain. Brain scans of people who sipped regular sugary drinks showed stronger activation of more regions involved in reward centers compared to those who sipped drinks with sweeteners. This means that artificial sweeteners may not be as satisfying as regular sugar, leaving a person craving for more sweet foods that ultimately leads to a higher total calorie intake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these factors are especially worrying when taking into consideration the estimated 1 in 4 children and 2 in 5 adults who consume low calorie sweeteners on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that artificial sweeteners do more harm than good? The jury’s still out on that one, as artificial sweeteners are helpful in certain populations, like diabetics. Regardless, both sugar and artificial sweeteners are best consumed in moderation—whether or not artificial sweeteners confer health benefits remains to be elucidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pase M.P. et al. Sugar and artificially sweetened beverages and the risks of incident stroke and dementia. Stroke. 2017;48:1139-1146. Doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.116.016027&quot;&gt;10.1161/STROKEAHA.116.016027&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mergenthaler, P., Lindauer, U., Dienel, G. A., Meisel, A. Sugar for the brain: the role of glucose in physiological and pathological brain function. Trends in Neurosciences. 2013; 36(10):587–597. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2013.07.001&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.tins.2013.07.001&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosinger A., Herrick K., Gahche J., Park S. Sugar-sweetened beverage consumption among US adults, 2011-2014. NCHS Data Brief. 2017 Jan;(270):1-8. PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28135185&quot;&gt;28135185&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avena, N. M., Rada, P., &amp;amp; Hoebel, B. G. Evidence for sugar addiction: Behavioral and neurochemical effects of intermittent, excessive sugar intake. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews. 2008; 32(1):20–39. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2007.04.019&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neubiorev.2007.04.019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pase M.P. et al. Sugary beverage intake and preclinical Alzheimer’s disease in the community. Alzheimers Dement. 2017 Mar 6. pii: S1552-5260(17)30050-X. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jalz.2017.01.024&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jalz.2017.01.024&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bellisle F., Drewnowski A. Intense sweeteners, energy intake and the control of body weight. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2007; 61:691–700; doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602649&quot;&gt;10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602649&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meghan B. Azad et al. Non-nutritive sweeteners and cardiometabolic health: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials and prospective cohort studies. CMAJ July 17, 2017 189:E929-E939; doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1503/cmaj.161390&quot;&gt;10.1503/cmaj.161390&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank G.K. et al. Sucrose activates human taste pathways differently from artificial sweetener. Neuroimage. 2008 Feb 15;39(4):1559-69. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.10.061&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.10.061&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sylvetsky AC, Jin Y, Clark EJ, Welsh JA, Rother KI, Talegawkar SA. Consumption of low-calorie sweeteners among children and adults in the United States. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2017. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jand.2016.11.004&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jand.2016.11.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/evelynlo-508511/&quot;&gt;evelynlo&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Better educated parents have children who are more relaxed, outgoing and explorative</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/25/better-educated-parents-have-children-who-are-more-relaxed-outgoing-and-explorative/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29319</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T13:06:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-3&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-508728647.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29335&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29335&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Family of four on vacation. Hiking in a national park. Southern USA. Autumn season.  Hispanic and African descent family members.  They pause to excitedly view wildlife.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1408794209&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;fstop123&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;165&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;160&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Multi-ethnic family hiking, backpacking outdoors in national park area.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Multi-ethnic family hiking, backpacking outdoors in national park area.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-508728647.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-508728647.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-508728647.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/25/better-educated-parents-have-children-who-are-more-relaxed-outgoing-and-explorative/multi-ethnic-family-hiking-backpacking-outdoors-in-national-park-area/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-508728647.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The researchers say the association between parents’ education and children’s personality is not entirely explained by genetic inheritance&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly how parents shape their children is a matter of controversy, especially since Judith Rich Harris’ book &lt;em&gt;The Nurture Assumption&lt;/em&gt; popularised the behavioural genetics position that the “shared environment” (so-called because it’s shared by siblings) – including the family home and parents’ methods of upbringing – has scant influence on how children turn out. But the debate is far from settled, and now a team chiefly from Florida State University has investigated whether more educated parents produce offspring with particular personality characteristics. &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-11240-001&quot;&gt;Published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the research identifies a number of personality differences that correlate with parental education, and the researchers suggest the causes of this association must be more than just genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29319&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, led by Andrea Sutin, is the largest and most focused investigation of personality and parental education to date, drawing from seven surveys, one of students and the rest wide-scale public surveys, for a total of over 60,0000 surveyants. The data included personality measures (these differed per study, but all mapped directly on to the so-called Big Five traits), and the years spent in education by each parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence showed that child personality was associated with parents’ levels of education. More educated parents were more likely to have offspring who scored higher in trait Openness to Experience across almost every survey, and in the bulk of the samples more education was also associated with higher Extraversion and lower Neuroticism. A way to integrate and make sense of these three associations is that children of the more highly educated are more relaxed, outgoing and explorative; they are oriented to approaching the world rather than avoiding it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The links between parental education and children’s personality were mediated by three factors that also give some insight into the reasons behind it all. First, parental education was associated more strongly with kids’ personality in families where the kids were also more highly educated. An obvious explanation for this finding would be that children’s personality is shaped by their own more intense education, however, previous research has found only weak evidence for this. It seems to me an alternative, if partial, explanation is that greater parental education usually has a beneficial effect on a child’s personality, but when a child withdraws from education much earlier than their parents – deviating from a script – this may indicate that they have more turmoil in their life, either as a cause or consequence of their educational decisions, and this may disrupt the personality benefits otherwise bestowed by an educated parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second mediating factor was children’s IQ in adolescence. That is, greater parental education correlated with their children having higher IQ in adolescence, and in turn, higher adolescent IQ correlated with higher Openness and Extraversion and lower Neuroticism. We already know that higher IQ leads to better executive functioning, and the adoption of better coping strategies in response to stress, so these could contribute to personality traits that indicate greater confidence to address the world and handle problems. And in principle, parents’ education could benefit their children’s IQ in adolescence due to factors like an enriched environment earlier in development, or differential levels of nutrition or disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third mediating variable was effect was familial income. Parental education was more strongly associated with children’s personality when the parents were richer. So it may be that the association is partly due to the fact that more educated parents tend to have wealthier families, giving their children a financial cushion against risk and stress, and providing more opportunities and experiences to broaden the mind and cultivate engagement in the world. But as with the other mediators, wealth didn’t fully explain the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we need to take stock and consider the elephant in the room: the genetic explanation. The observed associations between parental education and children’s personality (and the mediating factors) could all be explained by a gene complex passed between parent and child that shapes intelligence and personality in parent and child, and that encourages the pursuit of education, and facilitates higher lifetime income through the generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this possibility, Sutin and his colleagues traced 545 people in the surveys who were raised by adoptive parents, people for whom we should not expect to see these personality differences if they were due purely to genetics. But the adoptees showed personality associations with parental education that were similar and in some cases stronger than in the main group – such as (adopted) maternal education having a significantly greater association with Openness. This means that genetics cannot be the driving explanation for these associations, which adds to a corpus of recent research that challenges the behavioural genetic consensus on the irrelevance of the “shared environment” to fundamental psychological traits like personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intriguingly, there was also a beneficial developmental turn to the observed patterns. As the children of the more educated grew older – and many surveys provided data on these children beyond middle age and even into their nineties – they showed even more pronounced increases in Openness and Extraversion and a drop in Neuroticism, relative to children of the less educated. Summoning a comparison to the “cognitive reserve” – the notion that some people seem to maintain good mental functioning into older age even when suffering from neuropathology – Sutin’s team suggest that parents’ education may be bestowing a “personality reserve” in their children that helps them to resist the turn away from exploration that aging encourages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study doesn’t indicate a single definitive mechanism to explain why parental education is linked with children’s personality, and it’s likely that there are even more processes at that the researchers didn’t look into, such as the known association between lower Neuroticism / higher Openness and breastfeeding, an activity more common in more educated mothers. It seems likely that greater parental education provides their children with a constellation of benefits. And while there may be a genetic contribution, the adoption data suggests that the environment provided by educated parents may itself be shaping their children’s personality development. Identifying “always nurture” as a misleading assumption was an important step forward in psychology; for progress to continue, it looks like “never nurture” also needs to be consigned to history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-11240-001&quot;&gt;Parental educational attainment and adult offspring personality: An intergenerational life span approach to the origin of adult personality traits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29319/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29319/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29319&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Updated: Ohio State revokes PhD of co-author of now-retracted paper on shooter video games</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/25/co-author-now-retracted-paper-shooter-video-games-may-phd-revoked/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51548</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T12:00:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;[This post, which at 1200 UTC 8/25/17 originally reported on the then-upcoming vote, has been updated at 1800 UTC 8/25/17 to include the results of the vote.] A researcher who co-authored a paper about video games that was retracted earlier this year has had her PhD from The Ohio State University revoked. As WOSU reported […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/25/co-author-now-retracted-paper-shooter-video-games-may-phd-revoked/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Updated: Ohio State revokes PhD of co-author of now-retracted paper on shooter video games&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Map reveals the invisible universe of dark matter</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/map-reveals-invisible-universe-dark-matter"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/map-reveals-invisible-universe-dark-matter</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Dark Energy Survey reports a new tally of the dark universe.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Behind the Image: A turn of turtles</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/25/behind-image-turn-turtles/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9383</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T10:49:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-1_Overall-winner_Podocnemis-expansa_Ana-Carolina-Lima​-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone wp-image-9456&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Overall-1st-place-Podocnemis-expansa-by-Ana-Carolina-Lima--300x209.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;852&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your profession?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m doing a Ph.D. in Biology and Ecology of Global Change at the University of Aveiro, Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What type of research are you involved in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an aquatic ecologist with broad interests in conservation ecology, environmental impact and ecosystems management with emphasis on rivers associated with large dams. My research priority has been balancing the benefits of renewable resources represented by hydroelectric power, river fisheries, and biodiversity conservation. I have worked with fish communities affected by dams from different bioclimatic regions in Portugal, Brazil, and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you become interested in this area of research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I can remember, natural ecosystems have always fascinated me. It was a natural career choice becoming a biologist. When I realized how endangered our natural ecosystems were becoming I decided to pursue a Ph.D. in biology and ecology of global change. I am now increasingly interested in building bridges between science and policy-making, applying environmental legislation and participating in policy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you become interested in photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first years of University, I began to feel the urge to capture the beauty of the natural world around me. It later became a serious hobby and after a few photography courses, I carry my camera everywhere I go, whether it’s traveling for leisure or for work. I feel very lucky because being a researcher in ecology has allowed me to travel to natural places not many people have the opportunity to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where and how was this photo taken?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo was taken in one of the most important areas of conservation for the Giant South American turtle (&lt;em&gt;Podocnemis expansa&lt;/em&gt;), also known as the tartaruga-da-amazônia in the Cantão State Park, in Tocantins, Brazil. The Park is located in the Brazilian “Savanna” or Cerrado, a biodiversity hotspot that although it is yet poorly known it is thought to be equally or even more biodiverse than the Amazon ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why were you there at the time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was there as part of a research group working in the field and helping to collect data on the status of reptiles and amphibians’ populations for conservation purposes during my Ph.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you explain a bit more about the image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image is from a group of juveniles Giant South American turtles (&lt;em&gt;Podocnemis expansa&lt;/em&gt;) which were being counted, measured and weighed during field-work for research purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about this scene particularly interested you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scene was fascinating because I was in the middle of field-work, helping other researchers to collect data, which made this moment really special, not only for the aesthetic part but also for the important conservation work we were doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/25/behind-image-turn-turtles/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Behind the Image: A turn of turtles&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Francesca Martin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Has the European Union met its targets for reducing tuberculosis fatalities?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/25/has-the-european-union-met-its-targets-for-reducing-tuberculosis-fatalities/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9451</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T07:40:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/world-hands-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September 2000, The United Nations (UN) defined ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unmillenniumproject.org/goals/&quot;&gt;The Millennium Development Goals&lt;/a&gt;’ which outline targets to tackle extreme poverty in the world. This mission seeks to alleviate many global challenges – including poverty, hunger, disease, shelter limitations, equality, education and sustainability of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Union (EU) sought to address  the extent of these problems by 2015. A key aim has been to see a reduction in the number of deaths caused by tuberculosis (TB). This infectious disease is a public health concern, as one third of the global population is thought to be infected with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to global health initiatives, the UN aimed to see a 50% reduction in death rates caused by TB by 2015, in comparison to figures from 1990. Marieke J. van der Werf, Sandro Bonfigli and Frantiska Hruba  from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecdc.europa.eu/en&quot;&gt;European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control&lt;/a&gt;, Granitsväg, in Stockholm investigated whether these milestones were actually reached, so that we can prepare for the next steps to further improve global health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9453 alignright&quot; height=&quot;212&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/europe-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;318&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4544-9&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; article in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, by obtaining data from the Eurostat database, the researchers analyzed cause of death statistics for populations belonging to all 28 countries of the EU. Looking at the time frame of 1999-2014, it appeared that TB death rates had decreased by 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add to this promising news, ‘the annual average percentage decline’, which shows how fast the fatality percentage  declines from year to year, was a surprising 2.73%. This result was more than what was necessary for them to reach their target.This positive news shows that the EU has successfully reached its MDF goal of reducing TB fatalities in its member countries. Though, what hope do we have for the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2016, a new goal has been constructed by the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/post2015_strategy/en/&quot;&gt; World Health Organization.&lt;/a&gt; They raise the bar to ambitious levels, using figures from 2015 for comparison against a target for a 35% reduction in tuberculosis fatality by 2020, and a 95% drop by 2035. The authors comment that this will cause heavy demand on governments and health care services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other parts of the world are setting such objectives too. The General Assembly of the United Nations set out a list of goals to cease various global health problems by 2030, including as the TB epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reliably assess how the world copes with its public health initiatives, appropriate data collection and research will become increasingly important as we step into the public health challenges of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/25/has-the-european-union-met-its-targets-for-reducing-tuberculosis-fatalities/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Has the European Union met its targets for reducing tuberculosis fatalities?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Clarissa Wright</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">US energy agency asked scientists to scrub references to climate change</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/z-Ry92fUFwE/nature.2017.22513"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22513</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers were told to censor descriptions of projects funded by a Department of Energy laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22513&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22513&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/z-Ry92fUFwE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dinosaur trio roosted together like birds</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/HpL1qySDefg/nature.2017.22508"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22508</id>
		<updated>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The animals seem to have died while huddling together 70 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 510 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22508&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22508&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/HpL1qySDefg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Traci Watson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s what the &lt;em&gt;Science News&lt;/em&gt; family did for the eclipse</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/heres-what-science-news-family-did-eclipse"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/heres-what-science-news-family-did-eclipse</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T21:16:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 On August 21, 2017, the path of a total solar eclipse went coast to coast across the United States. Here are our dispatches.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">On social media, privacy is no longer a personal choice</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/social-media-privacy-no-longer-personal-choice"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/social-media-privacy-no-longer-personal-choice</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T19:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Data from the now-defunct social platform Friendster show that even people not on social media have predictable qualities.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Nitty-gritty of Homo naledi’s diet revealed in its teeth</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nitty-gritty-homo-naledis-diet-revealed-its-teeth"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nitty-gritty-homo-naledis-diet-revealed-its-teeth</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient humanlike species ate something that damaged its teeth.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Given “wrong pathology slides,” heart journal retracts paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/24/given-wrong-pathology-slides-heart-journal-retracts-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51531</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T15:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A cardiology journal has retracted a paper after the authors were unable to provide correct pathology slides to replace the wrong ones submitted with the original manuscript. The paper is titled “Aortic Valve Endocarditis and Coronary Angiography With Cerebral Embolic Protection,” published on April 10, 2017 in The Journal of the American College of Cardiology: […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/24/given-wrong-pathology-slides-heart-journal-retracts-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Given “wrong pathology slides,” heart journal retracts paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Darwin’s Backyard’ chronicles naturalist’s homespun experiments</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/darwins-backyard-chronicles-naturalists-homespun-experiments"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/darwins-backyard-chronicles-naturalists-homespun-experiments</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In the new book Darwin’s Backyard, a biologist explores Charles Darwin’s family life, as well as four decades’ worth of his at-home experiments.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sid Perkins</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, NASA whipped up astronaut waste into rocket fuel</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-whipped-astronaut-waste-rocket-fuel"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-whipped-astronaut-waste-rocket-fuel</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In 1967, scientists found a way to turn human waste into rocket fuel.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Cassie Martin</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">What should a journal do when a scientist who committed misconduct submits a new paper?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/24/journal-scientist-committed-misconduct-submits-new-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51524</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T12:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;In December of last year, Chris Surridge found himself in a situation not uncommon to journal editors: A researcher who had been found to have committed misconduct had submitted a manuscript to the journal Surridge edits, Nature Plants. Retraction Watch readers may recall the name of the corresponding author, Patrice Dunoyer, who has had five papers […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/24/journal-scientist-committed-misconduct-submits-new-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What should a journal do when a scientist who committed misconduct submits a new paper?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Ecology is now accepting Registered Reports!</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/24/bmc-ecology-is-now-accepting-registered-reports/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9356</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T10:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/registered-620x204-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Registered Reports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under this format, peer review of an article is split into two distinct stages. In stage 1, a paper is submitted and assessed &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; data is actually collected; manuscripts contain only an Introduction and Methods section (along with any relevant pilot data). This allows reviewers to focus purely on assessing the clarity of the scientific question being asked, the feasibility of the proposed methodology to answer it, and the rigor of proposed analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a paper passes stage 1 review, authors are offered ‘in principle acceptance’ indicating that the article will be published pending successful completion of the study. Once data has been collected, results analysed, and conclusions drawn, papers enter stage 2 of the review process. Reviewers assess whether the approved research protocol has been adhered to and whether the conclusions drawn are justified by the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a research question is worth asking, the answers are worth publishing – whatever they are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For full details of how Registered Reports work (for both authors and reviewers) please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/about/registered-reports&quot;&gt;our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why use Registered Reports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several potential benefits to this novel approach to peer review. For one, it removes any temptation on behalf of reviewers and editors to judge a study purely on the perceived novelty or importance of the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been written about the negative ramifications of such an approach; both the possibility of methodologically lacking but ‘sexy’ studies being published, and the potential for methodologically strong studies with ‘negative’ results to struggle to be considered (or simply be kept in the file drawer). Registered Reports are focused on the idea that if a research question is worth asking, the answers are worth publishing – whatever they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Registered Report format also reduces any temptations (whether conscious or not) on the behalf of researchers to change their research hypothesis post-hoc to match their eventual results. The field of ecology is perhaps especially prone to such conscious or unconscious ‘harking’; ecological research often involves an initial explorative approach leading to observational and correlational evidence that can be potentially tweaked to support multiple hypotheses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is of course also a benefit to researchers in receiving feedback on their methodology while it is still possible to make adjustments. In the traditional review process, when researchers are presented with that overlooked weakness in their methodology it is all too late; their time (and limited funding) has been wasted on a flawed project. With Registered Reports, researchers can fine-tune their protocols with the benefit of expert feedback before setting out to gather the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ecologists as a field have shown considerable enthusiasm for innovations in peer review&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered Reports are not a new idea. Or at least not that new; over 50 journals, in a wide variety of biomedical fields, have begun to accept the format in recent years. Just within BMC, our sister journals &lt;em&gt;BMC Biology&lt;/em&gt; and (from today) &lt;em&gt;BMC Medicine&lt;/em&gt; accept Registered Reports (you might be interested in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/on-biology/2017/05/03/scientific-odyssey-pre-registering-voyage/&quot;&gt;eloquent explanation&lt;/a&gt; by the then Chief Editor of &lt;em&gt;BMC Biology&lt;/em&gt; of her thoughts on the benefits of Registered Reports).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; is the first journal within the BMC-series to consider Registered Reports; more importantly, we are also the first dedicated ecology journal to do so. Why do we feel the field of ecology is a good place to trial Registered Reports? Partly it is because ecologists as a field have shown considerable enthusiasm for innovations in peer review; for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peerageofscience.org/&quot;&gt;Peerage of Science&lt;/a&gt; and (the sadly now defunct) &lt;a href=&quot;https://axiosreview.org/&quot;&gt;Axios Review&lt;/a&gt; were heavily driven by ecologists (and both were strongly supported by &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this suggests that ecologists find the novelty-based criteria used by many journals to be an increasingly large drain on their time and are keen to look for ways to get their work published in a quicker and fairer way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7620&quot; style=&quot;width: 4330px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Josef Settele&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-7620&quot; height=&quot;3240&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2016/05/coll-with-net-2012_08_16_OR_P1190177_Josef_Settele.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4320&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Field researcher with butterfly net&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Josef Settele&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aware that the ecological community has specific needs that may entail changes to the ‘default’ Registered Reports format. As standard, we will stipulate a timeframe of one year between the end of stage 1 review/in principle acceptance and submission of the completed study and the beginning of stage 2 review. However, we are aware that for some studies (such as those involving multiple field seasons) this will not be feasible; we will be happy to discuss extending this period when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, we know that the nature of ecological research means that even the best research protocols may need to change when faced with the reality of field-work; problems will be encountered that to solve will require modifications to the proposed protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we will be happy for authors to modify their protocols, and present exploratory analyses that may be suggested by interim results (along with serendipitous findings), as long as these are clearly marked as such in the final paper (and of course if our reviewers agree the changes and additions are justified). Note also that the Introduction cannot be changed after data collection, ensuring that the initial rationale of the study is clearly presented to readers no matter the changes that occurred during the actual course of the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the idea of Registered Reports will not appeal to everyone, and we intend it to complement rather than supplant the ‘traditional’ peer review process. We see the inclusion of Registered Reports in &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; very much as an experiment in itself; we are excited about working with the ecology community to determine if this format can improve peer review to better meet their needs. We believe that this initiative will help improve the credibility and transparency of the review process and we hope that our enthusiasm is shared by the authors, reviewers, and readers of &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to enquire about any aspect of the Registered Reports review process, or have any feedback, please do get in touch with us: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/24/bmc-ecology-is-now-accepting-registered-reports/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Ecology is now accepting Registered Reports!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christopher Foote</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lazy bees and clean hyenas: Review finds that animals vary in trait conscientiousness</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/24/lazy-bees-and-clean-hyenas-review-finds-that-animals-vary-in-trait-conscientiousness/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29296</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T09:28:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-164307835.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29313&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29313&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;a bee sleeping over her basket&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;macintroll2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Bee sleeping&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Bee sleeping&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-164307835.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-164307835.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-164307835.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2097,1430&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/24/lazy-bees-and-clean-hyenas-review-finds-that-animals-vary-in-trait-conscientiousness/bee-sleeping/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-164307835.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conscientiousness is a fundamental aspect of human personality, with higher levels associated with all kinds of benefits, from greater academic achievement and relationship stability to living for longer.  Yet it’s the only major human personality dimension not to have been widely identified in animals, which poses an evolutionary puzzle – if animals don’t show signs of conscientiousness, where did the human variety come from? But now a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-18573-001&quot;&gt;major review&lt;/a&gt; of hundreds of relevant papers, published in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Bulletin&lt;/i&gt;, concludes that in fact, “there are many documented examples of conscientiousness behaviour in other animals”. The work also suggests that there are two main branches to conscientiousness, each associated with an evolutionary drive to solve different types of problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29296&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this new research, the only clear evidence for animal conscientiousness was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0003347214004722&quot;&gt;a study of chimpanzees&lt;/a&gt; and a report of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16594834&quot;&gt;aspects of conscientiousness in a group of captive orangutans&lt;/a&gt;. Based on this limited data, some researchers suggested that conscientiousness evolved after the last common ancestor of chimps and humans diverged from other ape species, 7 to 10 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their new review, Mikel Delgado and Frank Sulloway at the University of California, Berkeley, looked for indirect evidence of animal conscientiousness, searching nearly 3,000 potentially relevant papers for any of 103 trait terms related to conscientiousness in descriptions of animal behaviour consistent with how it’s characterised in people (there are six facets to human conscientiousness including orderliness, dutifulness, competence and achievement striving).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers identified 876 papers that provided “strong” or “possible” evidence of animal conscientiousness. For example, in searching on the trait term “achievement”, they identified research showing that cows’ heart rates are higher when they’re learning. In searching on “lazy”, they found reports of trainers’ descriptions of some horses, and also work on variations in the willingness of bees to protect a hive. And in a search on “appearance” (which falls under the facet of “order”), they found a study that rated hyenas as appearing “attractive”, “clean” or “scruffy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this, the researchers identified two categories of conscientious behaviour in animals: the first includes the traits of achievement striving and competence; the second includes order, industriousness and responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delgado and Sulloway found that primates and other mammals are much more similar to each other than they are to other animal groups, particularly in scoring positively on the first conscientiousness category. In contrast, birds, insects and fish stood out for having positive scores on the second. Amphibians/reptiles and other invertebrates had neutral or low scores on both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notwithstanding some inconsistencies, the results…closely parallel the known phylogenetic relationship of the taxa involved,” they note. The noticeable exception was the placement of insects, which might have been expected to lie closer to other invertebrates than to birds and fish; the reason for this anomaly could be the relatively high number of studies of social insects, which have evolved caste systems and worker instincts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two categories of conscientious traits may have evolved separately to solve at least two different sets of problems, the researchers added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order/industriousness/responsibility category seems to relate to the building of nests or other protective structures, and colony life, and there are hints that at least some of these traits bring clear benefits – blackbirds with neat and tidy nests are better at rejecting foreign eggs, for example, and bees that remove more dead bodies from their hives gain more weight and rear more young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other category, focused on achievement striving and competence, relates more to intelligent behaviour generally and is important for an animal’s ability to cope with the demands of living in a group. So it’s possible that an increasingly complex social environment drove the development of this set of traits, Delgado and Sulloway write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We should be somewhat cautious in accepting these results as an actual phylogenetic model for the evolution of conscientiousness,” they add. “Nevertheless, the remarkably close parallel between the known phylogenetic record…and the results of our own study…suggest that the relationship is not coincidental and that the evolution of conscientiousness has closely tracked the increasing complexity of biological evolution more generally.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all conscientiousness-related traits that have been identified in people could be picked up in animals. Thanks to our advanced ability to work out what others are thinking, and to use language, we seem to be unique in feeling and demonstrating “dutifulness”, “conventionality”, “traditionalism” and “virtue”. In fact, because research on conscientiousness in people has so often focused on emotions, intentions and morality, rather than behaviours, this may explain why it hasn’t been picked up in a variety of animals before, Delgado and Sulloway suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important limitation of the new review, acknowledged by the authors, is that human biases may affect the labels that researchers give to animal behaviours. Are some insects really “orderly”, for example, rather than “competent” or “self-controlled”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the pair felt able to conclude, “We have found ample evidence that building blocks for the personality dimension of conscientiousness exist across species, from insects to primates, even if this domain of behaviour sometimes expresses itself differently in other animals than it does in humans.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-18573-001&quot;&gt;Attributes of conscientiousness throughout the animal kingdom: An empirical and evolutionary overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29296/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29296/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29296&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">3 facts about gender equality in science and health</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-facts-about-gender-equality-in-science-and-health"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-facts-about-gender-equality-in-science-and-health</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T09:25:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier’s information analytics reveal surprising insights about the role of women in the global research landscape</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">How do animals respond to human disturbance?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/24/how-do-animals-respond-to-human-disturbance/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9443</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T08:10:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/P4130140-2-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humans have altered natural environments in profound and permanent ways. Indeed, various forms of human disturbance, including habitat destruction, an influx of trash, noise pollution, or introduced species, represent the primary threat to many species worldwide. Understanding how animals respond to these environmental changes is key for predicting the future survival of key species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study we studied the effects of urbanization on native finches in the Galapagos Islands. The Galapagos have a well-known place in the heart and history of biology; Charles Darwin’s visit there in 1835 helped inspire his theory of evolution. The islands also present a great opportunity to study urbanization because unlike most Pacific archipelagos, the Galapagos were uninhabited until relatively recently. However, tourism and development on the islands has increased dramatically in the past 50 years, which creates new challenges for the native species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9444&quot; style=&quot;width: 435px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sabrina McNew &quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9444 &quot; height=&quot;283&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/DSC_0239-2-1024x683.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sabrina McNew &quot; width=&quot;425&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Boats moored near the fisherman’s dock in Puerto Ayora (Sabrina McNew, CC)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to investigate if finches near Puerto Ayora, the urban center of Santa Cruz Island, were different than finches living in a more undisturbed habitat about 10km away. We studied two species at each site: the medium ground finch (&lt;em&gt;Geospiza fortis&lt;/em&gt;) and the small ground finch (&lt;em&gt;Geospiza fuliginosa&lt;/em&gt;), both of which are part of the group of 18 or so species collectively known as “Darwin’s finches.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is “epigenetics?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally in evolutionary biology it’s assumed that for populations to change in response to the environment, selection must act on standing genetic variation. That is, certain genotypes are better suited to the new environment and so they will survive longer and have more offspring. However, the accumulation and spread of mutations that confer an advantage can be a slow and random process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new and exciting mechanism of adaptation to new environments involves “epigenetics.” These processes refer to molecular changes that affect when and how genes are expressed and can alter the phenotype of the organism independent of its DNA sequence. In this study we focused on DNA methylation, an epigenetic modification that can affect gene expression and, in some cases, is passed on to offspring. Importantly, other studies have found that DNA methylation can be affected by the environment, which means it’s a potential process by which animals can rapidly respond to changing environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could epigenetics be playing a part in the response of Darwin’s finches to urbanization? To find out we tested for DNA methylation variation, as well as morphological and genetic variation, between urban and rural populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did we find? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9445&quot; style=&quot;width: 374px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9445 &quot; height=&quot;273&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/beach-1024x768.jpg&quot; width=&quot;364&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The landscape of El Garrapatero, our “rural” site (Sabrina McNew, CC)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one of our two species, the medium ground finch, we saw that urban finches were bigger in nearly all measurements than rural finches, potentially due to an increase in food resources near Puerto Ayora. Small ground finches, however, showed no differences in size between the urban and rural sites. We’re not sure why we only found morphological differences in the medium ground finch; however, it could be due to the fact that medium ground finches are generally more variable in size and so selection would likely act faster on this species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did not find any genetic differences between urban and rural populations. These results are consistent with previous studies that find little genetic variation in Darwin’s finch populations and species. Interestingly, however, we found striking epigenetic differences between urban and rural populations for both species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does this matter? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biological studies are just beginning to study epigenetics in wild populations. Although we can’t be certain how the DNA methylation changes we observed affect the way the birds look or act, it’s exciting to find that there is epigenetic variation between two geographically close populations. This is a first step in understanding if epigenetics is key to adaptation to rapidly changing environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/24/how-do-animals-respond-to-human-disturbance/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How do animals respond to human disturbance?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sabrina McNew</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rumours swell over new kind of gravitational-wave sighting</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/iaN4hbCMGhI/nature.2017.22482"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22482</id>
		<updated>2017-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Gossip over potential detection of colliding neutron stars has astronomers in a tizzy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22482&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/iaN4hbCMGhI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Davide Castelvecchi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Meet the Bobcat Nanowagon, the world’s smallest monster truck</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/meet-bobcat-nanowagon-worlds-smallest-monster-truck"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/meet-bobcat-nanowagon-worlds-smallest-monster-truck</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T21:21:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Chemists are scratching their heads over the wreckage of minuscule monster trucks.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Patience is one virtue scientists must embrace</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/patience-one-virtue-scientists-must-embrace"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/patience-one-virtue-scientists-must-embrace</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T20:01:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses how being patient isn't always easy in scientific work.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inquiries about the moon's twilight zone, and more reader feedback</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/inquiries-about-moons-twilight-zone-and-more-reader-feedback"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/inquiries-about-moons-twilight-zone-and-more-reader-feedback</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T20:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers had questions about the moon's tidal locking, quantum communication, microneedles and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_7809828481992294=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">As Cassini’s tour of Saturn draws to a close, a look back at postcards from the probe</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-cassini-curtain-call"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-cassini-curtain-call</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T19:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 As Cassini prepares to plunge to its death, we celebrate the spacecraft's discoveries and breathtaking images of Saturn, its rings and moons.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Former MD Anderson researcher objects to retraction of his paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/former-md-anderson-researcher-objects-retraction-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51518</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T15:00:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A cell biology journal has retracted a 2016 paper after an investigation revealed that the corresponding author failed to include two co-authors and acknowledge the funding source. According to the retraction notice, the Journal of Cellular Physiology retracted the paper after the University of Texas, MD Anderson Cancer Center found that last author Jin Wang […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/former-md-anderson-researcher-objects-retraction-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Former MD Anderson researcher objects to retraction of his paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This ancient sea worm sported a crowd of ‘claws’ around its mouth</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-sea-worm-mouth-claws"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-sea-worm-mouth-claws</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newly discovered species of arrow worm that lived over half a billion years ago had about twice as many head spines as its modern kin.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Data had been manipulated,” again: Swiss probe prompts two more retractions</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/data-manipulated-swiss-probe-prompts-two-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51511</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T12:00:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A biologist at the University of Basel is retracting two papers, citing data manipulation uncovered during an institutional investigation. That investigation has already led to the retraction of a paper in Science Translational Medicine by some of the same authors earlier this year. The two latest retractions, in the Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC), share […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/data-manipulated-swiss-probe-prompts-two-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Data had been manipulated,” again: Swiss probe prompts two more retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Seeing one picture at a time helps kids learn words from books</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/seeing-one-picture-time-helps-kids-learn-words-books"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/seeing-one-picture-time-helps-kids-learn-words-books</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T11:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A small study found that children were better able to pick up vocabulary from books that show only one picture at a time.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T11:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Whether you snack or not is more about the presence of temptation than your willpower</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/23/whether-you-snack-or-not-is-more-about-the-presence-of-temptation-than-your-willpower/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29177</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T10:33:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy1&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-29268&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29268&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=403&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;403,400&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/23/whether-you-snack-or-not-is-more-about-the-presence-of-temptation-than-your-willpower/giphy1/&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=300&amp;amp;h=298&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re in the coffee shop and you watch your hand pick up the muffin and place it on your tray, how much of this was down to the situation, and how much to do with your (lack of) willpower or your long-term intentions? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12259/full?hootPostID=3f60ab0b40a8aad5d21ca2cae3244883&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; compared these influences and found that momentary cues, such as seeing someone else snacking, were more strongly associated with how much people snacked than their own baseline psychological traits and intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29177&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the scene for their research, Katherine Elliston at the University of Tasmania and her colleagues said that in Australia, around 30 to 41 per cent of people’s daily energy intake comes from snacking rather than from proper meals. This makes the psychology of snacking an important part of helping people to avoid over-eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers recruited 61 participants (42 women) through social media and flyers and asked them to complete a range of baseline psychological measures, including how much they think about the costs and benefits of healthy eating as occurring sooner rather than later (this comes from “Temporal Self-regulation Theory” – people are less likely to eat healthily when they see the benefits as distant and the costs as imminent); they also rated their intentions to eat more healthily; reported how often they’d eaten five fruit and veg per day recently; and rated their powers of self-regulation and willpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, for the next two weeks, the participants used an app to record any times that they ate food, and whether it was a snack (high or low energy) or a main meal. Sometimes they were also prompted at this point to record any situational cues relevant to snacking, such as: whether snacks were currently available; whether they were in a bad mood; whether they could see anyone else snacking; whether they were near a fast food shop. The app also beeped at random times through the day and asked the participants to record the presence of any of these same situational cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the participants recorded eating a total of 1127 snacks across the two-week study period. They reported the presence of other people snacking more often when they had just logged their own snacking than during times they weren’t snacking (i.e. when they were prompted randomly by the app), indicating a possible causal role for this situational cue, though the current design can’t prove this. The same pattern was also true for being in a bad mood and having snacks available and easily accessible – these were present more often during snacking than during random prompts when not eating, suggesting these cues may have contributed to snacking. Proximity to food outlets didn’t appear to be a relevant factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intentions and past healthy eating behaviour were not associated with the odds of snacking. Seeing the costs of healthy eating as coming early, before eating, was associated with more snacking. Lower self regulation was also associated with more high energy snacking overall, but these baseline measures were less strongly associated with snacking than momentary cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers said their study represented a successful application of Temporal Self-regulation Theory to explain snacking. “The results demonstrate that snacking is largely guided by momentary cues and that motivational-level factors may be less important in guiding snacking than previously thought,” they said, adding that helping people combat stress and low mood, and reducing the availability of snacks, could help people eat fewer unhealthy snacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings add to previous research that has shown that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/10/18/is-willpower-overrated/&quot;&gt;goal attainment&lt;/a&gt; and healthy behaviour is more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/01/03/already-struggling-to-keep-new-year-resolutions-heres-the-first-detailed-study-of-daily-temptation-and-resistance/&quot;&gt;avoiding temptation&lt;/a&gt; in the first place than exercising iron willpower. Avoid going to the cafe that sells those amazing muffins, especially when you’re in a bad mood, and you’ll probably find you snack on them less. This sounds simple enough, but unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2009/12/10/step-away-from-the-cookie-jar-over-confidence-in-self-control-leads-us-to-temptation/&quot;&gt;we have a tendency to overestimate our willpower&lt;/a&gt; – especially when we’re not hungry, we forget how tempting snacks can be when we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12259/full?hootPostID=3f60ab0b40a8aad5d21ca2cae3244883&quot;&gt;Personal and situational predictors of everyday snacking: An application of temporal self-regulation theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/akbZyUgsLW69q/download&quot;&gt;giphy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29177/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29177/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29177&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">New on Science Exchange: Nobel-worthy Nanosensors, MacroDSF, Fluidigm, and More</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/08/new-on-science-exchange-nobel-worthy-nanosensors-macrodsf-fluidigm-and-more/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1116</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T02:30:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nobel-worthy nanosensors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In 2007, Charles Lieber, the Harvard scientist who many say is in the running for a Nobel prize, co-founded &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/vista-nanobiosciences&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to enable drug discovery researchers to use his team’s nanosensor technologies for label-free, ultrasensitive detection of proteins, nucleic acids, and even single viral particles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_1118&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Functionalized-nanowires-vista-nanobiosciences.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Functionalized Nanowires Vista NanoBioSciences&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1118 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Functionalized-nanowires-vista-nanobiosciences-300x193.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences’ ultrasensitive biomarker detection platform (left) uses functionalized nanowires (“NW”) that respond to interactions with individual biomolecules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Vista NanoBioSensor&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1117&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Vista-NanoBioSensor-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Now available through Science Exchange, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/vista-nanobiosciences&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; offers biomarker assays using its portable NanoBioSensor™ and BioTracker™ platforms. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista’s NanoBioSensor precisely detects and measures biomarkers in a finger-stick drop of blood, other bodily fluid, or tissue culture – without labeling and in less than 10 minutes. Vista’s BioTracker provides continuous monitoring of dynamic changes in the targeted analytes of any biological material.  Both devices are portable, exhibiting very high sensitivity (10³&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; increase over ELISA), high specificity, across multiple logs of concentration, in real time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taking the pain out of protein purification with MacroDSF&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Empowered by high-throughput protein purification and structure determination technologies, structure-based drug discovery is enjoying a resurgence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/novalix&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NovAliX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a new provider on the Science Exchange network, gives you access to the ProteoPlex MacroDSF platform, an exciting tool for rapidly optimizing conditions for protein purification and crystallization. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The instrument quickly optimizes  protein concentration, pH value, salt, buffer, stabilizing additive, etc — potentially increasing a purified protein’s stability or even the resolution of its crystal structure!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/novalix&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NovAliX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; also offers a broad range of biophysical characterization services to provide a complete picture of the protein of interest. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fluidigm custom assay development&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Interested in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fluidigm&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fluidigm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;’s powerful mass cytometry and microfluidics platforms, but lack the resources to design the perfect assay? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Now you can take advantage of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fluidigm&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fluidigm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;’s expertise using the company’s own team of assay development scientists. Through Science Exchange, you can order custom assays for Fluidigm’s CyTOF®, Helios®, and integrated fluidic circuit-based platforms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Oncology, from ABL1 to ZAP70&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Based in Freiburg, Germany, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/proqinase&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ProQinase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; has been supporting oncology research for 16 years. Now on Science Exchange, ProQinase offers biochemical assay services (such as kinase screens), cellular assay services (such as proliferation, invasion and spheroid assays), and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; assay services (including immuno-oncology and metastasis models). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The scientific staff at ProQinase are thought leaders in oncology research. At the 2017 AACR Annual Meeting, they presented a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proqinase.com/sites/default/files/public/uploads/Poster/muellerd_aacr_washington_2017_web.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;novel assay platform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to distinguish ATP-competitive from non-ATP-competitive kinase inhibitors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Medicinal chemistry and process optimization&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you’re looking for a full-service laboratory to execute your chemistry projects, you’ll be happy to see the addition of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/kalexsyn-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Kalexsyn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a chemical synthesis powerhouse based in Michigan, U.S.A, to the Science Exchange network.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Whether it’s developing novel scaffolds, SAR, modification of complex natural products or challenging macrocyclic peptides, Kalexsyn’s deep bench of Ph.D. chemists provides IP-enabling expertise. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Kalexsyn team has produced over 1000 publications and patents and has served over 85 pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Connect with a new provider today!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you new to Science Exchange? &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.scienceexchange.com/hc/en-us&quot;&gt;See how it works.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-23T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">US science envoy resigns in protest at Trump policies</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Cq0yC1-wSV8/nature.2017.22510"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22510</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Energy researcher Daniel Kammen faults US president’s positions on climate change and energy and his failure to condemn white supremacists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 509 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22510&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22510&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Cq0yC1-wSV8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists solve mystery of US Civil War submarine</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/lxioyUaroXQ/nature.2017.22447"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22447</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Blast from  Hunley ’s own torpedo probably killed its crew instantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 511 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22447&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22447&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/lxioyUaroXQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ben Upton</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Creeping earth could hold secret to deadly landslides</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/mVr4AxrE56E/548384a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548384a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists investigate why mountain slopes can slip slowly for years and then suddenly speed up, with potentially fatal effects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 384 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548384a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548384a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/mVr4AxrE56E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jane Palmer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How machine learning could help to improve climate forecasts</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pHjg_VOuCaI/548379a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548379a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Mixing artificial intelligence with climate science helps researchers to identify previously unknown atmospheric processes and rank climate models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 379 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548379a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548379a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pHjg_VOuCaI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nicola Jones</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Oldest ice, censorship row and Yemen’s cholera emergency</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/-gTsvEYu410/548376a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548376a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 18–24 August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 376 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548376a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548376a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/-gTsvEYu410&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Magnetic antiparticle expands strange field of swirling science</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/RRofz08sECg/548371b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548371b</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Antiskyrmion offers promise for superfast spintronic computers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 371 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548371b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548371b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/RRofz08sECg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Kinetic analysis of a complete nitrifier reveals an oligotrophic lifestyle</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MiDavezW6FM/nature23679"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23679</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Nitrification, the oxidation of ammonia (NH3) via nitrite (NO2−) to nitrate (NO3−), is a key process of the biogeochemical nitrogen cycle. For decades, ammonia and nitrite oxidation were thought to be separately catalysed by ammonia-oxidizing bacteria (AOB) and archaea (AOA), and by nitrite-oxidizing bacteria (NOB). The recent discovery of complete ammonia oxidizers (comammox) in the NOB genus Nitrospira, which alone convert ammonia to nitrate, raised questions about the ecological niches in which comammox Nitrospira successfully compete with canonical nitrifiers. Here we isolate a pure culture of a comammox bacterium, Nitrospira inopinata, and show that it is adapted to slow growth in oligotrophic and dynamic habitats on the basis of a high affinity for ammonia, low maximum rate of ammonia oxidation, high growth yield compared to canonical nitrifiers, and genomic potential for alternative metabolisms. The nitrification kinetics of four AOA from soil and hot springs were determined for comparison. Their surprisingly poor substrate affinities and lower growth yields reveal that, in contrast to earlier assumptions, AOA are not necessarily the most competitive ammonia oxidizers present in strongly oligotrophic environments and that N. inopinata has the highest substrate affinity of all analysed ammonia oxidizer isolates except the marine AOA Nitrosopumilus maritimus SCM1 (ref. 3). These results suggest a role for comammox organisms in nitrification under oligotrophic and dynamic conditions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23679&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23679&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MiDavezW6FM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>K. Dimitri Kits</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Feedback regulation of steady-state epithelial turnover and organ size</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1ivPFJXtHQM/nature23678"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23678</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Epithelial organs undergo steady-state turnover throughout adult life, with old cells being continually replaced by the progeny of stem cell divisions. To avoid hyperplasia or atrophy, organ turnover demands strict equilibration of cell production and loss. However, the mechanistic basis of this equilibrium is unknown. Here we show that robustly precise turnover of the adult Drosophila intestine arises through a coupling mechanism in which enterocyte apoptosis breaks feedback inhibition of stem cell division. Healthy enterocytes inhibit stem cell division through E-cadherin, which prevents secretion of mitogenic epidermal growth factors (EGFs) by repressing transcription of the EGF maturation factor rhomboid. Individual apoptotic enterocytes promote divisions by loss of E-cadherin, which releases cadherin-associated β-catenin (Armadillo in Drosophila) and p120-catenin to induce rhomboid. Induction of rhomboid in the dying enterocyte triggers activation of the EGF receptor (Egfr) in stem cells within a discrete radius. When we blocked apoptosis, E-cadherin-controlled feedback suppressed divisions, and the organ retained the same number of cells. When we disrupted feedback, apoptosis and divisions were uncoupled, and the organ developed either hyperplasia or atrophy. Together, our results show that robust cellular balance hinges on the obligate coupling of divisions to apoptosis, which limits the proliferative potential of a stem cell to the precise time and place at which a replacement cell is needed. In this way, localized cell–cell communication gives rise to tissue-level homeostatic equilibrium and constant organ size. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23678&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23678&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1ivPFJXtHQM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jackson Liang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Public antibodies to malaria antigens generated by two LAIR1 insertion modalities</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5X5tA0lok3o/nature23670"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23670</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 In two previously described donors, the extracellular domain of LAIR1, a collagen-binding inhibitory receptor encoded on chromosome 19 (ref. 1), was inserted between the V and DJ segments of an antibody. This insertion generated, through somatic mutations, broadly reactive antibodies against RIFINs, a type of variant antigen expressed on the surface of Plasmodium falciparum-infected erythrocytes. To investigate how frequently such antibodies are produced in response to malaria infection, we screened plasma from two large cohorts of individuals living in malaria-endemic regions. Here we report that 5–10% of malaria-exposed individuals, but none of the European blood donors tested, have high levels of LAIR1-containing antibodies that dominate the response to infected erythrocytes without conferring enhanced protection against febrile malaria. By analysing the antibody-producing B cell clones at the protein, cDNA and gDNA levels, we characterized additional LAIR1 insertions between the V and DJ segments and discovered a second insertion modality whereby the LAIR1 exon encoding the extracellular domain and flanking intronic sequences are inserted into the switch region. By exon shuffling, this mechanism leads to the production of bispecific antibodies in which the LAIR1 domain is precisely positioned at the elbow between the VH and CH1 domains. Additionally, in one donor the genomic DNA encoding the VH and CH1 domains was deleted, leading to the production of a camel-like LAIR1-containing antibody. Sequencing of the switch regions of memory B cells from European blood donors revealed frequent templated inserts originating from transcribed genes that, in rare cases, comprised exons with orientations and frames compatible with expression. These results reveal different modalities of LAIR1 insertion that lead to public and dominant antibodies against infected erythrocytes and suggest that insertion of templated DNA represents an additional mechanism of antibody diversification that can be selected in the immune response against pathogens and exploited for B cell engineering. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23670&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23670&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5X5tA0lok3o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kathrin Pieper</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Homeostatic control of metabolic and functional fitness of Treg cells by LKB1 signalling</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/podmlYvf7Bw/nature23665"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23665</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Regulatory T cells (Treg cells) have a pivotal role in the establishment and maintenance of immunological self-tolerance and homeostasis. Transcriptional programming of regulatory mechanisms facilitates the functional activation of Treg cells in the prevention of diverse types of inflammatory responses. It remains unclear how Treg cells orchestrate their homeostasis and interplay with environmental signals. Here we show that liver kinase B1 (LKB1) programs the metabolic and functional fitness of Treg cells in the control of immune tolerance and homeostasis. Mice with a Treg-specific deletion of LKB1 developed a fatal inflammatory disease characterized by excessive TH2-type-dominant responses. LKB1 deficiency disrupted Treg cell survival and mitochondrial fitness and metabolism, but also induced aberrant expression of immune regulatory molecules including the negative co-receptor PD-1 and the TNF receptor superfamily proteins GITR and OX40. Unexpectedly, LKB1 function in Treg cells was independent of conventional AMPK signalling or the mTORC1–HIF-1α axis, but contributed to the activation of β-catenin signalling for the control of PD-1 and TNF receptor proteins. Blockade of PD-1 activity reinvigorated the ability of LKB1-deficient Treg cells to suppress TH2 responses and the interplay with dendritic cells primed by thymic stromal lymphopoietin. Thus, Treg cells use LKB1 signalling to coordinate their metabolic and immunological homeostasis and to prevent apoptotic and functional exhaustion, thereby orchestrating the balance between immunity and tolerance. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23665&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23665&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/podmlYvf7Bw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kai Yang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lhx6-positive GABA-releasing neurons of the zona incerta promote sleep</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1IA_uAjrOm4/nature23663"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23663</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Multiple populations of wake-promoting neurons have been characterized in mammals, but few sleep-promoting neurons have been identified. Wake-promoting cell types include hypocretin and GABA (γ-aminobutyric-acid)-releasing neurons of the lateral hypothalamus, which promote the transition to wakefulness from non-rapid eye movement (NREM) and rapid eye movement (REM) sleep. Here we show that a subset of GABAergic neurons in the mouse ventral zona incerta, which express the LIM homeodomain factor Lhx6 and are activated by sleep pressure, both directly inhibit wake-active hypocretin and GABAergic cells in the lateral hypothalamus and receive inputs from multiple sleep–wake-regulating neurons. Conditional deletion of Lhx6 from the developing diencephalon leads to decreases in both NREM and REM sleep. Furthermore, selective activation and inhibition of Lhx6-positive neurons in the ventral zona incerta bidirectionally regulate sleep time in adult mice, in part through hypocretin-dependent mechanisms. These studies identify a GABAergic subpopulation of neurons in the ventral zona incerta that promote sleep. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23663&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1IA_uAjrOm4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kai Liu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Heart disease: Putative medicines that mimic mutations</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/IgCeFa4azAA/nature23544"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23544</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Molecules that block the activity or production of the protein ANGPTL3 have now been found to lower blood levels of lipoproteins and cholesterol in mice and healthy humans, mimicking the protective effects of genetic mutations in ANGPTL3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23544&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23544&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/IgCeFa4azAA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sekar Kathiresan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Plant science: Sexual attraction channelled in moss</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/xBfiK5KzFeE/nature23543"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23543</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;An analysis reveals that both sexual reproduction and early-embryo development in the moss  Physcomitrella patens  are controlled by cellular calcium influxes through ion-channel proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23543&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23543&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/xBfiK5KzFeE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonie Steinhorst</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A heterochromatin-dependent transcription machinery drives piRNA expression</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1taAGhmla0M/nature23482"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23482</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Nuclear small RNA pathways safeguard genome integrity by establishing transcription-repressing heterochromatin at transposable elements. This inevitably also targets the transposon-rich source loci of the small RNAs themselves. How small RNA source loci are efficiently transcribed while transposon promoters are potently silenced is not understood. Here we show that, in Drosophila, transcription of PIWI-interacting RNA (piRNA) clusters—small RNA source loci in animal gonads—is enforced through RNA polymerase II pre-initiation complex formation within repressive heterochromatin. This is accomplished through Moonshiner, a paralogue of a basal transcription factor IIA (TFIIA) subunit, which is recruited to piRNA clusters via the heterochromatin protein-1 variant Rhino. Moonshiner triggers transcription initiation within piRNA clusters by recruiting the TATA-box binding protein (TBP)-related factor TRF2, an animal TFIID core variant. Thus, transcription of heterochromatic small RNA source loci relies on direct recruitment of the core transcriptional machinery to DNA via histone marks rather than sequence motifs, a concept that we argue is a recurring theme in evolution. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23482&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1taAGhmla0M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter Refsing Andersen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Excerpts from the 100-day food diary of Angela Meyer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BLFscFeCLY8/548494a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548494a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The road to change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 494 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548494a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548494a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BLFscFeCLY8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Beth Cato</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neurobiology: Diversity reaches the stars</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Ry5HpToYKHw/548396a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548396a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Cells called astrocytes promote and maintain neuronal function. The discovery that astrocytes vary in their gene expression, protein levels, cellular structure and function suggests that they are specialized to support distinct circuits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 396 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548396a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548396a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Ry5HpToYKHw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura E. Clarke</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Patrick Bateson (1938–2017)</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/H1Rnb3zv10E/548394a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548394a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Biologist who unravelled how animal behaviour develops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 394 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548394a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548394a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/H1Rnb3zv10E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kevin N. Laland</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Water management: Signing up to safe water for billions</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/80G0X6nZAh8/548393d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393d</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 393 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548393d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/80G0X6nZAh8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quentin Grafton</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientific journals: Rename the impact factor</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Hs5Gvpl5X54/548393c"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393c</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 393 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548393c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Hs5Gvpl5X54&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ajit Varki</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Counterfeit reagents: Fake serum has telltale fingerprint</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/nA4JOgjVOhc/548393b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393b</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 393 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548393b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/nA4JOgjVOhc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Robert Curry</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">UK regulations: Could fracking creep under the radar?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xqT3BFjKv6E/548393a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393a</id>
		<updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 393 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548393a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548393a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xqT3BFjKv6E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Smythe</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T17:00:29+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New antennas are up to a hundredth the size of today’s devices</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antennas-are-hundredth-size-todays-devices"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antennas-are-hundredth-size-todays-devices</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new type of antenna could be used in tiny electronics for wearable tech, injectable medical devices and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These chip-sized spacecraft are the smallest space probes yet</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-chip-sized-spacecraft-are-smallest-space-probes-yet"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-chip-sized-spacecraft-are-smallest-space-probes-yet</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T17:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Space initiative dubbed Breakthrough Starshot sent the smallest spacecraft yet into orbit around Earth.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_014267166549842503=0.6379469869378208</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T11:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Birth control research is moving beyond the pill</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/birth-control-research-moving-beyond-pill"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/birth-control-research-moving-beyond-pill</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T16:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 After decades of research, reproductive biologists are on the verge of developing new birth control options that stop sperm from maturing or save a woman's eggs for later.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_014267166549842503=0.6379469869378208</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T11:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Hey, that’s my case study: Another retraction after doctors claim rights to case write-up</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/hey-thats-case-study-another-retraction-doctors-claim-rights-case-write/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51505</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T14:30:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A group of researchers have retracted their 2016 case report about a rare dermatologic disorder in the wake of disputes about authorship and institutional approval. The paper describes a young boy with Job’s Syndrome, in which patients experience painful, itchy and frequently disfiguring skin lesions, along with a constellation of other possible symptoms. The condition […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/hey-thats-case-study-another-retraction-doctors-claim-rights-case-write/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hey, that’s my case study: Another retraction after doctors claim rights to case write-up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Some secrets of China’s terra-cotta army are baked in the clay</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-terra-cotta-army-clay"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-terra-cotta-army-clay</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T13:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Specialized production system lay behind the famous terra-cotta troops found in ancient Chinese emperor’s tomb.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_014267166549842503=0.6379469869378208</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T11:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">There is no such thing as the true self, but it’s still a useful psychological concept</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/22/there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-true-self-but-its-still-a-useful-psychological-concept/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29100</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T12:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-492740240.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29170&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29170&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sliced human head shaped onion on chopping board&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;crispy_fish_images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Layers of personality&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Layers of personality&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3317,2197&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/22/there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-true-self-but-its-still-a-useful-psychological-concept/layers-of-personality/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think you are truly mean, you have sad eyes” Tormund Giantsbane ponders the true self of Sandor ‘The Hound’ Clegane in &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones, Beyond The Wall&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are you really? Is there a “true you” beneath the masquerade? According to a trio of psychologists and philosophers &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691616689495&quot;&gt;writing in &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the idea that we each have a hidden true or authentic self is an incredibly common folk belief, and moreover, the way most of us think about these true selves is remarkably consistent, even across different cultures, from Westeros to Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the concept of a true self useful because it helps explain many of the judgments we make about ourselves and others. Yet, from a scientific perspective, there is actually no such thing as the true self. “The notion that there are especially authentic parts of the self, and that these parts can remain cloaked from view indefinitely, borders on the superstitious,” write Nina Strohminger and her colleagues at Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29100&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way that psychologists have investigated people’s views of the true self is to ask them to consider that a person has changed in various ways – either their memories, or their preferences, or their morals, or their personality, for example – and then ask them after which change has the person’s true self most been altered. The results are incredibly consistent: people most consider that the true self has been altered if a person’s moral sense is changed. In other words, most of us believe that the true self is the moral self.  This also manifests in the common reluctance we have to consider taking hypothetical drugs that might alter our moral judgments (more so than our reluctance to take drugs that would alter our personality, for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to this, explain Strohminger and her co-authors, is that most of us seem to be biased to see our own and other people’s true selves as essentially good. When a bad person turns good, we see this as their true self emerging. Conversely, if a good person turns bad, this is because circumstances have conspired to constrain or corrupt their true self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the normal bias most of us have to assume we are better than average disappears when it comes to the true self: that is, we see both our own and other people’s true selves in a similar, very positive light. “It is worth emphasising just how striking this discrepancy is” write Strohminger and co. “One of the most ubiquitous effects in the self literature – actor-observer valence asymmetry – fails to obtain for true self attribution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These widespread assumptions that the true self is moral and good is remarkably consistent across cultures: even Hindu Indians and Buddhist Tibetans see moral aspects of a person as especially central to their identity, even though the latter group deny that there is such a thing as the self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assumptions we hold about the true self also help explain the judgments we make about other people’s behaviour. For instance, if a person’s emotions lead them to behave badly, we judge them less harshly, presumably because we assume their true self was led astray. Conversely, if a person’s emotions lead them to behave admirably, our praise for them is undiminished, presumably because in this case we assume their virtuous true self was at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the concept of a true self is useful in terms of understanding people’s judgments and behaviour. And we can speculate and investigate why most of us think about the true self in the ways that we do: for example, perhaps we’ve evolved to see the human true self as fundamentally good because assuming the best in others helps foster social ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on the question of whether there really is such a thing as a true self, Strohminger and her colleagues are sceptical. They point out that views on the true self are highly subjective and skewed by our own judgments of what is good (psychopaths, for instance, see morality as less central to identity presumably because morals are less important to them). Our beliefs about the true self also seem “evidence-insensitive” – claims made about the true self “may completely contradict all available data”. The authors conclude: “These two features – radical subjectivity and unverifiability – prevent the true self from being a scientific concept.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691616689495&quot;&gt;The True Self: A Psychological Concept Distinct From the Self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29100/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29100/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29100&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">One way to boost your uni’s ranking: Ask faculty to cite each other</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/one-way-boost-unis-ranking-ask-faculty-cite/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51500</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T11:59:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Readers who follow scientific publishing will know the term “citation stacking” — as a profile-boosting technique, we’ve seen journals ask authors to cite them, and individual scientists work together to cite each other, forming “citation cartels.” And now, we’ve seen a university do it. A university in Malaysia has instructed its engineering faculty to cite […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/one-way-boost-unis-ranking-ask-faculty-cite/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;One way to boost your uni’s ranking: Ask faculty to cite each other&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-26T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">In pictures: Elsevierians experience the solar eclipse</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-pictures-elsevierians-watch-the-eclipse"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-pictures-elsevierians-watch-the-eclipse</id>
		<updated>2017-08-22T06:09:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In New York City, sharing the glory (and the glasses); in St. Louis — totality!</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Can you prevent memory loss and brain ageing?</title>
		<link href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/can-prevent-memory-loss-brain-ageing/"/>
		<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5077</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T23:51:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-5078&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/book-1659717_1280-1024x587.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here I take a look at some of the evidence linking education and occupation with better cognitive function in older age.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich lifetime experiences like higher education or engaging in mentally challenging occupations have a major influence on how you age cognitively. This is because mentally stimulating activities help build &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/what-is-cognitive-reserve-how-we-can-protect-our-brains-from-memory-loss-and-dementia-76591&quot;&gt;cognitive reserve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive reserve&lt;/em&gt; refers to the brain’s resilience or ability to cope despite damage or degeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor &lt;a href=&quot;http://sharpbrains.com/blog/2007/07/23/build-your-cognitive-reserve-yaakov-stern/&quot;&gt;Yaakov Stern&lt;/a&gt;, one of the earliest proponents of the notion, says individuals who lead mentally and physically stimulating lives have&lt;em&gt; reduced&lt;/em&gt; risk of developing Alzheimer’s disease because of an&lt;em&gt; increased&lt;/em&gt; cognitive reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Studies suggest that they have 35% to 40% less risk of manifesting the disease. The pathology will still occur, but they are able to cope with it better. Some won’t ever be diagnosed with Alzheimer’s because they don’t present any symptoms. Some individuals have a greater number of neurons and synapses, and somehow those extra structures provide a level of protection.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to university or continually learning and educating yourself promotes more efficient cognitive processing and use of brain networks, which effectively &lt;em&gt;slows &lt;/em&gt;the process of age-related cognitive decline. Often (but not always) better-educated Alzheimer’s disease patients are found to be in a more advanced state of neuropathology when they are first diagnosed than their symptoms might suggest—increased cognitive reserve has allowed them to function symptom-free despite their brain degeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2014-03/uom-mcj032414.php&quot;&gt;Research &lt;/a&gt;has also found that another way to maximise cognitive prowess is to work as a doctor, air traffic controller, financial analyst, or in some other mentally-demanding profession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwenith Fisher is an assistant professor of psychology at Colorado State University. Fisher’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14294-001&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; analysed 4,182 participants who worked in a wide variety of jobs and had been doing the same type of work for roughly 25 years before they retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fisher and her colleagues examined the mental requirements of each job, for example, analysing data, developing objectives and strategies, making decisions, solving problems, evaluating information and thinking creatively. Each retiree’s was assessed for mental functioning and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Based on data spanning 18 years, our study suggests that certain kinds of challenging jobs have the potential to enhance and protect workers’ mental functioning in later life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retirees who had worked in jobs with greater mental demands were more likely to have better memories before they retired, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; more likely to have slower declines in memory after retiring than people who had worked in jobs with fewer mental demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Working in a job that involves a lot of thinking, analysing, problem-solving, creativity, and other complex mental processing is related to higher levels of cognitive functioning not only before retirement but after retirement as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings have been supported by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25054282&quot;&gt;study &lt;/a&gt;from US-based Mayo Clinic researchers who found that a lifetime of learning and an intellectually enriching job can delay the onset of cognitive decline and diseases like dementia for up to three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2014-06-24/study-finds-preventing-cognitive-decline-takes-a/5545792&quot;&gt;ABC’s AM program&lt;/a&gt; Dr Prashanthi Vemuri lead researcher on the study explains,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We were focused on seeing if lifetime intellectual enrichment, whether it’s higher education, occupation and doing more cognitive activities later in life might help someone. And we found that, yes, lifetime intellectual enrichment does help in delaying the onset of cognitive impairment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you have a four-year college degree and then you’re in a professional speciality, like being a doctor or you’re a computer scientist, you’re at lower risk of developing dementia later in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where does this leave you if you don’t have a mentally demanding career or university education? Is it too late to build cognitive reserve? Thankfully, the answer is ‘no’. Cognitive decline is not inevitable, because intellectual enrichment goes beyond the work people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is never too late. Absolutely never too late, irrespective of what you did in your prior life,” say Vermi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We found that high mid- to late-life engagement in cognitively stimulating activities, such as reading books and magazines, playing games or music, artistic activities, craft, group activities, social activities and computer activities, all these help. And you have to engage in them at least three times a week during your mid and late life, that really helps in delaying the onset of dementia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the new retired ABC Active Memory blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/can-prevent-memory-loss-brain-ageing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can you prevent memory loss and brain ageing?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McKay</name>
			<uri>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Your Brain Health</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Discover neuroscience. Explore the brain. Understand your mind.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/"/>
			<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</id>
			<updated>2017-08-23T14:04:06+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">On a mountain in Wyoming, the eclipse brings wonder — and, hopefully, answers</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wyoming-eclipse-physics-corona"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wyoming-eclipse-physics-corona</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T23:38:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Astronomy writer Lisa Grossman joined scientists on a mountain in Wyoming who were measuring the corona using four different instruments to try to figure out why it’s so hot.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-26T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">SAGE journal retracts three more papers after discovering faked reviews</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/sage-journal-retracts-three-papers-discovering-faked-reviews/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51490</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T15:30:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;SAGE recently retracted three 2015 papers from one of its journals after the publisher found the articles were accepted with faked peer reviews. The retraction notices call out the authors responsible for submitting the reviews. This trio of retractions is the second batch of papers withdrawn by Technology in Cancer Research &amp;amp; Treatment over faked […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/sage-journal-retracts-three-papers-discovering-faked-reviews/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;SAGE journal retracts three more papers after discovering faked reviews&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-26T17:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">&quot;R-Factor&quot; Unlikely To Fix Science</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9052"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9052</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T15:20:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new tool called the R-factor could help ensure that science is reproducible and valid, according to a preprint posted on biorxiv: Science with no fiction. The authors, led by Peter Grabitz, are so confident in their idea that they've created a company called Verum Analytics to promote it. But how useful is this new metric going to be?



Not very useful, in my view. The R-factor (which stands for &quot;reproducibility, reputation, responsibility, and robustness&quot;) strikes me as a flawed idea.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-08-28T17:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mars has nighttime snow storms</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-has-nighttime-snow-storms"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-has-nighttime-snow-storms</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T15:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 When clouds of water-ice particles cool at night, snow starts to fall rapidly on Mars, simulations suggest. The squalls could explain observations made by the Phoenix lander in 2008.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_045095154695457995=0.10747940362031982</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-25T17:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Trans men show unusual connectivity patterns in brain networks involved in self perception</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/21/trans-men-show-unusual-connectivity-patterns-in-brain-networks-involved-in-self-perception/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29026</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T13:02:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29079&quot; style=&quot;width: 2140px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-08-21 13.55.14.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29079&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29079&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-08-21 13.55.14&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2140,780&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/21/trans-men-show-unusual-connectivity-patterns-in-brain-networks-involved-in-self-perception/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;Photographic stimuli from the “body morph” task that was used in the new research&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most brain imaging studies involving transgender people or people with gender dysphoria have focused on whether their brains look more like what’s typical for the gender they identify with, rather than the gender they were assigned at birth based on their biological sex. For example, whether trans men have “masculine” brains, and trans women have more “feminine” brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results have been mixed and if anything point towards trans people having brains with &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/cercor/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/cercor/bhu194&quot;&gt;distinct&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0085914&quot;&gt;features&lt;/a&gt; that are neither stereotypically male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Brain Imaging and Behaviour&lt;/em&gt; adds to this trend, showing that trans men have unusual patterns of connectivity in brain networks involved in processing of the self, as compared with male and female controls. “The present data do not support the hypothesis that sexual differentiation of the brain of individuals with gender dysphoria is in the opposite direction as their sex assigned at birth,” the researchers said, adding that the unusual connectivity patterns they found in trans men “was detected in comparison with both male and female controls, and there were no differences between the control groups”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29026&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team led by Jamie Feusner at University of California, Los Angeles, scanned the brains of 27 trans men (whom they refer to as female-to-male persons with gender dysphoria) recruited via a gender dysphoria clinic at the Karolinska Institute in Sweden where they’d been diagnosed with gender dysphoria, specifically transsexualism (according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icd10data.com/ICD10CM/Codes/F01-F99/F60-F69/F64-/F64.0&quot;&gt;ICD 10 criteria&lt;/a&gt;). The trans men had not yet undertaken the surgery and/or hormone treatment that they were seeking; they had no other current psychiatric or neurological diagnoses. There were also 27 male and 27 female cisgender controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a resting-state brain scan, so the participants simply lay in the scanner doing nothing. The researchers then analysed the participants’ patterns of neural activity at rest to look for signs of connectivity in various brain networks, including the “default mode network” (which is more active when we’re mind-wandering and thinking about the self rather than engaged with the outside world) and the “salience network” which processes internal bodily sensations, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighteen of the trans participants and some of the controls also completed a body morph test (see example photographs above): they looked at images of their own body, shown for either half a second or two seconds, that were morphed to varying degrees with the body of another man or woman, and they had to say to what degree the photo was of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trans men showed weak connectivity in areas of the default mode network as compared with both the male and female controls. As you’d expect, they were also more likely to rate the body morph photos as being themselves when they were morphed with a man’s body, rather than a woman’s or unmorphed. Moreover, at longer viewing times, this identification with a masculinised version of their own body correlated with greater connectivity within pregenual anterior cingulate cortex – part of the default mode network that’s associated with feelings of self. The controls didn’t show this correlation, but at shorter viewing times they (but not the trans participants) showed a correlation between seeing their unmorphed body as their own and connectivity within the right insula – a region involved in the rapid processing of internal bodily signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interpretation of these different brain activity patterns is highly speculative but the researchers said the results are consistent with the idea that in trans men “higher cortical systems” were modulating the activity of more reflex systems involved in self and own body processing. The researchers said: “Gender dysphoria individuals differ from controls with respect to connectivity within networks involved in self-directed thinking and that relate to own-body identification, which could represent a neurobiological correlate of their condition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether these unusual brain activity patterns play a role in causing gender dysphoria or are the consequence of it, or both, is not clear. It also remains to be seen how surgical or hormone treatment might interact with these neural patterns. More research, especially longitudinal that tests participants over time, is needed to tease out cause and effect; and research with trans women is also required to see if the current findings generalise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Intrinsic network connectivity and own body perception in gender dysphoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Feusner at al, 2017&lt;/a&gt; shows stimuli from the body morph task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29026/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29026/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29026&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Released FDA docs reveal details of agency’s (failed) attempt to retract paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/released-fda-docs-reveal-details-agencys-failed-attempt-retract-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51487</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T12:20:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a raging controversy regarding a new drug spilled into the pages of a leading medical journal: the head of the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and another official publicly called for the retraction or correction of a peer-reviewed article about the drug. They didn’t get their wish. Now, documents released by the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/released-fda-docs-reveal-details-agencys-failed-attempt-retract-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Released FDA docs reveal details of agency’s (failed) attempt to retract paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Charles Seife</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-08-25T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Today is the day! A last-minute guide for watching the Great American Eclipse</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/last-minute-guide-watching-great-american-eclipse"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/last-minute-guide-watching-great-american-eclipse</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T10:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 You’ve probably heard this already, but there’s a total solar eclipse traversing the United States today, August 21. Here’s what you need to know.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kate Travis</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_045095154695457995=0.10747940362031982</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-25T17:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ascorbate regulates haematopoietic stem cell function and leukaemogenesis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zKtVciSqncU/nature23876"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23876</id>
		<updated>2017-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Stem cell fate can be influenced by metabolite levels in culture but it is unknown whether physiological variations in metabolite levels in normal tissues regulate stem cell function in vivo. We developed a metabolomics method for analysis of rare cell populations isolated directly from tissues and used it to compare haematopoietic stem cells (HSCs) to restricted haematopoietic progenitors. Each haematopoietic cell type had a distinct metabolic signature. Human and mouse HSCs had unusually high levels of ascorbate, which declined with differentiation. Systemic ascorbate depletion in mice increased HSC frequency and function, partly by reducing Tet2 function, a dioxygenase tumour suppressor. Ascorbate depletion cooperated with Flt3ITD leukaemic mutations to accelerate leukaemogenesis, though cell-autonomous and possibly non-cell-autonomous mechanisms, in a manner that was reversed by dietary ascorbate. Ascorbate acted cell-autonomously to negatively regulate HSC function and myelopoiesis through Tet2-dependent and Tet2-independent mechanisms. Ascorbate thus accumulates within HSCs to promote Tet function in vivo, limiting HSC frequency and suppressing leukaemogenesis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23876&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23876&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zKtVciSqncU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michalis Agathocleous</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-08-24T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Eclipse watchers will go after the biggest solar mystery: Why is the corona so hot?</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-hot-corona"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-hot-corona</id>
		<updated>2017-08-20T10:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Usually when you move away from a heat source, it gets cooler. Not so in the sun’s atmosphere.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-08-25T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Smell as a Weapon, and Odor as Entertainment</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/mn1F_R825R0/smell-as-weapon-and-odor-as.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-3727540613042333745</id>
		<updated>2017-08-20T04:55:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GHOey04oFr8/WZFvcbz-ijI/AAAAAAAAMOw/aWsnB-EMPEMQU0P3Lc9P0CYtrVvIDPBgACLcBGAs/s1600/blue%2Bfish_Spongebob_Deaugh.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;415&quot; data-original-width=&quot;625&quot; height=&quot;265&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GHOey04oFr8/WZFvcbz-ijI/AAAAAAAAMOw/aWsnB-EMPEMQU0P3Lc9P0CYtrVvIDPBgACLcBGAs/s400/blue%2Bfish_Spongebob_Deaugh.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The use of smell as a weapon, or a deterrent, was explored in a fanciful way in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2017/08/olfactory-deterrence.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Olfactory Deterrence&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on nuclear threats. While poking around the literature, I found a fascinating unclassified document from the Army Research Laboratory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books/about/Olfaction_Warfare.html?id=Bmy4oQEACAAJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Olfaction Warfare: Odor as Sword and Shield&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arl.army.mil/arlreports/2013/ARL-SR-0258.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). The authors provide a sweeping overview of odor, from chemical tactics in the natural world to the use of scents in the beauty and entertainment industries. The primary military application discussed by Schmeisser et al. (2013) is the use of odor in stealth operations. These are designed to deceive the enemy by masking current location or projecting smells to a false location. Although the document does not propose putrid odor as an offensive weapon, the authors discuss the history of such efforts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stink Bombs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stink bombs are “devices designed to create an unpleasant smell forcing people to leave an area or protecting off-limits areas against being entered.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One unsavory application during WWII was used to make German officers smell like rotten meat, but unfortunately, “this substance was so volatile that it could not be confined to specific targets and contaminated everything in the area.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another unsuccessful project from 1966 tried to develop “culturally specific stink bombs, which would affect Vietnamese guerillas, leaving the U.S. troops unaffected. The project was abandoned due to technical barriers.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But a more contemporary program reached the pinnacle of olfactory deterrence:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;In 2001 the U.S. announced the development of the ultimate stink bomb aimed at driving away hostile forces by a stench so foul that it results not only in disgust or aversion but also fear. The odorant used in the bomb has been developed by a team of researchers led by Dr. Pamela Dalton at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monell.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Monell Chemical Senses Center&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia and is &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;a mixture of two agents: the U.S. Government Standard Bathroom Malodor (a mixture of eight chemicals with a stench similar to human feces but much stronger) and the Who-Me?, a sulphur-based odorant that smells like rotting carcasses&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;...&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scratch-and-Sniff&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schmeisser et al.'s technical report makes for surprisingly entertaining reading. It's highly unlikely that any other military document praises &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyester_(film)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Polyester&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, John Waters' 1981 multimodal film event that provided viewers with scratch-and-sniff cards. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The cards had 10 numbered spots (1.roses, 2.flatulence, 3.model airplane glue, 4.pizza, 5.gasoline, 6.skunk, 7.natural gas, 8.new car smell, 9.dirty shoes, and 10.air freshener) that the audience scratched and sniffed when the appropriate number flushed at the corner of the screen. This system, called Odorama, solved the problem with hanging odors that was the main problem of the early smell-distributing systems.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Waters' Odorama succeeded where the older scent distributions systems had failed. Smell-O-Vision (1939) and AromaRama (1959) were financial disasters for movie theaters, because “the odors were weak, the smells persisted longer than was desired, and the molecules were distributed by noisy systems.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Olorama&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Present day technology for odor delivery has advanced beyond scratch-and-sniff, of course, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/smells-in-cinema/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olorama&lt;/a&gt; offers an enhanced cinematic experience (“the smells jump off the screen”). The kits feature “very compact, hidden aromatization devices that are &lt;b&gt;installed under seats&lt;/b&gt; (1 device for every 5-7 seats, depending on their size).”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They also sell a product for home use. Olfactory enhancement of virtual reality is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hitl.washington.edu/people/tfurness/courses/inde543/reports/3doc/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not a new development&lt;/a&gt;, but this VR system looks stylish, at the very least.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uP6UdwVL8LM/WZkK2GB7BoI/AAAAAAAAMPY/oEzXI_C4PEMluR8yy-oEdM7DySGjwjrYACLcBGAs/s1600/Olorama.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;898&quot; data-original-width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uP6UdwVL8LM/WZkK2GB7BoI/AAAAAAAAMPY/oEzXI_C4PEMluR8yy-oEdM7DySGjwjrYACLcBGAs/s320/Olorama.jpg&quot; width=&quot;312&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olorama Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The company stocks over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/list-of-scents/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;70 scents&lt;/a&gt; in categories such as Fantasy, Food, Wild, and...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 style=&quot;font-family: Roboto; font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;ACTION&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;color: #887878; font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;FIRE - RAIN - FOREST   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(AND COMING SOON...): &lt;br /&gt;GUNPOWDER - BLOOD - BURNING RUBBER &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schmeisser E, Pollard KA, Letowski T. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arl.army.mil/arlreports/2013/ARL-SR-0258.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olfaction warfare: odor as sword and shield&lt;/a&gt;. ARMY RESEARCH LAB. ABERDEEN PROVING GROUND MD. HUMAN RESEARCH AND ENGINEERING DIRECTORATE; 2013 Mar.&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/mn1F_R825R0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-08-29T16:34:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
