<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:37+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Aroused’ recounts the fascinating history of hormones</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/aroused-recounts-fascinating-and-strange-science-hormones"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/aroused-recounts-fascinating-and-strange-science-hormones</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T20:10:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The new book &quot;Aroused&quot; demystifies hormones, the chemicals that put the zing into life.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erika Engelhaupt</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How domestication changed rabbits’ brains</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/how-domestication-changed-rabbit-brains"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/how-domestication-changed-rabbit-brains</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T19:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The fear centers of the brain were altered as humans tamed rabbits.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Karolinska finds Macchiarini, six other researchers guilty of misconduct</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/25/karolinska-finds-macchiarini-six-other-researchers-guilty-of-misconduct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=67283</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T17:05:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Former super-star surgeon Paolo Macchiarini is guilty of misconduct, along with six of his co-authors — including one who initially help alert authorities to problems with Macchiarini’s work, according to an announcement today by his former institution, the Karolinska Institute. KI is also calling to retract six articles co-authored by Macchiarini and his colleagues, including … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/25/karolinska-finds-macchiarini-six-other-researchers-guilty-of-misconduct/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska finds Macchiarini, six other researchers guilty of misconduct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The 5 Second Rule: Task Initiation</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/25/the-5-second-rule-task-initiation/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23746</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:55:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;The title—&lt;i&gt;The 5 Second Rule: Transform Your Life, Work, and Confidence with Everyday Courage&lt;/i&gt;—intrigued me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the publisher&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;Mel Robbins’s self-help book is &lt;i&gt;“&lt;/i&gt;based on a simple psychological tool that the author developed to motivate herself. Using a technique that involves counting down backwards from five to one, she gave herself the extra push she needed to complete dreaded tasks, become more productive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could this technique help solve my task-initiation problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a brain injury survivor. I have clusters of thin-walled blood vessels in my brain. Two of them bled. To prevent additional bleeds, I underwent brain surgeries, which left me with a number of challenging symptoms, including difficulties initiating tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though similar to procrastination in its end result, brain injury-related issues with task initiation feel very different. I am fully aware when I procrastinate, and I often laugh at myself in the process. When I procrastinate, I make conscious choices. Instead of working on the annual report, I choose to do the laundry, edit an essay, or take my dog for a walk. And when I run out of excuses or get too close to the deadline, I get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trouble initiating tasks is more akin to the difficulty of shifting to a new undertaking after completing a long and involved project, when it feels almost impossible to switch to the next activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually have no idea that I’m having trouble initiating a task. I know with absolute certainty that I will get to the task—just not right now. In my mind, starting isn’t an issue, because this internal conviction that “of course I’ll do it” is so strong. It’s as if there’s a disconnect between the belief that I’ll do the task and the cognitive action required to actually initiate it. I’m not choosing to distract myself, and I’m not trying to postpone the inevitable. There’s simply no conscious awareness and no control over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compounding the challenge is that brain injury-related task initiation problems don’t follow any recognizable pattern. They arise without warning and are frequently unrelated to the nature of the task, interfering equally with tasks I enjoy and those I’d rather avoid. They can last anywhere from several days to several years. They often end abruptly, for no apparent reason. When my brain releases me, I’m off and running, all signs of struggle gone, as if the problem never existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To combat my difficulties beginning an activity, my neuropsychologist suggested I keep a daily list and block off chunks of time in my calendar to work on those tasks. Fortunately, my brain injury brought on a level of rigidity—once an item is on that list, I feel compelled to address it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, identifying problematic tasks to include on the list is not straightforward, because the same “I know I’ll get to it” belief means there’s no problem, and it doesn’t occur to me that it belongs on the list. And I sometimes can’t initiate writing the list—I know I’ll write it, just not right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d recently been having trouble beginning a new essay on a topic I wanted to explore. It had been simmering in my mind for a while, and I felt ready to begin writing. But I couldn’t. I tried tricking my brain into cooperating by breaking the task into smaller and hopefully more manageable chunks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to sit down in front of my computer, but my brain refused to attempt the next task. Later, I managed to open a new file, but my mind wouldn’t move beyond that chunk. I left the file open, knowing I’d get to it (just not now). A few days later, I typed a title, but couldn’t start the body of the essay. I knew exactly how I wanted it to begin. The words were there. But &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; wasn’t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galvanized into action by Robbins’ five second rule, I was determined to try it the next morning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I finished getting dressed, I thought about working on the essay. “5-4-3-2-1” and there I was, at my computer, tapping away, the essay taking form just as I’d imagined it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time my inner voice suggested I needed to take a breather, before I had time to question my motive, I applied the five second rule. “5-4-3-2-1” and I was back on track. After finishing a first draft, I wondered about working on another troublesome essay. Five seconds later, I was back at the keyboard. Feeling like I was on a roll and afraid that I’d fall prey to my damaged brain if I paused, I moved on to sending email queries about speaking engagements and book events. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next problematic item that came to mind gave me pause—I needed to grade a pile of essays. This time, the five second rule failed, because common sense kicked in. I had reached my limit—fatigue overwhelmed me and my brain blanked out. I absolutely had to rest, or I’d be in no shape to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came away from that day feeling good about myself. I’d been more productive than I’d been in a long time. But I was also exhausted. Applying the five second rule had thoroughly drained me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have since realized that the five second rule doesn’t work for me exactly the way Mel Robbins explained it. I haven’t abandoned it, but as with so many other things post-injury, I am learning to adapt it to my particular circumstances. I have to pace myself, and as soon as I recognize the early signs of fatigue, I use the rule to take a nap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My conclusion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five second rule rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robbins, M. (2017). The 5 Second Rule: Transform your Life, Work, and Confidence with Everyday Courage. Savio Republic. ISBN-10: 1682612384&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/JESHOOTScom-264599/&quot;&gt;JESHOOTScom&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Deborah Brandon, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Research Data: What to keep? - Jisc</title>
		<link href="https://researchdata.jiscinvolve.org/wp/2018/06/12/research-data-what-to-keep/"/>
		<id>https://researchdata.jiscinvolve.org/wp/2018/06/12/research-data-what-to-keep/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:55:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jisc is working to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jisc.ac.uk/research-data&quot;&gt;develop shared infrastructure, influence policy and provide guidance to support institutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; with the growing need for robust research data management. There is a wide-range of needs and existing provision for creation, collection, storage and preservation, and reuse of data for UK HE.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Caroline Ingram</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Access: Erfolg mit Schattenseiten | Telepolis</title>
		<link href="https://www.heise.de/tp/features/Open-Access-Erfolg-mit-Schattenseiten-4080065.html"/>
		<id>https://www.heise.de/tp/features/Open-Access-Erfolg-mit-Schattenseiten-4080065.html</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:39:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): Open Access: success with dark pages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Welchen Beitrag leistet Open Access zur Steuerung und Ökonomisierung der Wissenschaft?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;What contribution does Open Access make to the control and economization of science?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Massive Bedenken gegen EU-Pläne für eine Urheberrechtsreform (Massive concerns about EU plans for copyright reform)</title>
		<link href="https://derstandard.at/2000081440418/Massive-Bedenken-gegen-EU-Plaene-fuer-eine-Urheberrechtsreform"/>
		<id>https://derstandard.at/2000081440418/Massive-Bedenken-gegen-EU-Plaene-fuer-eine-Urheberrechtsreform</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:39:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;From Google's English: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The European Parliament is currently preparing a copyright reform that could have a significant impact on the everyday behavior of internet users. Conservatives want to introduce a very strict copyright, which includes, for example, an ancillary copyright. So even the description of external content could be banned. For critics such as the MEP Julia Reda (pirates) that would be an &quot;attack on hyperlinks&quot;, which limits the freedom of the press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia warned that their operation could be subject to the rules. The same is true for open source platforms that regularly load code snippets. Even science portals would have to monitor user content increasingly in the future. In addition, network activists fear the creation of a surveillance machine as the planned filters monitor the activity of millions of users in real time. They could be misused for political purposes, for example, by screening political statements, logos or slogans instead of copyrighted material. The upload filters are, according to critics, in direct contradiction to other passages in EU law that prohibit the permanent observation of users. Organizations such as Human Rights Watch and Reporters Without Borders warned that the upload filters &quot;limit the freedom to distribute and receive information.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Neues EU-Copyright hilft den Netzgiganten (New EU copyright helps the net giant)</title>
		<link href="https://diepresse.com/home/techscience/5450404/Neues-EUCopyright-hilft-den-Netzgiganten"/>
		<id>https://diepresse.com/home/techscience/5450404/Neues-EUCopyright-hilft-den-Netzgiganten</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:32:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt; 
The concern of Internet activists: If the EU Parliament agrees with the proposal as expected, the &quot;censorship machines&quot; will rebuild the Internet from an open platform for ideas to a tool for systematic surveillance of citizens. Everything that will be uploaded to the EU in the future must first pass through the filter. And as sophisticated as the software may be, it is in no case error-free, showing the previous experience. Experts expect that in case of doubt, legitimate platforms - such as parodies - will censor off legal platforms in order to save themselves expensive claims for damages. Only non-commercial providers such as online dictionaries or scientific archives are exempted from the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">BE OPEN - Science &amp;amp; Society Festival</title>
		<link href="https://www.fwf.ac.at/de/ueber-den-fwf/be-open-science-society-festival/"/>
		<id>https://www.fwf.ac.at/de/ueber-den-fwf/be-open-science-society-festival/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:22:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt; 
On the occasion of its 50th anniversary, the Science Fund (FWF) is transforming together with partners from science and research the Vienna Maria Theresien-Platz into a garden of curiosity. 
 
Take a walk through 18 scientific pop-up pavilions and meet researchers who are in the lead worldwide. Discover fascinating exhibits and immerse yourself in the exciting world of basic research. Take a seat in the FWF dialogue arena and discuss scientific progress and social responsibility. Children and students can awaken their curiosity through an exciting research rally and two experimental mobiles. The youngest neo-Jungles are in good hands in the Mini Research Club. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;September 8 to 12, 2018  
Maria Theresien-Platz, 1010 Vienna  
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fwf.ac.at/fileadmin/files/Dokumente/Ueber_den_FWF/BE_OPEN/BE_OPEN_Festival-Broschuere_d.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Festival Program &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">IST Austria: IST Austria welcomes expansion of the European Research Council (ERC)</title>
		<link href="https://ist.ac.at/nc/de/news-media/news/news-detail/article/ist-austria-welcomes-expansion-of-the-european-research-council-erc/6/"/>
		<id>https://ist.ac.at/nc/de/news-media/news/news-detail/article/ist-austria-welcomes-expansion-of-the-european-research-council-erc/6/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:19:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Proposal of the EU Commission for the development of European top-level research as an important signal for strengthening Europe's research performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figures on the EU financial framework for research and innovation for the years 2021 to 2027, presented by EU Research Commissioner Carlos Moedas in Brussels last week, are welcomed by the Institute of Science and Technology Austria (IST Austria). In particular, the planned endowment of the pillar &quot;Open Science&quot; within &quot;Horizon Europe&quot; with 25.8 billion euros is striking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">&quot;Open Access wird allmählich Alltag&quot; (&quot;Open Access is becoming a part of everyday life&quot;)</title>
		<link href="https://news.univie.ac.at/uniview/wissenschaft-gesellschaft/detailansicht/artikel/open-access-wird-allmaehlich-alltag/"/>
		<id>https://news.univie.ac.at/uniview/wissenschaft-gesellschaft/detailansicht/artikel/open-access-wird-allmaehlich-alltag/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:16:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;From Google's English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;For Guido Blechl, head of the Open Access Office of the University of Vienna, Open Access is the contemporary publication model of the 21st century. In an interview he talks about his work and the possibilities for scientists at the University of Vienna.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Theresa Dirtl</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Offene Bildung Österreich (Open education Austria)</title>
		<link href="https://www.deri.at/offene-bildung/"/>
		<id>https://www.deri.at/offene-bildung/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T14:07:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;From Google's English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Open education is a collective term for educational organizations that seek to eliminate barriers to entry. For example, such institutions have no academic admission requirements. Examples are the Open University in the UK and the Athabasca University in Canada. Such programs are usually distance learning programs such as e-learning, MOOC or OpenCourseWare. Although many e-learning programs are free, the cost of obtaining a certificate can be an obstacle. Many open educational institutions offer free certification systems that are accredited by organizations such as UKAS in the United Kingdom and Anab in the US, where others, such as the Khan Academy, offer a badge.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Ökonomie und Ethik freier Daten: Warum sollten offene Daten reguliert werden? (Economics and Ethics of Free Data: Why should open data be regulated? )</title>
		<link href="https://derstandard.at/2000081308869/Oekonomie-und-Ethik-freier-Daten-Warum-sollten-offene-Daten-reguliert"/>
		<id>https://derstandard.at/2000081308869/Oekonomie-und-Ethik-freier-Daten-Warum-sollten-offene-Daten-reguliert</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T13:58:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;From Google's English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;In many places, the question of what to do with so-called &quot;open, freely available&quot; data, ie &quot;open data&quot;, from a political, economic and ethical point of view is discussed. On the one hand, the call for free use of publicly available data and information by all citizens often sounds, on the other hand, the reality of the media economy shows the limits of this desire: Many platform companies make commercial profits with private, but freely available (because knowingly or unknowingly released) data , E-commerce models are booming.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Radical Open Access II - The Ethics of Care at Coventry University, Coventry</title>
		<link href="https://allevents.in/coventry/radical-open-access-ii-the-ethics-of-care/1000044796943865"/>
		<id>https://allevents.in/coventry/radical-open-access-ii-the-ethics-of-care/1000044796943865</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T12:57:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Two days of critical discussion about creating a more diverse and equitable future for open access&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A critic with more than two dozen retractions can’t seem to stop plagiarizing</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/25/a-critic-with-more-than-two-dozen-retractions-cant-seem-to-stop-plagiarizing/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=67245</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T12:00:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A mysterious lit and film critic who built a significant portion of his career using the words of other scholars instead of writing his own appears to be attempting a second act.   Last year, Richard-Lawrence Etienne Barnett, who has lost more than two dozen papers for plagiarism, published a book called “The Adversarial Text,” which … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/25/a-critic-with-more-than-two-dozen-retractions-cant-seem-to-stop-plagiarizing/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A critic with more than two dozen retractions can’t seem to stop plagiarizing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Adam Marcus</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Whitehead Institute - To open science, destigmatize critique</title>
		<link href="http://wi.mit.edu/blog/open-science-destigmatize-critique"/>
		<id>http://wi.mit.edu/blog/open-science-destigmatize-critique</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T11:28:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;If we were comfortable with sharing our interim research products early, our science could more rapidly inform the research of others around the world. We could get better (and broader) feedback to improve our work. We could identify collaborators and reduce needless duplication of effort, or we could channel that duplication into robust and well-planned independent replications. Science as a whole would become more efficient.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Scholarcy - reference extraction made easy &amp;amp; thoughts on potential of crowdsourcing of open citations | Musings about librarianship</title>
		<link href="http://musingsaboutlibrarianship.blogspot.com/2018/06/scholarcy-reference-extraction-made.html"/>
		<id>http://musingsaboutlibrarianship.blogspot.com/2018/06/scholarcy-reference-extraction-made.html</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T11:21:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;I've been reading up lately about the idea of making research reproducible and replicable. That's one of the motivations of course to encourage researchers to deposit data, scripts and code into data repositories and to make them open (or at least available on request).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">European Open Access Platform - Google Docs</title>
		<link href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Djq16UP2MCD40ZO8Ma4DL3WfmBA9ErtqNkOTt80Ahgw/edit"/>
		<id>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Djq16UP2MCD40ZO8Ma4DL3WfmBA9ErtqNkOTt80Ahgw/edit</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T11:10:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;This post makes the case for a European Open Access Platform.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This volcano revealed its unique ‘voice’ after an eruption</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cotopaxi-volcano-ecuador-infrasound"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cotopaxi-volcano-ecuador-infrasound</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Identifying patterns in a volcano’s low-frequency sounds could help monitor its activity.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Guest Post: Time to Check Out of the Hybrid Hotel? - The Scholarly Kitchen</title>
		<link href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2018/06/25/guest-post-time-check-hybrid-hotel/"/>
		<id>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2018/06/25/guest-post-time-check-hybrid-hotel/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Heralded by many as a transition mechanism to full open access (OA), hybrid OA has shown impressive growth in recent years, but questions are now being asked of its sustainability. Rob Johnson considers the future prospects for hybrid publishing and argues that publishers need to get serious about offsetting arrangements, if recent progress is to continue.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Center for Open Science and AfricArXiv Launch Branded Preprint Service</title>
		<link href="https://cos.io/about/news/center-open-science-and-africarxiv-launch-branded-preprint-service/"/>
		<id>https://cos.io/about/news/center-open-science-and-africarxiv-launch-branded-preprint-service/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:55:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The Center for Open Science (COS) and AfricArXiv have launched a new preprint service that will advance scientific knowledge in African countries in multiple scientific fields.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">All Change: Pre-Prints Count – Hybrids Don’t : OpenAIRE blog</title>
		<link href="https://blogs.openaire.eu/?p=3403"/>
		<id>https://blogs.openaire.eu/?p=3403</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:51:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;In an interesting development from the European Commission, a statement has been released in a recent staff working document  in the context of the EC’s open access policies and recommendations to the Member States – stating changes for the implementation of Open Science in the European Commission’s new funding programme, Horizon Europe. In particular, publication costs will only be eligible for purely open access journals, i.e. not for publishing in hybrid journals, and depositing a pre-print will satisfy the open access mandate obligations.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">How green is our valley?: five-year study of selected LIS journals from Taylor &amp;amp; Francis for green deposit of articles</title>
		<link href="https://insights.uksg.org/articles/10.1629/uksg.406/"/>
		<id>https://insights.uksg.org/articles/10.1629/uksg.406/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:48:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Abstract: &quot;This study reviews content from five different library and information science journals: Behavioral &amp;amp; Social Sciences Librarian, Collection Management, College &amp;amp; Undergraduate Libraries, Journal of Electronic Resources Librarianship and Journal of Library Administration over a five-year period from 2012–2016 to investigate the green deposit rate. Starting in 2011, Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, the publisher of these journals, waived the green deposit embargo for library and information science, heritage and archival content, which allows for immediate deposit of articles in these fields. The review looks at research articles and standing columns over the five years from these five journals to see if any articles were retrieved using the OA Button or through institutional repositories. Results indicate that less than a quarter of writers have chosen to make a green deposit of their articles in local or subject repositories. The discussion outlines some best practices to be undertaken by librarians, editors and Taylor &amp;amp; Francis to make this program more successful.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Workshop opportunity : ScienceFoundational School in Research Data Science Foundational School in Research Data | NDANGIRA</title>
		<link href="http://www.ndangira.net/workshop-opportunity-sciencefoundational-school-in-research-data-science-foundational-school-in-research-data/"/>
		<id>http://www.ndangira.net/workshop-opportunity-sciencefoundational-school-in-research-data-science-foundational-school-in-research-data/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:45:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The goal of this workshop is to train researchers in Research Data Science (RDS). RDS refers to the principles and practice of Open Science and research data management and curation, the use of a range of data platforms and infrastructures, large scale analysis, statistics, visualization and modelling techniques, software development and data annotation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Data | Build an Open Data Community with ArcGIS Online</title>
		<link href="https://www.esri.com/en-us/arcgis/open-vision/standards/open-data"/>
		<id>https://www.esri.com/en-us/arcgis/open-vision/standards/open-data</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:42:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Many organizations use ArcGIS to share and work with open data. People are looking for ways to liberate data so they can communicate effectively, meet mandated transparency requirements, and enable greater insights. Esri includes open data capabilities at no cost in ArcGIS Online and ArcGIS Hub.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Some Open Access Journals Spark Controversy Due to Internal Problems but Also for Lack of Model Sustainability | Open Science</title>
		<link href="https://openscience.com/some-open-access-journals-spark-controversy-due-to-internal-problems-but-also-for-lack-of-model-sustainability/"/>
		<id>https://openscience.com/some-open-access-journals-spark-controversy-due-to-internal-problems-but-also-for-lack-of-model-sustainability/</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T10:41:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;As recent news on the HAU and Springer Machine Intelligence journal show, Open Access needs to be paired with sustainable publishing models to serve scholarly communities and deliver on its promise of unrestricted access to knowledge.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Open Access Tracking Project</name>
			<uri>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OATP primary</title>
			<subtitle type="html">This is the &quot;oa.new&quot; feed published by the OATP hub. It's a remix feed so that, over time, I can modify it without modifying the URL. For example, I 
&lt;span&gt;can filter out spam or make other modifications later on without changing the URL.&lt;/span&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss"/>
			<id>http://tagteam.harvard.edu/hubs/oatp/republished_feeds/6</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">People with “Maladaptive Daydreaming” spend an average of four hours a day lost in their imagination</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/25/people-with-maladaptive-daydreaming-spend-an-average-of-four-hours-a-day-lost-in-their-imagination/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34091</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T08:33:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34092&quot; style=&quot;width: 1500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-882115988.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34092&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34092&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;DMC-GX1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;human head, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1478083456&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;160&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.05&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;human head, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;human head, chakra power, inspiration abstract thought, world, universe inside your mind, watercolor painting&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-882115988.jpg?w=845?w=769&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-882115988.jpg?w=845?w=225&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-882115988.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1500,1998&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/25/people-with-maladaptive-daydreaming-spend-an-average-of-four-hours-a-day-lost-in-their-imagination/human-head-chakra-power-inspiration-abstract-thought-world-universe-inside-your-mind-watercolor-painting/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-882115988.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Maladaptive daydreaming can interfere with normal functioning, but it’s not clear all people with the condition will want treatment&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have been lost in a daydream for as long as I can remember….These daydreams tend to be stories…for which I feel real emotion, usually happiness or sadness, which have the ability to make me laugh and cry…They’re as important a part of my life as anything else; I can spend hours alone with my daydreams….I am careful to control my actions in public so it is not evident that my mind is constantly spinning these stories and I am constantly lost in them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 20-year-old woman who emailed these reflections to Eli Somer at the University of Haifa, Israel, diagnosed herself with Maladaptive Daydreaming, sometimes known as Daydreaming Disorder. While Maladaptive Daydreaming is not included in standard mental health diagnostic manuals, there are cyber-communities dedicated to it, and “in recent years it has gradually become evident that daydreaming can evolve into an extreme and maladaptive behaviour, up to the point where it turns into a clinically significant condition,” write Somer and Nirit Soffer-Dudek at Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5962718/&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; on the disorder, published in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34091&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is, they say, the first to explore the mental health factors that accompany Maladaptive Daydreaming (MD) over time – and it provides insights into not only what might cause these intense, vivid, extended bouts of daydreaming but also hints at how to prevent them, or how to stop them in their tracks. Because while many people who experience MD report enjoying their daydreams at the time, MD can also negatively affect their relationships with others, their day-to-day lives, and their overall emotional wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier work led researchers to suggest that MD might be either a dissociative disorder, a disturbance of attention, a behavioural addiction or an obsessive-compulsive spectrum disorder.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the new online study, Somer and Soffer-Dudek recruited 77 self-diagnosed sufferers of MD, from 26 different countries, ranging in age from 18-60. Just over 80 per cent were women (possibly because women seem to be more affected by MD than men, the researchers write).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants first provided details about any mental health diagnoses (21 had been diagnosed with depression, 14 with anxiety disorders and 5 with OCD, among other disorders). Then, each evening before bed, for 14 days, they completed a series of questionnaires that asked about their experiences that day. These scales assessed levels of dissociation, obsessive-compulsive symptoms, depression, general anxiety, social anxiety, and emotion – and also maladaptive day dreaming. (Participants were asked to report on the extent to which statements such as “I felt the need or urge to continue a daydream that was interrupted by a real-world event at a later point” had applied to them that day.)&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, participants reported spending four hours a day daydreaming. On days on which their MD was more intense and time-consuming, they also experienced higher levels of obsessive-compulsive symptoms, dissociation and negative emotion, and both types of anxiety. But only obsessive-compulsive symptoms consistently predicted the intensity and duration of maladaptive daydreaming on the next day, regardless of the levels of obsessive-compulsive symptoms on that following day.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these findings, the researchers note that only five of the participants had actually been diagnosed with OCD –  “This discrepancy suggests that obsessive-compulsive symptoms and MD share common mechanisms and interact with each other…but MD does not seem to be merely a subtype of OCD.” However, they added that many people with MD describe being consistently drawn to their daydreaming in a compulsive way. “The finding that a surge in obsessive-compulsive symptoms precedes MD [also] points to a key role of this construct as a contributing mechanism,” Somer and Soffer-Dudek argue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compulsions to daydream, or to carry on daydreaming even after many hours have passed, might be addressed using cognitive behavioural approaches developed to address other compulsions, the researchers suggest. They also speculate that low levels of the neurotransmitter serotonin may play a role in MD, as in OCD. If future work confirms this, drugs that modify serotonin levels may possibly be used in treatment.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some limitations of the study – in particular, that it was based entirely on self-reports. But as research on MD is scarce, and this is thought to be the first longitudinal exploration of the disorder, the results should at least help to inform future work in this area. Though it’s also possible that not all people with MD will want treatment. As the woman with MD who emailed Somer also wrote: “I am torn between the love of my daydreams and the desire to be normal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5962718/&quot;&gt;Trapped in a Daydream: Daily Elevations in Maladaptive Daydreaming Are Associated With Daily Psychopathological Symptoms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Feathered fruit-eater frozen in fossil form</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/25/feathered-fruit-eater-frozen-in-fossil-form/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10290</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T08:20:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Website-Image-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As many birdwatchers know, the best way to see an impressive number of avian species is to take a trip to the Southern Hemisphere. En route &lt;a href=&quot;https://noahstrycker.com/books/birding-without-borders/&quot;&gt;to encountering a record-setting 6,042 bird species in 2015&lt;/a&gt;, intrepid birdwatcher Noah Strycker spent three full months in South America (sometimes referred to as the Bird Continent), but only twelve days in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that European birds are any less interesting than those found at more southerly latitudes; it simply reflects the strikingly uneven global distribution of the world’s 11,000 living bird species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many major groups of birds are entirely restricted to South America, Africa, and Australasia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only are species numbers higher in the Southern Hemisphere, but many major groups of birds are entirely restricted to South America, Africa, and Australasia – all vestiges of the ancient southern supercontinent of Gondwana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how did this uneven geographic distribution of living bird diversity arise? Does it simply reflect the fact that most groups of living birds arose on the southern continents, and failed to disperse elsewhere? Or have more complex patterns governed the evolutionary history of avian geographic distributions through geological time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10291&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10291&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/34899743383_d94c503c01_z-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Knysna Turaco (Tauraco corythaix) Wilderness, Western Cape, South Africa&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Daniel J. Field&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way to definitively answer this question is to flesh out the fossil record of modern birds. In our new study, just published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt;, we examined a beautifully preserved 52-million-year-old fossil bird named &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt;. Originally discovered in western North America in the 1980’s, and named in the 1990’s, &lt;em&gt;F. panarium &lt;/em&gt;exhibits an enigmatic mix of anatomical features that has prevented a robust assessment of its affinities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By re-examining its anatomical features in an updated evolutionary context, our work supports &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt; as the earliest known relative of a group of living birds called turacos, or “banana eaters”. Turacos are an outrageously beautiful group of ~24 species of medium-sized fruit-eating birds, and the feathers of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/131708321@N02/sets/72157686118399406&quot;&gt;several species contain unique pigments&lt;/a&gt; that generate bright green and magenta tones. In addition to these interesting aesthetic attributes, modern turacos are also known for being entirely restricted to sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the fossil, &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt;, hails from North America, what does that tell us about the ancient geographic distribution of the group that gave rise to modern turacos? And how did modern turacos become restricted to Africa in the modern day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt; is far from the first example of a fossil bird being found outside the modern distribution of its closest living relatives. Many other groups of birds that today are restricted to southern landmasses, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/131708321@N02/sets/72157684444609383&quot;&gt;seriemas&lt;/a&gt; of South America , or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/131708321@N02/albums/72157687089869025&quot;&gt;mousebirds&lt;/a&gt; of Africa, have fossil representatives known from entirely different parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10292&quot; style=&quot;width: 210px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10292&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/19835422463_87049f5623_z-200x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Speckled Mousebird (Colius striatus), Nairobi National Park, Kenya&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Daniel J. Field&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our paper reaffirms the complexity such observations can introduce into analyses focused on discerning ancestral geographic distributions of modern birds (please see refs &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/1/11/e1501005&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/1/11/e1501005&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jbi.12969&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;). While our analyses examining only modern birds confidently infer that the most recent common ancestor of all living birds arose in the Southern Hemisphere, our analyses which incorporate fossils return a decidedly less certain result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These analyses tell us that either modern birds did not arise in the Southern Hemisphere, or, if they did, that subsequent fluctuations in the geographic distributions of modern birds have been vastly more complex than we could understand without the fossil record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future work will attempt to more clearly discern the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12549-011-0062-4&quot;&gt;major factors&lt;/a&gt; driving the dramatic shifts in geographic range documented by the fossil record. Are these ancient episodes of inferred dispersal related to periods of climatic change throughout Earth history? Or were they perhaps related to periodic extinction events throughout geological time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the implications for understanding the geographic history of the lineage including turacos, &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt; sheds additional light on the age of the turaco lineage itself. The age of the fossil makes &lt;em&gt;F. panarium &lt;/em&gt;not only the oldest-known representative of the turaco lineage, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature15697&quot;&gt;oldest representative&lt;/a&gt; of the major group that includes turacos, cuckoos, and bustards (which are large, ground-dwelling birds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, turacos must have diverged from their closest living relatives by at least 52 million years ago, which may suggest that this group was part of a rapid avian radiation in the aftermath of the end-Cretaceous mass extinction event, 66 million years ago (that famously wiped out the giant dinosaurs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many living birds that are strictly tree-dwelling have relatively short hindlimbs, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/287/1019/131&quot;&gt;specialization&lt;/a&gt; that lowers their centre of mass for enhanced perching stability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt; also provides interesting insights into the evolution of modern turaco biology. Many living birds that are strictly tree-dwelling have relatively short hindlimbs, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/287/1019/131&quot;&gt;specialization&lt;/a&gt; that lowers their centre of mass for enhanced perching stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the case for living turacos, which are both tree-dwelling and exhibit relatively short hindlimbs. However, the hindlimbs of &lt;em&gt;F. panarium&lt;/em&gt; are quite long, similar to living ground-dwelling birds. This observation may point to the relatively late acquisition of arboreality among the ancestors of turacos—consistent with the idea that a tree-dwelling lifestyle arose independently &lt;a href=&quot;http://theconversation.com/how-birds-survived-the-dinosaur-killing-asteroid-97021&quot;&gt;numerous times among living birds&lt;/a&gt; following the forest-destroying end-Cretaceous extinction event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multifaceted insights yielded by &lt;em&gt;Foro panarium&lt;/em&gt; illustrate the profound importance of the fossil record for accurately understanding the evolutionary history of modern birds. Clearly, a better understanding of the evolutionary affinities of modern bird fossils has the potential to radically improve our understanding of how and when modern birds, and their characteristic geographic distributions, evolved. Our picture of bird evolutionary history will continue to grow sharper as each new bird fossil gets unearthed … not unlike adjusting the focus on a distant turaco through binoculars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/25/feathered-fruit-eater-frozen-in-fossil-form/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Feathered fruit-eater frozen in fossil form&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Field &amp;#38; Allison Hsiang</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Karolinska requests retraction of Macchiarini and Jungebluth papers</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/25/karolinska-decides-on-macchiarini-and-jungebluth-papers/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24765</id>
		<updated>2018-06-25T05:00:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Today the Swedish Karolinska Institutet (KI) will announce its decision about 6 papers of their former professor and surgeon, Paolo Macchiarini. This article will be updated accordingly. Update 14:00: a decision was published, all 6 papers are to be retracted, 7 scientists found guilty of misconduct. The background: On 30 October 2017, Swedish Central Ethics … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/25/karolinska-decides-on-macchiarini-and-jungebluth-papers/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska requests retraction of Macchiarini and Jungebluth papers&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Is Public Engagement A Duty for Scientists?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9584"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9584</id>
		<updated>2018-06-24T21:40:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Do scientists have a responsibility to make their work accessible to the public?



&quot;Public Engagement&quot;, broadly speaking, means scientists communicating about science to non-scientists. Blogs are a form of public engagement, as are (non-academic) books. Holding public talks or giving interviews would also count as such.



Recently, it has become fashionable to say that it is important for scientists to engage the public, and that this engagement should be encouraged. I agree completely</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-06-24T23:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Lie of Precision Medicine</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/KV6ff768IOU/the-lie-of-precision-medicine.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-5219093309749498185</id>
		<updated>2018-06-24T07:27:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;My next blog post will be entitled &quot;The Lie of Precision Medicine&quot;&lt;/div&gt;— sarcastic_f (@sarcastic_f) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sarcastic_f/status/1010383716739264512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 23, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This post will be my own personalized rant about the false promises of personalized medicine. It will not be about neurological or psychiatric diseases, the typical topics for this blog. It will be about oncology, for very personal reasons: misery, frustration, and grief. After seven months of research on immunotherapy clinical trials, I couldn't find a single &lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;[acceptable]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; one&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in either Canada or the US that would enroll my partner with stage 4 cancer. For arbitrary reasons, for financial reasons, because it's not the “right” kind of cancer, because the tumor's too rare, because it's too common, because of unlisted exclusionary criteria, because one trial will not accept the genomic testing done for another trial.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Because of endless waiting and bureaucracy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But first, I'll let NIH explain a few terms. Is precision medicine the same as personalized medicine? Yes and no. Seems to me it's a bit of a branding issue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/primer/precisionmedicine/precisionvspersonalized&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is the difference between precision medicine and personalized medicine?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a lot of overlap between the terms &quot;precision medicine&quot; and &quot;personalized medicine.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;According to the National Research Council, &quot;personalized medicine&quot; is an older term with a meaning similar to &quot;precision medicine.&quot; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's a startling paper from &lt;b&gt;1971&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2370041/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Can Personalized Medicine Survive?&lt;/a&gt; (by W.M. GIBSON, MB, ChB in &lt;i&gt;Canadian Family Physician&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lOd7q1Kg34M/Wy6UAPcFycI/AAAAAAAAMkI/84i20v47hpoPB-OK0P1ILN-ht-XvelEwQCLcBGAs/s1600/sit%2Bhere%2B-%2Bspeak%2Bhere%2B-%2Bsuggested%2Btreatment%2B%25281971%2529.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;667&quot; data-original-width=&quot;819&quot; height=&quot;325&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lOd7q1Kg34M/Wy6UAPcFycI/AAAAAAAAMkI/84i20v47hpoPB-OK0P1ILN-ht-XvelEwQCLcBGAs/s400/sit%2Bhere%2B-%2Bspeak%2Bhere%2B-%2Bsuggested%2Btreatment%2B%25281971%2529.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[it's a defense of the old-fashioned family doctor (solo practitioner) by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2370041/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gibson&lt;/a&gt;]:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;...will the solo practitioner's demise be welcomed, his replacement being a battery of experts in the fields of medicine, surgery, psychiatry and all the new allied health sciences, infinitely better trained than their singlehanded predecessor? &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We wouldn't want any confusion between a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appropriations.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/FY17%20Labor%20HHS%20Education%20Conference%20Agreement%20Summary%20-%20Final.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;$320 million dollar initiative&lt;/a&gt; and the ancient art of medicine. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/primer/precisionmedicine/precisionvspersonalized&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NIH again&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;However, there was concern that the word &quot;personalized&quot; could be misinterpreted to imply that treatments and preventions are being developed uniquely for each individual; in precision medicine, the focus is on identifying which approaches will be effective for which patients based on genetic, environmental, and lifestyle factors.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Council therefore preferred the term &quot;precision medicine&quot; to &quot;personalized medicine.&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; However, some people still use the two terms interchangeably.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So “precision medicine” is considered a more contemporary and cutting-edge term.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Yo1wYvWA7ro/Wy8rs3eZvtI/AAAAAAAAMkU/aqNF3yQlJ0I2yJN4eA3SISG61sy078xoQCLcBGAs/s1600/Enter%2BPrecision%2BMedicine_health%2Bcare%2Btailored%2Bto%2Byou.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;468&quot; data-original-width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Yo1wYvWA7ro/Wy8rs3eZvtI/AAAAAAAAMkU/aqNF3yQlJ0I2yJN4eA3SISG61sy078xoQCLcBGAs/s400/Enter%2BPrecision%2BMedicine_health%2Bcare%2Btailored%2Bto%2Byou.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Archived from &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20150218031251/http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/01/30/precision-medicine-initiative-data-driven-treatments-unique-your-own-body&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The Precision Medicine Initiative: Data-Driven Treatments as Unique as Your Own Body&quot;&gt;The White House Blog&lt;/a&gt; (Obama edition), January 30, 2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/primer/precisionmedicine/precisionvspersonalized&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;What about pharmacogenomics?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/primer/genomicresearch/pharmacogenomics&quot;&gt;Pharmacogenomics&lt;/a&gt;  is a part of precision medicine. Pharmacogenomics is the study of how  genes affect a person’s response to particular drugs. This relatively  new field combines pharmacology (the science of drugs) and genomics (the  study of genes and their functions) to develop &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;effective, safe  medications and doses&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;  that are tailored to variations in a person’s  genes.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At present, precision pharmacogenomics is just a “tumor grab” with no promise of treatment in most cases. There are some serious and admirable efforts, but accessibility and costs are major barriers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cancer?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#cancer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/oncology?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#oncology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/genomics?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#genomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As of January 18, 2018... &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/4KWpuA3yVh&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/4KWpuA3yVh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;— sarcastic_f (@sarcastic_f) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sarcastic_f/status/953900950002982913?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 18, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But we've been promised such a utopia for quite a while. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrd3181&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Personalized medicine in oncology: the future is now&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (Schilsky, 2010):&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cancer chemotherapy is in evolution from non-specific cytotoxic drugs  that damage both tumour and normal cells to more specific agents and  immunotherapy approaches. Targeted agents are directed at unique  molecular features of cancer cells, and immunotherapeutics modulate the  tumour immune response; both approaches aim to produce greater  effectiveness with less toxicity. The development and use of such agents  in biomarker-defined populations enables a more personalized approach  to cancer treatment than previously possible and has the potential to  reduce the cost of cancer care.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zloTUBn8L04/Wy85lgcfi3I/AAAAAAAAMkg/Xl5Bs9JiUd8i-bJQD3n0m_P7HS9OJmK5gCLcBGAs/s1600/Schilsky%2B%25282010%2529%2B-%2Bknowledge%2Bof%2Bthe%2Bmolecular%2Bprofile%2Bblah%2Bblah%2Bblah.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;147&quot; data-original-width=&quot;361&quot; height=&quot;130&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zloTUBn8L04/Wy85lgcfi3I/AAAAAAAAMkg/Xl5Bs9JiUd8i-bJQD3n0m_P7HS9OJmK5gCLcBGAs/s320/Schilsky%2B%25282010%2529%2B-%2Bknowledge%2Bof%2Bthe%2Bmolecular%2Bprofile%2Bblah%2Bblah%2Bblah.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrd3181&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Schilsky (2010)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;IT'S 2018, WHERE IS THAT FUTURE YOU PROMISED US?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But wait, let's go back further, to 1999:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/content/4/5/426.long&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;New Era of Personalized Medicine &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Targeting Drugs For Each Unique Genetic Profile&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Certainly, there are success stories for specific types of cancer (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trastuzumab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;trastuzumab&quot;&gt;Herceptin&lt;/a&gt;). A more recent example is the PD-1 inhibitor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pembrolizumab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pembrolizumab&lt;/a&gt; (Keytruda®), which has shown remarkable results in patients with melanoma, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mskcc.org/blog/understanding-jimmy-carter-s-surprise-turnaround-conversation-jedd-wolchok&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jimmy Carter&lt;/a&gt;. The problem is, direct-to-consumer marketing creates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2018/06/04/cancer-care-dilemma-immunotherapy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;false hope&lt;/a&gt; about the probability that a patient with another form of cancer will respond to this treatment, or one of the many other immunotherapies with PR machines. But if there's a 25% chance or even a 10% chance it'll extend the life of your loved one, you'll go to great lengths to try to acquire it, one way or another. Speaking from personal experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-bZToBF92Zy4/Wy9B-zEYYbI/AAAAAAAAMks/0B8Nl0ABR6cK3b1YVHXPWRbVI3vw8mkcwCLcBGAs/s1600/Keytruda%2Bad.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;230&quot; data-original-width=&quot;259&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-bZToBF92Zy4/Wy9B-zEYYbI/AAAAAAAAMks/0B8Nl0ABR6cK3b1YVHXPWRbVI3vw8mkcwCLcBGAs/s1600/Keytruda%2Bad.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But exaggerated claims and the use of the superlatives in describing massively expensive cancer drugs (e.g., “breakthrough,” “game changer,” “miracle,” “cure,” “home run,”  “revolutionary,” “transformative,” “life saver,” “groundbreaking,” and  “marvel”) are highly questionable (&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaoncology/fullarticle/2464965&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Abola &amp;amp; Prasad, 2016&lt;/a&gt;) and even harmful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's a truly horrible feeling when you realize there are no options available, and all your hope is gone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Abola MV, Prasad V. (2016). &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaoncology/fullarticle/2464965&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The use of superlatives in cancer research&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;JAMA oncology&lt;/i&gt;. 2(1):139-41.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gibson WM. (1971). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2370041/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Can personalized medicine survive?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Can Fam Physician&lt;/i&gt;. 17(8):29-88.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Langreth R, Waldholz M. (1999). &lt;a href=&quot;http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/content/4/5/426.long&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New era of personalized medicine: targeting drugs for each unique genetic profile&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Oncologist&lt;/i&gt; 4(5):426-7.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schilsky RL. (2010). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blogger.com/Schilsky%20RL.%20Personalized%20medicine%20in%20oncology:%20the%20future%20is%20now.%20Nat%20Rev%20Drug%20Discov.%202010%20May;9(5):363-6.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Personalized medicine in oncology: the future is now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Nat Rev Drug Discov&lt;/i&gt;. 9(5):363-6.  {&lt;a href=&quot;http://bionmr.ustc.edu.cn/courses/nrd3181.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnotes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Oh, well, there was the one trial with a highly toxic combo -- &quot;you cannot travel more than X miles away from our center, because only WE can treat your terrible side effects.&quot; And that fun bit was omitted from the consent form.&lt;/div&gt;— sarcastic_f (@sarcastic_f) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sarcastic_f/status/1010387929347153921?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 23, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  But hey, we'll do yet another biopsy of your tumor, and let you know the results in 2-3 months, when you're too ill to be enrolled in any trial. Here's a highly relevant article &lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd yZ8quc&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5480788/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The fuzzy world of precision medicine: deliberations of a precision medicine tumor board&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ILfuVd yZ8quc&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; but I'm afraid to read it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; OMFG, you have got to be kidding me. Here is a subset of the possible side effects from one &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/%20S1470-2045(15)00544-6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;toxic&lt;/a&gt; monoclonal antibody duo:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Very likely (21% or more, or more than 20 people in 100)&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;fatigue/tiredness &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;decrease or loss of appetite, which may result in weight loss &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;cough &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;inflammation of the small intestine and / or large bowel causing abdominal pain and diarrhea which may be severe and life threatening &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Less likely (5 – 20% or between 5 and 20 people in 100)&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;pain and or inflammation in various areas including: muscles , joint, belly, back, chest, headache &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;flu-like symptoms such as body aches, fever, chills, tiredness, loss of appetite, cough &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;constipation &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;dizziness &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;shortness of breath &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;infection which may rarely be serious and become life threatening &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;nausea and vomiting &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;dehydration &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;skin inflammation causing hives or rash which may rarely be severe and become life threatening &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;anemia which may cause tiredness, or may require blood transfusion &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;itching &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;abnormal liver function seen by blood tests. This may rarely lead to jaundice (yellowing of the skin and whites of eyes) and be severe or life threatening &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;abnormal function of your thyroid gland which cause changes in hormonal levels. A decrease in thyroid function as seen on blood tests may cause you to feel tired, cold or gain weight while an increase in thyroid function may cause you to feel shaky, have a fast pulse or lose weight. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Swelling of arms and/or legs (fluid retention) &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Changes in the level of body salts as seen on blood tests. You may not have symptoms. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inflammation of the pancreas that results in increased level of digestive enzymoes (lipase, amylase) seen in bloods and may cause abdominal pain &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inflammation of the lungs (including fluid in the lungs) which could cause shortness of breath, chest pain, new or worse cough. It could be serious and/or life threatening. May occur more frequently if you are receiving radiation treatment to your chest or if you are Japanese. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Serious bleeding events leading to death may occur in patients with head and neck tumors. Please talk to your doctor immediately if you are experiencing bleeding. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decrease of a protein in your blood called albumin that may cause fluid retention and results in swelling of your legs or arms &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You get the idea. I'll skip:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rarely (1 – 4% or less than 5 in 100 people)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Very Rare (less than 1% or less than 1 in 100 people)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=KV6ff768IOU:eqHL7fSnddc:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/KV6ff768IOU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T13:22:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Seven common-sense building blocks for your child’s brain.</title>
		<link href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/seven-common-sense-building-blocks-for-your-childs-brain/"/>
		<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5561</id>
		<updated>2018-06-23T23:22:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-5563 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;655&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dandelion-761104_1920-1024x655.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All children differ in their biological susceptibility to life experiences in a ‘for better and for worse’ manner. Some kids are particularly sensitive to both highly stressful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; highly nurturing environments. Like orchids, such children bloom if lovingly cultivated, but wilt and wither if neglected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, adaptable resilient children who don’t get easily stressed are like little dandelions, they’ll grow and thrive anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19883141&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; are now showing ‘orchid’ and ‘dandelion’ genes linked to particular enzymes or brain chemical receptors, if and only if combined with early childhood toxic stress, can trigger behavioural problems and mood disorders later in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s possible we’ve underestimated the importance of childhood.” Professor Richie Poulton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poulton is head of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dunedinstudy.otago.ac.nz/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dunedin Study&lt;/a&gt;, a research programme that has closely tracked every aspect of the lives of 1037 people born in Dunedin, New Zealand in 1972 and 1973.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dunedin study has shown that early life experiences shape developing brain architecture and strongly affect whether children grow up to be healthy, productive members of society. Toxic stress — defined as stress that is extreme or long-lasting or occurs outside an environment of supportive, attached caregiver relationships — derails healthy brain development, with damaging effects on learning, behaviour, and physical and mental health across the lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While writing The Women’s Brain Book I spent much of Chapter 2 exploring what can go wrong during childhood – from the effects of trauma to family stress to learning negative gender stereotypes. I worried that if readers had young children they were probably ready to drop the book and run off to bulk-buy cotton wool and bubble wrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what we know about normal and abnormal brain development, what experiences do infants and children (the dandelions and the orchids) need to thrive, not just survive? What can adults who raise children do to foster healthy, happy brains?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with wading through decades of childhood development literature, I instead picked up the phone and called my friend and colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://drkristygoodwin.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr Kristy Goodwin&lt;/a&gt;. Goodwin is a children’s learning and development researcher and she has &lt;a href=&quot;https://drkristygoodwin.com/book/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;summarised&lt;/a&gt; seven essential experiences or, as she calls them ‘building blocks’ for optimal brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do growing brains need to thrive?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Attachments and relationships.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm, predictable and loving relationships allow children to feel secure, safe and unstressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Language.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infants and young children need ample opportunities to hear and use language: ‘serve-and-return’ interactions are crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Sleep.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is vital for children’s emotional, physical and mental development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Play.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through play, babies and children develop cognitive skills, creativity and emotional regulation. They need ample opportunities to experiment and explore, including time outdoors in nature. Dr Goodwin highlights the modern-day need to counteract ‘screen time’ with ‘green time’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Physical Movement.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children need to master simple then complex motor skills in order to develop more sophisticated, higher-order thinking skills later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. Nutrition.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality nutrition is vital for optimal development. Children’s diets need to be rich in foods that contain essential fatty acids optimal for brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. Executive Function Skills.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children need to master simple higher-order thinking skills such as impulse control and working memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Given that we know experience accounts for about 70%  of a child’s development. It’s critical that we provide them with the right types of experiences.” Dr Kristy Goodwin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poulton, Goodwin and I agree that childhood is a sacred time. It’s a unique period in the lifespan that needs to be treasured, nurtured and protected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This&lt;em&gt; is an edited excerpt from The Women’s Brain Book. The Neuroscience of Health, Hormones and Happiness. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/seven-common-sense-building-blocks-for-your-childs-brain/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Seven common-sense building blocks for your child’s brain.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McKay</name>
			<uri>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Your Brain Health</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Discover neuroscience. Explore the brain. Understand your mind.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/"/>
			<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</id>
			<updated>2018-06-24T05:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Psychology, Neuroscience: Lacking in Individuality?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9576"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9576</id>
		<updated>2018-06-23T13:44:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In research on people, scientists are typically interested in the group data - the mean, median, and variance of a sample of people. But according to a provocative new paper out in PNAS, the statistics of a group can obscure the variability within individuals, over time.





The paper, from Aaron J. Fisher, John D. Medaglia, and Bertus F. Jeronimus, isn't really making a new point. The pitfalls of generalizing from the group to the individual level have long been known - but these issues</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-06-24T23:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Bragging about burying bad science; women still underrepresented in Nature; does brilliance justify bad behavior?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/23/weekend-reads-bragging-about-burying-bad-science-women-still-underrepresented-in-nature-does-brilliance-justify-bad-behavior/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=67185</id>
		<updated>2018-06-23T13:00:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a look at a dozen scientific sleuths; the story of … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/23/weekend-reads-bragging-about-burying-bad-science-women-still-underrepresented-in-nature-does-brilliance-justify-bad-behavior/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Bragging about burying bad science; women still underrepresented in Nature; does brilliance justify bad behavior?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fighting sexual harassment in science may mean changing science itself</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/fighting-sexual-harassment-science-may-mean-changing-science-itself"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/fighting-sexual-harassment-science-may-mean-changing-science-itself</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T19:45:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sexual harassment is disturbingly prevalent in academia. But a course correction may involve tearing down the hierarchy that makes science run.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Celebrating Pride while recognizing the mental health challenges of the LGBTQ community</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/22/celebrating-pride-recognizing-mental-health-challenges-lgbtq-community/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10276</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T18:50:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;Pride Parade&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/gay-pride-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I decided to write this blog, my hope was to write something uplifting since Pride month is a time of celebration.  I was determined to find recently published articles on the advancements in LGBTQ health. After looking through all pertinent journals from BMC’s 185 journals on medicine and public health, my results were disappointing. All of the articles I found on LGBTQ health painted a dismal picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The articles I found addressed either LGBTQ health disparities or the challenges in obtaining health care. Article after article discussed how LGBTQ individuals experience greater rates of mental health issues compared to their heterosexual counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is crucial that we know what these health issues are, where they are found, and their etiological underpinnings. As I proceeded with my research, it became clear that the poor mental health amongst LGBTQ individuals could be attributed to stigma, three types in particular: enacted stigma, felt stigma, and internalized stigma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a 34.9% lifetime prevalence of suicidal ideation amongst MSM. This rate increases to 42.6% when looking at populations from high income countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enacted stigma includes overt behaviors of prejudice and victimization.  Felt stigma involves the psychological impact of rejection as well as concealing one’s sexual orientation. Internalized stigma, or internalized homophobia, involves LGBTQ individuals having negative feelings towards homosexuality and their own sexual orientation. One study conducted in Germany found that all three forms of stigma were &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1435-7&quot;&gt;positively correlated with mental health issues.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there have been recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/7998/4c4c55269fb42882379aca0e7b0ec50a10c2.pdf&quot;&gt;advances in LGBTQ rights and acceptance&lt;/a&gt; within the Western world. However, these advances are absent in other parts of the world such as China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that rates of internalized stigma are higher in men who have sex with men (MSM) in China than in other countries. It was also found that amongst Chinese MSM, higher rates of internalized homophobia are associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://equityhealthj.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12939-017-0530-1&quot;&gt;higher rates of psychological distress.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the subsequent effects from mental health issues that the LGBTQ group faces, suicide is the biggest concern. In Canada, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09581596.2014.946887?scroll=top&amp;amp;needAccess=true&quot;&gt;suicide&lt;/a&gt; is the number one cause of premature mortality amongst MSM. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1575-9&quot;&gt;One meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; found that there is a 34.9% lifetime prevalence of suicidal ideation amongst MSM. This rate increases to 42.6% when looking at populations from high income countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only did sexual minority women experience worse mental health compared to their exclusively heterosexual counterparts, but they also experienced greater rates of interpersonal violence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSM are not the only LGBTQ population that experience poor mental health. This pattern also occurs in sexual minority women. These findings primarily come by comparing exclusively heterosexual women to sexual minority women. Unfortunately there are few studies examining subsets of sexual minority women, which include mainly heterosexuals, bisexuals, and lesbians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/track/pdf/10.1186/s12905-017-0452-5&quot;&gt;In an Australian study&lt;/a&gt; not only did sexual minority women experience worse mental health compared to their exclusively heterosexual counterparts, but they also experienced greater rates of interpersonal violence. Of further concern, bisexual women have the highest levels of stress, anxiety symptoms, and depression while simultaneously having the lowest levels of mental health and life satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual and gender minorities from certain populations are also found to experience greater rates of mental health conditions. Sex workers experience high rates of violence and sexual health vulnerabilities, however research on mental health in this population is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-017-0491-y&quot;&gt;A study of sex workers in Canada&lt;/a&gt; found that 49% of sex workers are diagnosed with mental health conditions. When researchers delved further into the data they found that identifying as a sexual and/or gender minority was a significant predictor of obtaining a mental health diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10279&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10279 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;198&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/PFLAG-300x198.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;PFLAG (Parents and Friends of Lesibans and Gays)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;CreativeCommons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pride is unique because it is a time to celebrate love and acceptance; a time when literally all the colors of the rainbow permeate the streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, this is a reprieve from the day-to-day challenges that many LGBTQ individuals experience. It is a way to provide support and encouragement to these people who are in such desperate need of support and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot ignore the dangers that this community faces throughout the world and how stigma can result in millions of people experiencing poor mental health, psychiatric illness, suicidal ideation, and even death by suicide, but by rallying during Pride, LGBTQ individuals have an opportunity to not only embrace their true selves but also fight to protect themselves and others from the challenges they inevitably face throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/22/celebrating-pride-recognizing-mental-health-challenges-lgbtq-community/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Celebrating Pride while recognizing the mental health challenges of the LGBTQ community&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ben Ragen</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What is it about hogweed — and lemons and limes — that can cause burns?</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-hogweed-and-lemons-and-limes-can-cause-burns"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-hogweed-and-lemons-and-limes-can-cause-burns</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T14:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Some plants have compounds that, after exposure to sunlight, produce streaky or spotty burns.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A journal decided to correct, rather than retract, a paper that contained “potentially contentious advice.” Do you agree with their call?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/22/a-journal-decided-to-correct-rather-than-retract-a-paper-that-contained-potentially-contentious-advice-do-you-agree-with-their-call/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=67118</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T12:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In March, a journal published a paper about blood sugar levels in newborns that caused an immediate outcry from outside experts, who were concerned it contained a sentence that could be potentially harmful if misinterpreted by doctors. Recently, the journal explained — in impressive detail — why it’s not retracting the paper. That, of course, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/22/a-journal-decided-to-correct-rather-than-retract-a-paper-that-contained-potentially-contentious-advice-do-you-agree-with-their-call/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A journal decided to correct, rather than retract, a paper that contained “potentially contentious advice.” Do you agree with their call?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How a squishy clam conquers a rock</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-squishy-clam-conquers-rock"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-squishy-clam-conquers-rock</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Old boring clam research is upended after 82 years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New studies add evidence to a possible link between Alzheimer’s and herpesvirus</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alzheimers-herpesvirus-possible-link"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alzheimers-herpesvirus-possible-link</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T10:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers saw higher levels of herpesvirus in the brains of Alzheimer’s patients, which may contribute to plaque formation.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leah Rosenbaum</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Little world, big problems: unravelling the origin of slave-raiding in ants</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/22/little-world-big-problems-unravelling-the-origin-of-slave-raiding-in-ants/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10272</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T08:50:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Formica.sanguinea6.-.lindsey-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nobody can deny the fascination arising from the complexity of the social architecture which defines the life of the anthill, and the slave-raiding behaviour of some species of &lt;em&gt;Formica &lt;/em&gt;outstands as a spectacular case of social parasitism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evolutionary pathway towards slavery has been intriguing generations of natural scientists, and gave life to a discussion which finds its roots in Charles Darwin ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Origin_of_Species&quot;&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/a&gt;’ itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The father of the theory of evolution suggested that slave-raiding in the genus &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt; evolved progressively, through an intermediary step of so-called ‘temporary parasitism’. This hypothesis is sustained by several modern researchers, but other scientists propose an alternative explanation, suggesting that parasitic colony founding evolved several times independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To unravel the nodes of a 150-years old debate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jonathan_Romiguier&quot;&gt;Jonathan Romiguier&lt;/a&gt;, with a group of researchers from the University of Lausanne, Montpellier, British Columbia and Helsinki, took advantage of a modern phylogenomic approach to finally solve the intricate relationship among paleartic &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt; subgenera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a mixed experimental and bioinformatics methodology, Romiguier and his colleagues generated a phylogenetic tree to reconstruct the evolutionary steps of the four &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt; subgenera differentiation. Following the clades of their phylogenetic tree, we can retrace the history of paleartic &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt;, highlighting the key moments of the journey from freedom to slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10273&quot; style=&quot;width: 788px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-10273&quot; height=&quot;334&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/12862_2018_1159_Fig1_HTML.gif&quot; width=&quot;778&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Molecular phylogeny of &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Taken from manuscript&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the basal position of the tree, we find the free living &lt;em&gt;Serviformica&lt;/em&gt;, the only group which is able to form colonies independently, indicating that &lt;em&gt;Formica &lt;/em&gt;genus shares a free living ancestor with independent colony founding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the tree, and therefore the evolution of &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt;, we can find a single clade grouping the remaining subgenera, &lt;em&gt;Coptoformica&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Formica s. str.&lt;/em&gt; and the slave-making &lt;em&gt;Raptiformica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They all share some fundamental traits, such as the loss of the ability of independently found new colonies and temporary parasitic colony founding, suggesting that they can be considered quite close relatives, sharing a common ancestor that started to parasitize the &lt;em&gt;Serviformica &lt;/em&gt;nests, and which passed on this capability to all of the three groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coptoformica&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Formica s. str.&lt;/em&gt;, also known as ‘wood ants’, however, rely on mechanisms other than slavery to start new colonies. They normally perform ‘budding’, a process where new queens and workers leave to start a new colony nearby. This behaviour leads to the creation of super colonies of many inter-connected nests, and it is thought to be an adaptation to cold habitats, where the success of independent colony founding is limited by high queen mortality. In this context, intra-specific brood transport among nests is often observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wood ants can use so-called ‘temporary parasitism’; in this case, new queens enter the nest of a &lt;em&gt;Serviformica&lt;/em&gt; species, expelling and replacing the original queen, and use the host workers as helpers. With time, host workers are gradually replaced by the daughters of the temporary parasite queen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, &lt;em&gt;Raptiformica&lt;/em&gt; developed the unique feature of active slave-making, alongside temporary parasitism. This is perpetrated as seasonal, inter-specific brood robbing from &lt;em&gt;Serviformica&lt;/em&gt; nests to increase worker force. After emerging, &lt;em&gt;Serviformica&lt;/em&gt; workers behave as if they were in their own colony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, the brood exchange typical of wood ants could have evolved toward selfish brood robbing during territorial battles, to ultimately become the inter-specific slave-raiding observed in &lt;em&gt;Raptiformica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolving the deepest nodes of &lt;em&gt;Formica&lt;/em&gt; relationships led to the formulation of a theory that confirms Darwin first hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The branching order of phylogeny suggests the evolutionary pathway towards slavery had a single origin, which then developed in several steps, where temporary parasitism can be seen as an intermediary step between free-living hosts and slave-maker parasites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of our evolutionary journey, we can look at the phylogenetic tree of Romiguier as a solid backbone in support of the classic model described in ‘On the Origin of the Species’, which adds a dowel to the global puzzle of evolution of slave-making in ants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/22/little-world-big-problems-unravelling-the-origin-of-slave-raiding-in-ants/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Little world, big problems: unravelling the origin of slave-raiding in ants&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Marta Gritti</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Attack of the Photoclones: Sharma-Madhuri Prequel</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/22/attack-of-the-photoclones-sharma-madhuri-prequel/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24789</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T08:48:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Smut Clyde is a natural force I insidiously chose to harvest and unleash upon the worst cheaters of the research community. His previous contribution to my site, about the nanotechnology Photoshoppers Prashant Sharma and Rashmi Madhuri, flushed several promising  academic careers down the toilet, quite deservingly so. Both are under institutional investigation and public ridicule, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/22/attack-of-the-photoclones-sharma-madhuri-prequel/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Attack of the Photoclones: Sharma-Madhuri Prequel&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Burnout is common among psychotherapists – now a review has identified the personal characteristics that increase the risk further</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/22/burnout-is-common-among-psychotherapists-now-a-review-has-identified-the-personal-characteristics-that-increase-the-risk-further/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34082</id>
		<updated>2018-06-22T07:39:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-907578226.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34083&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34083&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;18&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 6D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman's Emotional Struggle, sleeping and dreaming&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1507060421&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Movement of light. Portrait beautiful woman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Movement of light. Portrait beautiful woman&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-907578226.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-907578226.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-907578226.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/22/burnout-is-common-among-psychotherapists-now-a-review-has-identified-the-personal-characteristics-that-increase-the-risk-further/movement-of-light-portrait-beautiful-woman/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-907578226.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working an emotionally-demanding job can leave you frazzled by alienation, exhaustion, and confusion about whether you are doing any good. Clinical psychologists and psychotherapists live their day-to-day at the interface of their clients’ most difficult emotions and recollections, so it is no surprise that burnout is a leading cause of problems for those in the profession. To better understand the risk factors that contribute to therapist burnout, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22615?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;new review article&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Clinical Psychology&lt;/i&gt; has examined findings from 30 years of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34082&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabrielle Simionato and Susan Simpson of the University of South Australia gathered 40 articles in English on the topic, involving a total of almost 9,000 psychotherapists. On average, participants expressed a low to moderate degree of occupational stress, with just over half of those canvassed reporting moderate to high burnout. Burnout is often broken into three elements, and of these, the one most prevalent for therapists was emotional exhaustion – feeling physical and emotional fatigue while at work. Also prevalent to a lesser degree were the other two aspects: depersonalisation and a reduced sense of personal accomplishment.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of factors correlated with burnout, although as the studies were overwhelmingly cross-sectional we have to take care about assigning causality.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnout rates were higher in psychologists who were less experienced, and also in those with less subjective confidence in their professional ability. Several studies showed a lack of social support in or outside the workplace was associated with burnout. However, other studies showed that frequent discussion of work frustration with others was itself associated with higher burnout. This could simply be because therapists on the brink of overload are more likely to vent. Alternatively, there could be a reverse causality – other research has suggested &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/23/workplace-venting-makes-it-harder-to-bounce-back-from-bad-experiences/&quot;&gt;venting can impede recovery&lt;/a&gt; from stressful situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, the evidence was contradictory: for example more burnout was identified in women in five studies, but more in men in another three, with no association with gender found in a further six, resulting in no clear message for gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The review flagged a number of protective strategies and behaviours, including the value of effective personal boundaries in order to maintain some emotional separation from clients’ problems. Another observation was that therapists experiencing more burnout tended not to use humour, or only in a self-defeating way, although again this could be a consequence of burnout rather than a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personality traits are reasonably stable so their association with burnout is more likely to be causal. As in previous research, perfectionism was linked to burnout, as was neuroticism, likely due to a heightened sensitivity to negative events. Less agreeable and less extraverted psychotherapists tended to report burnout; the authors suggest this may be because such individuals tend to have weaker social support networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on their findings, Simionato and Simpson make some specific recommendations for ways of approaching work that may be useful: maintaining boundaries, seeking support, staying in touch with humour. There is also some general evidence that mindfulness may be an effective route to reducing rumination and unrealistic expectations. Supervisors should consider that therapists who muster confidence in their abilities are likely to ward off emotional overload, and therefore ensure that their charges’ successes are recognised and their struggles put in context. The likely influence of personality factors reinforces the need for people to be holistically suited to the particular challenges of a job role. A therapist seeking to work in a highly challenging position, due to the nature of clients or the operating environment, should be both technically qualified and temperamentally suited, or else they may pay the price over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22615?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;Personal risk factors associated with burnout among psychotherapists: A systematic review of the literature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Koko the gorilla is gone, but she left a legacy</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/koko-gorilla-gone-she-left-legacy"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/koko-gorilla-gone-she-left-legacy</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T21:35:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An ape that touched millions imparted some hard lessons about primate research.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">It may take a village (of proteins) to turn on genes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/it-may-take-village-proteins-turn-genes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/it-may-take-village-proteins-turn-genes</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Clusters of proteins transiently work together to turn on genes, new microscopy studies of live cells suggest.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s how drinking coffee could protect your heart</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-drinking-coffee-could-protect-your-heart"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-drinking-coffee-could-protect-your-heart</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Coffee’s heart-healthy effects rely on boosting cells’ energy production, a study in mice suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Einstein’s general relativity reigns supreme, even on a galactic scale</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/einstein-general-relativity-reigns-supreme-even-galactic-scale"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/einstein-general-relativity-reigns-supreme-even-galactic-scale</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have made the most precise test of Einstein’s theory of gravity at great distances.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A 2,200-year-old Chinese tomb held a new gibbon species, now extinct</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-gibbon-species-extinct-ape-chinese-tomb"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-gibbon-species-extinct-ape-chinese-tomb</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T18:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers have discovered a new gibbon species in an ancient royal Chinese tomb. It's already extinct.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">#DataDive NYC: Follow the volunteer data scientists, statisticians, coders and hackers as they build solutions for human rights</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/datadive-nyc-data-scientists-are-volunteering-to-build-solutions-for-human-rights"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/datadive-nyc-data-scientists-are-volunteering-to-build-solutions-for-human-rights</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T12:57:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 At Google HQ in New York, Elsevier's technologists and data scientists are joining colleagues from Google Cloud, Teradata and 11th Hour Project for this DataKind event</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-22T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">He was once a prominent cancer researcher. Then his gambling — and a finding of scientific misconduct — got in the way.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/21/he-was-once-a-prominent-cancer-researcher-then-his-gambling-and-a-finding-of-scientific-misconduct-got-in-the-way/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=67072</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T12:26:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In September 2014, an investigation into the work of an award-winning cancer researcher in Illinois concluded that multiple papers had been affected by misconduct. Now, nearly four years later, two of those articles have been retracted. What happened in the intervening years reveals a complicated and at times bizarre story involving not only scientific misconduct, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/21/he-was-once-a-prominent-cancer-researcher-then-his-gambling-and-a-finding-of-scientific-misconduct-got-in-the-way/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;He was once a prominent cancer researcher. Then his gambling — and a finding of scientific misconduct — got in the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Hopes and fears for AI: the experts' view</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hopes-and-fears-for-ai-the-experts-view"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hopes-and-fears-for-ai-the-experts-view</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T09:31:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 It won’t end the world or single-handedly cure cancer, but AI is a powerful tool</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-22T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Psychology’s favourite moral thought experiment doesn’t predict real-world behaviour</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/21/psychologys-favourite-moral-thought-experiment-doesnt-predict-real-world-behaviour/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34043</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T07:58:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-170617385.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34058&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34058&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 30D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mice being used in scientific research.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1220779962&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;filo&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;320&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;White Research Mice&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;White Research Mice&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-170617385.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-170617385.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-170617385.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3504,2336&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/21/psychologys-favourite-moral-thought-experiment-doesnt-predict-real-world-behaviour/white-research-mice/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-170617385.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you wilfully hurt or kill one person so as to save multiple others? That’s the dilemma at the heart of moral psychology’s favourite thought experiment and its derivatives. In the classic case, you must decide whether or not to pull a lever to divert a runaway mining trolley so that it avoids killing five people and instead kills a single individual on another line. A popular theory in the field states that, to many of us, so abhorrent is the notion of deliberately harming someone that our “deontological” instincts deter us from pulling the lever; on the other hand, the more we intellectualise the problem with cool detachment, the more likely we will make a utilitarian or consequentialist judgment and divert the trolley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with thought experiments of this kind, psychologists have examined all manner of individual and circumstantial factors that influence the likelihood of people making  deontological vs. utilitarian moral decisions. However, there’s a fatal (excuse the pun) problem. A striking &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797617752640&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science &lt;/em&gt;finds that our answers to the thought experiments don’t match up with our real-world moral decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34043&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dries Bostyn and his colleagues at Ghent University recruited nearly 300 participants. All answered several hypothetical moral dilemmas derived from the classic trolley dilemma – for instance, in a building on fire, they had to say whether they would push a man through a locked window to his death in order to make an exit for the five children trapped inside. The participants also completed several questionnaires tapping psychological factors, such as psychopathy and “need for cognition”, previously identified as being associated with being more utilitarian in one’s moral decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fortnight later, just under 200 of the participants were invited to the psych lab, one at a time, to take part in a real-life moral dilemma involving live mice. The participants saw two cages – one housing one mouse, the other housing five – each wired to an electroshock machine. They were told that in 20 seconds, if they did nothing, the machine would deliver a very painful but nonlethal shock to the cage containing five mice. However, if the participants pressed a button in front of them, they could divert the electric shock to the cage containing one mouse, thus saving the other five from pain (in actuality this was an illusion and all participants were later informed that in fact no mice were shocked or harmed in the study).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining participants went to the psych lab but performed a hypothetical version of the mouse decision. They heard a description of the same two-cage set up faced by the others and they had to say whether they would press the button or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants who performed the real-life mouse task behaved differently than those who made a purely hypothetical decision – they were less than half as likely to let the five mice get shocked (16 per cent of them left the button unpressed compared with 34 per cent of the hypothetical group). In other words, faced with a real-life dilemma, the volunteers were more consequentialist / utilitarian; that is, more willing to inflict harm for the greater good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most important finding – at least for the validity of moral psychology which so often relies on thought experiments – is that the participants’ preference for deontological vs. utilitarian responding in their answers to the earlier battery of 10 hypothetical moral dilemmas bore no relation to their decision in the real-life mouse task (in contrast, the decisions of participants in the hypothetical mouse group were related to their answers to the earlier moral dilemmas). What is more, none of the psychological factors, such as psychopathy or need for cognition, were related to decision-making in the real-life moral dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For so long, moral psychology has relied on the notion that you can extrapolate from people’s decisions in hypothetical thought experiments to infer something meaningful about how they would behave morally in the real world. These new findings challenge that core assumption of the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is not to say people’s hypothetical decisions are meaningless. Although participants’ responses to the earlier moral thought experiments did not predict their later real moral decisions (i.e. whether or not to press the button to divert the electric charge), they were not totally unrelated. Among those who pressed the button in the real-life task, if they’d also earlier shown a preference for utilitarian decisions in the thought experiments then they tended to press the button more quickly; they also expressed less doubt and discomfort about their decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious criticism of this research is that the trolley problem and its derivatives involve humans, whereas the real-life moral dilemma used in this study involved mice. However, the researchers believe this is not a critical issue since the moral conflicts (deliberately harming the few to save the many) are the same in both cases. They also note that they used a questionnaire to measure their participants’ levels of empathy for animals, and how participants scored made no difference to the pattern of findings (meaning its unlikely that participants’ levels of concern or not for the mice explains the results).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bostyn and his team don’t know why people’s judgments on the moral thought experiments didn’t predict their choice in the real-life moral task. Current theory – based on the idea that emotional responding leads to more deontological decisions and rational thinking to more utilitarian decisions – isn’t much help because it would actually predict more deontological decisions in the more vivid and emotive real-life task, which is the opposite of what was found. The researchers speculate that perhaps people are more inclined to virtue-signal when answering in the hypothetical (i.e. signalling that they couldn’t possibly choose to deliberately harm another, even to save the majority), but one could just as easily make this case for the very opposite results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Future research will have to investigate these and other possibilities,” the researchers concluded. “… [W]e advance the argument that we will be able to bridge the gap between moral judgment and moral behaviour only by exploring new research paradigms that bring more decision making into the real world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797617752640&quot;&gt;Of Mice, Men, and Trolleys: Hypothetical Judgment Versus Real-Life Behavior in Trolley-Style Moral Dilemmas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 146 Alan Jasanoff on The Biological Mind</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-146-alan-jasanoff-on-the-biological-mind"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/f15cc616f184451aacff8cb86dd9149c</id>
		<updated>2018-06-21T01:10:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;This is an interview with MIT neuroscientist, Dr. Alan Jasanoff about his book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2JkF2HC&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;amazon link&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Biological Mind: How Brain, Body, and Environment Collaborate to Make Us Who We Are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We talk about what he calls the &quot;cerebral mystique&quot; and why it is important to remember because the brain is embodied it is not autonomous. The Mind is the result of the interaction of the brain, body, and its environment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&quot;&gt;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt; for full show notes and episode transcripts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try a free month of The Great Courses Plus at &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegreatcoursesplus.com/ginger&quot;&gt;http://thegreatcoursesplus.com/ginger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, Alan Jasanoff</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-22T16:01:56+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Splitting families may end, but migrant kids’ trauma needs to be studied</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/splitting-families-migrant-children-border-trauma"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/splitting-families-migrant-children-border-trauma</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T21:39:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The long-term effects of separating children from their parents at the U.S. border need to be studied, scientists say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Signal Propagation and Logic Gating in Networks of Integrate-and-Fire Neurons</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/06/20/signal-propagation-and-logic-gating-in-networks-of-integrate-and-fire-neurons.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-06-20:/2018/06/20/signal-propagation-and-logic-gating-in-networks-of-integrate-and-fire-neurons.html</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T14:35:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Sam Sutton's journal club session where he discusses the paper &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16291952&quot;&gt;Signal Propagation and Logic Gating in Networks of Integrate-and-Fire Neurons (Vogels and Abbott, 2005)&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transmission of signals within the brain is essential for cognitive function, but it is not clear how neural circuits support reliable and accurate signal propagation over a sufficiently large dynamic range. Two modes of propagation have been studied: synfire chains, in which synchronous activity travels through feedforward layers of a neuronal network, and the propagation of fluctuations in firing rate
across these layers. In both cases, a sufficient amount of noise, which was added to previous models from an external source, had to be included to support stable propagation. Sparse, randomly connected networks of spiking model neurons can generate chaotic patterns of activity. We investigate whether this activity, which is a more realistic noise source, is sufficient to allow for signal transmission. We find that, for rate-coded signals but not for synfire chains, such networks support robust and accurate signal reproduction through up to six layers if appropriate adjustments are made in synaptic strengths. We investigate the factors affecting transmission and show that multiple signals can propagate simultaneously along different pathways. Using this feature, we show how different types of logic gates can arise within the architecture of the random network through the strengthening of specific synapses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 22/06/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sam Sutton</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T14:35:20+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Are Dyslexics More Entrepreneurial?</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/20/are-dyslexics-more-entrepreneurial/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23742</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T14:30:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is rather common: it is estimated that around 5-10% of individuals are dyslexic. Despite an apparent disability, some are famous, like Tom Cruise or Richard Branson. Obviously, they do not suffer from a lack of intelligence and are, in fact, quite successful in the business world. So what is going on in their brains? Are they developing some compensatory mechanisms that help them to do things better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epidemiological research studies indicate that dyslexics develop coping strategies to compensate for their weaknesses, which helps them in later life. The resilience that they acquire while in school often helps them to be more successful in developing a business, in being an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics show that there are twice more dyslexics among entrepreneurs when compared to the general population. However, dyslexics are uncommon in higher management. They also tend to have a different business management style. Thus, they do better in startups and are better at handling particular types of businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is usually first identified when a child goes to school and struggles with scrambled text. Dyslexic children have difficulty in reading texts, interpreting them, and explaining the meaning of the text to others, even though they can be very intelligent otherwise. Dyslexia often results in poor academic performance, undue pressure, and psychological trauma. Each dyslexic child needs to learn to cope with these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although dyslexic children are as intelligent as their peers at school, they are often labeled as less capable. Children with dyslexia are often targets of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/03/school-bullying-forgive-ignore-or-revenge/&quot;&gt;bullying in school&lt;/a&gt;. Poor self-image at school often leads to worsening of self-esteem in many of these kids. As helping dyslexic children is not easy, they are often left to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s going on in the dyslexic brain? Neurological basis of dyslexia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a common disorder, dyslexia is the subject of multiple studies. Researchers agree that those living with dyslexia may have differences in the brain relative to non-dyslexic children, and these differences are the subject of intense clinical research. The recent explosion in brain imaging technology is helping us gain a deeper understanding of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurological theory of dyslexia is one of the earliest. The theory was proposed about a century ago when British physicians Morgan and Hinshelwood described dyslexia as a “visual word blindness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of adults &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/07/14/living-with-traumatic-brain-injury/&quot;&gt;living with brain trauma&lt;/a&gt; in the left parietal region demonstrated that many of these people develop reading difficulties. They find it challenging to process the optical image of letters. Thus, the early theory was that those with dyslexia have developmental defects in the parietal region of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left parietal involvement was also somewhat confirmed during pathological examination of the brains of those who died at an earlier age and were known to be dyslexic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important theory focuses on delayed brain lateralization in dyslexia. It is thought that some people have weak or insufficient brain lateralization that hinders the understanding of languages. This theory was the subject of multiple studies in the second half of last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest research into the neurophysiology of those living with dyslexia seems to indicate that dyslexia is phonological in nature: dyslexics have difficulty in manipulating the phoneme parts of speech. It is possible that there are developmental issues in the visual tract or other visual mechanisms in the brain may be contributing to the difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from defects in a specific subsystem of the vision pathway, researchers think that there are other brain developmental issues involved as well. It is entirely possible that people with dyslexia have temporal processing impairment, and therefore they are not able to process information fast enough. Thus, dyslexia is considered the result of multi-system deficits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is probably the result of deficits in the brain at multiple levels. There is an impaired phoneme discrimination resulting in difficulty in understanding spelling. Visual perceptual impairment leads to further worsening of word recognition, and phonological awareness impairment causes speech disturbances. In the center of all this is delayed temporal processing. The end result is delayed speech development, difficulties in reading and comprehending texts, and poor academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What makes a dyslexic a successful person?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Leonardo da Vinci to Einstein, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/04/16/opening-the-classroom-door-for-children-with-autism/&quot;&gt;children with learning disabilities&lt;/a&gt; prove that there is a limited link between disability and intelligence. Children with dyslexia are at least equally intelligent to non-dyslexic children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The higher success of individuals with dyslexia in certain professions is probably the result of resilience or compensatory mechanisms that they cultivate during the school days to overcome their difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these kids may develop better skills for interacting with others. They may focus more on specific arts or sciences. Many of them may not concentrate on studies and instead start doing business at an early age. This means that they can be found in any profession, and in the long run they are equally successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compensatory mechanisms developed at a young age may provide an edge over others in specific areas when the children grow up. Even though dyslexics may score poorly in school, they may outscore other children in practical life since they spend more time perfecting their verbal skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an entrepreneur, dyslexics are known to be good at delegating tasks, they are excellent mentors, and they are often creative. All of these qualities usually make them more successful entrepreneurs, though they may not be that good in roles where there is less space for creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving success with dyslexia is perhaps about learning different skills, mastering different approaches to solving the tasks, and developing strategies to compensate for certain limitations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habib, M. (2000) The neurological basis of developmental dyslexia: An overview and working hypothesis. &lt;em&gt;Brain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;123&lt;/em&gt;(12), 2373–2399. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/123.12.2373&quot;&gt;10.1093/brain/123.12.2373&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke, R., Scallan, S., Mann, R., &amp;amp; Alexander, G. (2015) Clinicians with dyslexia: a systematic review of effects and strategies. &lt;em&gt;The Clinical Teacher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(6), 394–398. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/tct.12331&quot;&gt;10.1111/tct.12331&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logan, J. (2009) Dyslexic entrepreneurs: the incidence; their coping strategies and their business skills. &lt;em&gt;Dyslexia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(4), 328–346. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/dys.388&quot;&gt;10.1002/dys.388&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logan, J. (2018) Analysis of the incidence of dyslexia in entrepreneurs and its implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toffalini, E., Pezzuti, L., &amp;amp; Cornoldi, C. (2017) Einstein and dyslexia: Is giftedness more frequent in children with a specific learning disorder than in typically developing children? &lt;em&gt;Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;, 175–179. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intell.2017.04.006&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.intell.2017.04.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yu, X., Zuk, J., &amp;amp; Gaab, N. What Factors Facilitate Resilience in Developmental Dyslexia? Examining Protective and Compensatory Mechanisms Across the Neurodevelopmental Trajectory. &lt;em&gt;Child Development Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt;(0). &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/cdep.12293&quot;&gt;10.1111/cdep.12293&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How to help your toddler be helpful (with caveats)</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/help-toddler-kids-social-skills"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/help-toddler-kids-social-skills</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T14:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Even very young toddlers like to help, a social skill that’s linked to later success in school and life.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rachel Ehrenberg</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A misconduct probe — which led to 20 retraction requests — took four years. Why?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/20/a-misconduct-probe-which-led-to-20-retraction-requests-took-four-years-why/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66964</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T12:00:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A probe into the work of a researcher who studied natural products for cancer had many stops and starts along the way — including five extensions granted by the U.S. Office of Research Integrity — according to documents obtained by Retraction Watch. Following a public records request, we recently obtained a copy of the report … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/20/a-misconduct-probe-which-led-to-20-retraction-requests-took-four-years-why/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A misconduct probe — which led to 20 retraction requests — took four years. Why?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Each year painted lady butterflies cross the Sahara — and then go back again</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/painted-lady-butterflies-migration-sahara-africa"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/painted-lady-butterflies-migration-sahara-africa</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Painted ladies migrate the farthest of any butterfly.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leah Rosenbaum</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New trial finds that frequent aerobic exercise reduces the hard-to-treat “negative symptoms” of schizophrenia</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/20/new-trial-finds-that-frequent-aerobic-exercise-reduces-the-hard-to-treat-negative-symptoms-of-schizophrenia/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34066</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T08:10:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-929514508.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34067&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34067&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector icon of heartbeat near running man&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cardio training icon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cardio training icon&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1748,1715&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/20/new-trial-finds-that-frequent-aerobic-exercise-reduces-the-hard-to-treat-negative-symptoms-of-schizophrenia/cardio-training-icon/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aerobic exercise – any activity that gets your heart pumping harder – improves &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/19/10-ways-that-running-changes-your-mind-and-brain/&quot;&gt;mood, anxiety and memory.&lt;/a&gt; It can help people with major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder and anxiety disorder. Now there’s evidence, from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00167/full&quot;&gt;randomised controlled trial&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt;, that a programme of regular aerobic exercise also reduces psychopathology in people diagnosed with schizophrenia. And it seems to have a particular impact on so-called “negative” symptoms, such as apathy and loss of emotional feeling, which are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25528757&quot;&gt;not improved by standard drug treatments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[W]hile antipsychotics [drug treatments] are essential in treating schizophrenia, interventions other than antipsychotic treatment…may be needed to achieve better outcomes,” write the authors of the new study, led by Peng-Wei Wang at Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34066&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers recruited 62 patients, all of whom had received a diagnosis of schizophrenia at least a year ago, and whose antipsychotic medication dosage had been stable for at least three months. These participants were randomly allocated into either an aerobic exercise group (30 minutes of “vigorous” aerobic exercise, taking into account each participant’s maximum heart rate) or a control group who performed stretching exercises (25 minutes of flexibility, toning and balance exercises), with a goal of five sessions a week, for 12 weeks. Not all participants managed to stick to the minimum requirement of three sessions per week for the full three months. But 24 in the exercise group and 22 in the control group did complete the study.  (There were no significant differences in gender make-up, age of onset of schizophrenia, or mean dosage of antipsychotics between the two groups.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A psychiatrist who was blind to the group allocations used a standard schizophrenia symptom evaluation scale to interview and evaluate all the participants at the start of the study; at the end of the 12 week intervention; and again, three months on. The control group showed no improvements in positive (e.g. hallucinations and delusions) or negative symptoms, or general psychopathology, during the intervention or the follow-up period. But for the aerobic exercise group, it was a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the 12-week intervention, their overall psychopathology and level of negative and positive symptoms decreased. Three months later, these improvements had been maintained (and, in the case of negative symptoms, actually continued to improve). Also, the more severe their negative symptoms and general psychopathology at the start of the study, the bigger their improvements by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These results imply that [aerobic exercise] could be a good non-pharmacotherapeutic intervention for antipsychotic-treated patients with schizophrenia,” the researchers conclude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various possible explanations for the effects. Vigorous exercise can boost levels of the neurotransmitter glutamate (other work has found that enhancing glutamate function can improve negative symptoms of schizophrenia); increase levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (which is involved in repairing damaged brain cells and triggering the growth of new ones; low levels of BDNF are associated with symptoms of schizophrenia); and also help regulate the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis – the stress response system. “HPA dysfunction is an important characteristic in schizophrenia,” the authors note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is a one-off 12-week programme really enough to produce lasting – and even escalating – improvements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers did not collect data on how much exercise the aerobic group did in the three months between the end of the 12-week intervention and the final assessment. If the participants continued to exercise, this may have accounted for the ongoing improvements. Future research will have to explore this. But if an exercise programme does have to be maintained, given all the manifold benefits, surely that’s no bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00167/full?utm_source=F-AAE&amp;amp;utm_medium=EMLF&amp;amp;utm_campaign=MRK_648100_68_Psychi_20180522_arts_A&quot;&gt;Effect of Aerobic Exercise on Improving Symptoms of Individuals With Schizophrenia: A Single Blinded Randomized Control Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How Gender Summits have shaped Elsevier’s role in the research community</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-gender-summits-have-shaped-elseviers-role-in-the-research-community"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-gender-summits-have-shaped-elseviers-role-in-the-research-community</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T07:52:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier CEO Ron Mobed talks about the importance of gender diversity in science</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-22T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">With this new system, robots can ‘read’ your mind</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-brain-waves-read-your-mind"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-brain-waves-read-your-mind</id>
		<updated>2018-06-20T04:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Giving robots instructions via brain waves and hand gestures could help the machines operate more safely and efficiently.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">To combat an expanding universe, aliens could hoard stars</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-expanding-universe-aliens-could-hoard-stars"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-expanding-universe-aliens-could-hoard-stars</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T18:50:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An advanced alien civilization might combat the impact of dark energy by harvesting stars.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">On Jupiter, lightning flashes from storms swirling at the poles</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-lightning-flashes-storms-swirling-poles"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-lightning-flashes-storms-swirling-poles</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T16:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 After almost 40 years, scientists have discovered that Jupiter has lightning that is similar to lightning on Earth — it just happens in a different place.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leah Rosenbaum</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Together We Witnessed History At #BIO2018</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/together-we-witnessed-history-at-bio2018/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1585</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T15:15:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1585&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-937dd8a elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;937dd8a&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-98579d1 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;98579d1&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-85ef566 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;85ef566&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The theme of this year’s BIO International Convention was “Make History”, and it did just that. The event, hosting over 1,800 exhibitors and thousands of speakers, drew over 18,289 global attendees and facilitated more than 46,000 one-on-one meetings during its 4-day duration (setting a Guinness World Record for “The Largest Business Partnering Event”). BIO attracted companies, academic centers, patient groups, researchers, investors, and even celebrities such as cancer survivor and award-winning journalist Robin Roberts as well as director, actor, and advocate Rob Reiner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had the honor of participating in this historic conference, and so we’d like to share select highlights with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;KEYNOTE SPEECHES&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;I believe in dreaming big and focusing small ~ great words to live by. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RobinRoberts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@RobinRoberts&lt;/a&gt; BIOConvention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JimGreenwood?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@JimGreenwood&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/bio2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#bio2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/x2VsBiJS35&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/x2VsBiJS35&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Jennifer Landress (@jlandress) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jlandress/status/1004002670661853184?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tweet capturing the Robin Roberts’ interview with BIO’s chief Jim Greenwood&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robin Roberts, ABC’s Good Morning America journalist, kicked off BIO. She discussed her triumphant victory over cancer and her trailblazing career in journalism during her interview with BIO president and chief executive officer Jim Greenwood.&lt;br /&gt;She also acknowledged how the collective work of people such as those attending BIO is the reason she is alive today.“This is the importance of why I want to meet with this group, to say thank you for the life-saving bone marrow transplant that I had,” she said, “It’s not about what we accomplish, it’s about what we overcome.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roberts also noted in her conversation with Greenwood, that she believed “in dreaming big and focusing small.” In other words, accomplishing great things takes time; Rome wasn’t built in a day, as the saying goes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Actor/Director Rob Reiner to address Bio Int. Conv. about his son overcoming battle w/addiction &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/t3jAFpkYjN&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/t3jAFpkYjN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Doug Cope (@dcopewbz) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dcopewbz/status/1004362448625963009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tweet showing Reiner’s interview with BIO’s chief Jim Greenwood&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Another keynote speaker was well-known actor and director Rob Reiner. Reiner urged the audience to continue working on drug research. He also shared a personal story about his son overcoming drug addiction and said, “We have a long way to go in trying to understand what causes people to want to use and how to treat them. There is no question about it; it’s an epidemic. I mean it’s rife across this country…people talk about doing something and don’t do anything about it.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;ANNOUNCEMENT &amp;amp; AWARDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;BIO has become a launching platform for new partnerships, ventures, and awards. To illustrate, U.S. Health and Human Services (HHS) unveiled a new initiative called DRIVe (Division of Research, Innovation, and Ventures) to come up with new solutions to some of the toughest health security challenges we are faced with such as early detection of illness and sepsis. Another announcement that caught everyone’s attention was a five-year alliance between Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson (J&amp;amp;J) and Boston University – an attempt to change the way we detect and treat lung cancer today. J&amp;amp;J will fund a Lung Cancer Center at Boston University Medical Center as part of this new alliance. Just as important, the Henri A. Termeer Biotechnology Visionary Award was given to Dr. Sue Desmond-Hellmann, CEO of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, for the innovative spirit and transformative impact on patients’ lives. This is the first-ever award created in honor of the late Genzyme CEO who was instrumental in transforming Boston into a thriving hub of life science research, development and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;WORLD AT BIO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Thousands of attendees from over 74 different countries participated in the event, and most of the essential biotech hubs and nations had a presence in the form of pavilions and summits at the event. For example, a “conference-within-a-conference” called the China Summit was one of the country-specific meetings at BIO which highlighted the complexities of the world’s second-largest biotech market, and among other vital issues focused on the importance of collaboration between U.S. and China in the scientific research and business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Great turnout at the China Summit at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BIO2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BIO2018&lt;/a&gt; - great timing too given news flow like CStone/Blueprint deal &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BPMC&amp;amp;src=ctag&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;$BPMC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ST1PnJjCsJ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/ST1PnJjCsJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/sq13t1Gpxw&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/sq13t1Gpxw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Josh Berlin (@BioPharmaJosh) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BioPharmaJosh/status/1003683091515396102?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 4, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tweet gives a&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;glimpse of the China Summit.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;Canada’s presence at BIO couldn’t be ignored&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;either.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;Economic development and tech transfer teams, businesses, scientists, and government officials from The Great White North were seen everywhere. A prominent Canadian politician from Nova Scotia even gave a forward-looking speech on the future of Canada’s bioeconomy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-dnt=&quot;true&quot; data-width=&quot;550&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Challenging &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BIOConvention?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BIOConvention&lt;/a&gt; delegates to a game &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BIO2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BIO2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/bio2018cdn?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#bio2018cdn&lt;/a&gt; visit booth #651. See you soon &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/UK7BMeXgGg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UK7BMeXgGg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— BIOTECanada (@BIOTECanada) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BIOTECanada/status/1004429860964425728?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;Tweet showing &lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;an&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;ice hockey game at the Canada Pavilion&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;UNCONVENTIONAL BIOTECH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Medical Research Institute (MRI), the new, unconventional biotech startup that operates independently of profits and investors, was introduced at the BIO International Convention by Dr. Penny Heaton, the institute’s CEO. The organization is a non-profit spinoff of the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation — the world’s wealthiest charity. Dr. Penny Heaton described the mission and approach of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Medical Research Institute and discussed the roles of both organizations and their strategies to combat infectious diseases globally. MRI aims to develop products that will potentially eradicate diarrheal disease and end the TB epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;PARTY AT BIO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Although we didn’t attend the over-the-top party called&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/unofficial-party-at-bio-featured-dancers-plastered-company-logos-outraging-leadership&quot;&gt; PABNAB&lt;/a&gt;, our team had a great time interacting with our customers and partners at BIO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;team-science-exchange&quot; height=&quot;852&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/image1-769x1024.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Science Exchange&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;FDA at BIO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;The world’s most powerful regulator, Scott Gottlieb, was also present. During the &lt;i&gt;Fireside Chats&lt;/i&gt; at &lt;i&gt;BIO 2018,&lt;/i&gt; the FDA commissioner expressed his thoughts on developing lower-cost generics and biosimilars. He also shed light on other things such as gene therapy, the opioid crisis, more opportunities for patients, and the new Right to Try law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;SPOTTED INNOVATIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Many innovative technologies and businesses also caught our attention. To illustrate, innovations like real-time patient monitoring, video collaboration tools, 3D cell cultures, AI-enabled knowledge databases, microfluidic platforms, virtual reality 3D molecular visualization, and new inventive liquid biopsy technologies were big head-turners at the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;In addition, we learned about new innovative initiatives by biotech companies, big and small alike. One such company is Recombinetics; they employ gene-editing technology not just to improve human health but also to improve the health, well-being and productivity of animals. The company’s gene-editing technology can potentially be used to create animals with welfare traits, such as pigs that don’t need to be castrated, hornless cattle, heat-tolerant livestock and other disease-resistant animals.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Another example is Alnylam Pharmaceuticals. In his “Bio Buzz” Interview, John Maraganore, the company’s CEO, talked about an entirely new class of medicines derived from the Nobel Prize-winning discovery of advances in RNA interference (RNAi). With investigational RNAi therapeutics, it is possible to block the production of disease-causing proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Just as important, Amgen shared its approach to treating migraines. The company believes a new method of theirs can treat a problem that affects nearly one billion people across the globe – migraines!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 'Open Sans', brandon-grotesque, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Arial, sans-serif; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;If you couldn’t attend, we hope our coverage of this year’s BIO convention gave you a sense of its scale, history and importance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gursatya &quot;Guru&quot; Singh</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Fastest Path to Scientific Breakthroughs and the Leading Marketplace for Outsourced R&amp;amp;D.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neurotic folk spend more time doing chores</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34060</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T14:15:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-183807870.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34061&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34061&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;she is tired of doing all the houseworkFOR MORE IMAGES IN THIS SERIES, PLEASE VISIT OUR LIGHTBOX:\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1300720051&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;OrangeDukeProductions&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;38&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman wants to pull out her hair..&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woman wants to pull out her hair..&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1824,1644&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/woman-wants-to-pull-out-her-hair/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If personality traits are a genuine concept and not merely an artefact of psychologists’ imagination, then how people choose to spend their time ought to correlate with their scores on personality questionnaires, notwithstanding the constraints of life that prevent us from doing what we want. In fact, there are relatively few studies that have looked at correlations between traits and everyday behaviour, and of those that have, many relied on student volunteers (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20170518-the-everyday-habits-that-reveal-our-personalities&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for an overview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published earlier this year in &lt;em&gt;Collabra&lt;/em&gt; helps plug this research gap – Julia Rohrer and Richard Lucas analysed the “Big Five” trait personality scores of over 1,300 German volunteers (part of a nationally representative sample), average age 51 years, who on three successive years completed detailed diaries of what they had been up to the day before. Specifically, they indicated whether they had spent any time, and if so how much, on nine key activities the previous day, including socialising, work, chores and watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34060&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings, controlling for age and gender, will mostly make comfortable reading for personality psychologists. For instance, consistent with trait theory, high scorers on conscientiousness spent more time working and studying, whether they were full-time employed or not. Similarly, strong extraverts, the highly agreeable and open-minded were more likely to report socialising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other findings are more nuanced and intriguing. For instance, the highly conscientiousness were no more or less likely to report watching TV the previous day, but they reported watching it for less time. Meanwhile, extraversion, emotional stability, agreeableness and conscientiousness all went together with less time spent reading. In contrast, openness to experience was correlated with reading, and a trend toward reading for longer. Openness also correlated with time spent playing sports. Cultural activities, which typically correlate with openness, were not assessed in this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-105&quot; style=&quot;width: 2238px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 14.52.53.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34062&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34062&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 14.52.53&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2238,1352&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;Rohrer and Lucas 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intriguing findings concerned chores – against trait theory, the highly conscientiousness were no more likely to say they’d spent time on chores (even though orderliness is a key facet of conscientiousness), perhaps because they had everything in order already, whereas the highly neurotic (i.e. people with low emotional stability who typically experience more low moods) were more likely to say they’d done some chores the previous day, and for longer. Again it’s speculation, but perhaps this is because the emotionally unstable find disorder and clutter more upsetting, while at the same time not necessarily being particularly adept at keeping order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a trend toward agreeableness correlating with doing chores. This chimes with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917303094&quot;&gt;previous study&lt;/a&gt; that found, more specifically, that agreeableness correlated with spending more time ironing and washing up. The likely explanation in both cases is that highly agreeable people are more concerned with doing things that benefit others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach of asking people whether they’d performed an activity at all, and if so, for how long, also threw up some interesting contradictions. For instance, high scorers on openness were more likely to report socialising, yet at the same time, they tended to report doing so for less time than low scorers, perhaps because they had so many other competing demands on their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main weakness of this new data is its reliance (as in so much personality research) on people’s self-reports of their traits and behaviour, and the memory challenge for them of recalling what they’d been doing the previous day and for how long. Nonetheless, the findings serve to complement similar efforts using different approaches. “Our study suggests that even under the constraints of everyday life, personality shows modest [effect sizes were in the range of .1 to .2] but meaningful associations with daily patterns,” Rohrer and Lucas concluded. “Personality therefore qualifies as a real-world phenomenon, exerting its influence beyond the context of the research laboratory and allowing for strong descriptions of human life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;Only so Many Hours: Correlations between Personality and Daily Time Use in a Representative German Panel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">7 ways you can use our SDG Resource Centre</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/7-ways-you-can-use-our-sdg-resource-centre"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/7-ways-you-can-use-our-sdg-resource-centre</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T13:32:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Interactive platform by RELX Group lets you find news, research and reports on sustainable development around the world</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-06-22T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Madagascar’s predators are probably vulnerable to toxic toads</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/madagascar-invasive-asian-common-toads-predators-toxin"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/madagascar-invasive-asian-common-toads-predators-toxin</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T13:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Asian common toad, an invasive species in Madagascar, produces a toxin in its skin that’s probably toxic to most of the island’s predators.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Zielinski</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Fecal transplant paper pulled for “personal issue”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/19/fecal-transplant-paper-pulled-for-personal-issue/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66721</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T12:00:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Last month, the Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition pulled an article on fecal transplantation for a reason that, well, doesn’t pass the sniff test. The paper, by Sonia Michail of Children’s Hospital Los Angeles, appeared online in October 2017 and described a randomized controlled trial of fecal transplants to treat kids with ulcerative colitis. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/19/fecal-transplant-paper-pulled-for-personal-issue/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Fecal transplant paper pulled for “personal issue”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Adam Marcus</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Science Exchange Appoints Two New Executives to Accelerate Growth</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/science-exchange-appoints-two-new-executives-to-accelerate-growth/"/>
		<id>http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1580</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T10:31:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1580&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-575fb96 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;575fb96&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-4335506 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;4335506&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2fd5b9a elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;2fd5b9a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Veteran marketing and business development executives join &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt; to help lead the company through its next phase of growth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, June 14, 2018 &lt;/b&gt;— Science Exchange, the&lt;i&gt; leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, has appointed senior team members Rob Mihalko as Vice President of Marketing and Alex Slater as Vice President of Business Development and General Manager Europe. Both executives, reporting to Science Exchange CEO Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., will add to an already talented management team that is driving industry-leading solutions to improve the quality and efficiency of scientific research around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mihalko is a leading expert in business commerce and procurement and has extensive experience in successfully implementing go-to-market strategies for business-to-business marketplaces on a global scale. As VP of Marketing, Mihalko will be responsible for Science Exchange’s worldwide marketing activities. He will lead the way in aligning Science Exchange’s brand and product positioning with global marketing programs to boost awareness, sales and adoption of the company’s industry-leading R&amp;amp;D marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Science Exchange, Mihalko was Global Vice President of Solution &amp;amp; Customer Marketing for SAP Ariba, where he led marketing and product initiatives that transformed SAP Ariba into the world’s leading procurement and business commerce company. He also has held several senior marketing, product and finance roles with leading technology companies, including Microsoft, and was a management consultant with A.T. Kearney, advising senior executives on strategy, sourcing and supply chain transformation initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m delighted to have joined such a passionate and mission-driven team at Science Exchange,” said Mihalko. “I’m looking forward to helping the company build on its leadership position in the outsourced research market and support its growth in new verticals and geographies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a VP of Business Development and General Manager Europe, Alex Slater will be spearheading Science Exchange’s continued expansion into the European market. Slater brings 23 years of business development experience within contract research organizations to Science Exchange, spanning the entirety of drug discovery, from basic research to clinical development. He has also led business development teams in Europe and Asia for Covance and, most recently, was the VP Global Business Development at Eurofins Pharma Discovery Services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his new role, Slater will provide key leadership and support of Science Exchange’s business development and expansion efforts in Europe. He will work with the global business development team to stimulate provider and researcher recruitment and expand the European support team that will give researchers the personalized scientific support they expect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“From my initial interactions with Elizabeth Iorns and the team at Science Exchange, I was impressed by their passion and commitment to simplifying researchers’ access to the services they need,” said Slater. “I look forward to working with such a driven team and helping expand the company’s European presence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We work in a rapidly changing environment, and so it’s critical for us to hire people that share our ambitious vision and have the expertise to help us execute it successfully,” said Elizabeth Iorns, CEO of Science Exchange. “I’m thrilled to be welcoming our two new team members, who each bring vast experience to Science Exchange, and I look forward to working closely with them in our mission to enable scientific breakthroughs through connections.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gursatya &quot;Guru&quot; Singh</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Fastest Path to Scientific Breakthroughs and the Leading Marketplace for Outsourced R&amp;amp;D.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New literature review warns that current sexual assault interventions might actually increase offending among high-risk men</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34047</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T08:37:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-178019463.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34048&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34048&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 40D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Stop rape culture&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1368553387&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;David Kam&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;30&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Stop Rape Culture&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Stop Rape Culture&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/stop-rape-culture/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology can help people one person at a time, but it also holds the promise of changing society at a mass scale, through campaigns to change attitudes and behaviour. One such endeavour is the development of programmes to reduce the rates of sexual assault of women on university campuses. But in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917303646&quot;&gt;literature review&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Aggression and Violent Behavior&lt;/em&gt;, researchers from the University of California make the case that such programmes may not just be ineffective, but counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34047&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 the US passed its Violence Against Women Act; in response most US university campuses launched programmes that aimed to reduce sexual assault by raising awareness, changing attitudes and behaviours and encouraging bystanders to take a stand. But there has been little systematic evaluation of these programmes, and the evidence for any benefits is thus far thin. Of the 140 college-based behaviour change programmes studied by the Center for Disease Control, it recommended only three on the balance of evidence; all three focused on changing bystander action and two of the three merely showed “promise of effectiveness”. Other reviews have produced slightly more positive conclusions but often with weak effects or without evidence of actual behaviour change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.34.50.png&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-34051 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34051&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.34.50&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845?w=374&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845?w=282&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;374,398&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;“Newish interventions have a thin evidence base, more work needed” is not a clamouring call for alarm, but based on their review of the field, Neil Malamuth and his team suspect there may be something worse at play: a boomerang effect.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly become clear that well-meaning interventions in other contexts can have the opposite effect to that intended; we’ve previously covered instances of backfiring interventions that aimed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/07/08/the-imagined-contact-intervention-for-reducing-prejudice-can-backfire/&quot;&gt;reduce prejudice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/23/the-backfire-effect-correcting-false-beliefs-about-vaccines-can-be-surprisingly-counterproductive/&quot;&gt;correct false beliefs on vaccine&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/11/pressuring-employees-to-be-do-gooders-can-backfire-badly/&quot;&gt;encourage employees to behave better in the workplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason boomerang effects are such a concern in the domain of sexual assault is that most interventions are being designed and evaluated around a broad target group – men – rather than looking at effects on the most high-risk individuals. Yet we know from previous evidence that the people most likely to respond contrarily are those most disposed to the problem behaviour in the first place. For instance, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0193841X16666196&quot;&gt;intervention intended to reduce acceptance of violent video games&lt;/a&gt; in students was effective for many participants, but post-intervention, those who had been classified as living a delinquent lifestyle became more enthusiastic about playing the games.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://refhub.elsevier.com/S1359-1789(17)30364-6/rf0040&quot;&gt;Another study&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated that an anti-violence campaign was effective in increasing opposition to violence in people low in trait aggression, but those who were highly aggressive became more enthusiastic about violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boomerang effects seem to happen when participants experience reactance: anger stemming from the sense that a mode of life or thinking is threatened combined with “motivated reasoning” – like finding reasons to doubt the source of the message. In the midst of reactance, the person sees themselves as defiantly resisting preachy attempts to deny them their entitlement.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is reactance likely to happen with the men most likely to commit sexual assault? Well, consider this profile of high-risk individuals: they tend to have hostility towards women, experience sexual arousal when physical force is involved, and have an impersonal sexual orientation (intimacy is not a prerequisite for what they seek in sex). As well as these sex-related factors, they tend to be anti-social, highly entitled and narcissistic. Evidence suggests these individuals are less likely to respond to cues of sexual disinterest, feeling that women are really into them or will be eventually, and they react more aggressively to interpersonal rejection. This seems a potent recipe for reactance.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.31.14.png&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-34050 alignright&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34050&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.31.14&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845?w=370&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845?w=212&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;370,524&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;There isn’t much evidence from existing anti-sexual assault programmes on specifically how these high-risk individuals respond, but smaller-scale experimental work reveals troubling signs. Messages promoting gender equality and greater consideration for women lead to lower aggressive tendencies for men already low in sexist attitudes, but more aggression among those who held more sexist attitudes from the start. A video intended to reduce acceptance of rape myths and increase victim empathy worked for men who had no history of sexually aggressive behaviour, but the high-risk men showed a boomerang effect. On the other hand, some experimental studies have shown some intervention content can have the desired effect on high-risk individuals, e.g. improving victim empathy. But if you hit the target on some occasions, and shoot yourself in the foot on others, you would want to take a good look at your technique before rolling it out nationwide.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger is that interventions could produce impressive-seeming results simply because the low-risk majority perceive sexual assault as even more deplorable than they already did – while the (roughly 30 per cent) of higher-risk men become even more intent on their agenda. Of course, such interventions may prevent certain sexual assaults – for example, through limiting predation opportunities through galvanising bystanders to act. But surely we should be working to maximise impact on those likely to commit the bulk of the assaults, rather than fire up their motivation still further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917303646&quot;&gt;Sexual assault interventions may be doing more harm than good with high-risk males&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Highlights of the BMC series: May 2018</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/19/highlights-bmc-series-may-2018/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10259</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T08:25:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/BMC-series-highlight-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-018-1740-9&quot;&gt;The role of oxytocin receptor gene (OXTR) DNA methylation (DNAm) in human social and emotional functioning: a systematic narrative review.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurotransmitter Oxytocin is widely known for its role in the regulation of social bonding as well as romantic attachment. It was initially discovered over 100 years ago after an extract derived from the human posterior pituitary gland was found to cause uterine contractions in pregnant cats. Since 1909 our understanding of this nonapeptide has somewhat progressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Impairment of methylation appeared to suggest increased prevalence of mood and anxiety disorders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxytocin binds a G protein coupled receptor that is coded for by the OXTR gene. Binding of oxytocin to its receptor unleashes a signalling cascade within the cell, leading to both psychological and physiological changes.  Much attention has been given to the OXTR gene as its expression essentially controls the rate limiting step in the oxytocin signalling process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A meta-analysis published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; this month looks at the possibility of a link between OXTR gene methylation and corresponding changes in social and emotional behaviour in human populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is still insufficient evidence to draw strong conclusions, early findings point towards a correlation between specific elevated patterns of methylation and impaired cognitive and social emotional behaviour. Conversely, impairment of methylation appeared to suggest increased prevalence of mood and anxiety disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish these patterns with greater certainty, more research is required to understand the relationship between OXTR gene methylation and OXTR expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-018-5399-4&quot;&gt;Sound pressure levels generated at risk volume steps of portable listening devices: types of smartphone and genres of music.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-10261&quot; height=&quot;201&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/headphones-300x201.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;It is thought that approximately 36% of the world’s population currently use a smart phone, with around 2.1 billion worldwide users reported in 2016. A significant number of these smartphone owning individuals are likely to take advantage of music playing applications found ubiquitously across most smartphone models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, listening to music on a smartphone or personal listening device comes with a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organisation (WHO) have warned many young adults are at risk of developing recreational noise induced hearing loss due to frequent exposure to noisy environments. It is thought that nearly 50% of young people aged from 12- 35 years of age in developed counties are exposed to dangerously high levels of music through their personal listening devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone manufacturers have now implemented their own recommendations for minimum volumes at which hearing loss may occur. However these volumes vary, even within different smartphone models issued by the same company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, authors Gibbeum Kim and Woojae Han put 6 smartphones to the test, using four genres of Korean pop music to determine the first risk volume level as defined by each device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results indicated a considerable 8-dB difference in sound pressure levels detected across the six devices, with dance-pop music having the highest output level of the genres tested. Based on these conclusions, the implementation of an international standard for safe use output volume is suggested across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC International Health and Human Rights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcinthealthhumrights.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12914-018-0160-8&quot;&gt;Causes of death among street-connected children and youth in Eldoret, Kenya.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common knowledge that homeless people will have lower life expectancy on average than their housed and settled counterparts. One recent study estimated the homeless youth of San Francisco to have a mortality rate that was 10 times that of the general population. Drug related deaths and suicide featured as the most common causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, little information exists on the causes of youth mortality in low and middle-income countries. A recent study published &lt;em&gt;in BMC International Health and Human Rights&lt;/em&gt; has documented the causes of death among street connected youth in Eldoret, Western Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of death of in Eldoret differ considerably from those in San Francisco. In Eldoret, HIV accounted for 37% of all deaths, killing 59% of females included in the study and roughly a quarter of all men. Among the male population, the greatest cause of death was assault, accounting for nearly 50% of recorded deaths in men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deaths for reasons such as these are largely preventable. The authors advocate appropriate responses such as targeted HIV treatment programs and child protection systems to decrease the prevalence of assault and HIV and thus avoidable youth mortality in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-018-1155-8&quot;&gt;Phylogenomic analysis of Apoidea sheds new light on the sister group of bees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-10262&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/wasp-300x298.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;This study published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt; investigates the evolutionary history of apoidea, a superfamily that includes apoid wasps and bees. A barrier to understanding the evolution of apoidea has been the difficulty in determining the geological age of bees as well as their phylogenetic origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Ohl’s group from the Institute for Evolution and Biodiversity Science in Berlin have pooled and analysed target DNA enrichment sites and transcriptomic sequence data, covering all major lineages in the apoidea superfamily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ammoplanina, a family of predatory wasps, began to lose their taste for thrips around 128 million years ago. Over time, they acquired a plant-based diet and evolved into what we now know as the modern bee. Further research must be done to understand the specific traits that enabled this radical dietary change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Ethics: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedethics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12910-018-0268-3&quot;&gt;Conscientious objection to participation in abortion by midwives and nurses: a systematic review of reasons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enshrined in the European Convention on Human Rights, is the right to freedom of thought conscience and religion. The freedom to manifest these beliefs, however, can be limited by law if thought to pose a risk to public health for example, or infringe on the rights and freedoms of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conscientious objection was widely accepted, despite largely polarised viewpoints on either side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under most abortion laws enacted across the developed world, a conscience clause is included, permitting the conscientious objection of healthcare professionals to opt out of providing such services on moral grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heated debate has ensued regarding the extent to which the rights of healthcare professionals to refuse provision of abortion services should be limited, in case this should infringe on a woman’s legal right to the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review, published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Ethics&lt;/em&gt;, aims to elucidate the reasons given for declining to participate in abortion on grounds of conscience. Surprisingly, it was found the viewpoints of midwives and nurses were largely absent from this debate, despite being the recommended providers of abortion services by the WHO. Across the literature studied, conscientious objection was widely accepted, despite largely polarised viewpoints on either side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, better representation of all relevant healthcare professionals in the debate and the consideration of all viewpoints is necessary when discussing such a sensitive topic, in order to inform beneficial health policy in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Oral Health: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0523-5&quot;&gt;Cone beam computed tomography in implant dentistry: recommendations for clinical use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10263&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10263&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/skull-300x267.gif&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Image taken from manuscript&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the ages of 35 to 44, 69% of US citizens are reported to have lost at least one tooth. 15 million of this population will have undergone crown and bridge replacements for missing teeth, while only 3 million of these have been reported to have had dental implants. However this number is said to be growing by half a million every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dental implants may be surgically inserted into a patient’s jaw, in order to support the introduction of a prosthetic element such as a crown or bridge. Cone beam computed tomography (CBCT) is a useful tool, providng high-quality, 3-dimensional images of surrounding tissues to aid this process. The low cost and reasonable dose of radiation administered has caused the popularity of this method to increase over recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;BMC Oral Health&lt;/em&gt; this month, Michael Bornstein’s group from the University of Leuven in Belgium review current literature to provide recommendations for the future use of CBCT imaging. Due to relatively high radiation doses, its clinical usage should be justified. For example, the authors advise to limit CBCT to cases involving post-operative complications following dental implant insertion, as well as the avoidance of this procedure in long term maintenance and follow up of dental implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lack of standardisation of radiation dose and image quality between different CBCT machines further prompted calls for more research to consistently achieve the lowest diagnostically acceptable radiation dose possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/19/highlights-bmc-series-may-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC series: May 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Micklem</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mental Illness Overlap</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/NZbmpmdASFU/scientificamerican0718-76"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 76 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mark Fischetti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A distinct set of genes may underlie several psychiatric conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/NZbmpmdASFU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Fischetti</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50, 100 &amp;amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/_hneDobOTtE/scientificamerican0718-75"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 75 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/_hneDobOTtE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel C. Schlenoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sex and Drugs</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/N00lph2hjXo/scientificamerican0718-74"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 74 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animals' inner lives are stranger than we can imagine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/N00lph2hjXo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Steve Mirsky</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Final Mysterians</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Z86rtyCQ6No/scientificamerican0718-73"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 73 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are consciousness, free will and God insoluble mysteries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Z86rtyCQ6No&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Shermer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Recommended</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/SWS34Kr7Oc8/scientificamerican0718-72"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 72 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/SWS34Kr7Oc8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Buzz Kill</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/-Gbisvf4zn4/scientificamerican0718-66"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 66 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Dan Strickman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mosquito-borne diseases spread, scientists are fighting back with new poisons, traps and genetic engineering techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/-Gbisvf4zn4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Strickman</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Building a Weather-Smart Grid</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/EjTQROUAfQM/scientificamerican0718-60"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 60 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Peter Fairley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewable energy will rule only when weather data drive the design of a new electric grid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/EjTQROUAfQM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter Fairley</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Letters</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/vFq9FMOVmHY/scientificamerican0718-6"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/vFq9FMOVmHY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Battle of the Brains</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/vTec13XzCSU/scientificamerican0718-58"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 58 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Josh Fischman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs beat their domesticated rivals, cats, in a new attempt to measure cognitive power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/vTec13XzCSU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Josh Fischman</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Clocks within Our Cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/l_OZi1G-RiA/scientificamerican0718-50"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 50 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Veronique Greenwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the body's cycles went from folk medicine to modern science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/l_OZi1G-RiA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Veronique Greenwood</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Real Paleo Diet</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/uiv4C8TPrp4/scientificamerican0718-42"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 42 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Peter S. Ungar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microscopic wear patterns on fossil teeth reveal what our ancestors ate—and provide insights into how climate change shaped human evolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/uiv4C8TPrp4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Peter S. Ungar</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Barriers between Realities</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/r7sTvX4Oo5s/scientificamerican0718-4"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 4 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/r7sTvX4Oo5s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariette DiChristina</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Science of Antiscience Thinking</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/g9snsbTnX7w/scientificamerican0718-36"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 36 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Douglas T. Kenrick, Adam B. Cohen, Steven L. Neuberg &amp;amp; Robert B. Cialdini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convincing people who doubt the validity of climate change and evolution to change their beliefs requires overcoming a set of ingrained cognitive biases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/g9snsbTnX7w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Douglas T. Kenrick</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crossing the Quantum Divide</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/nE6MccqTlWE/scientificamerican0718-28"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 28 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Tim Folger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The universe according to quantum mechanics is strange and probabilistic, but our everyday reality seems nailed down. New experiments aim to probe where—and why—one realm passes into the other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/nE6MccqTlWE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tim Folger</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Next Round of Merger Mania</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Ia80KuhtrZ0/scientificamerican0718-26"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 26 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 ideas for new companies that probably won't exist—but should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Ia80KuhtrZ0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Pogue</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Killer Infection: Is It Your Genes?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/drakPsj_E6k/scientificamerican0718-24"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtle mutations can undermine our ability to fend off a specific bug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/drakPsj_E6k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Claudia Wallis</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Blue's Clues</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/mzQ3IO3z4jg/scientificamerican0718-23"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 23 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Matthew Hutson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealthy families invest more in boys, backpack sales suggest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/mzQ3IO3z4jg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthew Hutson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Smart Walls</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/UYGDHzj9Sig/scientificamerican0718-22"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Prachi Patel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special paint turns a surface into a giant touch sensor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/UYGDHzj9Sig&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Prachi Patel</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quick Hits</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/aS00L62W-no/scientificamerican0718-21"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 21 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Tanya Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/aS00L62W-no&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tanya Lewis</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Power of Science Museums</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/2t128mPUmeA/scientificamerican0718-20"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20</id>
		<updated>2018-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new air and space museum director talks about the next generation of explorers and the post-truth era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/2t128mPUmeA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-06-20T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Venus’ thick atmosphere speeds up the planet’s spin</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/venus-thick-atmosphere-speeds-planets-spin"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/venus-thick-atmosphere-speeds-planets-spin</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T19:44:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Venus’ thick atmosphere can push on mountains on the surface, changing its rotation period by a few minutes every day.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-26T05:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How Weather Influences the Brain?</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/18/how-weather-influences-the-brain/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23740</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T14:00:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;We all know that the weather can strongly influence our mood and productivity. Many people feel better when the weather is nice and sunny. It is thus not surprising that people more often feel unhappy and depressed in winter. There is even a medical condition known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/02/08/winter-depression-new-discoveries-in-treatment-of-seasonal-affective-disorder/&quot;&gt;winter depression&lt;/a&gt;. Still, some researchers believe that our brain functions better during the cold days. In this article, I’ll briefly analyze what happens in our brain in relation to weather-related mood and mind changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific studies indicate that weather conditions such as high temperature and humidity can impair mental performance by affecting brain neurochemistry. For instance, it is believed that thermal stress can cause cognitive impairment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent study has investigated the impact of thermal stress on cognitive functions in soldiers spending at least one year in desert conditions. The evaluation of memory and cognitive functions indicated there is a decline in cognitive performance in hot climates when compared to normal weather. The decline was most pronounced for attention, concentration, verbal memory, and psychomotor performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another recent study has investigated the impact of sand and dust storms on children’s cognitive function. Using mathematical analysis and word-recognition test scores, how prenatal exposure to sand and dust storms affects the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/13/how-does-starting-school-early-impact-educational-attainment/&quot;&gt;cognitive performance of children &lt;/a&gt;was evaluated. The authors found a decline in both test scores, as well as a later beginning of counting and speaking in whole sentences in children prenatally exposed to storms. The findings imply that this kind of weather jeopardizes the cognitive functions of the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, results from scientific research on the effects of temperature on cognitive functions are quite mixed and contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One study investigated &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/13/how-temperature-affects-people-with-multiple-sclerosis/&quot;&gt;how temperature affects the cognitive performance of subjects with multiple sclerosis&lt;/a&gt;. Healthy subjects were included as controls. The researchers correlated cognitive status with temperature in both study groups. In patients with multiple sclerosis, unlike in healthy subjects, the higher temperatures were associated with worsening cognitive status. These findings confirmed that warmer outdoor temperatures lead to a higher incidence of clinical exacerbation and T2 lesion activity in subjects with this condition (T2 lesions represent the white spots observed by MRI that are used to diagnose and track the progress of multiple sclerosis).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to cognitive functions in cold weather, studies have shown both impairments and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, one study investigated the impact of exposure to the cold and the following rewarming on working memory and executive functions in 10 young males. The results demonstrated a decline in the test results when the subjects were exposed to 10°C, and these impairments persisted for one hour during the rewarming period. Although the underlying mechanisms were not tested, the authors suggested that acute vascular changes in the brain could explain the observed changes. According to the authors, another explanation could be a deregulation of catecholamine levels, particularly important for complex attentional functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other findings suggest that winter helps to wake up our mind and makes us think more clearly. It is well known that the brain utilizes glucose as its main energy source. Thus, when glucose is depleted, brain functioning is jeopardized. Energy, i.e., glucose, is also used for the regulation of body temperature, especially in extremely hot or cold conditions. It seems that more energy (glucose) is needed to cool down than to warm up the body. Thus, warm temperatures are more likely to deplete glucose levels and thus impair brain function and clarity of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been suggested that high temperatures increase the risk of mental disorders, especially in the elderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent study has analyzed data on emergency admissions linked to mental diseases and daily temperatures over a period of more than 10 years in 6 different cities. The results indicated that high temperatures might jeopardize mental health and be responsible for the exacerbation of symptoms of mental diseases. For instance, according to the results, more than 30% of admissions for anxiety were attributed to hot temperatures. Exposure to hot temperatures leads to reactions in the body that may cause an increase in stress hormone levels and brain temperature. Additionally, extremely hot weather may deregulate the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/01/10/tryptophan-in-mood-anxiety-and-depression/&quot;&gt;dopamine and serotonin levels&lt;/a&gt; (these neuromediators are important for the feeling of happiness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to widespread belief, weather can affect our mood. Although a lack of sunshine is commonly linked to seasonal depression, some researchers believe that not all individuals respond similarly to weather changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has linked an individual’s self-reported daily mood with the objective weather over a 30 day period. Large individual differences have been found in how people react to the weather. Accordingly, four distinct types of weather responders have been identified: summer lovers (i.e., a better mood with warmer weather and more sun), summer haters (i.e., a worse mood with warmer weather and more sun), rain haters (i.e.,  a bad mood on rainy days), and unaffected (i.e., no particular association between weather and mood). Interestingly, adolescents and their mothers are often the same type, suggestive of familial weather reactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of both scientific and popular literature permits the conclusion that extreme weather conditions can affect our cognitive function and mood. Most likely, this is caused by a decline in the brain’s energy source (glucose), which needs to be used for thermoregulation. Also, it is evident that extreme temperatures affect the level of catecholamines in the brain (such as dopamine and serotonin). Still, it seems that there is some individual variability in the brain’s response to weather, and it may run in the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saini, R., Srivastava, K., Agrawal, S., Das, R. C. (2017) Cognitive deficits due to thermal stress: An exploratory study on soldiers in deserts. &lt;em&gt;Med Journal Armed Forces India&lt;/em&gt;. 73(4):370-374. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mjafi.2017.07.011&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.mjafi.2017.07.011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li, Z., Chen, L., Li, M., Cohen, J. (2018) Prenatal exposure to sand and dust storms and children’s cognitive function in China: a quasi-experimental study.&lt;em&gt; The Lancet. Planetary Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2(5): e214-e222. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2542-5196(18)30068-8&quot;&gt;10.1016/S2542-5196(18)30068-8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leavitt, V.M., Sumowski, J.F., Chiaravalloti, N., Deluca, J. (2012) Warmer outdoor temperature is associated with worse cognitive status in multiple sclerosis. &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;. 78(13): 964-968. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31824d5834&quot;&gt;10.1212/WNL.0b013e31824d5834&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muller, M.D., Gunstad, J., Alosco, M.L., Miller, L.A., Updegraff, J., Spitznagel, M.B., Glickman, E,L. (2012) Acute cold exposure and cognitive function: evidence for sustained impairment. &lt;em&gt;Ergonomics&lt;/em&gt;. 55(7): 792-798. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00140139.2012.665497&quot;&gt;10.1080/00140139.2012.665497&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee, S., Lee, H., Myung, W., Kim, E.J., Kim, H. (2018) Mental disease-related emergency admissions attributable to hot temperatures.&lt;em&gt; The Science of Total Environment&lt;/em&gt;.616-617: 688-694. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.10.260&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.10.260&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klimstra, T.A., Frijns, T., Keijsers, L., et al. (2011) Come rain or come shine: individual differences in how weather affects mood.&lt;em&gt; Emotion&lt;/em&gt;. 11(6): 1495-1499. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0024649&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0024649&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Phone apps are helping scientists track suicidal thoughts in real time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/phone-apps-are-helping-scientists-track-suicidal-thoughts-real-time"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/phone-apps-are-helping-scientists-track-suicidal-thoughts-real-time</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T13:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers are using smartphones to tap into the ups and downs of suicidal thinking that occur over hours and days, hoping to help prevent suicides.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal holds firm on decision not to retract Macchiarini paper, despite outside pressure</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/18/journal-holds-firm-on-decision-not-to-retract-macchiarini-paper-despite-outside-pressure/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66729</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T12:00:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Earlier this year, the president of the Karolinska Institute, Ole Petter Ottersen, contacted the journal Respiration, saying KI had conducted an investigation and determined that a 2015 paper co-authored by once-lauded surgeon Paolo Macchiarini had been tainted by misconduct. Please retract the paper, Ottersen said. When the journal said no — opting to publish correspondence … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/18/journal-holds-firm-on-decision-not-to-retract-macchiarini-paper-despite-outside-pressure/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journal holds firm on decision not to retract Macchiarini paper, despite outside pressure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The most ancient African baobabs are dying and no one knows why</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-ancient-african-baobabs-are-dying-and-no-one-knows-why"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-ancient-african-baobabs-are-dying-and-no-one-knows-why</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T11:00:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists aren’t sure what’s killing the oldest African baobabs, nine of which have lost big chunks or died in the last 13 years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8509746334617392=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Edinburgh breaks silence to announce Stancheva retractions</title>
		<link href="https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/18/edinburgh-breaks-silence-to-announce-stancheva-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24684</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T10:35:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In October 2017, I brought an exclusive story of a mysterious sacking at the University of Edinburgh. The molecular biologist and epigenetics researcher Irina Stancheva was removed from her post as senior lecturer at the Scottish university, in total secret, all online traces of her employment rapidly deleted (even a promo video on Vimeo), her … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/18/edinburgh-breaks-silence-to-announce-stancheva-retractions/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Edinburgh breaks silence to announce Stancheva retractions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Leonid Schneider</name>
			<uri>https://forbetterscience.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">For Better Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Science journalism by Leonid Schneider, on research integrity and academic publishing in life sciences and biomedicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forbetterscience.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Researchers have compared different cognitive strategies for falling out of love</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/18/researchers-have-compared-different-cognitive-strategies-for-falling-out-of-love/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34035</id>
		<updated>2018-06-18T08:59:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-18 10.00.47.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34039&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34039&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-18 10.00.47&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2482,1476&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/18/researchers-have-compared-different-cognitive-strategies-for-falling-out-of-love/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;i&gt;You’ve Lost that Lovin’ Feeling&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Nothing Compares 2 U&lt;/i&gt;, there’s no shortage of songs about heartbreak. None, I suspect, contains the line, “Now it’s time to give negative reappraisal a go.” But whether you’ve just been dumped or you’ve done the dumping, if you’re still in love with your ex, this could be your best strategy for falling out of love and moving on, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/2017-37800-001&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Romantic break-ups can have serious consequences including insomnia, reduced immune function, broken heart syndrome, depression and suicide,” note the authors, Sandra Langeslag and Michelle Sanchez at the University of Missouri, St Louis. Strategies that help people to fall out of love could relieve the agony of unrequited love or make it easier to get out of a dysfunctional relationship.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34035&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langeslag and Sanchez recruited 20 women and four men for their study. (As it was hard to get male volunteers, they decided to sacrifice gender balance in favour of having enough participants for the statistical analysis). All these people had experienced a romantic break-up, were still upset about it, and could supply 28 digital pictures of their ex. These pictures had to include a range of facial expressions, and show the ex-partner in different situations (all non-intimate), to mimic the kinds of real-world reminders the participants might endure – seeing their ex on the street, or on social media, for example.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the lab, the researchers showed the participants their full collection of pictures four times over. In between seeing each shot, they were prompted to engage in one of three potential strategies to down-regulate love, and then report on a sliding scale how “in love” and how generally positive or negative they felt. One strategy was “love reappraisal” (they were presented with statements such as “It’s okay to love someone I’m no longer with”, for example.) Another involved simple distractions (between photos, they were asked to think about their favourite food, for example). There was also a control, in which they were asked to think about nothing in particular. And finally, there was “negative reappraisal” which involved reminding themselves of the negative qualities of their ex partners (prompts included ‘What is an annoying habit of your ex?’ for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While neither love reappraisal or distraction changed how in love the participants reported feeling, negative reappraisal of the ex did. Negative reappraisal also made the participants feel more negative in the moment – but such short-term discomfort may be worth enduring if this strategy helps people to get over a break-up, the researchers write.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is an “if”, however. As Langeslag and Sanchez concede, this study only looked at feelings of love immediately after each photo was presented. The practicalities of the strategy also remain unclear. If you know you’re going to bump into your ex at work, say, should you be focusing on their negative qualities during every commute in – or would an occasional bout of negative reappraisal have the same effect? And what exactly would using the negative reappraisal strategy mean in terms of how long it takes you to get over the relationship?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To evaluate which regulation strategies would best help people cope with a break-up, it would be essential to consider both the short-term and long-term effects,” the researchers write. It will also be important to study more men.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-37800-001&quot;&gt;Down-regulation of love feelings after a romantic break-up: Self-report and electrophysiological data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Meet the scientific sleuths: A dozen who’ve had an impact on the scientific literature</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/17/meet-the-scientific-sleuths-ten-whove-had-an-impact-on-the-scientific-literature/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66827</id>
		<updated>2018-06-17T13:52:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Over the years, we have written about a number of the sleuths who, on their own time and often at great risks to their careers or finances, have looked for issues in the scientific literature. Here’s a sampling: Elisabeth “Eagle Eyes” Bik showed that one in 25 papers she examined had evidence of inappropriate image manipulation. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/17/meet-the-scientific-sleuths-ten-whove-had-an-impact-on-the-scientific-literature/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Meet the scientific sleuths: A dozen who’ve had an impact on the scientific literature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-06-25T23:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
