<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: ‘Pile of dung’ republished; Diverging views on publishing negative results; Economists share regrets</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/03/weekend-reads-pile-dung-republished-diverging-views-publishing-negative-results-economists-share-regrets/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50440</id>
		<updated>2017-06-03T13:59:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured an unusual warning from the New England Journal of Medicine, and the withdrawal of a paper over a fear of legal threats. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A paper exposed as a “pile of dung” has been accepted for publication — for the second time. Tom Spears is at it […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/03/weekend-reads-pile-dung-republished-diverging-views-publishing-negative-results-economists-share-regrets/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: ‘Pile of dung’ republished; Diverging views on publishing negative results; Economists share regrets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">The role of urban green spaces on mental wellbeing</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/03/the-role-of-urban-green-spaces-on-mental-wellbeing/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9087</id>
		<updated>2017-06-03T09:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/640px-St_Jamess_Park_Lake_–_East_from_the_Blue_Bridge_-_2012-10-06-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over half the world’s population today resides in cities, creating a challenge for urban planners to efficiently accommodate increasing numbers of residents in a healthy and positive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental health in particular is important, with statistics showing that one in four of us experience mental health difficulties each year, while those with better, positive mental wellbeing display increased levels of longevity, productivity, and prosperity. In fact, the UK government now measures mental wellbeing, alongside traditional GDP, as an indicator of national progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biophilia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous research found those in greener urban environments &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797612464659)&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; fewer symptoms of mental distress and better life satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory of Biophilia suggests that individuals have an innate desire to connect with nature, due to the savannah landscapes humans evolved in, and are hence best adapted to. People may therefore still experience positive emotions in more natural environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous research has suggested this to be true in a modern context, where those in greener urban environments &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797612464659)&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; fewer symptoms of mental distress and better life satisfaction. In particular, these symptoms have been shown to reduce for individuals &lt;a href=&quot;http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/es403688w&quot;&gt;relocating to greener areas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore important that green spaces are designed into urban areas to provide places for individuals to connect with nature. These spaces may also offer opportunities to pursue other health-promoting behaviours such as exercising, active travel, preserving wildlife, and socialising, which can help foster a supportive network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental wellbeing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, little research has focused on mental wellbeing, a concept which comprises positive aspects of mental health, such as happiness, functioning and purpose in life. Our study set out to examine whether local-area proportions of green space would be associated with this broader definition of mental wellbeing, measured using the Warwick-Edinburgh Mental Well-Being Scale (SWEMWBS). This questionnaire consists of 7 questions, asking respondents how they have been feeling over the past 2 weeks, covering aspects such as optimistic about the future, relaxed and useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9091&quot; style=&quot;width: 391px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9091 &quot; height=&quot;272&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/800px-Park_in_bath_england_arp.jpg&quot; width=&quot;381&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Parade Gardens, Bath&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial results showed that green space was positively associated with the mental wellbeing measure, but after controlling for a range of personal and environmental factors, we found that individual lifestyle factors and local-area deprivation were significant predictors of mental wellbeing, while green space was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this was not the finding we expected, it opens up many other questions regarding the relationship between green space and mental wellbeing. It could be that defining local-area green space as the amount within a census boundary is too coarse a measure, as in this project, and that taking account of how far people have to travel to visit their nearest green space, may yield more positive results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green space itself is also much more complex than a single entity, and may take the form of a nature reserve, park, sports pitch, cemetery, allotment, or many others. We speculate that the features of these different places may be beneficial in themselves, and we have begun pursuing investigations into the associations between these different green characteristics and mental wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found that individual lifestyle factors and local-area deprivation were significant predictors of mental wellbeing, while green space was not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may also be that potential benefits depend on the individuals themselves. For example, older people may prefer green spaces with benches and toilets available, whilst young families may find play equipment and open spaces preferable. Those who commute may have more opportunity to benefit from green space nearer their workplace than home, or areas traversed while commuting, as this is where they spend most of their time during the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads on to the concept of exposure: while studies do not agree whether having greater amounts of local green space is associated with usage, examination of visiting patterns and activity types may also be an interesting area of further research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is clear, however, is that future studies need to examine different green space characteristics in association with this broader definition of mental wellbeing, in order to understand if, and where, these relationships exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longitudinal studies will also allow potential consideration of causality. Our future research will focus on a spatial modelling approach to expand our understanding of accessibility and the importance of these different green space types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With urban growth currently increasing at an unprecedented rate, there is rising pressure on city planners to ensure that limited space is put to its optimum use. Green spaces are only present in urban areas at the expense of buildings, and as such it is important that they are designed well to offer to greater benefit to the widest population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Informed green space design will help create a healthier, happier and more productive urban landscape, while there may be wider benefits still for the environment and the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/03/the-role-of-urban-green-spaces-on-mental-wellbeing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The role of urban green spaces on mental wellbeing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Houlden</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">RAND withdraws report on child welfare reform for further analysis</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/rand-withdraws-report-child-welfare-reform-analysis/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50418</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T23:19:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last week, Emily Putnam-Hornstein, an associate professor at the University of Southern California, was reading what seemed like a noteworthy new report from the RAND Corporation on the child welfare system. But then she realized that some of the key estimates were off. When she sent the report to some colleagues, they agreed. Curious, Putnam-Hornstein and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/rand-withdraws-report-child-welfare-reform-analysis/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;RAND withdraws report on child welfare reform for further analysis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When it comes to the flu, the nose has a long memory</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-it-comes-flu-nose-has-long-memory"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-it-comes-flu-nose-has-long-memory</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mice noses have specialty immune cells with long memories.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal retracts Ohio State CrossFit study at center of lawsuits</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/journal-retracts-ohio-state-crossfit-study-center-lawsuits/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50393</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The fallout continues for a study conducted at a local CrossFit gym by researchers at The Ohio State University. First it was corrected, now it’s been retracted, and it continues to be the basis of litigation against both the authors and the publisher. Editors at the Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research have decided to […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/journal-retracts-ohio-state-crossfit-study-center-lawsuits/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal retracts Ohio State CrossFit study at center of lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Publisher retracts “conceptual penis” hoax article</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/publisher-retracts-conceptual-penis-hoax-article/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50402</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T15:14:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;File this under “not a surprise.” After the authors of a paper entitled “The conceptual penis as a social construct” confessed it was a hoax immediately after publication, the publisher has retracted it. The notice is sparse: This article has been retracted by the publisher. For more information please see the statement on this article. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/publisher-retracts-conceptual-penis-hoax-article/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Publisher retracts “conceptual penis” hoax article&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sooty terns’ migration takes the birds into the path of hurricanes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/sooty-terns-migration-hurricanes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/sooty-terns-migration-hurricanes</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T14:35:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sooty terns migrate south from southern Florida and back again. The track sometimes takes the birds into the path of hurricanes, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Zielinski</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Oral Health launches its Digital Dentistry section!</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/02/bmc-oral-health-launches-its-digital-dentistry-section/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9077</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T12:47:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Immagine1-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Digital revolution is changing the world: computers and Digital devices are now part of our life, and Dentistry is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The future of Dentistry is Digital&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital technologies are rapidly advancing in Dentistry. In fact, fast and accurate devices for 3D models/image acquisition such as intraoral scanners, desktop scanners, face scanners, and cone beam computed tomography (CBCT) – as well as powerful software for data elaboration/processing such as computer aided design/computer aided manufacturing (CAD/CAM) software for prosthodontics, surgery, and orthodontics – have been introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, new materials for prosthetic restorations – zirconia, lithium disilicate, and ceramics – have been proposed, along with innovative fabrication procedures such as milling, 3D printing, and layered manufacturing. These new devices, software, materials and fabrication methods are already changing the way we treat our patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital revolution has begun. In the coming months and years there will be a further, huge flood of new improvements and newly introduced devices, software and machines. The Digital technologies will dramatically change the world of dentistry, changing patients’ expectations towards dental treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, dental professionals need to change the way they think, communicate and work, to adapt to this new fascinating scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of Dentistry is Digital, therefore &lt;em&gt;BMC Oral Health&lt;/em&gt; is happy to launch a section entirely dedicated to the world of Digital Dentistry. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/sections/digital-dentistry&quot;&gt;This section &lt;/a&gt;will collect high quality original research articles, clinical studies, technical advances, and case reports focused on the different areas of Digital Dentistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential topics of this section will include intraoral, desktop, and face scanners; CBCT and new imaging techniques in dento-maxillofacial radiology; CAD/CAM softwares in digital dentistry; digital prosthodontics; new materials (zirconia, lithium disilicate, and others) in digital dentistry; milling, additive manufacturing and 3D printing in dentistry; guided implant surgery; custom-made bone regeneration; custom-made implants; and digital orthodontics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to receiving your article. Let’s go Digital!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the first article published in the Digital Dentistry section, authored by Dr Mangano, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-017-0383-4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/02/bmc-oral-health-launches-its-digital-dentistry-section/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Oral Health launches its Digital Dentistry section!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Francesco Mangano</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">NEJM issues unusual warning for readers about 1980 letter on opioid addiction</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/nejm-issues-unusual-warning-readers-1980-letter-opioid-addiction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50386</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T12:00:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This week, the New England Journal of Medicine issued a type of editor’s note we’ve never seen before, on a highly influential letter published nearly 40 years ago. Above the one-paragraph letter, which reports data suggesting pain medications are not likely to cause addiction, the journal has added a note warning readers that the letter has […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/02/nejm-issues-unusual-warning-readers-1980-letter-opioid-addiction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NEJM issues unusual warning for readers about 1980 letter on opioid addiction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Can a multidisciplinary approach to tourism tackle poverty and support sustainable development?</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/can-a-multidisciplinary-approach-to-tourism-tackle-poverty-and-support-sustainable-development"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/can-a-multidisciplinary-approach-to-tourism-tackle-poverty-and-support-sustainable-development</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T11:08:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers in Thailand are investigating “creative tourism” as a way to support local economies and protect their land</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">AI’s revolutionary role in healthcare</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ais-revolutionary-role-in-healthcare"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ais-revolutionary-role-in-healthcare</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T10:42:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Experts debate the pros and cons of artificial intelligence, which is changing many aspects of patient care</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Unintentional drowning: Role of medicinal drugs and alcohol</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/02/unintentional-drowning-role-of-medicinal-drugs-and-alcohol/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9081</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T10:34:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/15730249079_01affe8bc2_k-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unintentional drowning is a global concern, which encompasses all cases of drowning and their associated outcomes – morbidity, no morbidity, and death. As a water-centered society, Finland faces one of the highest rates of this in the developed world. In fact, an extensive population-based study (1970-2000) revealed over 9000 unintentional drownings, and named alcohol consumption as a key risk factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4306-8&quot;&gt;article &lt;/a&gt;recently published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Pajunen et al studied data from a nationwide survey provided by the Laboratory of Forensic Toxicology at the University of Helsinki. Already knowing that psychotropic drugs can impact psychomotor functioning and cognition, their aim was to determine if this was another potential risk factor associated with unintentional drowning. The dataset they used spanned over a 10-year period (2000-2009) and included 2,828 cases of fatal drownings; however, some cases were excluded from this study based on the manner of drowning e.g. accident, suicide, homicide, undetermined intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of the authors carried out post-mortem toxicology for the 1,746 eligible cases, with 100% of these tested for alcohol, and 91.5% subjected to a full toxicological analysis to test for both alcohol and other drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this testing, two of the authors of this paper used a well-established 6-grade scale to independently evaluate the contribution of each drug to fatal drowning, and then a summary score for each drug. The scoring process also considered factors such as drug concentration, concentration-dependent impairment, post-mortem changes and redistribution of drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data reinforced the previously reported concentration-effect relationship between alcohol and drowning, which make it almost undeniable that alcohol consumption contributes to drowning during aquatic activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of medicinal drugs on unintentional drowning has been less well studied, thus this article may be considered unique by evaluating both the individual and combined effects of several drugs. The findings suggest that psychotropic drugs may also play a significant role in unintentional drowning, as it became apparent that they contributed to up to 14.6% of cases, whether taken independently or in addition to alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the analysis revealed over 70 different psychotropic drugs, with benzodiazepines as the most commonly taken. This result might be most relevant to health professionals and their patients – as this class of drug is already known to affect cognitive and psychomotor skills, appropriate caution and warning is imperative for those patients engaging in aquatic activities; especially those likely to consume alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, among the 10 most common psychoactive and non-psychoactive drugs detected in the case samples, several may contribute to fatal drowning by causing drug-induced long-QT syndrome. This is a condition causing an abnormal heart rhythm, thereby affecting the normal pumping of blood in the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unintentional drowning is an issue which has warranted nation-wide drowning-prevention campaigns already.  Whilst the role of alcohol in such cases is fairly well studied, that of medicinal drugs has only just been considered in detail, and further investigation is still required to determine the mechanism of drug actions involved. In light of this, however, this study suggests that appropriate information should be conveyed to the public to ensure that they are aware of the risks associated with their medical status, lifestyle, and behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/02/unintentional-drowning-role-of-medicinal-drugs-and-alcohol/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unintentional drowning: Role of medicinal drugs and alcohol&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Afsaneh Khetrapal</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How research analytics is driving success at a Nigerian university</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-research-analytics-is-driving-success-at-a-nigerian-university"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-research-analytics-is-driving-success-at-a-nigerian-university</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T10:08:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In its 15 years, Covenant University has powered its way up the country’s research rankings and is looking to compete internationally</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Your personality may affect your vulnerability to mental health problems</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/02/your-personality-may-affect-your-vulnerability-to-mental-health-problems/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24294</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T08:14:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_24453&quot; style=&quot;width: 1456px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mental health&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24453&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24453&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Human Mind. The shape of a man's head tangled up with threads of string - mental health concept.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mental health&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mental health&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/gettyimages-667879286.jpg?w=845?w=724&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/gettyimages-667879286.jpg?w=845?w=212&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/gettyimages-667879286.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1456,2059&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/02/your-personality-may-affect-your-vulnerability-to-mental-health-problems/mental-health/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/gettyimages-667879286.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Swiss researchers used longitudinal data to test a “personality centred model of psychopathology”&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your personality describes your behavioural tendencies, your habits of thought and ways of relating to the world. For instance, some of us find it a lot harder to keep our negative emotions in check, which is measured by the Big Five personality trait of neuroticism (or “emotional instability”). It seems logical that people with this kind of disposition might be more prone to developing mental health problems like anxiety and depression, and indeed many studies suggest this to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a scientific perspective, however, it’s not clear which comes first: perhaps mental health problems contribute to a more neurotic personality, or maybe living through adversity contributes to a neurotic personality and mental health difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00406-017-0796-8&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;span class=&quot;JournalTitle&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;European Archives of Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; helps clarify the picture because it is the first, to the researchers’ knowledge, to look simultaneously at people’s personality, life events and mental health problems as they unfold over time. Though they come with important caveats, the findings suggest that some people have a personality profile that predisposes them to mental health problems, to more serious mental health problems when they occur, and even to more adverse life events.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24294&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data come from a cohort of nearly 600 participants in Switzerland, who were first interviewed in 1979 when they were aged 19 to 20 about their mental health, any problems with drugs or alcohol, and their family background. The researchers led by Michael Hengartner at Zurich University then interviewed the same group again about their mental health and any experiences of relationship break-up and/or job loss in 1981, 1988, 1993, 1999 and finally in 2008 (now aged 50 years, 335 of the original sample were still participating).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants also completed measures of their personality in 1988 when they were aged 29-30 and again in 1993 when aged 34-35: specifically, these questionnaires revealed their levels of aggressiveness (including lack of self-control), extraversion (how cheerful and self-confident) and neuroticism (including their day-to-day emotional instability and propensity to worry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after controlling for family background and education, the researchers found that personality – averaged across the two times it was measured – was strongly related to the likelihood of experiencing mental health problems through the study: for instance, higher neuroticism was associated with increased odds of depression and anxiety and drink or drug problems. Higher extraversion, by contrast, was associated with less risk of mental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quantifying the personality-mental health link, the researchers said that “persons scoring high on aggressiveness and neuroticism and low on extraversion had an approximately 6 times increased risk for internalising disorder [a catch-all term for various depression and anxiety-related conditions] compared to persons scoring low on aggressiveness and neuroticism and high on extraversion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adverse life events were also associated with risk of mental problems: for example, and perhaps unsurprisingly, participants who endured job losses and relationship breakups were more likely to develop major depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But personality and life events were not independent factors. Personality was related, albeit weakly, to the likelihood of experiencing negative life outcomes: participants who scored higher on aggressiveness were more likely to go through job losses and relationship breakups through the course of the study, and higher scorers on neuroticism were more likely to go through job losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, adverse life events were more strongly associated with future mental health problems for participants with more neurotic personalities. And finally, when mental health problems occurred, they tended to be more severe for participants with more neurotic personalities (differences in trait neuroticism accounted for over half the variation in severity of problems between participants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our findings stress the fundamental role of personality, mainly neuroticism, for the occurrence, persistence and severity of psychopathology [i.e. mental health problems]” the researchers said, adding: “Our data further highlight that the relationship between critical life events and psychopathology is at least in part moderated by personality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings complement &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/12/07/many-of-the-same-genes-that-influence-our-personality-also-affect-our-mental-health/&quot;&gt;recent research&lt;/a&gt; that’s shown that many of the same genes that influence personality are also involved in mental health disorders. They also dovetail with the recent finding that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/01/19/a-little-discussed-effect-of-therapy-it-changes-your-personality/&quot;&gt;psychotherapy is associated with reductions in trait neuroticism&lt;/a&gt;, and with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/article-abstract/2629064&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; out of Sweden involving over a million men that found their teenage personality, especially their neuroticism, was related to their future chances of being diagnosed with severe mental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hengartner and his team make no claims about the precise nature of the cognitive and neural mechanisms that might underlie a neurotic personality and a vulnerability to mental health problems, but they propose that the personality-mental health link can be understood in terms of “life history strategy” – an idea from evolutionary biology that notes how some of us follow a fast strategy (a short-term approach to life which can pay off in high risk environments), whereas others follow a slow strategy (playing a longer, more patient game). Seen this way, people with more impulsive, nervous, aggressive personalities are well-adapted for the fast life, but at the cost of being at much greater risk for mental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this comes with some weighty caveats, most notably that despite the longitudinal nature of this study, it’s still not proven which way the causal arrow points between the different factors involved. In particular, it’s unfortunate that the first personality measure wasn’t taken until the participants were aged 29, raising the possibility that participants’ personalities had already been shaped by mental health issues and life events before that time (though the researchers argue this is unlikely, especially in light of past research showing that personality traits are relatively stable through young adulthood. In other words, they think their participants’ traits as measured at age 29 and 34 are probably much the same as they would have been if measured at the start of the study at age 19/20).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another limitation is that because of its roots in the 1970s and 80s, the study depended on personality measures that are now somewhat obsolete; in particular some aspects of personality such as Openness were not studied at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A strong association between personality and psychopathology may imply causation, but this is not necessarily true,” the researchers admitted. “Genetically and environmentally informed long-term prospective studies beginning in childhood are, therefore, required to better understand the causal role of personality traits in the occurrence and course of severe psychopathology.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this idea that some people’s personalities render them more vulnerable (to mental health problems and adverse life events) is borne out by future research, it could allow help and support to be targeted at those likely to be need it most. It also raises the interesting question of whether future mental health problems might be averted by helping youth to develop more resilient personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00406-017-0796-8&quot;&gt;Articulation and testing of a personality-centred model of psychopathology: evidence from a longitudinal community study over 30 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24294/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24294/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24294&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How scientists reacted to the US leaving the Paris climate agreement</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_Ey0m1dvLYg/nature.2017.22098"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22098</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;What the United States' departure from the historic pact means for efforts to fight global warming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22098&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22098&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_Ey0m1dvLYg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Next-generation cancer drugs boost immunotherapy responses</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/LScDHpHmQTI/nature.2017.22092"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22092</id>
		<updated>2017-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Early clinical trial data suggest that combining medicines improves treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22092&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22092&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/LScDHpHmQTI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Heidi Ledford</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Antarctica’s Larsen C ice shelf is within days of completely cracking</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctica-larsen-c-ice-shelf-cracking"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctica-larsen-c-ice-shelf-cracking</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T22:26:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The crack in Antarctica’s Larsen C ice shelf grew another 17 kilometers between May 25 and May 31, 2017 and is at risk of breaking off a massive iceberg.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">New Feature for Requesters: Add Collaborators to Your Order</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/06/new-feature-for-requesters-add-collaborators-to-your-order/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1076</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T22:05:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;by Elizabeth Iorns, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CEO, Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science, by its very nature, lends itself to collaboration. At Science Exchange, we endeavor to make discovery and access to scientific services as easy as possible – while also improving researchers’ ability to collaborate effectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;With that goal in mind, we have released the Requester Collaboration feature. This feature allows requesters of scientific services to invite and manage additional collaborators for a project. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples of collaborators include:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;A member of your organization’s accounting team who needs to view the project to make payment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;A colleague helping you to work through the project details with the service provider.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;An administrator seeking a high level overview of research activities of their organization on Science Exchange. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new feature will enable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Intuitive addition of collaborators to existing projects&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Transparent communication between collaborating requesters and the service provider&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Easy transfer of ownership between requesters/collaborators&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We will continue to listen to our users and bring new features to our platform to facilitate scientific discovery. To learn more about the Requester Collaboration Feature, view our video demo or &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;check out the Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; below. If you’d like a personal demo of this feature or the Science Exchange marketplace, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;submit a request here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requester Collaboration Feature Video Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requester Collaboration Feature Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What can collaborators do?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Invited collaborators will see the order on their Science Exchange Dashboard. The collaborator can access the order page, post messages, accept quotes, and mark orders as completed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;How will collaborators be notified?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Collaborators will get email notifications regarding new messages that have been posted to the order page. They can also reply to the new message email notification from their inbox and the response will be posted to the order page. However, they will not get email notifications when the provider generates a quote for the request or that the order has been completed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;How does this change what the primary Requester can do?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;There are no changes for the primary Requesters — they can still do everything, e.g., post messages, accept quotes, and mark orders as completed. As the primary Requester, you will also be notified via email of main updates regarding the order, e.g., messages, quotes submitted, quotes accepted, provider completing the order. However, you can transfer the ownership of the order to a collaborator so that they become to primary Requester.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do I invite a collaborator?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Go to the order page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;On the right-hand side, under “Researchers,” you’ll see a link called “Manage.” Click on that link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Enter your collaborator’s email and then invite them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The collaborator will get an email from Science Exchange with the invitation. They should click on the green button in the email.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The collaborator will (sign up for a Science Exchange account, and then) arrive at the order page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Collaborator can post messages, accept quote, mark order as complete.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;How do I transfer ownership of the order to my collaborator?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Go to the order page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;On the right-hand side, under “Researchers,” you’ll see a link called “Manage.” Click on that link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;You’ll see your collaborator’s name. Click on the blue “Make Owner” link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;Still have questions?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We’re happy to help! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/contact&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Contact us &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;here with your questions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Transforming Scientific Collaboration: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">U.S. will withdraw from climate pact, Trump announces</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/trump-us-withdrawal-paris-climate-pact"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/trump-us-withdrawal-paris-climate-pact</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T21:58:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 President Trump announced June 1 that the United States will withdraw from the Paris climate accord.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When preventing HIV, bacteria in the vagina matter</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-preventing-hiv-bacteria-vagina-matter"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-preventing-hiv-bacteria-vagina-matter</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T18:52:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Vaginal bacteria affect how well microbicide gels used to prevent HIV work.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brains encode faces piece by piece</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brains-encode-faces-piece-piece"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brains-encode-faces-piece-piece</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T17:58:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Cells in monkey brains build up faces by coding for different characteristics.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Researchers develop non-invasive deep brain stimulation method</title>
		<link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2017/jun/01/researchers-develop-non-invasive-deep-brain-stimulation-method"/>
		<id>http://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2017/jun/01/researchers-develop-non-invasive-deep-brain-stimulation-method</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T16:00:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers at MIT have developed a new method of electrically stimulating deep brain tissues without opening the skull&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 1997, more than 100,000 Parkinson’s Disease patients have been treated with deep brain stimulation (DBS), a surgical technique that involves the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2007/03/brainsurgery/&quot;&gt;implantation of ultra-thin wire electrodes&lt;/a&gt;. The implanted device, sometimes referred to as a ‘brain pacemaker’, delivers electrical pulses to a structure called the subthalamic nucleus, located near the centre of the brain, and effectively alleviates many of the physical symptoms of the disease, such as tremor, muscle rigidity, and slowed movements. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DBS is generally safe but, like any surgical procedure, comes with some risks. First and foremost, it is highly invasive, requiring small holes to be drilled in the patient’s skull, through which the electrodes are inserted. Potential &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2117492/&quot;&gt;complications&lt;/a&gt; of this include infection, stroke, and bleeding on the brain. The electrodes, which are implanted for long periods of time, sometimes move out of place; they can also cause swelling at the implantation site; and the wire connecting them to the battery, typically placed under the skin of the chest, can erode, all of which require additional surgical procedures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;Related: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2015/jan/15/blowing-up-the-brain-to-reveal-its-finer-details&quot;&gt;Blowing up the brain to reveal its finer details&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;Related: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2012/sep/14/memory-traces-in-a-dish&quot;&gt;Traces of memory in a dish | Mo Costandi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/2017/jun/01/researchers-develop-non-invasive-deep-brain-stimulation-method&quot;&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mo Costandi</name>
			<uri>https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neurophilosophy | The Guardian</title>
			<subtitle type="html">by &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurophilosophy.wordpress.com/about-the-author/&quot;&gt;Mo Costandi&lt;/a&gt;</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy/rss"/>
			<id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/neurophilosophy</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:23+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. 2017</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">NIH neuroscientist up to 16 retractions</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/01/nih-neuroscientist-16-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50162</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T15:30:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Neuroscientist Stanley Rapoport just can’t catch a break. Rapoport, who’s based at National Institute on Aging, is continuing to experience fallout from his research collaborations, after multiple co-authors have been found to have committed misconduct. Most recently, Rapoport has had four papers retracted in three journals, citing falsified data in a range of figures. Although the notices do not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/01/nih-neuroscientist-16-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NIH neuroscientist up to 16 retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">LIGO snags another set of gravitational waves</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ligo-snags-another-set-gravitational-waves"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ligo-snags-another-set-gravitational-waves</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Two black holes stirred up the third set of gravitational waves ever detected.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Clumsy but genuine errors” prompt PNAS correction</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/01/clumsy-genuine-errors-prompt-pnas-correction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50364</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T13:30:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Some accidental mistakes have led researchers to issue a long correction to a 2016 PNAS paper. According to the notice, when the cell biology paper’s corresponding authors became aware of duplications in two images, they immediately notified the journal and the University of Nottingham. After examining the original data archives, the university found that the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/06/01/clumsy-genuine-errors-prompt-pnas-correction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Clumsy but genuine errors” prompt PNAS correction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">CiteScore metrics updated with 2016 annual values</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-metrics-updated-with-2016-annual-values"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-metrics-updated-with-2016-annual-values</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T13:03:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Improvements to CiteScore include greater transparency and clarity</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, antibiotic resistance alarms went unheeded</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-antibiotic-resistance-alarms-went-unheeded"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-antibiotic-resistance-alarms-went-unheeded</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have worried about antibiotic resistance for decades.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Babies categorize colors the same way adults do</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-categorize-colors-same-way-adults-do"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-categorize-colors-same-way-adults-do</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Babies divide hues into five categories, much like adults, a result that suggests color categorization is built into the brain.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">‘Do as I say, and do as I do’ – The influence of parents’ screen viewing perceptions and behaviors on their children’s screen viewing</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/do-as-i-say-and-do-as-i-do-the-influence-of-parents-screen-viewing-perceptions-and-behaviors-on-their-childrens-screen-viewing/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9074</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T09:45:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/children-403582_640-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recently updated American Academy of Pediatrics guidelines, mentioned in the paper, highlight that our thinking around children’s screen time needs to take into account the ubiquity of screens. We not only need to be thinking about &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; they are watching, but &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; they are watching as well (although psychologists have been telling us this for years). But now it’s not just enough to talk about watching TV, we have video games, tablets and smart phones to think about too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important question to ask is whether this proliferation of screens is accompanied by an increased awareness of screen time recommendations for children, a greater understanding of the dangers of too much screen time, and better skills for monitoring children’s screen use? It would seem not, and studies seem to indicate that parents view screen time as educational, a good babysitter, and a helpful bartering tool for dealing with uncooperative children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their paper, Jago and colleagues report on some results from the B-Proact1v study with 5-6 year old children, based in the greater Bristol area in the UK. For this paper, they focus on the screen viewing of these children and their parents, who were classified according to their level of household deprivation and their child’s level of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity, measured using activity devices called accelerometers. Parents were interviewed about their child’s screen viewing (how much and if they thought it was appropriate), who influences their child’s screen viewing, and the ways in which they manage their child’s screen viewing. Parents also completed a questionnaire about their own and their child’s screen viewing habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents and children who went over the 2-hour mark had a less structured and more laid back family environment, with minimal rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the recommendation for school-going children is no more than 2 hours per day of screen time per day, parents and children who followed this recommendation were compared with parents and children who exceeded this 2-hour threshold. Not surprisingly, there were some clear differences, and these related to parents’ personal screen-related views and behaviors, the family environment, and setting rules and limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, parents and children who stuck to the &amp;lt;2 hour recommendation tended to have a family environment that encouraged activity, sought non-screen alternatives for family time, and were more likely to have rules that managed screen viewing time and content. In contrast to this, parents and children who went over the 2-hour mark had a less structured and more laid back family environment, with minimal rules and a tendency to choose screen viewing as the preferred activity for the family to relax together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings support previous work that has shown that, in comparison to permissive parents, authoritative parents who place some restrictions on the screen viewing tend to have children who spend less time in front of screens. Authoritarian parents are responsive to their children’s needs, but not afraid to put rules and limits in place, and this parenting style has been linked to a host of other positive outcomes in children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study also indicates that there is much work still to be done on informing parents of the negative impact of non-educational screen time. And that relying on screens for their educational value has its shortcomings. Lastly, when life is busy and some downtime is needed, families can watch some TV or a movie together, but this needs to be balanced with other family activities that get everyone moving. Since screens are not going anywhere, the more that parents can strike a healthy balance, the better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/do-as-i-say-and-do-as-i-do-the-influence-of-parents-screen-viewing-perceptions-and-behaviors-on-their-childrens-screen-viewing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;‘Do as I say, and do as I do’ – The influence of parents’ screen viewing perceptions and behaviors on their children’s screen viewing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Catherine Draper</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">25 years in the service of Russian science</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/25-years-in-the-service-of-russian-science"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/25-years-in-the-service-of-russian-science</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T09:28:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Russian Foundation for Basic Research (RFBR) enters a new phase in supporting the Russia’s knowledge-based economy, with Elsevier as a partner</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Can you will yourself to be more creative?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/01/can-you-will-yourself-to-be-more-creative-yes-but-only-if-youre-a-novice-says-study-of-jazz-pianists/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24263</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T08:52:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-24272 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24272&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/giphy.gif?w=845?w=320&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/giphy.gif?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;320,222&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/01/can-you-will-yourself-to-be-more-creative-yes-but-only-if-youre-a-novice-says-study-of-jazz-pianists/giphy-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely creativity is about freedom. Dropping your inhibitions – maybe with the help of a few substances – and letting ideas writhe free from the unconscious unfiltered. What to make then of the research showing that creativity is associated with higher levels of executive functioning – the mind’s suite of control processes – which seem to help by inhibiting irrelevant information and combining the rest in novel ways? Does it mean you can use this mental control to make yourself perform more creatively? According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-14257-001/&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Psychology of Aesthetics, Creativity, and the Arts&lt;/i&gt; involving jazz pianists the answer may depend in part on your creative experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24263&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Rosen and his team from Drexel University suspected that the need for conscious control may be more acute when creative people are still novices, referencing saxophonist Charlie Parker’s observation that &lt;i&gt;“you’ve got to learn your instrument. Then, you practice, practice, practice. And then, when you finally get up there on the bandstand, forget all that and just wail.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this, the researchers recruited 22 mostly male jazz pianists using their number of completed professional gigs – as few as three and as many as 400 – as a measure of their creative expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After warming up at the keyboard, the musicians attempted to improvise a pre-recorded track “as you normally would in a jazz setting.” After the first take, they were given three more tries. Crucially, before one of these efforts they were told that from now on they should “improvise even more creatively than your past performance(s).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could the participants deliberately boost their creativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the experiment, the musicians said they’d taken the instruction to heart: “I tried other things that I wouldn’t normally try”; “I felt totally freed. I felt like I’d been given license to go wherever my mind took me”; “I considered new elements of my performance while improvising with explicit instructions”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for performers with fewer gigs behind them, this seemed to help: independent judges rated their improvisations as more proficient, aesthetically appealing, and creative, as compared to equivalent takes with no instructions. But more experienced musicians saw smaller benefits, with the effect for the most experienced players tipping (non-significantly in statistical terms) in the other direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings add to past research showing that while mental control may be important for creativity, there is also a part to play for automatic, uncontrolled mental processes. For example, Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) and even brain damage to the frontal regions involved in executive function are both associated with heightened creativity. Mind-wandering and dreaming also seem to produce creative leaps. One explanation is that creativity is an interplay between automatic associative processes and deliberate effortful ones, or Type One and Type Two processes (as per Daniel Kahneman’s terminology). Freedom &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen in these terms, expert players may, over time, find their own balance of Type One and Two processes when improvising, such that conscious attention can’t easily lead to further improvements. In contrast, those with lower levels of mastery can find it productive to call on creative techniques intentionally or test out variants – “I wonder if I can try dropping different notes from an arpeggio run.” So for those of us not yet at the top of our creative game, making the conscious effort to focus on novel, creative outcomes might be the tactic to take us to new heights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-14257-001/&quot;&gt;All You Need to Do Is Ask? The Exhortation to Be Creative Improves Creative Performance More for Nonexpert Than Expert Jazz Musicians&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://gph.is/2clkRbP&quot;&gt;Giphy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24263/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24263/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24263&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Mice, Ants and Amazing Pictures: Chromatin and Epigenetics EMBO Conference 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/mice-ants-and-amazing-pictures-chromatin-and-epigenetics-embo-conference-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9035</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T07:15:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/heidelberg-1703363_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chromatin and Epigenetics EMBO conference is a biannual event that gathers together top speakers covering the latest advances in chromatin and epigenetics research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the front cover of the conference booklet was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Wolffe&quot;&gt;Dr Alan Wolffe&lt;/a&gt; (1959-2001) a scientist who in the last three years of his life alone, published a number of articles on epigenetics including the role of DNA methylation in regulating gene expression in normal and pathological states, chromatin remodeling in transcriptional repression and activation, and the molecular mechanisms of gene misregulation in disease, including cancer and Rett syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific programme was broadly along the same lines. It was organized into a number of sessions, namely chromatin regulation, developmental epigenetics, making and breaking heterochromatin, histone modifications, RNA and metabolism, transcriptional and posttranscriptional regulation, nuclear architecture and remodelling chromatin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest was the series of talks on epigenetic reprogramming and regulation, including HOX genes regulation during vertebrate development, epigenetic reprogramming in mouse development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite was a fascinating talk on the &lt;strong&gt;role of epigenetic regulation on social behavior in ants&lt;/strong&gt;, describing work by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.med.upenn.edu/apps/faculty/index.php/p8678096&quot;&gt;Dr Roberto Bonasio&lt;/a&gt;  and colleagues from the University of Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-9036 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/ant-954015_1920-300x200.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Pixabay&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonasio explained how ant societies are very sophisticated, with different groups (or castes) arising from a single genome and having different roles. Each caste is distinct in appearance (morphology) and has different behavioral traits. Female embryos become &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_ant&quot;&gt;queens&lt;/a&gt; or one of a number of different types of worker ants. The developmental path of each individual ant is – strikingly – completely independent from their genetic makeup. The differences between each ant caste (their phenotype) must therefore be due to epigenetic modifications (i.e. not explained by changes in DNA sequence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonasio’s group have sequenced the genome for the ant species; &lt;em&gt;Camponotus floridanus&lt;/em&gt;, obtaining both genome-wide DNA methylation and chromatin structure profiles. Unlike for some other ant species, Harpegnathos queens can be replaced by worker ants, which then develop the behavioral and phenotypic traits of the queen. This unique behavior allows researchers to investigate the role of epigenetic pathways in regulating brain function and behavior. By obtaining the gene expression profiles of Harpegnathos ants before, during and after their transition from worker to queen, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuropeptide&quot;&gt;neuropeptide&lt;/a&gt; has been identified that that stimulates worker ant behaviors such as foraging while blocking the transition to queen status. This is exciting as it’s the first time a neuropeptide, and transcriptional regulation in general, is shown to play a role in caste determination and caste-specific behavior in a social organism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other main highlights of the conference were, as expected, the two Keynote lectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imaging the 3D organization of the genome and transcriptome in single cells&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhuang.harvard.edu/&quot;&gt;Professor Xiaowei Zhuang&lt;/a&gt;, from Harvard University presented some super-resolution imaging and multiplex &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fluorescence_in_situ_hybridization&quot;&gt;fluorescent in situ hybridization&lt;/a&gt; (FISH) imaging methods developed in her laboratory that have produced high resolution images of the 3D conformation of chromatin in the cell nucleus. She demonstrated,  with the help of a collection of beautiful images,  how these methods have been used to, for example,  confirm that chromatin is organized into large contact domains called TADS (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topologically_associating_domain&quot;&gt;topologically associating domains&lt;/a&gt;), but folding in a way that differs from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs10577-010-9177-0&quot;&gt;classical fractal-globule model&lt;/a&gt; at large length scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;MERFISH has helped map the distribution of RNA inside cells and distinct cell types in complex tissues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single-cell transcriptome imaging method called multiplexed error-robust FISH (&lt;a href=&quot;http://zhuang.harvard.edu/merfish.html&quot;&gt;MERFISH&lt;/a&gt;) was also described,  Professor Zhuang presented a number of applications for the technique, including mapping the distribution of RNA inside cells and also distinct cell types in complex tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epigenetics and Rett syndrome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very last talk presented at the conference was one by &lt;a href=&quot;http://birdlab.bio.ed.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Professor Adrian Bird&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Edinburgh.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nhs.uk/conditions/rett-syndrome/Pages/Introduction.aspx&quot;&gt;Rett syndrome&lt;/a&gt; is a devastating autistic spectrum disorder that affects the development of female children; it is very rarely seen in males. Sufferers seem normal at first, with symptoms typically appearing around the age of 2 to 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Bird has discovered the cause of the disorder, mutations to the so-called Rett gene &lt;em&gt;MeCP2. &lt;/em&gt;He explained that the MeCP2 protein binds to DNA sites that can be chemically altered by DNA methylation, which has an effect on gene expression. Although other hypotheses do exist, it is thought that the primary function of the MeCP2 protein is to affect DNA methylation in such a way as to block transcription; this is supported by biochemical and genetic analyses of the protein and also by the number of different mutations to the gene that causes the condition. MeCP2-deficiency leads to the development of a number of serious neurological disorders, including, of course, Rett syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part of the talk, however, was a very visual demonstration, using mice as models, that the disorder is potentially curable with the aid of videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 1 shows a MeCP2-deficient mouse with Rett Syndrome like symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Taken from the &lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt; YouTube channel – url https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XHXU25NTGf4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video 2 shows the same mouse after MeCP2-replacement therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Taken from the &lt;em&gt;New Scientist&lt;/em&gt; YouTube channel – url https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVUq5C9LS-4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, I would certainly recommend this conference to anyone with an interest in the field and I look forward to the programme in two years time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/mice-ants-and-amazing-pictures-chromatin-and-epigenetics-embo-conference-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mice, Ants and Amazing Pictures: Chromatin and Epigenetics EMBO Conference 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Cuff</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">The evolution of earthworms</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/the-evolution-of-earthworms/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9052</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T06:00:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/earthworm-686593_960_720-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Para&quot; id=&quot;Par6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;em class=&quot;EmphasisTypeItalic&quot;&gt;The plough is one of the most ancient and most valuable of man’s inventions; but long before he existed the land was in fact regularly ploughed, and still continues to be thus ploughed by earth-worms. It may be doubted whether there are many other animals which have played so important a part in the history of the world, as have these lowly organised creatures.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;Para&quot; id=&quot;Par7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Darwin, &lt;em class=&quot;EmphasisTypeItalic&quot;&gt;The formation of vegetable mould through the actions of worms, with observations on their habits&lt;/em&gt;, pg. 313&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earthworms digging about in your back yard are members of a large, ubiquitous group with a deep evolutionary history. There are over 6000 earthworm species, found on all continents except Antarctica. Most earthworms dwell in soil, but many live in leaf litter, decaying logs and riverbanks, while some live in trees and even along the seashore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earthworms are major terrestrial ecosystem engineers and their economic impact is immense—earthworms turn over, aerate and drain soils, providing crucial assistance to farmers and gardeners, and compost-dwelling species are used to process food waste and animal manures. Aristotle recognized their importance as the “Intestines of the Earth”, and their reputation was burnished by Charles Darwin in &lt;em&gt;The Formation of Vegetable Mould through the Action of Worms&lt;/em&gt;. On the other hand, a Chinese sage said “watch the earthworm, miss the eclipse”, implying that there are better things to observe. We might disagree, especially in the cases of bioluminescent earthworms, one of which (&lt;em&gt;Avelona ligra&lt;/em&gt;) was sampled for this project, wildly colored earthworms (e.g., &lt;em&gt;Archipheretima&lt;/em&gt; spp.), and those capable of remarkable feats of climbing, some found 40 meters up in French Guyana rainforests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9057&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9057&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/A.ligra-impression-ps.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The bioluminescent worm &lt;em&gt;Avelona ligra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Marcel Koken&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their value, earthworms are generally ignored until they are needed for bait or become a problem. Approximately one-third of the earthworm species in North America have been introduced from Europe or Asia. Some have been introduced into northern forests, which have been free from earthworms since the end of the last ice age ~11,000 years ago. Many other species in these forests rely on a deep layer of decaying leaf material, and earthworms are uniquely adapted to disturb this material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although earthworms are among the most familiar and economically important groups of large invertebrates, their evolutionary history is not well understood. As part of a collaborative effort funded by the US National Science Foundation to study annelid phylogeny, we harnessed high-throughput DNA sequencing to generate transcriptomes for representatives of nearly all of the eighteen living earthworm families as well as several groups thought to be closely related to them and used these data to infer phylogenetic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9058&quot; style=&quot;width: 470px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9058&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Archipheretima-middletoni-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;460&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The colourful earthworm species &lt;em&gt;Archipheretima middletoni&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Sam James&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that the earthworm tree of life consists of two major branches, both with subgroups in the Northern and Southern Hemispheres. One of these branches includes at least three families, two found in eastern North America and one in Madagascar. The other branch contains the vast majority of earthworm species—the northern subgroup includes Lumbricidae, comprising nearly all familiar European species, and the southern subgroup includes Megascolecoidea (a group represented on all southern landmasses plus much of North America), two large Neotropical families and a tropical African family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One long-standing question is whether the broad geographic distribution of earthworms is due to dispersal between continents (e.g., by rafting) or vicariance—riding the continents as they’ve drifted over several hundred million years—or a combination of these processes. We can use our phylogeny to assess the relative importance of these competing mechanisms, but to do so, we had to calibrate our phylogeny to the geological time scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earthworms have left an impressive record of trace fossils, but it is difficult to determine which species made a particular set of fossilized burrows, since body fossils are extremely rare. However, earthworms and their relatives lay their eggs in cocoons, and sometimes these cocoons fossilize. Leech cocoon fossils are known from the late Triassic, 201 million years ago, which tells us not only the minimum age of leeches, but also the minimum age of the common ancestor of leeches and earthworms. We were able to use these fossils to calibrate our phylogeny and infer divergence dates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9059&quot; style=&quot;width: 970px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9059&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Eisenia_cocoon.png&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;An earthworm cocoon.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our analyses reveal that the ancestor of all living earthworms probably lived over 209 million years ago, making earthworms about as old as mammals and dinosaurs. Our date estimates for the divergences between the Northern and Southern Hemisphere subgroups of the two major branches of earthworms fall between 178-186 million years ago, coinciding with the breakup of the supercontinent Pangaea 180-200 million years ago and corroborating the hypothesis that continental breakup influenced early earthworm diversification. This also implies that earthworms likely inhabited Antarctica before the continent’s southward drift made it inimical to most terrestrial animal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our phylogeny also provides a robust framework for investigating several questions about earthworm evolution. At several points in the phylogeny, earthworms have transitioned from terrestrial to aquatic habitats and vice versa. Most species in Clitellata (the group that includes earthworms) are aquatic, so earthworm genomes may retain ancestral genes that enable transitions between habitats. Alternatively, certain features may have been reinvented at each habitat transition. We have begun to explore this question, and hope to investigate other aspects of earthworm gene and genome evolution in our future work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/01/the-evolution-of-earthworms/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The evolution of earthworms&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Frank Anderson &amp;#38; Dr. Samuel James</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Trump pulls United States out of Paris climate agreement</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ZKLgQIajVf0/nature.2017.22096"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22096</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Withdrawal from global pact may take almost four years — which could give the winner of the 2020 presidential race the final word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22096&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ZKLgQIajVf0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Methane exploded from Arctic sea-floor as Ice Age ended</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/gEw_7p5G8OM/nature.2017.22095"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22095</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Huge ocean-floor craters were caused by the expulsion of pressurized greenhouse gas thousands of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22095&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22095&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/gEw_7p5G8OM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Web of Science owner buys up booming peer-review platform</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4XKLuDZI49o/nature.2017.22094"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22094</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Acquisition could lead to new commercial services in scientific peer review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22094&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22094&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4XKLuDZI49o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Richard Van Noorden</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">LIGO spots gravitational waves for third time</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_l7Bxl_5p-8/nature.2017.22093"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22093</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Detection made from another black-hole merger — but physicists are now keen to see such waves from different types of event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22093&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22093&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_l7Bxl_5p-8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Davide Castelvecchi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neuroscientists rethink how the brain recognizes faces</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_HY7LJdARzg/nature.2017.22091"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22091</id>
		<updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Brain cells in monkeys are tuned to react to specific combinations of features, rather than to a whole face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22091&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22091&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_HY7LJdARzg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McQuate</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Behind sociability? The medial prefrontal cortex</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/6lXTWQImTvY/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19356</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T21:59:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/05/Brain-Blue-1-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sociability and the medial prefrontal cortex &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be possible to run a normal existence without social life? Indeed, sociability is an important aspect for individuals and social interactions build our lives. In fact, social interaction enhances quality of life and improves the stability of communities. Impaired sociability is a classical symptom observed in many neuropsychiatric disorders including autism, schizophrenia, depression, anxiety and generalized fear. Interestingly, many studies have pointed to the medial prefrontal cortex (mPFC), a brain area located in the ventromedial part of the frontal lobe, as a key region involved in the neural bases of sociability (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=25727858&quot;&gt;Valk et al, 2015&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=25109665&quot;&gt;Treadway et al., 2015&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=17714666&quot;&gt;Frith et al., 2007&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prelimbic cortex (PL) and the infralimbic cortex (IL), two subregions of the mPFC, have been strongly suggested to play an important role in the neural mechanisms underlying sociability as isolation rearing in rats results in impaired social behavior and structural modifications in the PL and IL. Isolation rearing is a neurodevelopmental manipulation that produces neurochemical, structural, and behavioral alterations in rodents that in many ways are consistent with psychiatric disorders such as schizophrenia, anxiety and depression. In particular, it has been shown that isolation rearing can alter the volume of mPFC, the dendritic length and the spine density of pyramidal neurons. However, the detailed mechanisms involved in sociability disorders remain elusive and poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Altered mPFC activity after isolation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent article published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0176740&quot;&gt;Plos ONE&lt;/a&gt; by Minami and colleagues aimed at measuring neural activity in the PL and IL of control and isolated rats during social interaction in order to determine whether there is neural activity related to social behavior in these areas. Experimentally, animals were divided equally into 2 groups at postnatal day (P) 21 and were housed either in groups (control, group-reared rats) or single-cage (isolation-reared rats).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does isolation influence mPFC activity? To tackle this question, multiunit recording was used as technique to record neural activity in freely moving animals during social behavior testing. However, as stated by the authors, “&lt;em&gt;the conventional technique requires that the animal be tethered to recording instruments with a cable of electrical wires&lt;/em&gt;” and this technical aspect may not facilitate natural and spontaneous social behavior in rats. To overcome these issue, Minami and colleagues used a wireless telemetry system to record the neural activity of a pair of freely moving rats during social interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviors in the social interaction test were categorized as &lt;em&gt;sole&lt;/em&gt; (rats behave separately from each other), &lt;em&gt;approaching&lt;/em&gt; (rat approaching the partner, reduction of distance), &lt;em&gt;contact&lt;/em&gt; (which includes social exploration, aggressiveness and defensiveness), and &lt;em&gt;leaving&lt;/em&gt; (rat leaving the partner).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_19357&quot; style=&quot;width: 410px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/05/social-behavior.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-19357&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/05/social-behavior-300x293.jpg&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Examples showing the behavior of the rats during the social interaction test. A, B: Sole behavior. Rats are behaving separately. The rat (no mark on its back) is exploring around by itself at the lower left corner of the test box and the partner (a black mark on its back) is resting at the lower right corner (A). Both rats are walking along the wall (B). C, D: Approaching behavior. The rat (arrow) is approaching the partner (C), and the partner (arrow) is approaching the rat (D). E–G: Contact behavior. Rats are sniffing (E) and boxing (F) each other, and the rat (arrow) is pinning and biting the partner (G). H, I: Leaving behavior. The rat (arrow) is leaving the partner (H), and the partner (arrow) is leaving the rat (I).&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In control rats (non isolated ones) PL neurons showed increased firing rate during both approaching and contact behaviors, especially when the rat attacked the partner. In contrast to PL neurons, IL neurons showed increased firing only during leaving behavior. Several studies using electrophysiological recordings have shown that the increased firing of PL neurons is correlated with sustained fear, whereas the increased firing of IL neurons is correlated with the recall of extinction (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=16420154&quot;&gt;Gilmartin and McEchron, 2005&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=24231425&quot;&gt;Fitzgerald PJ et al., 2014&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about isolated animals? Is neuronal activity different during social interaction?&lt;strong&gt; “&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isolation-reared rats showed an increased frequency and decreased duration of contact behavior in the present study. These results may be interpreted as that isolation-reared rats are interested in a novel partner but cannot continue contact behavior with the partner for a long period&lt;/em&gt;”, report the authors of the study. In agreement with this hypothesis, it has been reported that isolation-reared animals show a decreased duration of sociability as well as a hyperactivity to novel stimuli. Details analysis of the results revealed that PL neurons were characterized by increasing firing during approaching and contact behaviors (as reported in non-isolated rats). Conversely, IL neurons in isolation-reared rats did not show increased firing during leaving behavior (as observed in control animals), indicating that the increased firing of IL neurons observed during leaving behavior in group-reared rats is suppressed by isolation rearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;The present data demonstrate the neural activity of the PL and IL during social interaction and the influence of isolation rearing on this activity. The differential effects of isolation rearing on the neural activity of the PL and IL may be one of the neural bases of isolation-induced behavior&lt;/em&gt;”, conclude Akira Mitani, the senior investigator of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further investigations are needed to fully understand the role of mPFC in sociability, perhaps paving the way to discovery of alternative solutions for neuropsychiatric disorders such as schizophrenia, anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Peppe-BW&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-17882 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/10/Peppe-BW-238x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;117&quot; /&gt;Giuseppe Gangarossa &lt;/b&gt;received his PhD in Biomedical Sciences, specialty Neuroscience, from the University of Bologna. He has been a visiting fellow at the Karolinska Institutet (Sotckholm, Sweden), the French Inserm (Montpellier, France) and the Collège de France (Paris, France). Giuseppe is currently Assistant Professor of Physiology at the University Paris Diderot. His main research topic is dopamine-related brain disorders. You can follow him on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peppeganga?lang=en&quot;&gt;@PeppeGanga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/6lXTWQImTvY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Giuseppe Gangarossa</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mummy DNA unveils the history of ancient Egyptian hookups</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mummy-dna-unveils-history-ancient-egyptian-hookups"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/mummy-dna-unveils-history-ancient-egyptian-hookups</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T20:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A study of DNA extracted from Egyptian mummies untangles ancient ancestry and attempts to resolve quality issues.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Some topics call for science reporting from many angles</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/some-topics-call-science-reporting-many-angles"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/some-topics-call-science-reporting-many-angles</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T20:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 There’s heartbreak in this issue. Science News investigates different facets of the ongoing opioid epidemic in the United States.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers puzzled by proton's properties</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-puzzled-protons-properties"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-puzzled-protons-properties</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T19:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers sent feedback on under-ice greenhouses in the Arctic, the Martian atmosphere and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">For babies exposed to opioids in the womb, parents may be the best medicine</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/babies-exposed-opioids-womb-parents-may-be-best-medicine"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/babies-exposed-opioids-womb-parents-may-be-best-medicine</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T19:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A surge in opioid-exposed newborns has U.S. doctors revamping treatments and focusing on families.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Meghan Rosen</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">New Thematic Series for BMC Immunology: Cancer Immunotherapy and Vaccines</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/new-thematic-series-for-bmc-immunology-cancer-immunotherapy-and-vaccines/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9065</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T16:10:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/cancer-389921_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaccines are the most effective and cost-efficient weapons that can be used to prevent (preventive vaccines) or cure (therapeutic vaccines) diseases caused by infectious agents or cancer cells. Usually, when one thinks about the word vaccine, the first thought that comes into the mind is related to an artificial administration of a stimulus that instructs the immune system to fight against the cause of a particular pathological state (the pathogen). However, in the case of cancer vaccines, the main view, still unknown to the majority of the people not working in the field,  is represented by the exploitation of the host’s immune system to treat or prevent cancer. The idea, however, dates back decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way a “traditional” vaccine works, a cancer vaccine can promote the eradication of malignant cells during their initial transformation from safe to harmful cells. This eradication process, commonly referred to as immune surveillance of tumors [1], is carried out by the immune system and, most of the time, it happens without any external intervention. Tumors are the result of a particular combination of factors related to genetic and epigenetic changes that enable immortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the same way a “traditional” vaccine works, a cancer vaccine can promote the eradication of malignant cells during their initial transformation from safe to harmful cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a completely undetectable process: during the transformation of a normal cell into a malignant one, foreign antigens (neo-antigens or, to be more specific, onco-antigens) are created;  these should render neoplastic cells visible by the immune system that can target them for elimination. Tumors cells, like every living organisms, want, nevertheless, to live. Hence, tumors try to become resistant and invisible to immune system attacks by developing multiple resistance mechanisms that include local immune evasion, induction of tolerance and systemic interference of T cell signaling. Besides, mimicking the metaphor of Darwin’s natural selection, immune recognition of cancer cells enforces a selective pressure on developing ones. This favors the development of less immunogenic and more apoptosis-resistant neoplastic cells, through a mechanism well known as immune editing [2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that cancer cells are particularly good at evading any action from the immune system, most anti-cancer treatments are based on other means like surgery, radiation therapy, and chemotherapy. Nowadays, however, it is clear that the various arms of the immune system play an essential role in protecting humans from cancer. After unsatisfactory efforts and explicit clinical failures, the field of cancer immunotherapy has received a significant boost, thanks mainly to the development in 2010 of an autologous cellular immunotherapy, sipuleucel-T, for the treatment of prostate cancer [3] and the approval of the anti-cytotoxic T lymphocyte-associated protein 4 (CTLA-4) antibody ipilimumab (2011) and anti-programmed cell death protein 1 (PD1) antibodies (2014) for the treatment of melanoma [4]. These achievements have renovated the field and brought attention to the opportunities that immunotherapeutic approaches can offer [5,6].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9070&quot; style=&quot;width: 248px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9070&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/syringe-30012_1280-238x300.png&quot; width=&quot;238&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The field of cancer immunotherapy has recently received a significant boost&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still, however, some difficulties to be overcome when developing effective immunotherapy strategies against cancer. The general lack of understanding of the mechanisms of immunization, the role of dendritic cells, the ability of cancer to induce tolerance, and the identification of the most suitable antigens to use are just some examples of how the development of effective strategies is still problematic [7-10]. There are several biotechnological methodologies, based on both&lt;em&gt; in silico&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; techniques, that study and suggest possible candidates for use in immunotherapies. However, they are not able, on their own, to quantify and analyze the immune system response globally. Moreover, there are now several computational techniques to predict T cell epitopes (and, to some extent, also B cell epitopes) [11,12]. Computational simulations may help in solving these issues, but these need to be integrated with the &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in silico&lt;/em&gt; molecular analyses [13,14]. So, a complete computational/biological pipeline that allow the best integration of  &lt;em&gt;in silico&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt; methodologies may potentially  boost and improve cancer immunotherapy development and effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the thematic series is to bring together the latest advances in both biological and computational research, looking broadly at the basic biological aspects of immunotherapy, emerging immunotherapies (both prophylactic and preventive) and different vaccination approaches. The novel, and, at the same time, established character of computation in immunology greatly improves and speeds-up the development of novel vaccination strategies, both therapeutic and preventive, against cancer. We welcome original research, methodology, software, and database article submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for submission of manuscripts is 30th November 2017. For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biomedcentral.com/collections/civ&quot;&gt;visit the &lt;em&gt;BMC Immunology &lt;/em&gt;website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;References&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharma P, Wagner K, Wolchok JD, Allison JP. Novel cancer immunotherapy agents with survival benefit: recent successes and next steps. Nat Rev Cancer. 2011;11:805–12.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mahoney KM, Rennert PD, Freeman GJ. Combination cancer immunotherapy and new immunomodulatory targets. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2015;14:561–84.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topalian SL, Weiner GJ, Pardoll DM. Cancer immunotherapy comes of age. J Clin Oncol. 2011;29:4828–36.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharma P, Allison JP. Immune checkpoint targeting in Cancer Therapy: toward combination strategies with curative potential. Cell. 2015;161:205–14.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mellman I, Coukos G, Dranoff G. Cancer immunotherapy comes of age. Nature. 2011;480:480–9.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sofia Farkona, Eleftherios P. Diamandis and Ivan M. Blasutig. Cancer immunotherapy: the beginning of the end of cancer? BMC Medicine 2016;14:73.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosenberg SA, Yang JC, Restifo NP. Cancer immunotherapy. Moving beyond current vaccines. Nat Med. 2004;10:909–15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palucka K, Banchereau J. Dendritic-cell-based therapeutic cancer vaccines. Immunity. 2013;39:38–48.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palucka K, Banchereau J. Cancer immunotherapy via dendritic cells. Nat Rev Cancer. 2012;12:265–77.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chen DS, Mellman I. Oncology meets immunology: the cancer-immunity Cycle. Immunity. 2013;39:1–10.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sheikh, QM, Gatherer, D, Reche, PA &amp;amp; Flower, DR 2016, ‘Towards the knowledge-based design of universal influenza epitope ensemble vaccines’ Bioinformatics, vol. 32, no. 21, pp. 3233-3239.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sivalingam, Ganesh N., and Adrian J. Shepherd. “An Analysis of B-Cell Epitope Discontinuity.” Molecular Immunology 51.3-4 (2012): 304–309.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pappalardo, F, Fichera, E, Paparone, N, et al. A computational model to predict the immune system activation by citrus derived vaccine adjuvants. Bioinformatics, 32(17):2672–2680, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pappalardo, F, Pennisi, M, Ricupito, A, et al. Induction of T cell memory by a dendritic cell vaccine: a computational model. Bioinformatics, 30(13):1884–1891, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palladini, A, Nicoletti, G, Pappalardo, F, et al. In silico modeling and in vivo efficacy of cancer-preventive vaccinations. Cancer Research, 70(20):7755–7763, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/new-thematic-series-for-bmc-immunology-cancer-immunotherapy-and-vaccines/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;New Thematic Series for BMC Immunology: Cancer Immunotherapy and Vaccines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Professor Francesco Pappalardo</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Yikes: Peer reviewer stole (and published) author’s data</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/31/yikes-peer-reviewer-stole-published-authors-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50303</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T15:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A gastroenterology and hepatology journal has retracted a 2017 review after discovering it included data “accessible only during peer review for another journal.” Although we don’t know the details of this particular case—for instance, how the editors and publisher of Alimentary Pharmacology &amp;amp; Therapeutics learned about the transgression and which author was responsible—the journal acted quickly […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/31/yikes-peer-reviewer-stole-published-authors-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Yikes: Peer reviewer stole (and published) author’s data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Researchers stumble onto a new role for breast cancer drug</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/researchers-stumble-new-role-breast-cancer-drug"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/researchers-stumble-new-role-breast-cancer-drug</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 At first, ophthalmologist Xu Wang thought her experiment had failed. But instead, she revealed a new role for the breast cancer drug tamoxifen — protection from eye injury.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Western style diet and transcriptional programming in muscle</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/western-style-diet-transcriptional-programming-muscle/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9060</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T12:54:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Fast-food-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lifestyle changes including increased consumption of high fat diets have caused a considerable rise in individuals who are overweight and obese in the past decades. Obesity is a major risk factor for type 2 diabetes. These individuals have increased blood sugar (hyperglycemia) and cholesterol levels, leading to various other health complications. According to International Diabetes Federation (IDF), 1 in 11 adults have diabetes, and 21% of the world’s population will be affected by diabetes by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several clinical trials have proposed the useful effects of lifestyle intervention for controlling obesity and diabetes, however, in many cases restoring the glycemic index to normal levels does not ameliorate diabetic complications. This has been attributed to “metabolic memory” or “legacy effect”. High glucose conditions induce long-term cellular changes which are not completely restored after normalizing glycaemia. Metabolic memory due to programing has been attributed to induced epigenetic modifications like DNA methylation which alter normal gene expression and cell function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3799-y&quot;&gt;published recently&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,  assessed the physiological and cellular effects of high caloric diet induced hyperglycemia followed by caloric restriction, a common approach of controlling obesity in accordance with metabolic memory in non-human primates. Skeletal muscle being the major site of glucose intake, was the tissue of interest for this study. We included 6 male rhesus macaques and put them on western style calorie dense diets for 6 months followed by a calorie restricted diet to 70% of their required caloric intake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed that a high-fat diet increased body weight, blood glucose and caused insulin resistance in macaques and calorie restriction in the same animals returned these levels to normal but had only a partial effect on fat loss. Findings from our transcriptional analysis showed that high-fat diet reprograms the skeletal muscle to induce changes which persist even after calorie restriction. Genes involved in glucose metabolism and insulin signaling remained downregulated post high-fat diet and caloric restriction while those involved in extracellular matrix remodeling remained upregulated. We also suspect that changes in the inflammatory response induced by high fat diet might induce ROS-related stress and other metabolic pathway changes which adapts the skeletal muscle to high fat environment. Related to metabolic memory, we identified a major epigenetic modifier SETD7 to be expressed at reduced levels following calorie restriction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve long term problems associated with obesity it is important to identify the changes it induces within the cell. Identification of these factors through our study as compared to other studies provides possible cellular changes within the cell which can be targeted through medical intervention in addition to lifestyle intervention to improve health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9061&quot; style=&quot;width: 1010px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9061 size-full&quot; height=&quot;318&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Western-diet-and-obesity-blog-figure.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diet-induced metabolic memory:&lt;/strong&gt; The figure summarizes our study in Rhesus macaques skeletal muscle tissue following dietary changes that change body weight and insulin resistance. High-fat western style diet leads to hyperglycemia and hyperinsulinemia which induces transcriptional memory within the fat cell, which is not restored to normal even after glycemic normalization post calorie restricted diet.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/western-style-diet-transcriptional-programming-muscle/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Western style diet and transcriptional programming in muscle&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Mithila Handu</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Open Position: PhD studentships in Computational Neuroscience</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/05/31/open-position-phd-studentships-in-computational-neuroscience.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-05-31:/2017/05/31/open-position-phd-studentships-in-computational-neuroscience.html</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T12:20:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for PhD positions in the Biocomputation Research Group at the University of Hertfordshire. Projects involve the development and simulation of models of neurons and neuronal networks to study information processing in the cerebellum or olfactory system and/or the application of machine learning techniques for the analysis of neural data. A description of our research interests and a list of publications can be found on our webpage (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applicants should have excellent computational and numerical skills and a very good first degree in computer science, biology, maths, physics, neuroscience, or a related discipline. Successful candidates are eligible for a research studentship award from the University (GBP 14,553 per annum bursary plus payment of the student fees). Applicants from outside the UK or EU are eligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in Computer Science at the University of Hertfordshire has been recognised as excellent in the latest Research Excellence Framework Assessment, with 50% of the research submitted rated as internationally excellent or world leading. The Centre for Computer Science and Informatics Research  provides a very stimulating environment, offering a large number of specialised and interdisciplinary seminars as well as general training and researcher development opportunities. The University  is situated in Hatfield, in the green belt just north of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact Dr Volker Steuber for informal enquiries. Application forms are available under &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Volker Steuber</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-05-31T12:20:03+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How upset should we get when articles are paywalled by mistake?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/31/how-upset-should-we-get-when-articles-are-paywalled-by-mistake/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50341</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T12:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Mistakes happen. Including, sometimes, putting articles that should be freely available behind a paywall. This occasionally happens — though likely not with alarming frequency, according to publishing expert Charles Oppenheim, who recently wrote about the issue in Scholarly Kitchen. Still, the costs can literally be high, both for the authors who paid to make their articles free […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/31/how-upset-should-we-get-when-articles-are-paywalled-by-mistake/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How upset should we get when articles are paywalled by mistake?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Peru’s plenty brought ancient human migration to a crawl</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perus-plenty-brought-ancient-human-migration-crawl"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perus-plenty-brought-ancient-human-migration-crawl</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient Americans reached Peru 15,000 years ago and stayed put, excavations suggest.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Psychologists have shown that it’s possible to train one-year-olds’ attention skills</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/31/psychologists-have-shown-that-its-possible-to-train-one-year-olds-attention-skills/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24245</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T09:44:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_24254&quot; style=&quot;width: 820px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-529044883&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24254&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24254&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;GettyImages-529044883&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-529044883.jpg?w=845?w=820&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-529044883.jpg?w=845?w=240&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-529044883.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;820,1024&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/31/psychologists-have-shown-that-its-possible-to-train-one-year-olds-attention-skills/gettyimages-529044883/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-529044883.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;What’s the best age for a child start school? Four, as in the UK? Six or seven, as in Sweden? What about one?&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/dev/53/5/815.html&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Developmental Psychology, &lt;/i&gt;children as young as 12-months-old can be taught to get better at focusing their attention – which may help with their acquisition of language, and other types of learning. This new study involved typical, healthy infants. But the findings could also be taken as support for the idea that interventions aimed at children showing problems with attention (who may go on to be diagnosed with Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder, for example) can, and should, start at a very young age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24245&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on children aged four and over has found that training tasks designed to improve attentional control can lead to more general improvements in attention (so not just on the tasks used in training). But there hasn’t been much work on younger children, and the limited work that has been done hasn’t investigated whether any improvements last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaili Clarkson at the University of Cambridge, and colleagues, divided 48 boys and girls, all aged about one, into a training group and two control groups. Each child first completed a roughly 20-minute series of tests of attentional control. These included an evaluation of how long they took to predict the next letter in a ABABAB sequence, the number of times they had to look at picture of a child’s face before they learned to recognise it, as well as an evaluation of general attentiveness during the entire testing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training group then received a total of 95 minutes of training over five sessions, spaced out over about two weeks. While sitting on their parent’s laps, these infants were presented in each session with six different tasks that rewarded them if they focused on a target. For example, in one, if a child looked away from a moving butterfly (the target) to a distractor, the display froze, and only un-froze when the child again focused on the butterfly. Another task required the infants to work out (with animations given as rewards) when the target changed from an image of an elephant to a chicken, while, again, ignoring distractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after the fifth training session, and then also six weeks later, the infants in all groups took the initial tests of attentional control again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after training, there were significant improvements in the training group’s sustained attention, compared with their initial scores. These infants were also faster at learning to recognise another child’s face and at sequence learning and general attentiveness. (The controls showed no significant improvements.) The trained children only failed to improve on one test: memory for an image that they had previously learned to recognise. (At this young age, short term memory capacity may be too weak to be trained, the researchers suggested.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarkson and her colleagues also found lower levels of the stress hormone cortisol in the trained infants, compared with the controls, during these post-training testing sessions. And they think this is important because it suggests that targeting attention skills may lead to improved self-regulation, and lower anxiety levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six weeks on, the trained infants’ improvements in general attentiveness and habituation to a face had gone, as had the reduction in their cortisol levels. However, although  improvements in their sustained attention had faded a little, they were still statistically significant, and the trained infants were still faster at learning sequences than they were initially, and in comparison with the control groups’ scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the relative brevity of the training, it’s not surprising that there was a loss of or deterioration in improvements after six weeks. For comparison, the work on attention training in older children has generally involved training periods of around 10 hours, over 20-25 sessions. Future work should investigate whether longer-term training of one-year-olds could boost and sustain the types of improvements seen right after training in this study – and whether there are wider ranging benefits for language learning and other aspects of development. “Given the evidence that cortical activation patterns are less localised and specialised early in development”, it’s likely that training one-year-olds would lead to more generalised improvements than in older children, the researchers suggested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So should parents be rushing off to train their infants’ attention? This study (and others) have found benefits in the short term, in the lab. But what real-world effects training might – or might not – bring is not yet clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/index.cfm?fa=buy.optionToBuy&amp;amp;id=2017-18450-001&quot;&gt;Changes in behavior and salivary cortisol after targeted cognitive training in typical 12-month-old infants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: by Constance Bannister Corp/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24245/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24245/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24245&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Rapid gene isolation in barley and wheat by mutant chromosome sequencing</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/05/31/rapid-gene-isolation-in-barley-and-wheat-by-mutant-chromosome-sequencing.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-05-31:/2017/05/31/rapid-gene-isolation-in-barley-and-wheat-by-mutant-chromosome-sequencing.html</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T09:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Cristina Barrero-Sicilia's journal club session where she discusses the paper, &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-016-1082-1&quot;&gt;Rapid gene isolation in barley and wheat by mutant chromosome sequencing (Sánchez-Martín et al. (2016))&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identification of causal mutations in barley and wheat is hampered by their
large genomes and suppressed recombination. To overcome these obstacles, we
have developed MutChromSeq, a complexity reduction approach based on flow
sorting and sequencing of mutant chromosomes, to identify induced mutations by
comparison to parental chromosomes. We apply MutChromSeq to six mutants each of
the barley Eceriferum-q gene and the wheat Pm2 genes. This approach
unambiguously identified single candidate genes that were verified by Sanger
sequencing of additional mutants. MutChromSeq enables reference-free forward
genetics in barley and wheat, thus opening up their pan-genomes to functional
genomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 02/06/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Cristina Barrero-Sicilia</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-05-31T12:20:03+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Clinical trials in the twenty first century – highlights from ICTMC 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/clinical-trials-in-the-twenty-first-century-highlights-from-ictmc-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9044</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T09:05:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Liverpool-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) are the gold standard for testing new medical interventions on a population, with their use increasing exponentially throughout the twentieth century up to the present day. With their increasing use and complexity, new challenges have emerged in regards to how RCTs are conducted. This congress brought together leaders in the field to discuss every aspect of the methodology of RCTs including trial design, data analysis and reporting of trial outcomes amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current issues and challenges &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first of the three keynote talks, by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.med.upenn.edu/apps/faculty/index.php/g275/p4930413&quot;&gt;Dr Susan Ellenberg&lt;/a&gt; of the University of Pennsylvania, considered the on-going challenges and the emerging issues of clinical trials in the twenty first century. The first published RCT of the modern era was conducted in 1948 and since then the RCT has undergone constant change and development. One example of this is increasing the complexity of a clinical trial by incorporating individualized treatments dependent on specific biomarkers present in certain members of the study population. However, this brings with it a range of issues including which diseases require individualized treatment, the ethics of pursuing targeted treatments over broad treatments and the cost of these more complex trials. Another issue discussed was how clinical research can be carried out in an emergency situation such as the Ebola outbreak of 2014. In order to both treat patients and also investigate the most effective treatments, clinical research should be implemented from the beginning of the response to ensure that answers are found as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9046&quot; style=&quot;width: 3811px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9046&quot; height=&quot;2681&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Keynote1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3801&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Susan Ellenberg&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical trials in the age of big data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another huge development in medical research in the last few decades has been the proliferation of “big data”. One of the most ambitious projects aiming to use big data in healthcare research is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.research.va.gov/mvp/&quot;&gt;Million Veteran Program&lt;/a&gt; (MVP) with one of the leaders, &lt;a href=&quot;http://physiciandirectory.brighamandwomens.org/details/652/john-gaziano-cardiovascular_medicine-boston&quot;&gt;Dr Michael Gaziano&lt;/a&gt;, delivering the second keynote talk. The project aims to enrol one million veterans and will store a range of information on each individual, including self-reported lifestyle data alongside biospecimens. This forms one of the most comprehensive data sets in the world and can be used to research human health and disease. The development of such a large data set has brought many challenges such as learning how to structure and phenotype the data to allow it to be used to answer specific research questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing of clinical trial data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With more and more data being collected on individual participants in clinical research, another theme at the conference was data sharing to improve research efficiency. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liverpool.ac.uk/translational-medicine/staff/catrin-tudur-smith/&quot;&gt;Catrin Tudur Smith&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ed.ac.uk/profile/steff-lewis&quot;&gt;Steff Lewis&lt;/a&gt; led a very interesting invited session with contributors discussing how clinical trial data can be shared more effectively, how participants view data sharing, and what data sharing might look like in the future. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bmj.com/about-bmj/editorial-staff/trish-groves&quot;&gt;Trish Groves&lt;/a&gt;, Editor in Chief of &lt;em&gt;BMJ Open&lt;/em&gt;, provided the point-of-view of the publisher and suggested that journals have a big part to play in encouraging the publication of anonymized data sets alongside trial results. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctu.mrc.ac.uk/about_us/senior_staff_profiles/matt_sydes/&quot;&gt;Matt Sydes&lt;/a&gt; of the MRC Clinical Trials Unit presented some of the challenges surrounding data sharing, including effective anonymization of the data as well as deciding which data sets are worth preparing for sharing as this can be a time consuming and costly process. The importance of data security was also covered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://medhealth.leeds.ac.uk/profile/400/1451/gillian_booth&quot;&gt;Gillian Booth&lt;/a&gt; as well as the importance of obtaining appropriate consent for data sharing from the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UK NIHR Health Technology Assessment Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final keynote was delivered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nottingham.ac.uk/medicine/people/hywel.williams&quot;&gt;Professor Hywel Williams&lt;/a&gt; who spoke about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nihr.ac.uk/funding-and-support/funding-for-research-studies/funding-programmes/health-technology-assessment/&quot;&gt;UK NIHR Health Technology Assessment Programme&lt;/a&gt; which is one of the largest UK funding bodies of clinical trials, with results directly influencing clinical practice in the NHS. One of the main aims of the program is to conduct timely research to answer specific questions that are required to improve current clinical practice. This is done through a prioritization process to determine which research projects are most needed and are generally those that are important to the NHS, are supported by current evidence, are feasible and that are clear and well defined. One of the take home messages was that the program aims to strike a balance between influencing the research community and also being led by the research community in terms of deciding which projects should be funded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9047&quot; style=&quot;width: 3307px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9047&quot; height=&quot;2217&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/05/Keynote3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3297&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Hywel Williams&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/05/31/clinical-trials-in-the-twenty-first-century-highlights-from-ictmc-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Clinical trials in the twenty first century – highlights from ICTMC 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emma Cookson</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Infographic: How China’s One Belt, One Road initiative will change research collaboration</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/infographic-how-chinas-one-belt-one-road-initiative-will-change-research-collaboration"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/infographic-how-chinas-one-belt-one-road-initiative-will-change-research-collaboration</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T08:14:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Modern “silk road” will connect 65 countries in Asia, Europe and Africa</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Navigating the Fragmented Outsourced Manufacturing Sector</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/05/navigating-the-fragmented-outsourced-manufacturing-sector/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1073</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:46:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Contract manufacturing of pharmaceuticals is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://resultshealthcare.com/insight/pharma-biotech-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;growing rapidly&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and has recently seen an uptick in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2017/05/15/patheon-stock-thermo-fisher/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;merger and acquisition activity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, such as Thermo Fisher’s bid to acquire Patheon.  Despite the consolidation, outsourced pharmaceutical manufacturing remains a fragmented market, as outlined in a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://resultshealthcare.com/insight/pharma-biotech-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;recent report&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsourcedpharma.com/doc/m-a-crucible-in-contract-drug-development-and-manufacturing-0001?vm_tId=1990990&amp;amp;user=2ef1f69e-200b-45fb-8201-50dde0ac0940&amp;amp;utm_source=et_6214173&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=OUTPH_04-05-2017&amp;amp;utm_term=2ef1f69e-200b-45fb-8201-50dde0ac0940&amp;amp;utm_content=M%2526amp%253bA+Crucible+in+Contract+Drug+Development+And+Manufacturing&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. Discovering and qualifying outsourced service providers is already challenging, and the persistent fragmentation compounds the challenges. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange has a unique vantage point for evaluating contract manufacturing services based on our diverse client base and the associated customer experience scorecard data we gather. In this post, we share our insights around navigating the complex contract manufacturing sector.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Demand for contract manufacturing services&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The high demand for external manufacturing capacity and expertise is one driving force behind the proliferation of CMOs and CDMOs. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;According to a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niceinsight.com/articles.aspx?post=3058&amp;amp;title=Strong+CMO/CDMO+Market+Outlook+for+2016,+but+Beware+Moderating+Factors&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;2016 survey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, biopharma organizations cite the need to improve quality as the primary reason for using contract manufacturing organizations (CMOs) and contract development and manufacturing organizations (CDMOs). Additional goals for outsourcing include reducing time to market, controlling costs, achieving supply chain diversity, leveraging regulatory expertise, and accessing specialized technologies, including those required for complex biologics manufacturing processes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Competition between CMOs: Innovative manufacturing services&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Competition in the marketplace is driving CMOs to develop innovative manufacturing technologies to capture new service categories — choosing a cutting-edge CMO partner can give a biopharma company advantages over its competitors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Many CMOs and CDMOs have adopted process improvements to provide their clients with faster cycle times and more informed decision-making. These improvements include cloud-based computing, real-time risk-monitoring tools, and integrated quality-by-design during process development. Suc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;h process improvements are especially important given &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;the ability of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://resultshealthcare.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pharmaceutical-Manufacturing.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;multiple CMOs to manufacture the same API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. Nearly &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://resultshealthcare.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Results-Healthcare_Pharma-Biotech-2017-Review-of-outsourced-manufacturing_Whitepaper.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;90%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; of the volume of drugs sold are generic small molecule therapeutics, requiring high production capacity that &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;may be provided by any number of CMOs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Other CMOs differentiate themselves through specialized expertise – for example, they may be leaders in developing novel formulations, such as nanoparticles or lipid-based delivery systems. Some CMOs offer specialized regulatory certifications, such as CLIA/CAP, GLP, and GCP. Although cGMP compliance is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcisynthesis.com/how-to-get-your-organization-prepared-for-an-fda-inspection/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;not absolutely required for all CMO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;s, most reputable CMOs are cGMP certified.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contract manufacturing of biologics and complex therapeutics: a growth opportunity&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;It has been &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biopharma-reporter.com/Upstream-Processing/Biologics-CMO-demand-to-drop-as-Big-Pharma-favours-in-house-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;challenging to outsource the manufacture of biologics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, such as vaccines, therapeutic monoclonal antibodies, and cell therapies, and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nyas.org/Events/Detail.aspx?cid=07082904-d593-4f0e-ada7-446ec8e7444b&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;non-biological complex drugs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. These fast-growing segments are fac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ed with regulatory hurdles, a need for specialized drug delivery devices, and inherent risks involved in method transfer and ensuring consistent supply. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Despite the challenges of method transfer, technological improvements are facilitating partnerships between biopharma companies and CMOs in biologics pipelines. Emerging categories of therapeutics, such as cell therapies and antibody-drug conjugates, as well as novel formulations, such as nanoparticles, have benefited from specialized manufacturers. Even though some of these specialty drug products may require bespoke manufacturing processes, CMOs stay agile through integrated quality-by-design during process development and take advantage of connected single-use technologies for streamlined yet flexible bioprocessing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Barriers facing discovery and qualification of manufacturing service providers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The demand for contract manufacturing, combined with the growth opportunities around innovation and biologics, have resulted in a marketplace with thousands of active CMOs and CDMOs. It can be time-consuming and difficult to identify qualified service providers with the right certifications to meet regulatory compliance requirements. Though many service providers are staffed by innovative, highly qualified scientists with experience in the biopharma industry, many service providers lack such expertise. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Because there are no clear third-party qualification processes or objective benchmarks for quality, and because biopharma companies lack the time to perform regulatory compliance audits of all the service providers in this fragmented sector, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niceinsight.com/articles.aspx?post=3058&amp;amp;title=Strong+CMO/CDMO+Market+Outlook+for+2016,+but+Beware+Moderating+Factors&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;over 68% of biopharma companies use a preferred provider strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; for outsourced manufacturing. Relying on preferred providers may decrease the agility of companies to take advantage of emerging technologies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For contract manufacturing to add maximum value to an organization, responsible teams should consider adhering to a defined sourcing strategy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Checklist for a successful contract manufacturing partnership&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To maximize the advantages offered by a successful CMO partnership, the procurement and external resource management teams of a biopharma company must ensure that their sourcing strategy includes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Keeping abreast of emerging technologies and service providers;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Stringently qualifying service providers based on turnaround time, product quality, cost, and regulatory compliance;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Identifying service gaps and assessing value of existing preferred providers; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Streamlining the contracting process to enable rapid onboarding of innovative service providers;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Establishing contracts that protect intellectual property and confidentiality, to maintain competitive advantage and minimize risk;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Managing project milestones to ensure that projects are completed on time and as planned;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Keeping meticulous records so that methods can be transferred in house or to other service providers as needed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Science Exchange  streamlines management of strategic manufacturing partnerships&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange, the largest marketplace for outsourced scientific services, enables biopharma companies to rapidly find and order cutting-edge technologies and services from a proprietary network of 2500+ qualified service providers, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;including many providers of contract manufacturing services.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange’s Provider Management Team continually seeks to build its network by adding high-quality, innovative service providers with cutting-edge expertise in emerging manufacturing technologies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange’s dedicated staff scientists on our Sourcing Team help biopharma manufacturing teams find the best service provider for each scope of work, obtain multiple competitive quotes, and provide end-to-end project management. By using Science Exchange, manufacturing teams save hours or days per project that they would otherwise spend identifying providers, obtaining quotes, and managing projects. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange mitigates inherent risks of outsourced manufacturing; all service providers on the platform are pre-qualified through a stringent vetting process and provides information on past performance, using an ISO 9001 Quality Systems-certified process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Manufacturing scientists at top biopharma companies are already using Science Exchange to access hundreds of qualified specialty providers. The platform is enabling these scientists to order services from known and new manufacturing service providers, such as ImQuest, Almac Sciences, Recipharm, ChemPartner, Synovel Laboratory, Bioneer A/S, Solvias AG, WuXi AppTec, Lonza, and Piramal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/contact&quot;&gt;Contact Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt; today to discuss your manufacturing needs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Transforming Scientific Collaboration: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:40+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pay-to-view blacklist of predatory journals set to launch</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ii2XJedN7DU/nature.2017.22090"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22090</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Private firm says its watchlist of untrustworthy journals will be objective and transparent — but not free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22090&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22090&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ii2XJedN7DU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew Silver</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why function is catching on in conservation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0jOBX5Up1cY/nature.2017.22058"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22058</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Counting what species do is becoming as important as counting how many there are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 7 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22058&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22058&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0jOBX5Up1cY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Taxonomy anarchy hampers conservation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/9JLTdu4UVio/546025a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546025a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The classification of complex organisms is in chaos. Stephen T. Garnett and Les Christidis propose a solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 25 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546025a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546025a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/9JLTdu4UVio&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Stephen T. Garnett</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Biodiversity moves beyond counting species</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/AgSCFMOumF8/546022a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546022a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ecologists are increasingly looking at how richness of traits — rather than number of species — helps set the health of ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 22 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546022a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546022a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/AgSCFMOumF8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rachel Cernansky</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neutron stars set to open their heavy hearts</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/TyQBSBJrCCc/546018a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546018a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Space mission will peer inside the densest matter in the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 18 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546018a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546018a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/TyQBSBJrCCc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">UK election: science spending pledges overshadowed by Brexit</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/T6ph5hxGrIE/546016a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546016a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Parties promise more money for research, but scientists fear impact of split with European Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 16 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546016a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546016a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/T6ph5hxGrIE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Cressey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Trials of embryonic stem cells to launch in China</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BPY5e6WFxfE/546015a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546015a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Studies to treat vision loss and Parkinson’s disease are the first to proceed under new regulations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 15 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546015a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546015a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BPY5e6WFxfE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Cyranoski</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">LHC fires up, Google bot retires and Jupiter up close</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5G2SJaxto7E/546012a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546012a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 26 May–1 June 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 12 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546012a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546012a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5G2SJaxto7E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Announcement: Towards greater reproducibility for life-sciences research in Nature</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/9TenErdR0BE/546008a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546008a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 8 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546008a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546008a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/9TenErdR0BE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Keep shouting to save science</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/jaQQRSHOzjE/546007a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546007a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As political leaders on either side of the Atlantic set out contrasting positions on science funding, researchers everywhere need to ensure that their voices are heard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 7 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/546007a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546007a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/jaQQRSHOzjE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crystal structure of the GLP-1 receptor bound to a peptide agonist</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/BnTJbe3Anu4/nature22800"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22800</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1) regulates glucose homeostasis through the control of insulin release from the pancreas. GLP-1 peptide agonists are efficacious drugs for the treatment of diabetes. To gain insight into the molecular mechanism of action of GLP-1 peptides, here we report the crystal structure of the full-length GLP-1 receptor bound to a truncated peptide agonist. The peptide agonist retains an α-helical conformation as it sits deep within the receptor-binding pocket. The arrangement of the transmembrane helices reveals hallmarks of an active conformation similar to that observed in class A receptors. Guided by this structural information, we design peptide agonists with potent in vivo activity in a mouse model of diabetes. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22800&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22800&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/BnTJbe3Anu4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ali Jazayeri</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neurodegenerative disease: RNA repeats put a freeze on cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/r0oRoLFOt9k/nature22503"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22503</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Droplet-like assemblies of RNA in cell nuclei are associated with certain neurodegenerative diseases. Experiments reveal that these assemblies become 'frozen' gels in cells, potentially explaining their toxicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22503&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22503&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/r0oRoLFOt9k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David W. Sanders</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Evolution: Differences can hold populations together</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/N2-1fTxxNs0/nature22502"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22502</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Evolution favours the body form best adapted to the local environment, but it can also favour rare forms. Stickleback experiments reveal how these two selection forces can interact, and how this can limit population divergence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22502&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/N2-1fTxxNs0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David N. Reznick</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecular biology: Local metabolites linked to memory</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/bSjbIwBYKjw/nature22498"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22498</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Production of the metabolite acetyl-CoA near specific regions of DNA modulates gene expression in mouse neurons during cellular differentiation and memory formation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22498&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22498&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/bSjbIwBYKjw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>L. Ashley Watson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure of the Cpf1 endonuclease R-loop complex after target DNA cleavage</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/hRHBbM10ao8/nature22398"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22398</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Cpf1 is an RNA-guided endonuclease that is emerging as a powerful genome-editing tool. Here we provide insight into its DNA-targeting mechanism by determining the structure of Francisella novicida Cpf1 with the triple-stranded R-loop generated after DNA cleavage. The structure reveals the machinery involved in DNA unwinding to form a CRISPR RNA (crRNA)–DNA hybrid and a displaced DNA strand. The protospacer adjacent motif (PAM) is recognized by the PAM-interacting domain. The loop-lysine helix–loop motif in this domain contains three conserved lysine residues that are inserted in a dentate manner into the double-stranded DNA. Unzipping of the double-stranded DNA occurs in a cleft arranged by acidic and hydrophobic residues facilitating the crRNA–DNA hybrid formation. The PAM single-stranded DNA is funnelled towards the nuclease site through a mixed hydrophobic and basic cavity. In this catalytic conformation, the PAM-interacting domain and the helix–loop–helix motif in the REC1 domain adopt a ‘rail’ shape and ‘flap-on’ conformations, respectively, channelling the PAM strand into the cavity. A steric barrier between the RuvC-II and REC1 domains forms the ‘septum’, separating the displaced PAM strand and the crRNA–DNA hybrid, avoiding DNA re-annealing. Mutations in key residues reveal a mechanism linking the PAM and DNA nuclease sites. Analysis of the Cpf1 structures proposes a singular working model of RNA-guided DNA cleavage, suggesting new avenues for redesign of Cpf1. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22398&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/hRHBbM10ao8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Stefano Stella</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">RNA phase transitions in repeat expansion disorders</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MJ_9W26CY2c/nature22386"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22386</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Expansions of short nucleotide repeats produce several neurological and neuromuscular disorders including Huntington disease, muscular dystrophy, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. A common pathological feature of these diseases is the accumulation of the repeat-containing transcripts into aberrant foci in the nucleus. RNA foci, as well as the disease symptoms, only manifest above a critical number of nucleotide repeats, but the molecular mechanism governing foci formation above this characteristic threshold remains unresolved. Here we show that repeat expansions create templates for multivalent base-pairing, which causes purified RNA to undergo a sol–gel transition in vitro at a similar critical repeat number as observed in the diseases. In human cells, RNA foci form by phase separation of the repeat-containing RNA and can be dissolved by agents that disrupt RNA gelation in vitro. Analogous to protein aggregation disorders, our results suggest that the sequence-specific gelation of RNAs could be a contributing factor to neurological disease. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22386&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22386&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MJ_9W26CY2c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ankur Jain</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dynamic corticostriatal activity biases social bonding in monogamous female prairie voles</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/hPTRiHeqCYw/nature22381"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22381</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Adult pair bonding involves dramatic changes in the perception and valuation of another individual. One key change is that partners come to reliably activate the brain’s reward system, although the precise neural mechanisms by which partners become rewarding during sociosexual interactions leading to a bond remain unclear. Here we show, using a prairie vole (Microtus ochrogaster) model of social bonding, how a functional circuit from the medial prefrontal cortex to nucleus accumbens is dynamically modulated to enhance females’ affiliative behaviour towards a partner. Individual variation in the strength of this functional connectivity, particularly after the first mating encounter, predicts how quickly animals begin affiliative huddling with their partner. Rhythmically activating this circuit in a social context without mating biases later preference towards a partner, indicating that this circuit’s activity is not just correlated with how quickly animals become affiliative but causally accelerates it. These results provide the first dynamic view of corticostriatal activity during bond formation, revealing how social interactions can recruit brain reward systems to drive changes in affiliative behaviour. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22381&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22381&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/hPTRiHeqCYw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth A. Amadei</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genetic wiring maps of single-cell protein states reveal an off-switch for GPCR signalling</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/oLE73S3l1fY/nature22376"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22376</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 As key executers of biological functions, the activity and abundance of proteins are subjected to extensive regulation. Deciphering the genetic architecture underlying this regulation is critical for understanding cellular signalling events and responses to environmental cues. Using random mutagenesis in haploid human cells, we apply a sensitive approach to directly couple genomic mutations to protein measurements in individual cells. Here we use this to examine a suite of cellular processes, such as transcriptional induction, regulation of protein abundance and splicing, signalling cascades (mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK), G-protein-coupled receptor (GPCR), protein kinase B (AKT), interferon, and Wingless and Int-related protein (WNT) pathways) and epigenetic modifications (histone crotonylation and methylation). This scalable, sequencing-based procedure elucidates the genetic landscapes that control protein states, identifying genes that cause very narrow phenotypic effects and genes that lead to broad phenotypic consequences. The resulting genetic wiring map identifies the E3-ligase substrate adaptor KCTD5 (ref. 1) as a negative regulator of the AKT pathway, a key signalling cascade frequently deregulated in cancer. KCTD5-deficient cells show elevated levels of phospho-AKT at S473 that could not be attributed to effects on canonical pathway components. To reveal the genetic requirements for this phenotype, we iteratively analysed the regulatory network linked to AKT activity in the knockout background. This genetic modifier screen exposes suppressors of the KCTD5 phenotype and mechanistically demonstrates that KCTD5 acts as an off-switch for GPCR signalling by triggering proteolysis of Gβγ heterodimers dissociated from the Gα subunit. Although biological networks have previously been constructed on the basis of gene expression, protein–protein associations, or genetic interaction profiles, we foresee that the approach described here will enable the generation of a comprehensive genetic wiring map for human cells on the basis of quantitative protein states. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22376&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22376&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/oLE73S3l1fY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Markus Brockmann</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Deletion of a mycobacterial divisome factor collapses single-cell phenotypic heterogeneity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/T86AS1NKIEw/nature22361"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22361</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Microorganisms are often studied as populations but the behaviour of single, individual cells can have important consequences. For example, tuberculosis, caused by the bacterial pathogen Mycobacterium tuberculosis, requires months of antibiotic therapy even though the bulk of the bacterial population dies rapidly. Shorter courses lead to high rates of relapse because subpopulations of bacilli can survive despite being genetically identical to those that are easily killed. In fact, mycobacteria create variability each time a cell divides, producing daughter cells with different sizes and growth rates. The mechanism(s) that underlie this high-frequency variation and how variability relates to survival of the population are unknown. Here we show that mycobacteria actively create heterogeneity. Using a fluorescent reporter and a fluorescence-activated cell sorting (FACS)-based transposon screen, we find that deletion of lamA, a gene of previously unknown function, decreases heterogeneity in the population by decreasing asymmetric polar growth. LamA has no known homologues in other organisms, but is highly conserved across mycobacterial species. We find that LamA is a member of the mycobacterial division complex (the ‘divisome’). It inhibits growth at nascent new poles, creating asymmetry in polar growth. The kinetics of killing individual cells that lack lamA are more uniform and more rapid with rifampicin and drugs that target the cell wall. Our results show that mycobacteria encode a non-conserved protein that controls the pattern of cell growth, resulting in a population that is both heterogeneous and better able to survive antibiotic pressure. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22361&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22361&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/T86AS1NKIEw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>E. Hesper Rego</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The B-cell receptor controls fitness of MYC-driven lymphoma cells via GSK3β inhibition</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/W8OAhR863Fs/nature22353"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22353</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Similar to resting mature B cells, where the B-cell antigen receptor (BCR) controls cellular survival, surface BCR expression is conserved in most mature B-cell lymphomas. The identification of activating BCR mutations and the growth disadvantage upon BCR knockdown of cells of certain lymphoma entities has led to the view that BCR signalling is required for tumour cell survival. Consequently, the BCR signalling machinery has become an established target in the therapy of B-cell malignancies. Here we study the effects of BCR ablation on MYC-driven mouse B-cell lymphomas and compare them with observations in human Burkitt lymphoma. Whereas BCR ablation does not, per se, significantly affect lymphoma growth, BCR-negative (BCR−) tumour cells rapidly disappear in the presence of their BCR-expressing (BCR+) counterparts in vitro and in vivo. This requires neither cellular contact nor factors released by BCR+ tumour cells. Instead, BCR loss induces the rewiring of central carbon metabolism, increasing the sensitivity of receptor-less lymphoma cells to nutrient restriction. The BCR attenuates glycogen synthase kinase 3 beta (GSK3β) activity to support MYC-controlled gene expression. BCR− tumour cells exhibit increased GSK3β activity and are rescued from their competitive growth disadvantage by GSK3β inhibition. BCR− lymphoma variants that restore competitive fitness normalize GSK3β activity after constitutive activation of the MAPK pathway, commonly through Ras mutations. Similarly, in Burkitt lymphoma, activating RAS mutations may propagate immunoglobulin-crippled tumour cells, which usually represent a minority of the tumour bulk. Thus, while BCR expression enhances lymphoma cell fitness, BCR-targeted therapies may profit from combinations with drugs targeting BCR− tumour cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22353&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22353&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/W8OAhR863Fs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gabriele Varano</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Frequency dependence limits divergent evolution by favouring rare immigrants over residents</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5x41hG7XTZQ/nature22351"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22351</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Two distinct forms of natural selection promote adaptive biological diversity. Divergent selection occurs when different environments favour different phenotypes, leading to increased differences between populations. Negative frequency-dependent selection occurs when rare variants within a population are favoured over common ones, increasing diversity within populations. These two diversifying forces promote genetic variation at different spatial scales, and may act in opposition, but their relative effects remain unclear because they are rarely measured concurrently. Here we show that negative frequency-dependent selection within populations can favor rare immigrants over locally adapted residents. We reciprocally transplanted lake and stream ecotypes of threespine stickleback into lake and stream habitats, while manipulating the relative abundance of residents versus immigrants. We found negative frequency-dependence: survival was highest for the locally rare ecotype, rather than natives. Also, individuals with locally rare major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class IIb genotypes were infected by fewer parasites. This negative frequency-dependent selection will tend to favour rare immigrants over common residents, amplifying the effect of migration and undermining the efficacy of divergent natural selection to drive population differences. The only signal of divergent selection was a tendency for foreign fish to have higher parasite loads than residents, after controlling for MHC genotype rarity. Frequency-dependent ecological interactions have long been thought to promote speciation. Our results suggest a more nuanced view in which negative frequency dependence alters the fate of migrants to promote or constrain evolutionary divergence between populations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22351&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22351&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5x41hG7XTZQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel I. Bolnick</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Cryptosporidium PI(4)K inhibitor is a drug candidate for cryptosporidiosis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/brrHdhTUu9k/nature22337"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22337</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Diarrhoeal disease is responsible for 8.6% of global child mortality. Recent epidemiological studies found the protozoan parasite Cryptosporidium to be a leading cause of paediatric diarrhoea, with particularly grave impact on infants and immunocompromised individuals. There is neither a vaccine nor an effective treatment. Here we establish a drug discovery process built on scalable phenotypic assays and mouse models that take advantage of transgenic parasites. Screening a library of compounds with anti-parasitic activity, we identify pyrazolopyridines as inhibitors of Cryptosporidium parvum and Cryptosporidium hominis. Oral treatment with the pyrazolopyridine KDU731 results in a potent reduction in intestinal infection of immunocompromised mice. Treatment also leads to rapid resolution of diarrhoea and dehydration in neonatal calves, a clinical model of cryptosporidiosis that closely resembles human infection. Our results suggest that the Cryptosporidium lipid kinase PI(4)K (phosphatidylinositol-4-OH kinase) is a target for pyrazolopyridines and that KDU731 warrants further preclinical evaluation as a drug candidate for the treatment of cryptosporidiosis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22337&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22337&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/brrHdhTUu9k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ujjini H. Manjunatha</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How to choose</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pGSt2Km4jbA/546180a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546180a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Physics and maths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 180 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546180a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546180a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pGSt2Km4jbA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Haynes</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Biomedical research: Premature lambs grown in a bag</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ooHBAyLfUeE/546045a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546045a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A bag that mimics the environment of the womb can support lambs born extremely prematurely for four weeks. This development points to ways to improve the prospects of extremely premature babies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 45 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546045a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546045a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ooHBAyLfUeE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Claire T. Roberts</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Microbiology: Diversity breeds tolerance</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/J0x_s3HbBXc/546044a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546044a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A gene has been identified that underpins the capacity of mycobacterial cells to divide to produce physiologically different daughter cells. This finding has implications for drug treatment of tuberculosis.  See Letter    p.153&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 44 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546044a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546044a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/J0x_s3HbBXc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David G. Russell</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genomics: Sunflowers sequenced</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tZMuDq-f6xo/546043a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546043a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 43 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546043a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546043a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tZMuDq-f6xo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Orli G. Bahcall</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 &amp;amp; 100 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/R0HZkg7GkjY/546042a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546042a</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 42 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546042a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546042a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/R0HZkg7GkjY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature Biological Sciences Research</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ageing: Rejuvenation study stirs old memories</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/vYt-nvPHfEI/546033e"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546033e</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 33 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546033e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546033e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/vYt-nvPHfEI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthis Krischel</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Data management: Stable identifiers for collection specimens</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_s3YnQkwFXA/546033d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546033d</id>
		<updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 546 33 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/546033d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/546033d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_s3YnQkwFXA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quentin Groom</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Having an open-minded personality manifests at a basic level of visual perception</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/30/having-an-open-minded-personality-manifests-at-a-basic-level-of-visual-perception/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=24155</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T19:24:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rene Descartes' diagram of the human brain and eye, 1692.&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-24229&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;24229&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Print Collector\/Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Rene Descartes' diagram of the human brain and eye, 1692. From Opera Philosophica by Rene Descartes. (Frankfurt-am-Main, 1692). Originally published in his Tractatus de homine. (Paris, 1664). (Photo by Oxford Science Archive\/Print Collector\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Oxford Science Archive \/ Heritage Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Rene Descartes' diagram of the human brain and eye, 1692.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Rene Descartes’ diagram of the human brain and eye, 1692.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-463919043.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-463919043.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-463919043.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;4936,3539&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/30/having-an-open-minded-personality-manifests-at-a-basic-level-of-visual-perception/rene-descartes-diagram-of-the-human-brain-and-eye-1692/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/gettyimages-463919043.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openness to Experience is one of the so-called Big Five personality traits and, among other things, it’s associated with being more creative, curious and appreciative of the arts. Like all the traits, where you score has important implications – for instance, there’s recent evidence that being more Open is associated with having more “cognitive reserve”, which gives you protection from the harmful effects of dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Openness correlates with, but is distinct from, intelligence, and psychologists are trying to find out more about what the basis of Openness is at a cognitive and neural level. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092656617300338?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Research in Personality&lt;/em&gt; shows that the trait runs deep, even affecting a very basic aspect of visual perception. It seems Open people literally see the world differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-24155&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Antinori and her colleagues asked 134 undergrad students to perform a binocular rivalry task, which involves two different images being presented separately to each eye. The brain usually deals with this clash by alternately suppressing the images, which leads to the subjective experience of seeing one image then the other, back and forth. Occasionally, the perception of the two images can meld together and the researchers were interested in whether this experience correlates with the personality trait of Openness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what they found. They presented their participants with a red striped pattern to one eye and a green pattern to the other simultaneously for two minutes, and asked participants to press keyboard keys to indicate what they could see from one moment to the next, whether the red pattern, the green, or a mixture of the two. Those participants who scored higher on a questionnaire measure of Openness to Experience (they agreed with items like “I need a creative outlet”) experienced a “mixed percept” a greater amount of time than lower scorers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers don’t think this is a simple response bias – that is, having a lower threshold for saying when the image seemed mixed – because the personality link disappeared when they used larger stimuli that are known to increase the experience of a mixed percept (if there is a personality-related response bias, you’d expect it to occur again with the bigger stimuli). In a final experiment, the researchers showed that inducing positive mood, via an imagination task and music, increased the mixed percept experience especially for higher scorers in Openness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We provided the first evidence that individuals reporting greater openness to experience may also have characteristically different low-level visual perceptual experiences,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They think the same neural processes may underlie this visual effect and previous behavioural findings related to Openness, such as that it correlates with superior divergent thinking skills. The precise nature of these neural processes awaits further investigation, but for now a clue may come from the fact that the psychedelic compound psilocybin (found in magic mushrooms) also increases the experience of mixed percepts during binocular rivalry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092656617300338?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Seeing it both ways: Openness to experience and binocular rivalry suppression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Rene Descartes’ diagram of the human brain and eye, 1692. From Opera Philosophica by Rene Descartes. (Frankfurt-am-Main, 1692). Originally published in his Tractatus de homine. (Paris, 1664). (Photo by Oxford Science Archive/Print Collector/Getty Images).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24155/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/24155/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=24155&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The opioid epidemic spurs a search for new, safer painkillers</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/opioid-epidemic-spurs-search-new-safer-painkillers"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/opioid-epidemic-spurs-search-new-safer-painkillers</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Today’s opioids stop pain — but they’re also dangerous. Scientists are hunting for replacements.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Drug researcher up to ten retractions</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/30/drug-researcher-ten-retractions/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50121</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T16:25:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A pharmaceutical researcher has received his tenth retraction. The reason, once again: duplicating his previous work. Giuseppe Derosa, based at the University of Pavia in Italy, lost a 2011 paper this month after journal editors identified “substantial duplication of an earlier published paper.” According to the notice, the authors failed to cite the previous work and to disclose that the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/30/drug-researcher-ten-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Drug researcher up to ten retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sea scorpions slashed victims with swordlike tails</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-scorpions-slashed-victims-swordlike-tails"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-scorpions-slashed-victims-swordlike-tails</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient sea scorpion used a flexible, swordlike tail to hack at prey and defend against predators.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">BMJ journal yanks paper on cancer screening in India for fear of legal action</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/30/bmj-journal-yanks-paper-cancer-screening-india-fear-legal-action/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50318</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T13:51:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;BMJ Global Health has pulled a paper that criticized U.S. research of the effects of cervical cancer screening in India over defamation concerns. That’s not what the notice on the paper says, however — at the moment, it just reads: This article has been withdrawn. However, forwarded email correspondence between the first author and an associate […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/30/bmj-journal-yanks-paper-cancer-screening-india-fear-legal-action/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMJ journal yanks paper on cancer screening in India for fear of legal action&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Elsevier People: Playing matchmaker with research and industry</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-people-playing-matchmaker-with-research-and-industry"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-people-playing-matchmaker-with-research-and-industry</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T13:11:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 For a society to prosper, academia, government and industry need to work together; using the right tools can make the wheels turn more smoothly</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why you can hear and see meteors at the same time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-you-can-hear-and-see-meteors-same-time"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-you-can-hear-and-see-meteors-same-time</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T11:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 People can see and hear meteors simultaneously because of radio waves produced by the descending space rocks.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thomas Sumner</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Elsevier and European Commission collaborate to advance gender equality in science</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-and-european-commission-collaborate-to-advance-gender-equality-in-science"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-and-european-commission-collaborate-to-advance-gender-equality-in-science</id>
		<updated>2017-05-30T09:38:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Findings of report spark conversation about the story behind the data – and next steps</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Neuroanatomy of Gossips</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/05/29/the-neuroanatomy-of-gossips/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22672</id>
		<updated>2017-05-29T15:30:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;We talk a lot. We are the only species on the planet that exchange information predominantly through talking. Other species, such as dolphins or primates, have their own languages, but they do not rely on verbal communication to the same degree, almost to the exclusion of other communication channels, as we do. Verbal communication is a cornerstone of our society. So what are we talking about so much? According to scientific research, we talk mostly about other people. In fact, a whopping two-thirds of our conversations consist of gossips. Of course, we discuss other things such as work, politics, sports, and weather, but overwhelmingly we talk about other people’s affairs, often not in a very positive light. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scientific statistics on gossiping came as a surprise to me: what the intelligent, sensible and, as a rule, genuinely compassionate people around me would gain from spending so much time on gossips? I always believed that I almost never &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/01/02/the-purpose-of-rumors/&quot;&gt;gossip&lt;/a&gt;. But when I tried to recall the topics of recent conversations with my friends, I have to admit that discussing other people does indeed take the lion’s share of what we talk about. Gossiping might be just a reflection of curiosity that all humans possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, according to psychologists and evolutionary scientists, gossiping plays a key role in societal cohesion by spreading reputational information. The studies show that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individuals readily communicate reputational information about others, and recipients used this information to selectively interact with cooperative individuals and ostracize those who had behaved selfishly, which enabled group members to contribute to the public good with reduced threat of exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, gossips mitigate egoistic behavior and counteract possible incentives to exploit the cooperative tendencies of others. They also serve to protect vulnerable members of society. Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “gossip” tends to have a negative connotation. Cambridge Dictionary defines gossip as conversation or reports about other people’s private lives that might be unkind, disapproving, or not true. Typically, the information shared via gossips is not substantiated by hard evidence. Although gossips are indeed often negative (and we will see below why we find negative gossiping more engaging), we do often talk about positive aspects of other people’s behavior too. We simply don’t view this kind of information sharing as gossiping. Negative gossiping might require a degree of secrecy (i.e., the subjects of the gossips are not informed about the fact that they were discussed – we talk about them behind their back). Unsurprisingly, people do not like when they find that they are being gossiped about, and hence there is a moral stigma attached to the people who are gossiping too much. However, more often than not, the gossips are not entirely negative – they tend to be a mixture of both positive and negative things. We provide other people with our assessment of another person’s reputation as we see it, typically involving both the person’s strengths and weaknesses, and with only limited evidence to substantiate either. These assessments might still be viewed unfavorably by the subjects of gossips, even when the assessment is predominantly positive.  Nonetheless, we accept positive assessments with pleasure, but tend to be annoyed by criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being social creatures, we pay lots of attention to the opinion of others about us. Positive assessments by others are associated with higher social status, a larger number of friends and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2010/03/06/why-some-human-brains-become-leaders-while-others-followers/&quot;&gt;followers&lt;/a&gt;, and better chances of succeeding in any new venture and finding and attracting the best mating partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part of the brain responsible for our social behavior is the prefrontal cortex. The prefrontal cortex is involved in social cognition and executive control. Social cognition refers to our ability to regulate our behavior and actions based on the real or assumed presence of other people. This is a trait that makes some want to conform to the norms and rules of society in which we live. Executive control channels our actual behavior and thoughts in the desirable direction. Studies with the use of functional MRI brain scans revealed the patterns of activation in the prefrontal cortex in response to positive and negative gossip about themselves, their best friends, and celebrities. A very interesting and revealing picture has emerged from these studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two separate areas of the prefrontal cortex get activated in response to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/04/25/how-does-the-brain-respond-to-gossip/&quot;&gt;positive and negative gossip&lt;/a&gt;: positive gossip activates the orbital prefrontal cortex region, while negative gossip activates the superior medial prefrontal cortex. The intensity of responses was, however, very different depending on whether the gossip was about the subject of study or other people. Substantial activation of the superior medial prefrontal cortex was observed in both cases, regardless of the subject of the negative gossip. The orbital prefrontal cortex region was highly activated by positive gossip about the subjects themselves. However, this response was rather muted when the subjects listened to positive gossip about their friends or celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study revealed volumes about the internal processes in our brain. It is quite clear that our ego makes us very attentive to any kind of information about ourselves passed around by other people. However, when it comes to information about others, we are biased to notice and register negative information preferentially. No wonder that the stories of scandals involving celebrities attract more attention than anything good these people do! Our own neuroanatomy makes celebrity magazines filled with the stories of scandals, cheating, and divorces, much more popular that magazines about happy family life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baumeister, R., Zhang, L., &amp;amp; Vohs, K. (2004). Gossip as cultural learning.(2), 111-121 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/1089-2680.8.2.111&quot;&gt;10.1037/1089-2680.8.2.111&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bosson, J. et al. (2006). Interpersonal chemistry through negativity: Bonding by sharing negative attitudes about others Personal Relationships, 13 (2), 135-150 DOI:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1475-6811.2006.00109.x&quot;&gt;10.1111/j.1475-6811.2006.00109.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunbar, R. (2004). Gossip in evolutionary perspective. Review of General Psychology, 8 (2), 100-110 DOI:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/1089-2680.8.2.100&quot;&gt;10.1037/1089-2680.8.2.100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feinberg, M., Willer, R., &amp;amp; Schultz, M. (2014). Gossip and Ostracism Promote Cooperation in Groups Psychological Science, 25 (3), 656-664 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0956797613510184&quot;&gt;10.1177/0956797613510184&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feinberg, M., Willer, R., Stellar, J., &amp;amp; Keltner, D. (2012). The virtues of gossip: Reputational information sharing as prosocial behavior. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 102 (5), 1015-1030 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0026650&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0026650&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martinescu, E., Janssen, O., &amp;amp; Nijstad, B. (2014). Tell Me the Gossip: The Self-Evaluative Function of Receiving Gossip About Others Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 40 (12), 1668-1680 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0146167214554916&quot;&gt;10.1177/0146167214554916&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peng X, Li Y, Wang P, Mo L, &amp;amp; Chen Q (2015). The ugly truth: negative gossip about celebrities and positive gossip about self entertain people in different ways. Social neuroscience, 10 (3), 320-36 PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25580932&quot;&gt;25580932&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Baruska-448271/&quot;&gt;Baruska&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-05-29T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">It’s not just whistleblowers who deserve protection during misconduct investigations, say researchers</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/29/not-just-whistleblowers-deserve-protection-misconduct-investigations-say-researchers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50323</id>
		<updated>2017-05-29T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;In 2010, the former PhD supervisor of Sven Hendrix, a neuroanatomist at Hasselt University in Belgium, was accused of misconduct. Although the allegations were eventually dropped, the experience was emotionally and professionally draining – and Hendrix wanted the research community to know about it. In 2015, he shared his story at a conference in Rotterdam; […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/29/not-just-whistleblowers-deserve-protection-misconduct-investigations-say-researchers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;It’s not just whistleblowers who deserve protection during misconduct investigations, say researchers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Citizen scientists join the search for Planet 9</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/citizen-scientists-join-search-planet-9"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/citizen-scientists-join-search-planet-9</id>
		<updated>2017-05-29T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Backyard Worlds: Planet 9, a citizen science project, lets space enthusiasts search for undiscovered objects in the sky, including a hypothesized planet at the far reaches of the solar system.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure of the human multidrug transporter ABCG2</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/TPhCaI72Bq4/nature22345"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22345</id>
		<updated>2017-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 ABCG2 is a constitutively expressed ATP-binding cassette (ABC) transporter that protects many tissues against xenobiotic molecules. Its activity affects the pharmacokinetics of commonly used drugs and limits the delivery of therapeutics into tumour cells, thus contributing to multidrug resistance. Here we present the structure of human ABCG2 determined by cryo-electron microscopy, providing the first high-resolution insight into a human multidrug transporter. We visualize ABCG2 in complex with two antigen-binding fragments of the human-specific, inhibitory antibody 5D3 that recognizes extracellular loops of the transporter. We observe two cholesterol molecules bound in the multidrug-binding pocket that is located in a central, hydrophobic, inward-facing translocation pathway between the transmembrane domains. Combined with functional in vitro analyses, our results suggest a multidrug recognition and transport mechanism of ABCG2, rationalize disease-causing single nucleotide polymorphisms and the allosteric inhibition by the 5D3 antibody, and provide the structural basis of cholesterol recognition by other G-subfamily ABC transporters. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22345&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22345&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/TPhCaI72Bq4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nicholas M. I. Taylor</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T05:00:27+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Unattractive People Are Seen As Better Scientists</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8829"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8829</id>
		<updated>2017-05-28T13:36:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Good looking, sociable people don't make good scientists, according to popular stereotypes.

This is one of the findings of an interesting new study of how scientists are perceived, from British researchers Ana I. Gheorghiu and colleagues.


Gheorghiu et al. took 616 pictures of scientists, which they downloaded from the faculty pages at various universities. They gave the portraits to two sets of raters. The first group were asked to rate the attractiveness of the portraits and to say whet</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-05-28T17:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: The editor who’s a dog; the fake author; a monument to peer review</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/27/weekend-reads-editor-whos-dog-fake-author-monument-peer-review/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50332</id>
		<updated>2017-05-27T13:30:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of a much-discussed paper on using blockchain to prevent scientific misconduct, and a researcher who lost nine studies at once from a single journal. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Ollie’s on the editorial board of seven journals, maybe because she always obeys a “sit” command. She’s a dog, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/27/weekend-reads-editor-whos-dog-fake-author-monument-peer-review/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: The editor who’s a dog; the fake author; a monument to peer review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-02T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Trump’s proposed 2018 budget takes an ax to science research funding</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/trump-proposed-budget-science-research-funding"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/trump-proposed-budget-science-research-funding</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T21:26:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Administration would cut total federal research spending by about 17 percent, according to a preliminary estimate.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-06-03T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“There is an injustice in this article”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/there-is-an-injustice-in-this-article/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50255</id>
		<updated>2017-05-26T17:30:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The editors of a plant biology journal have retracted a 2007 paper because of “an injustice.” According to the notice, the editors of Cytologia found evidence of “apparent figure manipulation,” and decided to retract the paper. This marks the 10th retraction for plant biologist Dibyendu Talukdar. Talukdar, who is first and corresponding author on the 2007 paper and listed at the University of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/05/26/there-is-an-injustice-in-this-article/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“There is an injustice in this article”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-06-01T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
