<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-07-31T05:01:08+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">#ElsevierHacks: Two days to change the face of medical education</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hackathon-two-days-to-change-the-face-of-medical-education"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hackathon-two-days-to-change-the-face-of-medical-education</id>
		<updated>2017-07-29T19:27:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Channelling the creativity of 60 young minds, the hackathon will take on challenges facing the world’s medical students</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Are Underpowered Studies Ever Justified?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9007"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9007</id>
		<updated>2017-07-29T19:03:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Is a small scientific study better than none at all? A provocative piece in Frontiers in Psychology raises the question of whether we should ever do under-powered studies. The authors are Dutch researchers Rik Crutzen and Gjalt-Jorn Y. Peters.





Crutzen and Peters begin by questioning the idea that even a little evidence is always valuable. Taking the example of a study that only manages to recruit a handful of patients because it's studying a rare disease, the authors say that:
Underp</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T23:00:23+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Subscription journals doomed?; Are scientists most often wrong?; “Buxom grapefruits”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/29/weekend-reads-subscription-journals-doomed-scientists-often-wrong-buxom-grapefruits/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51239</id>
		<updated>2017-07-29T13:30:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured an update on a Harvard lab whose PI is subject to a restraining order by one of his grad students, and the retraction of a paper that used male-only pronouns. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Sci-Hub’s cache of pirated papers is so big, subscription journals are doomed,” suggests Daniel […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/29/weekend-reads-subscription-journals-doomed-scientists-often-wrong-buxom-grapefruits/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Subscription journals doomed?; Are scientists most often wrong?; “Buxom grapefruits”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Three Kinds of Human Smiles</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8998"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8998</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T19:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 There are three basic types of human smile: &quot;reward&quot;, &quot;affiliative&quot; and &quot;dominance&quot; smiles. That's according to a new paper by psychologists Magdalena Rychlowska and colleagues.



Here's the authors' illustration of the types, as posed by actors:

Reward smiles, the authors say, are used to signal enjoyment:
Reward smiles are displayed to reward the self or other people and to communicate positive experiences or intentions... the reward smile may have evolved from the play face of primat</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T23:00:23+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Potential ingredient for alien life found on Titan</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/potential-ingredient-alien-life-found-titan"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/potential-ingredient-alien-life-found-titan</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T18:32:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The atmosphere and oceans of Saturn’s moon Titan contain vinyl cyanide, a compound predicted to form cell-like bubbles.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Does doom and gloom convince anyone about climate change?</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/new-york-magazine-climate-change"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/new-york-magazine-climate-change</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T17:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New York magazine spurred conversation with a recent article on climate change. Will its apocalyptic approach have an impact?</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erika Engelhaupt</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Do We Sense Each Other’s Sickness?</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/28/do-we-sense-each-others-sickness/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22697</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T15:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Social behavior is important for our survival as a species. But social interaction also gives pathogens a chance to spread, and it thereby increases our exposure to infection. Our immune system is a complex defense system that has evolved to protect us from infections. Therefore, it makes sense to assume that our immune system must have developed ingenious strategies to protect us from new pathogens to which social interaction has exposed us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Evidence of a link between the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/24/can-our-immune-system-drive-our-social-behavior/&quot;&gt;immune system and our social behavior&lt;/a&gt; has been accumulating in the last years. A direct connection between the brain and the immune system, through lymphatic vessels in the meninges, was recently revealed. Then it was shown that the immune system can directly affect, and even control social behavior and the desire for social interaction – an impaired immunity was shown to induce deficits in social behavior. This sounds like a clever preventive self-defense mechanism designed to avoid contagion – in times of poor immunity, our brain gets the message to reduce social interaction and, consequently, exposure to pathogens.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;This is a self-defense mechanism that is activated when our body signals a poor immunological status; it’s an internal chemical communication system. But is there an external threat signaling system? The ability to detect and avoid infected individuals would clearly be a great evolutionary asset in strengthening our protection mechanisms. Many animals can detect sickness via odors, leading to a restraint in social interaction, most likely intended to reduce exposure to disease. Do humans have a similar sensory sickness detection system, something that allows us to detect infectious threat in others?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;To answer this question, a new study aimed at determining whether humans can detect sickness in others from visual and olfactory cues. Sickness was experimentally induced through the injection of lipopolysaccharide (LPS), a molecule found in the membrane of Gram-negative bacteria that provokes robust immune responses. The activation of immune responses leads to an increase in the production of pro-inflammatory molecules that activate sickness responses and behaviors. It is known that visual cues of sickness, such as redness of the skin, allow us to infer the health of others. But although LPS induces a strong sickness response, its observable effects are subtle, and odor cues are difficult to perceive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Photos of the face and samples of body odors of both sick and healthy individuals were presented to a group of naïve participants while their cerebral responses were recorded using fMRI. These participants were not aware that they would be seeing and smelling sick and healthy people. They were asked to focus on the faces while the odors were also presented and rate how much they liked the person. Faces were also rated on attractiveness, health, and desired social interaction, and odors were rated on intensity, pleasantness and health. This allowed the assessment of the “liking behavior” towards the faces, an indication of the will to approach and interact with others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The rating of sick and healthy faces showed that photos obtained during acute sickness were generally considered less attractive, less healthy, and less socially desirable than the faces of participants receiving the placebo treatment. When faces were presented concomitantly with an odor, there was a lower liking of sick than of healthy faces, regardless of the odor presented with the face. Although participants were not able to perceive sickness in the odors, nor did they rate sick odors as more unpleasant or more intense than healthy odors, faces, regardless of being sick or healthy, were also less liked when paired with sick body odor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;These results show that we can detect early and subtle signs of sickness in others from both facial and olfactory cues, even just a couple of hours after activation of their immune system. Moreover, fMRI data revealed that visual and olfactory sickness cues activated their respective visual face processing and olfactory sensory cortices,  as well as multisensory convergence zones. And even though odors were often too weak to be consciously detected, these olfactory sickness cues still led to activation of the olfactory cortex. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;The study also revealed that this perception of subtle cues of sickness leads to reduced liking and decreased will for social interaction. This response may represent a human behavioral defense system against disease. The integration of olfactory and visual sickness cues in the brain may be part of a mechanism designed to detect sickness, resulting in behavioral avoidance of sick individuals, and in avoidance of impending threats of infection.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Filiano AJ, et al (2016). Unexpected role of interferon-? in regulating neuronal connectivity and social behaviour. Nature, 535(7612):425-9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v535/n7612/full/nature18626.html?foxtrotcallback=true&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature18626&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Kipnis J (2016). Multifaceted interactions between adaptive immunity and the central nervous system. Science, 353(6301):766-71. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/353/6301/766&quot;&gt;10.1126/science.aag2638&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Louveau A, et al (2015). Structural and functional features of central nervous system lymphatic vessels. Nature, 523(7560):337-41. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v523/n7560/full/nature14432.html&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature14432&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Regenbogen C, et al (2017). Behavioral and neural correlates to multisensory detection of sick humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A, pii: 201617357. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/114/24/6400&quot;&gt;10.1073/pnas.1617357114&lt;/a&gt;. [Epub ahead of print]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Shattuck EC, Muehlenbein MP (2015). Human sickness behavior: Ultimate and proximate explanations.Am J Phys Anthropol, 157(1):1-18. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ajpa.22698/abstract&quot;&gt;10.1002/ajpa.22698&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/junko-214956/&quot;&gt;junko&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sara Adaes, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Toronto wife-husband research team lose bid to re-open labs</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/28/toronto-wife-husband-research-team-lose-bid-re-open-labs/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51235</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T14:30:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A pair of Canadian scientists may be running out of options to save their laboratories, which have been permanently closed based on findings of research misconduct. Sylvia Asa, once the head of the largest hospital diagnostic laboratory in Canada, and her husband and collaborator Shereen Ezzat, have spent almost five years fighting allegations of research misconduct […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/28/toronto-wife-husband-research-team-lose-bid-re-open-labs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Toronto wife-husband research team lose bid to re-open labs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Newborn baby’s infection offers a cautionary tale about placenta pills</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/oregon-newborn-infection-placenta-pills"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/oregon-newborn-infection-placenta-pills</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T13:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newborn came down with a dangerous bacterial infection. The culprit, scientists suspect, was contaminated placenta pills eaten by the mother.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal retracts paper it says authors published twice. Authors disagree.</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/28/authors-object-journals-decision-retract-paper-duplication/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51199</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T12:27:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A journal has retracted a 2012 paper after determining that the authors had already published it elsewhere. According to the retraction notice, the editors-in-chief of the Journal of Occupational Medicine and Toxicology concluded that the article had  been published in another journal—In Vitro Cellular &amp;amp; Developmental Biology – Animal—the previous month. The authors, however, did not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/28/authors-object-journals-decision-retract-paper-duplication/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal retracts paper it says authors published twice. Authors disagree.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Astronomers may have found an exomoon, and Hubble is going to check</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/potential-first-exomoon-hubble"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/potential-first-exomoon-hubble</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T10:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A distant object may be the first exomoon detected.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">We adjust the pitch of our voice based on the status of who we’re talking to</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/28/we-adjust-the-pitch-of-our-voice-based-on-the-status-of-who-were-talking-to/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27550</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T08:36:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-493076370.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27567&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27567&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A hand drawn vector doodle illustration of a job seeker being interviewed by the employer.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;lemonadeserenade&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Job Interview&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Job Interview&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-493076370.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-493076370.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-493076370.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2106,1424&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/28/we-adjust-the-pitch-of-our-voice-based-on-the-status-of-who-were-talking-to/job-interview-3/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-493076370.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lexie_Thorpe&quot;&gt;Lexie Thorpe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In most human societies those with a higher social status enjoy privileges beyond the reach of others. Such status can be obtained through dominance, using intimidation or force, or acquiring prestige by demonstrating knowledge and skill. To make best use of the benefits though, other people need to know that you are top dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you’re of a lower status, there are probably times when it pays to avoid challenging those higher up the pecking order. In which case, you might want to convey your recognition of their authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using body language, such as by taking up more space (adopting “power poses”) may be one of the most obvious, visible modes of asserting ourselves. But of course speech also conveys status, not only in its content, but in the characteristics of the voice itself. Indeed, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0179407&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;PLOS One&lt;/i&gt; we adjust the pitch of our voice depending on who we are talking to. The research group at the University of Stirling found that the direction of this unconscious vocal tuning depends on the speaker’s perception of their social status relative to the listener.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27550&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juan David Leongómez and his colleagues recorded students as they took part in simulated interviews for a job as an admin assistant with three different male employers (the order of the interviews was varied between participants). A picture and description of each employer showed one to be highly dominant (Chief of Security at a prison, described as tough and intimidating), another highly prestigious (Head of Department at a Business School, described as well-respected and competent), and a third was neutral (from the HR department at a secondary school, described as your average boss).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants had to introduce themselves to the employer, and explain why they were suited to the job. They were also asked about how they would approach their boss if they had a disagreement with a colleague. After all the interviews, the participants filled out a questionnaire about their own and the employers’ dominance and prestige.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the recordings, the researchers calculated the “fundamental frequency” of the participants’ voices (an objective measure of pitch) and tracked variations in their voice pitch as they spoke. A low fundamental frequency would equate to sounding calm and in control, and has been found to be perceived as more dominant in both male and female voices, although the natural sex difference in absolute pitch was accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking to the highly dominant and prestigious employers, both male and female students who also perceived themselves as more dominant lowered their voice pitch, whilst students who perceived themselves to be less dominant did the opposite. These changes in pitch were most noticeable when the students explained why they were the best candidate and talked about how they would resolve the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings add to past research showing that lower voice pitch conveys traits related to social status, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/277/1699/3509&quot;&gt;physical strength&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/evan.20166/abstract%253Bjsessionid=7B1CDF1E0D76686151076240323D21EA.f03t03&quot;&gt;attractiveness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed that the students’ perception of their own status led them to use different vocal strategies in the interviews with the high-status employers. The students with higher self-perceived dominance may have felt more confident and in control of the situation, and thus more able to compete for the job. Conversely, for those who rated themselves less dominant, and may have felt more intimidated, appearing deferent to the employer may have been a beneficial strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the employers were actually computerised faces created to appear prestigious, dominant or neither, so it’s not clear how these findings would relate to a prestigious employer in real-life, or to a less formal social setting. Mock job interviews have been shown to increase anxiety, and recording the participants’ speech is likely to have increased their stress further, making voice alterations more or less pronounced than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real-life implications of the effect are also not known, as the study did not address which group were more likely to be successful in the interview. Whilst being intimidated might not come across well, it’s probably not a good idea to compete with your boss either. CEOs with lower-pitched voices tend to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ehbonline.org/article/S1090-5138(13)00023-8/fulltext&quot;&gt;manage larger companies and make more money&lt;/a&gt;, but then again, surgeons whose voices were perceived to be higher in dominance, and possibly arrogance, were more likely to have been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surgjournal.com/article/S0039-6060(02)00022-3/fulltext&quot;&gt;sued for malpractice&lt;/a&gt;.  Suffice then to say that, when asserting status, context – and subtlety – is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0179407&quot;&gt;Perceived differences in social status between speaker and listener affect the speaker’s vocal characteristics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;IMG_2496&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-27570 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27570&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;IMG_2496&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/img_2496.jpg?w=640&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/img_2496.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/img_2496.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;640,640&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/28/we-adjust-the-pitch-of-our-voice-based-on-the-status-of-who-were-talking-to/img_2496/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/img_2496.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by Lexie Thorpe (&lt;span class=&quot;username u-dir&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ProfileHeaderCard-screennameLink u-linkComplex js-nav&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lexie_Thorpe&quot;&gt;@Lexie_Thorpe&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://digest.bps.org.uk&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Lexie is currently an Assistant Psychologist and freelance science writer. She writes about psychology, psychiatry and neuroscience and occasionally blogs at &lt;a class=&quot;m_7827447291529585405yiv8591497444edited-link-editor&quot; href=&quot;https://cognitales.wordpress.com/&quot; id=&quot;m_7827447291529585405yiv8591497444yui_3_16_0_ym19_1_1501152347442_3643&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cognitales&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27550/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27550/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27550&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Protecting the next generation from Hepatitis B</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/28/protecting-the-next-generation-from-hepatitis-b/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9322</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T08:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/5800280179_79e5efb43d_o-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hepatitis B – What it is and why it matters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1365-2893.2003.00487.x/full&quot;&gt;2 billion individuals&lt;/a&gt; have been infected by Hepatitis B virus (HBV) at some point during their lifetime. Within the first 6 months after an individual is first infected with HBV, they experience a short term (acute) illness. In some cases of acute infection, the HBV remains in an individual’s body causing them to be chronically infected with Hepatitis B. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hepatitis/publications/global-hepatitis-report2017/en/&quot;&gt;2015 WHO report on Hepatitis&lt;/a&gt; estimated 257 million people (3.5% of the global population) were living with a chronic HBV infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since HBV primarily attacks the liver, chronic HBV infection can imply significant long term health problems including liver damage, failure or even death. Untreated chronic infection can lead to life threatening long term complications such as chronic hepatitis, cirrhosis and hepatocellular carcinoma (a form of liver cancer). HBV is the 10th leading cause of death globally and results in &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1365-2893.2003.00487.x/full&quot;&gt;500,000 to 700,000 deaths annually&lt;/a&gt;. Although relatively rare in the West, in regions where HBV remains endemic like Asia, the Western Pacific region and Africa, chronic HBV infection is common and individuals are often first exposed to the virus as infants or children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B can be spread through bodily fluids such as blood, semen etc. from an infected individual. The most common routes are sexual contact, sharing items (needles, razors, toothbrushes) with an infected person, exposure to infected blood or perinatal transmission (from a mother to child around the time of birth or during breastfeeding). The latter is the main route of transmission in areas where Hepatitis B is endemic like Asia, the Western Pacific and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The challenge and importance of preventing HBV transmission to infants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The younger an individual is when they contract acute HBV, the higher the likelihood that they will develop the chronic form. This is visualized in the graph below which reflects the percentage of individuals who become chronic HBV carriers in relation to the age at which they were acutely infected. For example approximately 90% of infants who are infected around the time of birth become chronic carriers , in contrast less than 5% of individuals acutely infected as adults are chronic carriers of the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9323&quot; style=&quot;width: 519px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9323&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/age-risk-HBV-e1501072076560.png&quot; width=&quot;509&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Data from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hepatitis/publications/global-hepatitis-report2017/en/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WHO Global Hepatitis report 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To minimize the risk of infants being acutely infected, babies born to HBV-positive women are regularly given vaccines and other immunoprophylaxis after birth. However 5-10% of vaccinated infants still contract the acute form of the virus. This indicates additional intervention is required to effectively reduce or eliminate transmission to infants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infants are an especially critical target population in reducing the prevalence of Hepatitis B, especially since infection rates are still relatively high, and early exposure leads to a higher risk of the disease becoming a chronic life-long disease. For example, long term follow up of individuals infected as infants or young children showed that 15-25% of those chronically infected die prematurely due to cirrhosis or &lt;a href=&quot;http://jgo.amegroups.com/article/view/12998/10854&quot;&gt;hepatocellular carcinoma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0163445312003891?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;High HBV activity in the mother correlates with the infant’s risk of contracting the condition&lt;/a&gt;, even if the infant has been immunized after birth. Therefore an antiviral therapy which reduces the HBV activity in the mother may be able to prevent the infant from contracting the disease. There are six globally licensed treatments for adults affected by chronic HBV, but none are currently regularly used in pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An antiviral drug &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telbivudine&quot;&gt;telbivudine&lt;/a&gt; is an attractive candidate for preventing mother to child transmission of HBV. It has been classified as pregnancy category B, which implies that no risk has been shown in other studies, but risk has not been definitively excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1542356512001553&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0168827811002832?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;) have reported that administration of the antiviral telbivudine in the second and third trimesters was highly safe and effective in blocking mother to infant transmission . However, further extensive studies are required to ensure safety and efficacy before it can be considered for regular use during pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The issue of establishing drug safety in pregnancy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9327&quot; style=&quot;width: 309px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-9327&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/15514557255_56036a1775_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Flickr, cc Jerry Lai&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is critical that any treatment given for a maternal medical condition, such as HBV, does not disrupt the baby’s normal process of development or cause significant negative side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was clearly illustrated by thalidomide, a drug taken by expecting mothers to combat morning sickness. When &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/bdrc.21096/full&quot;&gt;thalidomide&lt;/a&gt; was first introduced as an over the counter drug in 1957, scientists did not believe drugs could cross the placenta and harm the fetus. Unfortunately, this was not the case and it is estimated that over 10,000 children in 46 countries were born with developmental abnormalities (classically of the limbs called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phocomelia&quot;&gt;phocomelia&lt;/a&gt;)  as a result of thalidomide exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although finally taken off the market in 1961, the detrimental effects of thalidomide were long reaching and prompted the implementation of more rigorous rules for the testing and licensing of drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, tolerability of a drug by the growing fetus may depend on its stage of development- certain drugs may therefore be potentially safe to take in late pregnancy but not during the first trimester when the fetus is very vulnerable to environmental insults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of HBV treatment during pregnancy, one of the questions which remains unanswered is whether there is a difference in efficacy if antivirals are given to pregnant women during early pregnancy, and additionally whether this can be tolerated by a more vulnerable, less developed fetus. To begin to answer this, Dr. Sun and colleagues recently conducted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-017-0608-7&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; to evaluate the efficacy and safety of telbivudine if commenced in early or middle pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiviral HBV treatment during early and mid-pregnancy &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Sun and colleagues compared markers of HBV infection and activity in three different experimental groups. One group of women began the antiviral treatment in early pregnancy (12 weeks), another in middle pregnancy (20-28 weeks) while the third group acted as a control and received no drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per standard care, all infants in all groups received standard vaccinations and preventative treatment after birth. At 28 weeks following birth, infants were tested to check for the presence of HBV DNA or HBV antibodies, which indicates maternal to child transmission of the disease had occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the study were clear cut- none of the infants born to mothers who were receiving the antiviral treatment showed biological markers of the disease. In contrast, in the group that did not receive the antiviral during pregnancy, ~18% of infants had markers of HBV activity 28 weeks after their birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to previous studies, these results suggest that treating mothers during to pregnancy with the antiviral telbivudine together with infant vaccination at birth appears more effective than infant vaccination alone. Additionally, it suggests antiviral administration may be equally effective if begun in early versus middle pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking to the future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9328&quot; style=&quot;width: 331px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9328&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/11522188665_5145d29be7_o.jpg&quot; width=&quot;321&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Flickr, cc Jens Bergander&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the work by Sun and colleagues showed promising results, it also raises a number of other important questions which would need to be resolved before the antiviral can be used outside of controlled clinical trials. For example, the optimal timing and dosage are still to be determined, as well as how late in pregnancy the antiviral can be given and still successfully prevent transmission. Additionally, while no ill effects were observed in the infants whose mothers received telbivudine during pregnancy, it is important to note that potential negative effects have not been ruled out and more extensive studies with long term follow up are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study provides a critical stepping stone towards the development, implementation and safety of programs which could drastically reduce the perinatal transmission of HBV- and provide infants a healthy start to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in reading more on this topic, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Gastroenterology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or the papers below can provide more in-depth information on topics discussed in this blog:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12916-017-0820-x&quot;&gt;Elimination of Hepatitis B: Is It a Mission Possible?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Hepatitis B during pregnancy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2393-13-222&quot;&gt;Management of hepatitis B in pregnant women and infants: a multicentre audit from four London hospitals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12884-016-0884-1&quot;&gt;Maternal hepatitis B virus carrier status and pregnancy outcomes: a prospective cohort study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2393-13-119&quot;&gt;Effect of elective cesarean section on the risk of mother-to-child transmission of hepatitis B virus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Immunization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpediatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12887-014-0307-2&quot;&gt;Immunization interventions to interrupt hepatitis B virus mother-to-child transmission: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2334-14-7&quot;&gt;Efficacy and effectiveness of infant vaccination against chronic hepatitis B in the Gambia Hepatitis Intervention Study (1986–90) and in the nationwide immunisation program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Telbivudine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-017-0582-0&quot;&gt;Comparison of telbivudine and entecavir on the change of off- treatment eGFR after 3 years of treatment in non-cirrhotic chronic hepatitis B patients&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-017-0572-2&quot;&gt;Telbivudine versus entecavir in patients with undetectable hepatitis B virus DNA: a randomized trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/28/protecting-the-next-generation-from-hepatitis-b/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Protecting the next generation from Hepatitis B&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amelia Gunnarsson</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why astronomers reluctantly announced a possible exomoon discovery</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Oq5xWIzE1Rg/nature.2017.22377"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22377</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;After hints leaked out on Twitter, researchers made last-minute decision to reveal what might be the first discovery of a satellite outside our Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22377&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22377&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Oq5xWIzE1Rg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Davide Castelvecchi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Clues emerge in mystery of flickering quasars</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0KrOgmR4vbY/nature.2017.22376"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22376</id>
		<updated>2017-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Some of the Universe's most luminous objects have disappeared much faster than expected&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22376&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22376&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0KrOgmR4vbY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shannon Hall</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Harvard lab head, the grad student, and the restraining order: An ongoing saga</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/harvard-lab-head-grad-student-restraining-order-ongoing-saga/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51222</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T20:26:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Regular Retraction Watch readers may recall a remarkable story from January involving Harvard’s Lee Rubin and one of his graduate students. As we reported in Science at the time, the graduate student, Gustavo German, said he had been subjected to a forced psychiatric evaluation as “an act of revenge by Rubin, retaliation prompted by German’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/harvard-lab-head-grad-student-restraining-order-ongoing-saga/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Harvard lab head, the grad student, and the restraining order: An ongoing saga&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Tardigrades aren’t champion gene swappers after all</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tardigrades-arent-champion-gene-swappers-after-all"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tardigrades-arent-champion-gene-swappers-after-all</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T18:06:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Genetic studies reveal more secrets of the bizarre creatures known as tardigrades.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Slug slime inspires a new type of surgical glue</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/slug-slime-inspires-new-type-surgical-glue"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/slug-slime-inspires-new-type-surgical-glue</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new glue that mimics a slug’s mucus secretions sticks well, even when wet. The adhesive could be used in place of sutures or staples in surgeries.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The thinnest films of copper look flat, but they aren’t</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/thinnest-films-copper-look-flat-they-arent"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/thinnest-films-copper-look-flat-they-arent</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 It turns out that thin films of copper don’t lay flat, a discovery that has implications for computers and handheld electronics.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Why did it take a journal two years to retract a paper after a misconduct finding?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/take-journal-two-years-retract-paper-misconduct-finding/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51208</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T16:55:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A 2014 paper containing data manipulated by a former graduate student has finally been retracted, two years after the U.S. Office of Research Integrity (ORI) published its findings. In August 2015, the ORI published a report that Peter Littlefield, who was working on his PhD at the University of California, San Francisco (UCSF), had committed […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/take-journal-two-years-retract-paper-misconduct-finding/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Why did it take a journal two years to retract a paper after a misconduct finding?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ancient DNA offers clues to the Canaanites’ fate</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-dna-offers-clues-canaanites-fate"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-dna-offers-clues-canaanites-fate</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T16:31:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 DNA is painting a more detailed portrait of the ancient Canaanites, who have largely been studied through the secondhand accounts of their contemporaries.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Looking to avoid a bad lab? A new site wants to help</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/looking-good-lab-new-site-wants-help/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51193</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard horror stories of lab disputes that can quickly spin out of control. (Such as a graduate student obtaining a restraining order against his supervisor, which we covered earlier this year for Science.) Naturally, prospective students want to do their homework before committing to a particular laboratory or supervisor. A new website, QCist, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/27/looking-good-lab-new-site-wants-help/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Looking to avoid a bad lab? A new site wants to help&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Diet segregation in American bison of Yellowstone National Park</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/27/diet-segregation-american-bison-yellowstone-national-park/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9315</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T11:07:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Bison-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mammals, sexes often differ in adult body size, with adult males being substantially larger than their female counterparts. This variation in body size can lead to significant differences in nutritional requirements, a phenomenon commonly referred to as diet segregation. Females, due to their smaller size and shorter digestive tract, tend to process food more rapidly than males do, and as a result, require higher quality food. Because of their larger size, males are more efficient at converting low-quality food into usable energy, and thus, are more concerned with quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differences in nutritional demands between sexes can lead to different habitat requirements, particularly among large mammalian herbivores. One such example is the American bison (&lt;em&gt;Bison bison&lt;/em&gt;), which once roamed freely over much of North America. Although American bison primarily eat grass, they also consume minor amounts of herbs, shrubs, and twigs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In American bison, the sexes vary greatly in size, with the average male weighing 350 kg more than the average female. During the late-summer mating season, male and female bison form large herds, and remain in these groups for approximately one month. Throughout the rest of the year, females and calves remain in groups, while males typically spend this time roaming the landscape as individuals. If segregation behavior in bison is influenced by sex-specific nutritional demands, then differences in the diets of males and females should be more apparent during certain times of year than others (e.g., mating season vs. the rest of the year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yellowstone National Park (YNP), which lies in the northwest corner of Wyoming U.S.A., is a forested mountain ecosystem with grasslands, wetland meadows, and geothermal areas. Yellowstone is the only place in the United States where bison have lived continuously since prehistoric times, and they are one of seven species of native ungulate resident to the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9318&quot; style=&quot;width: 1156px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9318&quot; height=&quot;860&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Bison-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1146&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;A herd of bison at Yellowstone&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;John Berini&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Yellowstone, the bison population consists of two geographically distinct subpopulations that reside in the Northern and Central ranges. These ranges differ in bedrock geology, soil type, topography, geothermal activity, and winter severity. In addition, both elk and bison are more abundant on the Northern Range than on the Central Range. These differences likely influence the composition and quality of bison diets in each range. If segregation of bison in YNP is influenced by sex-specific nutritional demands, then the degree of diet segregation in each range should differ as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine if the diets of males and females are different, we collected samples of bone from the skeletons of adult bison. We also collected fresh fecal samples by observing and following individual adults during the late-summer mating season. From these samples, we determined the stable isotopes of carbon and nitrogen, and fecal nitrogen content. These properties of bone and fecal samples indicate the protein content and diversity of plants consumed by individual animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-9319 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1321&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Bison-3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;John Berini&quot; width=&quot;991&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings show that the diets of male and female bison in YNP vary in composition, quality, and breadth. During the mating season, the average diet of male and female bison is composed of different plants. Females have higher quality diets, and males have more diverse diets. Throughout the rest of the year, the average diets of male and female bison are composed of similar items. However, females still have higher quality diets, and males, more diverse diets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also found that both subpopulations exhibit diet segregation, but they do so during different times of year. In the Central Range, diet segregation was apparent during the mating season, whereas in the Northern Range, diet segregation was apparent during the non-mating season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/27/diet-segregation-american-bison-yellowstone-national-park/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Diet segregation in American bison of Yellowstone National Park&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>John Berini &amp;#38; Catherine Badgley</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, diabetic mice offered hope for understanding human disease</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-diabetic-mice-offered-hope-understanding-human-disease"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-diabetic-mice-offered-hope-understanding-human-disease</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mice described in 1967 are still helping researchers understand diabetes.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Perfectionism as a risk factor for suicide – the most comprehensive test to date</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/27/perfectionism-as-a-risk-factor-for-suicide-the-most-comprehensive-test-to-date/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27424</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T09:55:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-466113888.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27537&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27537&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D300&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LEIGH ON SEA - UNITED KINGDOM: A Samaritans sign is seen on a railway platform at Chalkwell Station on March 13, 2015 in Leigh on Sea, United Kingdom. (Photo by John Keeble\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1426261378&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2015 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.000625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Samaritans Sign&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Samaritans Sign&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466113888.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466113888.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466113888.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,680&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/27/perfectionism-as-a-risk-factor-for-suicide-the-most-comprehensive-test-to-date/samaritans-sign/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466113888.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organisation, someone takes their own life every 45 seconds. To help prevent future tragedies, we need to know more about the factors that make some people especially vulnerable to suicidal thoughts and acting on those thoughts. One candidate is perfectionism: the tendency some people have to hold themselves to consistently impossible standards and/or feeling the need to meet or surpass the lofty expectations of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1995 the late psychologist Sidney Blatt highlighted the apparent link between perfectionism and suicide in an influential article for &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt; titled “&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/1996-14509-001.pdf&quot;&gt;The Destructiveness of Perfectionism&lt;/a&gt;” in which he profiled three highly talented, ambitious but harshly self-critical individuals all of whom took their own lives: Vincent Foster, a deputy counsel to President Bill Clinton; writer, singer and broadcaster Alasdair Clayre; and athlete and scholar Roger D Hansen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because of the need to maintain a personal and public image of strength and perfection, [perfectionists] are constantly trying to prove themselves, are always on trial, feel vulnerable to any possible implication of failure or criticism, and often are unable to turn to others, even the closest of confidants, for help or to share their anguish” Blatt wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, since Blatt’s paper, research progress on the topic has been slow, hampered in part by a confusing multitude of definitions of perfectionism and a paucity of studies with the longitudinal methodology needed to establish that perfectionist tendencies increase suicidal risk. But now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;writing in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a team led by Martin Smith at the University of Ontario say there is enough data to conduct a “meta-analysis”, which is what they’ve done, producing “the most comprehensive test of the perfectionism-suicidality link to date”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27424&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found 45 relevant, suitably robust studies involving collectively 54 samples, totalling 11,747 participants. Forty-eight of the samples were cross-sectional (measures were only taken at a single point in time) while six had the all-important longitudinal design, granting insight into whether perfectionism may precede suicidal thoughts or behaviours. Collectively, the studies covered 15 of the different definitions and ways of measuring perfectionism that exist, most falling under the main categories of either placing excessive expectations on oneself, feeling pressure from others (including parents or society at large), or holding other people to perfectionistic standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the analysis showed that 13 of the 15 different measures of perfectionism had associations with increased suicidal thoughts (in statistical terms the effect size was small to moderate). Aspects of perfectionism related to concerns about meeting others’ expectations were additionally associated with making more suicide attempts. Meanwhile, holding others to high standards, and being perfectionist in terms of tidiness and organisation, were not related to suicidal thoughts or attempts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Perfectionists,” the researchers explained, “are their own worst critics … locked in an endless loop of self-defeating over-striving in which each new task is another opportunity for harsh self-rebuke, disappointment, and failure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most pernicious form of perfectionism seems to be feeling the weight of meeting other people’s expectations – this was related to increased suicidal thoughts in longitudinal studies that followed the same participants over time and that controlled for their baseline levels of suicidal thought.  “Our findings lend credence to the long-standing notion that feeling incapable of living up to the lofty standards of others is a part of the premorbid personality of people at risk for suicide,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s notable that past research has found trait conscientiousness (one of the Big Five personality traits associated with self-discipline and orderliness) is associated with &lt;em&gt;reduced&lt;/em&gt; risk of suicide. This suggests perfectionism as defined here – holding oneself to unrealistic standards, or seeking to meet the unrealistic standards of others – is not simply a form of excessive conscientiousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this is the most thorough examination of the links between perfectionism and suicide to date, and the data suggests that perfectionism is a relevant risk factor, it’s important to note that the research base is still lacking. There is especially a need for more longitudinal research, more research with diverse groups (most of the studies to date have involved White Western people) and more research that tests whether perfectionism adds risk even after other factors are taken into account, such as depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, the researchers said the data are consistent with “case histories and theoretical accounts suggesting people high in perfectionism appear to think, behave, perceive, and relate in ways that have suicidogenic consequences”. Perfectionism is associated with “intense psychological pain” they said. Perfectionists have a “harsh way of relating to a self they find deficient”. Their lives are typically stressful and they often have a “prickly, conflictual style of relating to others,” leaving them isolated and lacking support. “Amid such pain,” Smith and his colleagues conclude,” perfectionists may think about, or engage in, suicide as a means of escaping a life they find unbearable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;The Perniciousness of Perfectionism: A Meta-Analytic Review of the Perfectionism-Suicide Relationship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27424/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27424/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27424&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Plum Analytics metrics are now available to more researchers</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/plum-analytics-metrics-are-now-available-to-more-researchers"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/plum-analytics-metrics-are-now-available-to-more-researchers</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T09:09:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 PlumX has been integrated into Elsevier’s leading products and services, enabling more researchers to access these comprehensive metrics</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Q&amp;amp;A with Johannes Herrmann, new President of German Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (GBM)</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-with-johannes-herrmann-new-president-of-german-society-for-biochemistry-and-molecular-biology-gbm"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-with-johannes-herrmann-new-president-of-german-society-for-biochemistry-and-molecular-biology-gbm</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T08:50:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Prof. Herrmann speaks about his plans in his new role and his ambition to support early career researchers</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">Are journals necessary filters?</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/are-journals-necessary-filters/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1433</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T07:53:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/the-great-misunderstanding-about-peer-review-and-the-nature-of-scientific-facts/&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I argued that one reason why many people cling to the idea that papers should be formally peer-reviewed before they are published, cited and discussed, despite the fact that this system is a recent historical addition to the scientific enterprise, is a philosophical misunderstanding about the nature of scientific truth. That is, the characteristic of science, as opposed to religion, is that it is never validated; it can and must be criticized. Therefore, no amount of peer reviewing can ever be a stamp of approval for “proven facts”. Instead what we need is public discussion of the science, not stamps of approvals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to that post came up another common reason why many people think it’s important to have journals that select papers after peer-review. The reason is that we are crowded with millions of papers and you can’t read everything, so you need some way to know which paper is important, based on peer-review. So here this is not just about peer-reviewing before publishing, but also about the hierarchy of journals. Journals must do an editorial selection so that you don’t have to waste your time reading low-quality papers, or uninteresting papers. What this means, quite literally, is that you only read papers from “top journals”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I want to show that this argument is untenable, because selecting their readings based on journal names is not what scientists should do or actually do, and because the argument is logically inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it logically inconsistent? If the argument is correct, then those papers accepted in lower rank journals should not be read because they are not worth reading. But in that case, why publish them at all? There seems to be no reason for the existence of journals that people do not read because they do not have time to read bad papers. If we argue that those journals should exist because in some cases there are some papers worth reading there, for any sort of reason, then we must admit that we don’t actually use journals as filters, or that we should not use them as filters (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it good scientific practice to use journal names as filters? What this implies is that you ignore any paper, including papers in your field and potentially relevant to your own studies, which are not published in “top journals”. So for example, you would not cite a relevant study if it’s not from a top journal. It also means that you don’t check that your own work overlaps other studies. So you potentially take credit for ideas that you were not the first to have. Is this a professional attitude?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If in fact you don’t totally ignore those lower journals, then you don’t actually use journal name as a filter, you actually do look at the content of papers independently of the journal they are published in. Which is my final point: to use journal names as filters is not the normal practice of scientists (or maybe I’m optimistic?). When you look for relevant papers on your topic of interest, you typically do a search (eg pubmed). Do you only consider papers from “top journals”, blindly discarding all others? Of course not. You first look at the titles to see if it might be relevant; then you read the abstract if they are; if the abstract is promising you might open the paper and skim through it, and possibly read it carefully if you think it is worth it. Then you will look at cited papers; or at papers that cite the interesting you just read; or you will read a review; maybe a colleague or your advisor will suggest a few readings. In brief: you do a proper bibliographical search. I cannot believe that any good scientist considers that doing a bibliographical search consists in browsing the table of contents of top journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only case when you do use journal names to select papers to read is indeed when you read tables of contents every month for a few selected journals. How much of this accounts for the papers that you cite? You can get a rough idea of this by looking at the cited half-life of papers or journals. For Cell, it’s about 9 years. I personally also follow new papers on biorxiv using keywords, while most new papers in journals are irrelevant to me because they cover too many topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary: using journals as filters is not professional because it means poor scholarship and misattribution of credit. Fortunately it’s not what scientists normally do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One related argument that came out in the discussion of my previous post is that having papers reviewed post-publication could not work because that would be too much work, and consequently most papers would not be reviewed, while at least in the current system every paper is peer reviewed. That is wrong in several ways. First, you can have papers published then peer-reviewed formally and publicly (as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://f1000research.com/&quot;&gt;F1000 Research&lt;/a&gt;), without this being coupled to editorial selection. Second, if anything, having papers submitted a single time instead of many times to different journals implies that there will be less work for reviewers, not more. Third, what is exactly the advantage of having each paper peer-reviewed if it is argued that those papers should not be read or cited? In the logic where peer review in “good journals” serves as filters for important papers, it makes no difference whether the unimportant papers are peer reviewed or not, so this cannot count as a valid argument against post-publication review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this being said, there is still a case for &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/free-the-journals/&quot;&gt;editorial selection &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; publication&lt;/a&gt;, as one of the many ways to discover papers of interest, see for example my &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/&quot;&gt;free journal of theoretical neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>admin</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Half of the Milky Way comes from other galaxies</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/half-milky-way-comes-other-galaxies"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/half-milky-way-comes-other-galaxies</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T01:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A galaxy may swipe up to half of its atoms from other galaxies, making the Milky Way mostly extragalactic stuff, new simulations suggest.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Huge landslide triggered rare Greenland mega-tsunami</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/k5ExiaLwtdg/nature.2017.22374"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22374</id>
		<updated>2017-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists hope studying last month’s deadly event will improve modelling of rockslides that could become more frequent with climate change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22374&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/k5ExiaLwtdg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quirin Schiermeier</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Borrowed genes give mums the blues</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borrowed-genes-give-mums-blues"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borrowed-genes-give-mums-blues</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T19:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have genetically modified chrysanthemums to be “true blue” for the first time.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Balloons will broadcast the 2017 solar eclipse live from on high</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/balloons-broadcast-2017-solar-eclipse-livestream"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/balloons-broadcast-2017-solar-eclipse-livestream</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T17:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Astrophysicist Angela Des Jardins is coordinating the first-ever livestream of a solar eclipse filmed from balloons.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Expert eavesdroppers occasionally catch a break</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/expert-eavesdroppers-occasionally-catch-break"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/expert-eavesdroppers-occasionally-catch-break</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T17:15:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses the many ways we watch, listen and learn about science.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers question hominid family tree</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-hominid-family-tree"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-hominid-family-tree</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T17:04:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers sent feedback on hominid origins, fast cameras, slimy sea creatures and more.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Perovskites power up the solar industry</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perovskites-power-solar-industry"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perovskites-power-solar-industry</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T16:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Perovskites are the latest hot materials in solar energy production.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">More hints of Martian hot springs may hold promise for Mars 2020 mission</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-hints-martian-hot-springs-may-hold-promise-mars-2020-mission"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-hints-martian-hot-springs-may-hold-promise-mars-2020-mission</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T15:10:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An analysis of ridges in a crater of Margaritifer Terra on Mars offers evidence of ancient hot springs and also hints at the potential for finding signs of life.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Nurturing the Brain – Part 11, Magnesium</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/26/nurturing-the-brain-part-11-magnesium/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22677</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T15:00:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Magnesium is everywhere – it does not occur free in nature, only in combination with other elements, but it is the eighth most abundant chemical element in the Earth’s crust and the third most abundant element in seawater; it is even the ninth most abundant in the Milky Way. In the human body, magnesium is the fourth most abundant ion and the eleventh most abundant element by mass, being stored in bones, muscles, and soft tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is fundamental for health: it is essential to all cells and to the function of hundreds of enzymes, including enzymes that synthesize DNA and RNA, and enzymes involved in cellular &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;energy metabolism&lt;/a&gt;, many of which are vital. Magnesium is involved in virtually every major metabolic and biochemical process in our cells and it plays a critical role in the physiology of basically every single organ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low plasma levels of magnesium are common and are mostly due to poor dietary intake, which has lowered significantly in the last decades. Magnesium can be found in high quantities in foods containing &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/19/the-brain-gut-axis-part-2-brain-gut-microbiota-communication/&quot;&gt;dietary fiber&lt;/a&gt;, including green leafy vegetables, legumes, nuts, seeds, and whole grains. But although magnesium is widely distributed in vegetable and animal foods, some types of food processing can lower magnesium content up to 90%. Also, the soil used for conventional agriculture is becoming increasingly deprived of essential minerals. In the last 60 years, the magnesium content in fruit and vegetables has decreased by around 20 to 30%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptomatic magnesium deficiency due to low dietary intake in healthy people is not very frequent, but a consistently poor dietary supply of magnesium has insidious effects. Magnesium deficiency alters biochemical pathways and increases the risk of a wide range of diseases over time, namely &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2006/12/21/hypertension-drugs-affect-alzheimers/&quot;&gt;hypertension&lt;/a&gt; and cardiovascular diseases, metabolic diseases, osteoporosis, and migraine headaches, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the brain, magnesium is an important regulator of neurotransmitter signaling, particularly glutamate and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2007/06/25/yoga-increases-gaba-levels-in-brain/&quot;&gt;GABA&lt;/a&gt;, the main neurotransmitters by modulating the activation of NMDA glutamate receptors and GABA&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; receptors. It also contributes to the maintenance of adequate calcium levels in the cell through the regulation of calcium channels’ activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These physiological roles make magnesium an essential element in important neuronal processes. Magnesium participates in the mechanisms of synaptic transmission, neuronal plasticity, and consequently, learning and memory. Accordingly, increased levels of magnesium in the brain have been shown to promote multiple mechanisms of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/25/exercise-and-brain-aging/&quot;&gt;synaptic plasticity&lt;/a&gt; that enhance different forms of learning and memory, and delay age-related cognitive decline. Increased levels of magnesium in the brain have also been linked to an increased proliferation of neural stem cells, indicating that it may promote the generation of new neurons (neurogenesis) in adulthood. This is an important feature because neurogenesis is a key mechanism in the brain’s structural and functional adaptability, in cognitive flexibility, and in mood regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium supplementation has also been shown to modulate the neuroendocrine system and to improve sleep quality by promoting slow wave (deep) sleep, which, among many other functions, is also important for cognition and memory consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, magnesium may enhance the beneficial effects of exercise in the brain, since it has been shown to increase the availability of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/06/26/blood-glucose-and-the-brain-sugar-and-short-term-memory/&quot;&gt;glucose&lt;/a&gt; in the blood, muscle, and brain, and diminish the accumulation of lactate in the blood and muscles during exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just as increasing magnesium levels can be beneficial, magnesium deficiency can have serious harmful effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium has important roles in the regulation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/08/stress-shortens-life/&quot;&gt;oxidative stress&lt;/a&gt;, inflammatory processes and modulation of brain blood flow. In circumstances of magnesium deficiency, all of these functions can potentially be dysregulated, laying ground for neurological disorders. Also, in a context of low magnesium availability in the brain, NMDA glutamate receptors, which are excitatory, may become excessively activated, and GABAA receptors, which are inhibitory, may become insufficiently activated; this can lead to neuronal hyperactivity and to a condition known as glutamate excitotoxicity. This causes an excessive accumulation of calcium in neurons, which in turn leads to the production of toxic reactive oxygen species and, ultimately, to neuronal cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium deficiency has been associated with several neurological and psychiatric diseases, including migraine, epilepsy, depression, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, stress, and neurodegenerative diseases. Magnesium supplementation has shown beneficial effects on many of these conditions, as well as in post-stroke, post-traumatic &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/01/traumatic-brain-injury-can-deep-sleep-be-neuroprotective/&quot;&gt;brain injury&lt;/a&gt;, and post-spinal cord injury therapies. This therapeutic action is likely due to its action in blocking NMDA glutamate receptors and decreasing excitotoxicity, in reducing oxidative stress and inflammation, and in increasing blood flow to the brain, all of which are determinant in the outcome of these conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple benefits to be obtained from magnesium, both from a health promotion, and from a disease prevention and management perspective. The recommended daily intake of magnesium is of 320mg for females and 420mg for males. Too much magnesium from food sources has no associated health risks in healthy individuals because the kidneys readily eliminate the excess. However, there is a recommended upper intake level for supplemental magnesium, since it can cause gastrointestinal side effects. So, keep it below 350mg/day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen HY, et al (2014). Magnesium enhances exercise performance via increasing glucose availability in the blood, muscle, and brain during exercise. PLoS One, 9(1):e85486. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0085486&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0085486&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;de Baaij JH, et al (2015). Magnesium in man: implications for health and disease. Physiol Rev, 95(1):1-46. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://physrev.physiology.org/content/95/1/1.long&quot;&gt;10.1152/physrev.00012.2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Held K, et al (2002). Oral Mg(2+) supplementation reverses age-related neuroendocrine and sleep EEG changes in humans. Pharmacopsychiatry, 35(4):135-43. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thieme-connect.com/DOI/DOI?10.1055/s-2002-33195&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.pbb.2004.01.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jia S, et al (2016). Elevation of Brain Magnesium Potentiates Neural Stem Cell Proliferation in the Hippocampus of Young and Aged Mice. J Cell Physiol, 231(9):1903-12. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jcp.25306/abstract&quot;&gt;10.1002/jcp.25306&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Institutes of Health, Office of Dietary Supplements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/Magnesium-HealthProfessional/&quot;&gt;Magnesium Fact Sheet for Health Professionals &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slutsky I, et al (2010). Enhancement of learning and memory by elevating brain magnesium. Neuron. 2010 Jan 28;65(2):165-77. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(09)01044-7&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neuron.2009.12.026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Brett_Hondow-49958/&quot;&gt;Brett_Hondow&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sara Adaes, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Controversial CRISPR paper earns second editorial note</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/controversial-crispr-paper-earns-second-editorial-note/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51187</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T15:00:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Against the authors’ objections, Nature Methods has added an expression of concern to a 2017 paper that drew fire for suggesting a common gene editing technique could cause widespread collateral damage to the genome. The latest note — the second to be added in two months — alerts readers to an alternative interpretation of the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/controversial-crispr-paper-earns-second-editorial-note/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Controversial CRISPR paper earns second editorial note&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS ONE retracts paper after researcher admits to fabricating data</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/plos-one-retracts-paper-researcher-admits-fabricating-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51179</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T12:00:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;On June 19, 2017, the U.S. Office of Research Integrity published its first misconduct finding of the year. The ORI reported that Brandi M. Baughman — a former research training awardee at the National Institute of Environmental and Health Sciences (NIEHS) — had “falsified and/or fabricated data” in 11 figures in a 2016 paper published in PLOS […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/plos-one-retracts-paper-researcher-admits-fabricating-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE retracts paper after researcher admits to fabricating data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">We’re ready for the Charles River Annual Research Symposium!</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/07/were-ready-for-the-charles-river-annual-research-symposium/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1108</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T11:56:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;by Annie Chen, Event Marketing Specialist, Science Exchange | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We are excited to attend the annual research symposium hosted by Charles River, a leading service provider on the Science Exchange network — and we hope to see you there!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Join your colleagues and industry experts from Bluebird, Janssen, Pfizer, and Amgen in Carlsbad, CA September 11–13 at Charles River’s biotech symposium, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cvent.com/events/annual-biotech-symposium-biotechnology-derived-therapeutics-perspectives-on-nonclinical-development/event-summary-a32daae4dce048aea021e98df2e54435.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biotechnology-Derived Therapeutics: Perspectives on Nonclinical Development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;With five different session tracks, join Charles River to learn about:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biotherapeutic development programs and related case studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biomolecules and modifications to prolong a molecule’s half-life&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Preclinical development of inhaled therapeutics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Microphysiology systems for biotherapeutics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Arrive one day early and attend the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cvent.com/events/annual-biotech-symposium-biotechnology-derived-therapeutics-perspectives-on-nonclinical-development/event-summary-a32daae4dce048aea021e98df2e54435.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;pre-symposium workshop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; titled, Where Does My Protein Go and Why Does It Matter? The Role of PK/PD in Biotherapeutics on Sunday, September 10.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Discounted room rates are available until August 11 and special registration fees are available to SOT BTSS members.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.criver.com/e/60962/4dce048aea021e98df2e54435-aspx/d3chlv/555769021&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register Now!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum tunneling takes time, new study shows</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tunneling-takes-time-new-study-shows"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tunneling-takes-time-new-study-shows</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new measurement disfavors the idea that electrons can escape atoms instantaneously.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">The great misunderstanding about peer review and the nature of scientific facts</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/the-great-misunderstanding-about-peer-review-and-the-nature-of-scientific-facts/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1430</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T10:11:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;Last week I organized a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computational-neuroscience-of-sensory-systems.org/workshop-on-emerging-models-in-scientific-communication-and-discussion/&quot;&gt;workshop on the future of academic publication&lt;/a&gt;. My point was that our current system, based on private pre-publication peer review, is archaic. I noted that the way the peer review system is currently organized (where external reviewers judge both the quality of the science and the interest for the journal) represents just a few decades in the history of science. It can hardly qualify as the way science is or should be done. It is a historical feature. For example, only one of Einstein’s papers was formally peer-reviewed; Crick &amp;amp; Watson’s DNA paper was not formally peer-reviewed. Many journals introduced external peer review in the 1960s or 1970s to deal with the growth in the number and variety of submissions (see e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4528400/&quot;&gt;Baldwin, 2015&lt;/a&gt;); before that, editors would decide whether to publish the papers they received, depending on the number of pages they could print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the possibilities that offers the internet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/a-vision-of-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;it seems that there is no reason anymore to couple t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/a-vision-of-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;he two current roles of peer review&lt;/a&gt;: editorial selection and scientific discussion. One could simply share their work online, get feedback from the community to discuss the work, and then let people recommend papers to their colleagues and &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/free-the-journals/&quot;&gt;compile all sorts of reader’s digests&lt;/a&gt;. No time wasted in multiple submissions, no prestige misattributed to publications in glamour journals, who do not do a better a job than any other journal at pointing errors and frauds. Just the science and the public discussion of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a lot of resistance to this idea, namely the idea that papers should be formally approved by peer reviewers before they are published. Because otherwise, so many people claim, the scientific world would be polluted by all sorts of unverified claims. It would not be science anymore, just gossip. I have attributed this attitude to conservatism, first because as noted above this system is a rather recent addition to the scientific enterprise, and second because papers &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; published before peer review. We call those “preprints”, but really these are scientific papers made public, so by definition they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; published. I follow the preprints in my field and I don’t see any particular loss in quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I think I was missing a key element. The more profound reason why many people, in particular experimental biologists, are so attached to peer review is in my view that they hold naive philosophical views about the notion of truth in science. A paper should be peer-reviewed because otherwise you can’t cite it as a true fact. Peer review validates science, thanks to experts who make sure that the claims of the authors are actually true. Of course it can go wrong and reviewers might miss something, but it is the purpose of peer review. This view is reflected in the tendency, especially in biology journals, to choose titles that look like established truths: “Hunger is controlled by HGRase”, instead of “The molecular control of hunger”. Scientists and journalists can then write revealed truths with a verse reference, such as “Hunger is controlled by HGRase (McDonald et al., 2017)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great misunderstanding is that truth is a notion that applies to logical propositions (for example, mathematical theorems), not to empirical claims. This has been well argued by Popper, for example. Truth is by nature a theoretical concept. Everything said is said with words, and in this sense it always refers to theoretical concepts. One can only judge whether observations are congruent with the meaning attributed to the words, and that meaning necessarily has a theoretical nature. There is no such thing as an “established fact”. This is so even of what we might consider as direct observations. Take for example the claim “The resting potential of neurons is -70 mV”. This is a theoretical statement. Why? First, because to establish it, I have recorded a number of neurons. If you test it, it will be on a different neuron, which I have not measured. So I am making a theoretical claim. Probably, I also tested my neurons with a particular method (not mentioning a particular region and species). But my claim makes no reference to the method by which I have made the inference. That would be the “methods” part of my paper, not the conclusion, and when you cite my paper, you will cite it because of the conclusion, the “established fact”, you will not be referring to the methods, which you consider are the means to establish the fact. It is the role of the reviewers to check the methods, to check that they do establish the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are trivial remarks. It is not just that the method matters. The very notion of an observation always implicitly relies on a theoretical background. When I say that the resting potential is -70 mV, I mean that there is a potential difference of -70 mV across the membrane. But that’s not what I measure. I measure the difference in potential between some point outside the cell and the inside of a patch pipette whose solution is in contact with the cell’s inside. So I am assuming the potential is the same in all points of the cytosol, even though I have not tested it. I am also implicitly modeling the cytosol as a solution, even though the reality is more complex than that, given the mass of charged proteins in it. I am assuming that the extracellular potential is constant. I am assuming that my pipette solution reasonably matches the actual cytosol solution, given that “solution” is only a convenient model. I am implicitly making all sorts of theoretical assumptions, which have a lot of empirical support but are still of a theoretical nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried with this example to show that even a very simple “fact” is actually a theoretical proposition, with many layers of assumptions. But of course in general, papers typically make claims that rely less firmly on accepted theoretical grounds, since they must be “novel”. So it is never the case that a paper definitely proves its conclusions. Because conclusions have a theoretical nature, all that can be checked is whether observations are consistent with the authors’ interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the goal of peer review can’t be to establish the truth. If it were the case, then why would reviewers ever disagree? They disagree because they cannot actually judge whether a claim is true; they can only say whether they are personally convinced. This makes the current peer review system extremely poor, because all the information we get is: two anonymous people were convinced (and maybe others were not, but we’ll never find out). What would be more useful would be to have an open public discussion, with criticisms, qualifications and alternative interpretations fully disclosed for anyone to read and make their own opinion. In such a system, the notion of a stamp of approval on a paper would simply be absurd; why hide the disapprovals? There is the paper, and there is the scientific discussion of the paper, and that is all there needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some concern these days that peer reviewed research is unreliable. Well, science is unreliable. That is almost what defines it: it can be criticized and revised. Seeing peer review as the system that establishes the scientific truth is not only a historical error, it is a great philosophical error, and a dangerous bureaucratic view of science. We don’t need editorial decisions based on peer review. We need free publication (&lt;a href=&quot;http://biorxiv.org/&quot;&gt;we have it&lt;/a&gt;) and we need open scientific discussion (&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubpeer.com/&quot;&gt;it’s coming&lt;/a&gt;). That’s all we need.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>admin</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Booty more amusing than ass, according to first in-depth study of the funniness of English words</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/26/booty-more-amusing-than-ass-according-to-first-in-depth-study-of-the-funniness-of-english-words/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27334</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T09:29:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-484958654.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27419&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27419&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;9&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A donkey on an island off the west coast of Ireland looks as though he is laughing. Shot in Black and White.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1403960790&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mariongalt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.001&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laughing Donkey&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Laughing Donkey&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/26/booty-more-amusing-than-ass-according-to-first-in-depth-study-of-the-funniness-of-english-words/laughing-donkey/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was at primary school, we used to type out the word “BOOBIES” using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calculator_spelling&quot;&gt;upside-down digits&lt;/a&gt; on our electronic calculators and we thought it was hilarious. This was an all-boys school in the late 80s, cut us some slack. And anyway, maybe we weren’t so daft. The word (although spelt differently as “Booby”) was among the top-three most funny words as identified in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13428-017-0930-6&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Behaviour Research&lt;/em&gt;, which is the first in-depth investigation of the perceived funniness of individual English words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the 5000 words that were studied, Booty was rated the funniest of all, scoring 4.32 on average on a scale from 1 (not funny at all) to 5 (most funny). The lowest scoring word was Rape with an average of 1.18. The researchers Tomas Engelthaler and Thomas Hills at the University of Warwick, England hope their findings will provide a useful resource, a “highly rudimentary ‘fruit fly’ version” of humour” for &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-26/edition-4/how-many-psychologists-does-it-take-explain-joke&quot;&gt;researchers studying the psychology of what makes us laugh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27334&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 821 participants for the study (average age 35; 58 per cent were female) were recruited via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk online survey website. To ease them into the challenge, they each began by rating 11 “calibrator words” selected from pilot research because they’d attracted a wide range of funniness scores from high (Turd, scored at 3.78 in pilot research) to low (Drought, scored 1.13). After this, each participant rated the funniness of  approximately 200 more words selected at random from the 5000-word pool (taken from earlier studies into the subjective perception of English words). Participants were instructed to make their ratings based on their first and immediate reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 words to attract the highest funniness ratings were, in descending order from most funny:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Booty, Tit, Booby, Hooter, Nitwit, Twit, Waddle, Tinkle, Bebop, Egghead, Ass and Twerp&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 words to attract the lowest funniness ratings were, starting with the most humourless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rape, Torture, Torment, Gunshot, Death, Nightmare, War, Trauma, Rapist, Distrust, Deathbed, Pain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers main objective was to create a useful data-set for future experiments into humour (similar to how others have created average ratings of concreteness, arousal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/05/18/why-do-so-many-people-dislike-the-word-moist/&quot;&gt;pleasantness&lt;/a&gt; and age-of-acquisition for other words), but they did perform a few comparisons with their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the researchers looked at the words for which men and women most strongly differed in the funniness ratings they gave, including the following which were rated funnier on average by men than women:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bondage, Birthmark, Orgy, Brand, Chauffeur, Doze, Buzzard, Czar, Weld, Prod, Corn, Raccoon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the following words, which were rated as funnier by women than men:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Giggle, Beast, Circus, Grand, Juju, Humbug, Slicker, Sweat, Ennui, Holder, Momma, Sod&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the following words were those that attracted the most similar high funniness ratings across both sexes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chug, Fluff, Scrotum, Jabber, Joke, Buttocks, Boon, Yank, Tinker, Prance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the words that tended to attract high funniness ratings and seeing how they have scored for other dimensions in previous research, Engelthaler and Hills found that they tended to be less frequent and to take people longer to recognise as words. Another thing: whereas previous research has found that we tend to have a positive bias towards words, finding most of them to be positive in tone and meaning, the current research found that we have a bias toward seeing most words as more unfunny than funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, time for me to stop all this jabber, I’m going to waddle off for a tinkle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13428-017-0930-6&quot;&gt;Humor norms for 4,997 English words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27334/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27334/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27334&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How personalized metrics can change behavior and improve research performance</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-personalized-metrics-can-change-behavior-and-improve-research-performance"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-personalized-metrics-can-change-behavior-and-improve-research-performance</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T09:26:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Using SciVal, Queen’s University Belfast worked with Elsevier’s Research Metrics team to increase citations and change its approach to publishing</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Big names in statistics want to shake up much-maligned P value</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oZsASln3Z2w/nature.2017.22375"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22375</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;One of scientists’ favourite statistics — the  P  value — should face tougher standards, say leading researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22375&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22375&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oZsASln3Z2w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dalmeet Singh Chawla</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">'True blue' chrysanthemum flowers produced with genetic engineering</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hDgsWbx6v0w/nature.2017.22365"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22365</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists added two genes to the plant's genome to get the new hue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22365&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22365&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hDgsWbx6v0w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rachael Lallensack</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">China’s quest to become a space science superpower</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/IMSmRgZUL6s/547394a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547394a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;With major spaceflight milestones behind it, China is working to build an international reputation for space science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 394 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547394a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547394a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/IMSmRgZUL6s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jane Qiu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brain’s stem cells slow ageing in mice</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/-sON1YoqqaA/547389a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547389a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Transplanted cells offer middle-aged rodents an increased lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 389 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547389a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547389a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/-sON1YoqqaA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sara Reardon</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">HIV milestone, discrimination suit and China's AI plans</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/p0HMohZzH38/547384a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547384a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 21–27 July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 384 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547384a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547384a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/p0HMohZzH38&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">More universities must confront sexual harassment</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/YcXSRu3nTdY/547379a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547379a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Too many institutions give low priority to tackling sexual misconduct in science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 379 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547379a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547379a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/YcXSRu3nTdY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">In vivo FRET–FLIM reveals cell-type-specific protein interactions in Arabidopsis roots</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/nIjsZVVakvE/nature23317"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23317</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 During multicellular development, specification of distinct cell fates is often regulated by the same transcription factors operating differently in distinct cis-regulatory modules, either through different protein complexes, conformational modification of protein complexes, or combinations of both. Direct visualization of different transcription factor complex states guiding specific gene expression programs has been challenging. Here we use in vivo FRET–FLIM (Förster resonance energy transfer measured by fluorescence lifetime microscopy) to reveal spatial partitioning of protein interactions in relation to specification of cell fate. We show that, in Arabidopsis roots, three fully functional fluorescently tagged cell fate regulators establish cell-type-specific interactions at endogenous expression levels and can form higher order complexes. We reveal that cell-type-specific in vivo FRET–FLIM distributions reflect conformational changes of these complexes to differentially regulate target genes and specify distinct cell fates. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23317&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23317&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/nIjsZVVakvE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yuchen Long</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Derivation of ground-state female ES cells maintaining gamete-derived DNA methylation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/j3wz3Nie17w/nature23286"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23286</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Inhibitors of Mek1/2 and Gsk3β, known as 2i, enhance the derivation of embryonic stem (ES) cells and promote ground-state pluripotency in rodents. Here we show that the derivation of female mouse ES cells in the presence of 2i and leukaemia inhibitory factor (2i/L ES cells) results in a widespread loss of DNA methylation, including a massive erasure of genomic imprints. Despite this global loss of DNA methylation, early-passage 2i/L ES cells efficiently differentiate into somatic cells, and this process requires genome-wide de novo DNA methylation. However, the majority of imprinting control regions (ICRs) remain unmethylated in 2i/L-ES-cell-derived differentiated cells. Consistently, 2i/L ES cells exhibit impaired autonomous embryonic and placental development by tetraploid embryo complementation or nuclear transplantation. We identified the derivation conditions of female ES cells that display 2i/L-ES-cell-like transcriptional signatures while preserving gamete-derived DNA methylation and autonomous developmental potential. Upon prolonged culture, however, female ES cells exhibited ICR demethylation regardless of culture conditions. Our results provide insights into the derivation of female ES cells reminiscent of the inner cell mass of preimplantation embryos. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23286&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23286&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/j3wz3Nie17w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Masaki Yagi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Stimulation of functional neuronal regeneration from Müller glia in adult mice</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/qq7pogCCsuw/nature23283"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23283</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Many retinal diseases lead to the loss of retinal neurons and cause visual impairment. The adult mammalian retina has little capacity for regeneration. By contrast, teleost fish functionally regenerate their retina following injury, and Müller glia (MG) are the source of regenerated neurons. The proneural transcription factor Ascl1 is upregulated in MG after retinal damage in zebrafish and is necessary for regeneration. Although Ascl1 is not expressed in mammalian MG after injury, forced expression of Ascl1 in mouse MG induces a neurogenic state in vitro and in vivo after NMDA (N-methyl-d-aspartate) damage in young mice. However, by postnatal day 16, mouse MG lose neurogenic capacity, despite Ascl1 overexpression. Loss of neurogenic capacity in mature MG is accompanied by reduced chromatin accessibility, suggesting that epigenetic factors limit regeneration. Here we show that MG-specific overexpression of Ascl1, together with a histone deacetylase inhibitor, enables adult mice to generate neurons from MG after retinal injury. The MG-derived neurons express markers of inner retinal neurons, synapse with host retinal neurons, and respond to light. Using an assay for transposase-accessible chromatin with high-throughput sequencing (ATAC–seq), we show that the histone deacetylase inhibitor promotes accessibility at key gene loci in the MG, and allows more effective reprogramming. Our results thus provide a new approach for the treatment of blinding retinal diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23283&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23283&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/qq7pogCCsuw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nikolas L. Jorstad</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Hypothalamic stem cells control ageing speed partly through exosomal miRNAs</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/JjUMDNrU3xg/nature23282"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23282</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 It has been proposed that the hypothalamus helps to control ageing, but the mechanisms responsible remain unclear. Here we develop several mouse models in which hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells that co-express Sox2 and Bmi1 are ablated, as we observed that ageing in mice started with a substantial loss of these hypothalamic cells. Each mouse model consistently displayed acceleration of ageing-like physiological changes or a shortened lifespan. Conversely, ageing retardation and lifespan extension were achieved in mid-aged mice that were locally implanted with healthy hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells that had been genetically engineered to survive in the ageing-related hypothalamic inflammatory microenvironment. Mechanistically, hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells contributed greatly to exosomal microRNAs (miRNAs) in the cerebrospinal fluid, and these exosomal miRNAs declined during ageing, whereas central treatment with healthy hypothalamic stem/progenitor cell-secreted exosomes led to the slowing of ageing. In conclusion, ageing speed is substantially controlled by hypothalamic stem cells, partially through the release of exosomal miRNAs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23282&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23282&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/JjUMDNrU3xg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yalin Zhang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Prolonged Mek1/2 suppression impairs the developmental potential of embryonic stem cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/xUhQ6yQFQ00/nature23274"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23274</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Concomitant activation of the Wnt pathway and suppression of Mapk signalling by two small molecule inhibitors (2i) in the presence of leukaemia inhibitory factor (LIF) (hereafter termed 2i/L) induces a naive state in mouse embryonic stem (ES) cells that resembles the inner cell mass (ICM) of the pre-implantation embryo. Since the ICM exists only transiently in vivo, it remains unclear how sustained propagation of naive ES cells in vitro affects their stability and functionality. Here we show that prolonged culture of male mouse ES cells in 2i/L results in irreversible epigenetic and genomic changes that impair their developmental potential. Furthermore, we find that female ES cells cultured in conventional serum plus LIF medium phenocopy male ES cells cultured in 2i/L. Mechanistically, we demonstrate that the inhibition of Mek1/2 is predominantly responsible for these effects, in part through the downregulation of DNA methyltransferases and their cofactors. Finally, we show that replacement of the Mek1/2 inhibitor with a Src inhibitor preserves the epigenetic and genomic integrity as well as the developmental potential of ES cells. Taken together, our data suggest that, although short-term suppression of Mek1/2 in ES cells helps to maintain an ICM-like epigenetic state, prolonged suppression results in irreversible changes that compromise their developmental potential. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23274&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23274&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/xUhQ6yQFQ00&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jiho Choi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Higher-order interactions stabilize dynamics in competitive network models</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ZxFGAp7Y08E/nature23273"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23273</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Ecologists have long sought a way to explain how the remarkable biodiversity observed in nature is maintained. On the one hand, simple models of interacting competitors cannot produce the stable persistence of very large ecological communities. On the other hand, neutral models, in which species do not interact and diversity is maintained by immigration and speciation, yield unrealistically small fluctuations in population abundance, and a strong positive correlation between a species’ abundance and its age, contrary to empirical evidence. Models allowing for the robust persistence of large communities of interacting competitors are lacking. Here we show that very diverse communities could persist thanks to the stabilizing role of higher-order interactions, in which the presence of a species influences the interaction between other species. Although higher-order interactions have been studied for decades, their role in shaping ecological communities is still unclear. The inclusion of higher-order interactions in competitive network models stabilizes dynamics, making species coexistence robust to the perturbation of both population abundance and parameter values. We show that higher-order interactions have strong effects in models of closed ecological communities, as well as of open communities in which new species are constantly introduced. In our framework, higher-order interactions are completely defined by pairwise interactions, facilitating empirical parameterization and validation of our models. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23273&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23273&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ZxFGAp7Y08E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jacopo Grilli</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Complex cellular logic computation using ribocomputing devices</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Im5ft398v8c/nature23271"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23271</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Synthetic biology aims to develop engineering-driven approaches to the programming of cellular functions that could yield transformative technologies. Synthetic gene circuits that combine DNA, protein, and RNA components have demonstrated a range of functions such as bistability, oscillation, feedback, and logic capabilities. However, it remains challenging to scale up these circuits owing to the limited number of designable, orthogonal, high-performance parts, the empirical and often tedious composition rules, and the requirements for substantial resources for encoding and operation. Here, we report a strategy for constructing RNA-only nanodevices to evaluate complex logic in living cells. Our ‘ribocomputing’ systems are composed of de-novo-designed parts and operate through predictable and designable base-pairing rules, allowing the effective in silico design of computing devices with prescribed configurations and functions in complex cellular environments. These devices operate at the post-transcriptional level and use an extended RNA transcript to co-localize all circuit sensing, computation, signal transduction, and output elements in the same self-assembled molecular complex, which reduces diffusion-mediated signal losses, lowers metabolic cost, and improves circuit reliability. We demonstrate that ribocomputing devices in Escherichia coli can evaluate two-input logic with a dynamic range up to 900-fold and scale them to four-input AND, six-input OR, and a complex 12-input expression (A1 AND A2 AND NOT A1*) OR (B1 AND B2 AND NOT B2*) OR (C1 AND C2) OR (D1 AND D2) OR (E1 AND E2). Successful operation of ribocomputing devices based on programmable RNA interactions suggests that systems employing the same design principles could be implemented in other host organisms or in extracellular settings. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23271&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Im5ft398v8c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexander A. Green</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sequencing and de novo assembly of 150 genomes from Denmark as a population reference</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QSlVa-oC1tY/nature23264"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23264</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Hundreds of thousands of human genomes are now being sequenced to characterize genetic variation and use this information to augment association mapping studies of complex disorders and other phenotypic traits. Genetic variation is identified mainly by mapping short reads to the reference genome or by performing local assembly. However, these approaches are biased against discovery of structural variants and variation in the more complex parts of the genome. Hence, large-scale de novo assembly is needed. Here we show that it is possible to construct excellent de novo assemblies from high-coverage sequencing with mate-pair libraries extending up to 20 kilobases. We report de novo assemblies of 150 individuals (50 trios) from the GenomeDenmark project. The quality of these assemblies is similar to those obtained using the more expensive long-read technology. We use the assemblies to identify a rich set of structural variants including many novel insertions and demonstrate how this variant catalogue enables further deciphering of known association mapping signals. We leverage the assemblies to provide 100 completely resolved major histocompatibility complex haplotypes and to resolve major parts of the Y chromosome. Our study provides a regional reference genome that we expect will improve the power of future association mapping studies and hence pave the way for precision medicine initiatives, which now are being launched in many countries including Denmark. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23264&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23264&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QSlVa-oC1tY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lasse Maretty</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ecology: Contests between species aid biodiversity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/r3mChb-0wuQ/nature23103"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23103</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A modelling approach used to investigate competition between different species provides insight into how contests that have multiple players can help to maintain biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23103&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/r3mChb-0wuQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>James P. O'Dwyer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Stem cells: The cost of perpetual youth</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/NdgvXFqpuxg/nature23102"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23102</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The ability to become nearly any cell type is restricted to eggs, sperm and primitive stem cells in very early embryos. Two studies reveal that maintaining this pluripotent state  in vitro  comes at a cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23102&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23102&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/NdgvXFqpuxg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thomas P. Zwaka</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Wilhelm et al. reply</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/l57yDkMiE7I/nature22294"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22294</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 E23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22294&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22294&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/l57yDkMiE7I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mathias Wilhelm</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Can we predict protein from mRNA levels?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/g-NldABHMmU/nature22293"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22293</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 E19 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22293&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22293&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/g-NldABHMmU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nikolaus Fortelny</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Good news</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CIjlH98udwM/547486a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547486a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A global success?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 486 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547486a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547486a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CIjlH98udwM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jack McDevitt</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Imaging: History's take on the atomic forge</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/d31jTU0366U/547403e"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403e</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/d31jTU0366U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Isaacson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Thirty Meter Telescope: Alternative telescope site is a good back-up</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6F_kHLplC7Q/547403d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403d</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6F_kHLplC7Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sergio Bonaque-González</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Biodiversity: Factor in species' conservation value</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oCWs-gS0f0Y/547403c"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403c</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oCWs-gS0f0Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Axel Hochkirch</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Open data: support from Swiss funder</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/czS-XuUQdjg/547403b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403b</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/czS-XuUQdjg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthias Egger</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Open data: enforce materials sharing</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/kv43JOAQyYY/547403a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/kv43JOAQyYY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Joanne Kamens</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">In retrospect: Das Kapital</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PIxwuTXtaL0/547401a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547401a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As the world is reshaped by another industrial revolution, Gareth Stedman Jones revisits Karl Marx's opus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 401 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547401a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547401a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PIxwuTXtaL0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gareth Stedman Jones</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Climate change: Al Gore gets inconvenient again</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/fvlBdGNDy-c/547400a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547400a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Michael Mann views the US statesman's second film probing climate change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 400 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547400a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547400a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/fvlBdGNDy-c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael E. Mann</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Most football players who donated their brains to science had traumatic injury</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-football-players-who-donated-their-brains-science-had-traumatic-injury"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-football-players-who-donated-their-brains-science-had-traumatic-injury</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T20:28:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A self-selected sample of 202 deceased football players, the largest to date, finds that the majority suffered from chronic traumatic encephalopathy.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Add penis bacteria to the list of HIV risk factors</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/add-penis-bacteria-list-hiv-risk-factors"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/add-penis-bacteria-list-hiv-risk-factors</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T16:33:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Certain bacteria found on the penis raise the risk of HIV infection, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How earthquake scientists eavesdrop on North Korea’s nuclear blasts</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earthquakes-north-korea-nuclear-testing"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earthquakes-north-korea-nuclear-testing</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers monitor the power and location of underground nuclear weapons testing by North Korea.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=3799</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">May the sting be with you: Another journal prank, too good to overlook</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/may-sting-another-journal-prank-good-overlook/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51172</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T14:05:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Yes, yes, we know: It’s easy to publish “fake” papers in journals and expose the inherent flaws of academic publishing. We’ve covered many such stings, but there are simply too many for us to cover all.  Still, occasionally one is just too clever to ignore. On Saturday, the pseudonymous blogger Neuroskeptic announced that they had […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/may-sting-another-journal-prank-good-overlook/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;May the sting be with you: Another journal prank, too good to overlook&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Uni dings schizophrenia studies for problems with informed consent, other flaws</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/uni-dings-schizophrenia-studies-problems-informed-consent-flaws/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51149</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T12:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Psychiatry journals have retracted two papers evaluating a schizophrenia drug after a university in Japan flagged issues, such as a lack of written informed consent. The papers—published in Human Psychopharmacology: Clinical &amp;amp; Experimental in 2012 and Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences in 2014—examined the safety and effectiveness of an antipsychotic drug in patients with schizophrenia. According […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/uni-dings-schizophrenia-studies-problems-informed-consent-flaws/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Uni dings schizophrenia studies for problems with informed consent, other flaws&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">There’s a long way to go in understanding the brain</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/neuroscience-understanding-brain"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/neuroscience-understanding-brain</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Neuroscientists offer multiple “perspectives” on how to plug gaps in current knowledge of the brain’s inner workings.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">CiteScore highlights top-cited journals neglected by other metrics</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-highlights-top-cited-journals-neglected-by-other-metrics"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-highlights-top-cited-journals-neglected-by-other-metrics</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T09:48:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 CiteScore is the only metric for more than 200 top-quality academic journals from numerous publishers</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Your face gives clues to your name, suggesting your name has affected your appearance</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/25/your-face-gives-clues-to-your-name-suggesting-your-name-has-affected-your-appearance/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27296</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T08:54:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_27320&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-07-25 09.49.22&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-27320 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27320&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-07-25 09.49.22&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=732&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;732,674&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/25/your-face-gives-clues-to-your-name-suggesting-your-name-has-affected-your-appearance/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22/&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=276&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Example of test material from &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2017-08698-001.html&quot;&gt;Zwebner et al&lt;/a&gt;. See footer for correct name.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we tell about someone from their face? Their favoured facial expressions can hint at their temperament, the weathering of their skin at their life history, their facial hair and makeup at their aesthetic taste. But now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-08698-001&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;i&gt;Attitudes and Social Cognition&lt;/i&gt; suggests that we can also intuit their names, because a person’s given name influences their facial appearance in adult life. On the face of it (sorry) this is hard to believe, but the case, made across eight studies, is based on plenty of careful evidence, and also proposes a plausible explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27296&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first of several experiments, Yonat Zwebner at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem and his team showed student participants 20 colour headshots of a person with a neutral expression and asked them to choose which of five given names they would assign to each face based on sheer intuition. The given names included the true name of the person in the photo and four alternatives. When participants picked the name that genuinely belonged to the photo’s subject, they were scored as correct. Chance performance (i.e. random guessing) would mean getting 20 per cent correct, on average, but the participants performed better, at 28 per cent. For 17 of the 20 faces they achieved greater accuracy than you’d expect based on random guessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another study was similar but this time Zwebner and his colleagues used photos only belonging to people from an Ashkenazi Israeli ethnic background and who were in their mid-twenties, and the mix of actual and filler names were all drawn from the same ethnic population (the intention was that this would avoid potential confounds due to participants choosing the correct name because of extrapolation from the name or ethnicity). This study also threw in a control condition – participants had the same menu of names to pick from, but the photos were covered up – the idea was to check whether participants’ were being drawn to the correct names because they were for some reason simply more pickable. In fact, participants in the control condition showed no tendency towards picking the true names, whereas participants who could see the photos managed an average face-name matching accuracy of 25 per cent (again better than you’d expect if they’d just guessed at random).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In further studies, the researchers made sure they took account of the possible influence of the relative popularity of different names. They also conducted a replication in France with photos of French people and featuring French names. Whatever changes they made, the researchers found the same thing: based purely on the appearance of someone’s face, participants had an inkling of their name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same proved true when the researchers programmed a computer to match names to faces. Through machine learning processes using a training set of nearly 100,000 faces drawn from an online networking site, a computer programme learned to distinguish between true and false names of faces at better than chance levels. The data was rich enough to evaluate specific comparisons, so we know that in this dataset the algorithm found it impossible to tell from her photo whether a woman was called Emilie as opposed to Jeannie, but found it almost no trouble to tell whether another woman was called Emma rather than Veronique (in this case achieving 95 per cent accuracy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s going on? One possibility is that we give babies names that somehow reflect their physical properties, and observers are simply drawing on these same associations to guide their judgments. This would be an example of the wonderfully titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bouba/kiki_effect&quot;&gt;bouba-kiki effect&lt;/a&gt;, wherein across cultures certain sounds seem soft or round, others hard or sharp. However this seems a bit of a reach, given that at the time most babies are named, they are still pretty similar-looking (sorry parents).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, when the researchers looked for cross-cultural effects by testing Israeli students with French stimuli and vice-versa, they found none: the participants lost the ability to match names at better than chance levels. If the bouba-kiki effects was behind it, the feel of the names – independent of their cultural meaning – would be sufficient to make the associations. So &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/2017/02/27/dorian-gray-effect-name-alters-face/&quot;&gt;despite some earlier coverage&lt;/a&gt;, this isn’t a compelling explanation for the new data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zwebner and his team think it is likelier that their findings reflect some sort of self-fulfilling prophecy. Within a given culture, names carry associations – historical and celebrity figures, “types” (a Kevin versus a Brad), and cues related to class or background (contrast Tony with Tristan). Once a person is named, these associations form a filter through which all their future interactions take place – starting with parental guidance and expectations, then first encounters with schoolyard peers, career guidance counselling – and even if the filter is a subtle one, over a lifetime these effects can accumulate to impact how we act in the world, and ultimately this ends up written in our faces –  by our preference for smiles over frowns, big mugging expressions over wry understated ones, or an open relaxed visage rather than one tight-lipped and controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this explanation is correct, we’d expect to see a stronger influence of names upon those parts of the face and appearance that are more under voluntary control. Consistent with this, in one study the researchers found that removing hair style (arguably one of the aspects of our appearance over which we have most control) from the photos significant reduced participants’ ability to identify the correct names for the photos, though they still performed better than chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate this more deeply, Zwebner’s team turned to their algorithm, investigating which pixels of each photo were most useful in making accurate name-matches, and using this data to create heat-maps of the faces. These clearly showed the margins of the faces (aside from hair itself) were next to useless and the nose and ears were also of limited value. The most important facial areas for correct name identification were the brows, eyes and mouth – areas that are habitually engaged in voluntary facial expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests that the effect due to given names is an extension of the Dorian Grey effect, the phenomenon where personality influences facial appearance. In terms of links between facial appearance and personality, we already know that short-tempered people tense certain facial muscles more frequently than do relaxed people, which can make their resting face appear angry, for example. Or that adolescent women who are more sociable are perceived as more attractive later in life, presumably because smile lines are construed as more attractive than a tight-set face.  The bundle of associations that make Celina’s name reflected in her face are arguably doing the same thing, but through a more circuitous route (for example, the name label leading to differential treatment that then contributes to personality, and finally onto the face), which would explain why the effects were statistically significant but not large in size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re struggling to pick the ideal appellation for your newborn, these new findings suggest that on top of everything else you have to worry about, your decision will likely influence what they look like as an adult – but only to a small extent. If you want to predict their future appearance, you won’t find the answers by gazing at their potential namesakes. But you might get a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-08698-001&quot;&gt;We look like our names: The manifestation of name stereotypes in facial appearance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2017-08698-001.html&quot;&gt;Zwebner et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;. The correct name for this example is Dan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27296/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27296/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27296&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Australia cuts conservation protections in marine parks</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5Ci3v8G1Xvc/nature.2017.22369"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22369</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Conservationists accuse government of ignoring science-based recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22369&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22369&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5Ci3v8G1Xvc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nicky Phillips</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Metrology is key to reproducing results</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/l-YzDMPYbF8/547397a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547397a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists of all stripes must work with measurement experts so that studies can be compared, urge Martyn Sené, Ian Gilmore and Jan-Theodoor Janssen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 397 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547397a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547397a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/l-YzDMPYbF8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Martyn Sené</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Budding UK innovation agency gains cash — and clout</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/jH6EQ9SFRsQ/547390a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547390a</id>
		<updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Business-focused funding agency Innovate UK is driving British efforts to commercialize research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 390 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547390a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547390a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/jH6EQ9SFRsQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Making Contact’ chronicles an astronomer’s struggle to find E.T.</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/making-contact-chronicles-astronomers-struggles-find-aliens"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/making-contact-chronicles-astronomers-struggles-find-aliens</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T20:33:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 For decades, astronomer Jill Tarter led the hunt for extraterrestrial intelligence, as detailed in a new biography.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Following uproar, surgery journal retracts paper with male-only pronouns</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/following-uproar-surgery-journal-retracts-paper-male-pronouns/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51164</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T17:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The Annals of Surgery has retracted a paper that used only male pronouns to describe surgeons following outcry from readers. The journal plans to replace the article — a recent presidential address of the European Surgical Association — with a new version with more “gender inclusive language.” The problem, said editor Keith D. Lillemoe, is that […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/following-uproar-surgery-journal-retracts-paper-male-pronouns/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Following uproar, surgery journal retracts paper with male-only pronouns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Nootropics: How Smart Can You Get on Smart Drugs?</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/24/nootropics-how-smart-you-can-get-on-smart-drugs/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22686</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T15:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;The use of smart drugs is becoming “trendy”. Lots of people are taking various substances regularly, many others try them from time to time. The idea of enhancing the brain’s ability, or tapping into its unused reservoir is definitely sexy, and many people are actively looking for information on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shortage of scientifically verified information is exactly the reason I’m writing this article. Although thousand of publications on “&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/18/memory-enhancement-nootropics-and-electromagnetic-stimulation/&quot;&gt;smart drugs&lt;/a&gt;”, “cognitive enhancers”, and “nootropics” etc. can be found online, the overwhelming majority of claims are unsubstantiated or unashamedly commercialized. This means that the info you come across mostly consists of descriptions of personal opinions or experiences, or compilations of facts published elsewhere, or just articles from popular media where people can write whatever they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple websites publish all kind of rubbish just to convince you to buy yet another wonderfully effective smart drug. Few people make an effort to refer to their sources of information, not to mention to present scientific and statistical data backing their claims. This is particularly enigmatic when these articles provide recipes for various drug combinations and claim the superiority of some of these combinations/compounds over the others. However, even scientific data on the subject is rather incomplete. Many studies were done using only a small number of participants, or in the absence of any reasonable controls. On their own, studies of such kind are of little, if any, value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, several systematic reviews and meta-analyses on the use of nootropics were published in the last couple of years. Systematic reviews and meta-analyses combine data from multiple individual studies, thus making the data statistically significant. This is a better way of assessing the efficacy of different drugs in the general, healthy population, and these are the publications that I will mostly use as reference points in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to prove that a smart drug is really smart?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart drugs (e.g., nootropics and cognitive enhancers) are defined as substances that improve cognitive function, particularly executive functions, memory, creativity, or motivation, in &lt;u&gt;healthy individuals&lt;/u&gt;. The last bit is important: there are many drugs that were specifically developed to enhance brain functions in people with various cognitive disorders or deficits. Such drugs won’t necessarily smarten up healthy people, and when they do, they are not necessarily safe. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/01/29/nootropics-reduce-the-severity-of-brain-trauma/&quot;&gt;Nootropics &lt;/a&gt;may come in many forms, from classical pharmaceutics in the form of pills to herbal supplements and “functional foods”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only few smart drugs that are proven to improve some aspects of cognition. Proving that a compound has the properties of a nootropic is not a simple task. There is no straightforward way of measuring whatever cognitive enhancement you may experience once the pill is taken. The drug may indeed work and visibly increase your productivity. But it may also simply improve your mood if you anticipate a positive effect. On top of this, any given drug may work for some people and not work for others. Furthermore, the use of any drug is associated with potential side effects (e.g., headaches) that might eliminate its advantages in productivity and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/12/14/decoding-creativity-its-in-the-genes/&quot;&gt;creativity&lt;/a&gt;. If the changes in productivity can be measured using some tests, creativity still remains something arguably impossible to quantify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How smart drugs work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several mechanisms that can be involved in the functioning of smart drugs. Some drugs can increase the blood flow (and thus oxygen supply) to the brain. Others can accelerate neuronal communication through increased release of certain neuromediators or through agonistic effects on the receptors of these neuromediators. Some compounds can serve as biochemical precursors of neuromediators, others may prevent oxidative damage to brain cells or provide them with a source of energy. Some of these changes can be achieved quickly making the drugs work almost instantly. Others, such as amendment/prevention of neuronal damage, manifest themselves only after prolonged use of the drug, thus making any changes in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/15/brain-training-can-we-really-enhance-our-cognitive-skills/&quot;&gt;cognitive functions&lt;/a&gt; not so fast and not so obvious (although they can still be substantial).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short overview of most popular nootropics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/18/memory-enhancement-nootropics-and-electromagnetic-stimulation/&quot;&gt;Amphetamines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are a class of pharmaceuticals that include &lt;strong&gt;adderall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;dextroamphetamine&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;lisdexamphetamine&lt;/strong&gt;. The drugs were developed to treat people with ADHD (attention deficit hyperactivity disorder) and this is where their effects are the most prominent. The drugs were also demonstrated to improve episodic memory, working memory, and some aspects of attention in the general population. At low doses they improve memory consolidation, recall of information, and motivation to perform tasks that require high degree of attention. &lt;strong&gt;Ritalin&lt;/strong&gt; is structurally different from amphetamines and works through different mechanisms, although produces similar effects. Both amphetamines and ritalin improve cognitive functions, albeit only at lower doses. At high doses they stimulate other neural pathways not involved in learning that effectively cancel their positive effects on cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wakefulness-promoting agents&lt;/strong&gt;, such as &lt;strong&gt;modafinil&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;armodafinil&lt;/strong&gt;, increase alertness, counteract fatigue, and increase productivity and motivation. Modafinil is praised for its ability to improve reaction time, logical reasoning, and problem-solving. The drug is clinically prescribed  for a number of conditions including sleep apnea, narcolepsy, and shift work sleep disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compounds from the &lt;strong&gt;racetam family&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;piracetam, oxiracetam&lt;/strong&gt; etc.) are more extensively studied compared than the newer nootropics. Piracetam was developed back in the 1960s and has an almost perfect safety profile. Convincingly, it was shown to improve cognitive abilities, particularly in older people and those with cognitive impairment. Although piracetam is officially recognized as a nootropic, its brain-enhancing effects in healthy people are considered to be moderate. There is a number of other derivatives from this group of drugs which, allegedly, work better. A good example is &lt;strong&gt;phenotropil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; This compound was developed in Russia where it is available as a prescription drug. It was demonstrated to have a memory enhancing effect. The drug can be used as a stimulant and enhances resistance to extreme temperatures and stress. Due to its stimulating effect, phenotropil is banned by the World Anti-Doping Agency, which means that it cannot be used by athletes intending to compete in official events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xanthines, such as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/26/nurturing-the-brain-part-i-caffeine/&quot;&gt;caffeine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, are some of the most commonly used compounds with nootropic effects. In particular, they increase alertness and performance levels. Caffeine is not what comes to mind when we think of nootropics, but apparently its effect is comparable to many pharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L-Theanine&lt;/strong&gt;, a chemical component of green tea, is very well studied and its effects on promoting alertness and attention are confirmed by multiple research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to nutraceuticals and herbal supplements, recent studies appear to be contradictory. Some data do support the memory-enhancing effects of such plants as &lt;em&gt;Gingko biloba&lt;/em&gt;, Asian ginseng, and &lt;em&gt;Bacopa monnieri&lt;/em&gt;, but systematic reviews do not find convincing evidence of their effectiveness. It is likely that herbal supplements may work well over longer periods of time and improve cognitive abilities, but in the short term their effects are not particularly obvious. The same applies to many vitamins, such as vitamin E and B group vitamins, as well as Omega-3 fatty acids: the evidence supporting their benefits are limited at the present time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, only few drugs are scientifically proven to be associated with moderate cognitive enhancement effects in the healthy population. Being sceptical when assessing information on smart drugs from the internet is a good idea: lots of ridiculous rubbish is published online. Most nootropics are relatively safe, but side effects are always a possibility since the response to nootropics is highly individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer BC et al. (2015) The Cognition-Enhancing Effects of Psychostimulants Involve Direct Action in the Prefrontal Cortex. Biological Psychiatry 77, 940–950. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016%2Fj.biopsych.2014.09.013&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.09.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilieva IP et al. (2015) Prescription Stimulants’ Effects on Healthy Inhibitory Control, Working Memory, and Episodic Memory: A Meta-analysis. J Cogn Neurosci. 27, 1069-1089. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1162%2Fjocn_a_00776&quot;&gt;10.1162/jocn_a_00776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagot KS and Kaminer Y (2014) Efficacy of stimulants for cognitive enhancement in non-attention deficit hyperactivity disorder youth: a systematic review. Addiction 109, 547–557. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1111%2Fadd.12460&quot;&gt;10.1111/add.12460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linssen AMW et al. (2014) Cognitive effects of methylphenidate in healthy volunteers: a review of single dose studies. &lt;em&gt;Int J Neuropsychopharmacol&lt;/em&gt; 17, 961-977. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1017%2FS1461145713001594&quot;&gt;10.1017/S1461145713001594&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban KR and Gao WJ (2014) Performance enhancement at the cost of potential brain plasticity: neural ramifications of nootropic drugs in the healthy developing brain. Front. Syst. Neurosci.| &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2014.00038&quot;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnsys.2014.00038&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winblad B (2005) Piracetam: a review of pharmacological properties and clinical uses. CNS Drug Rev. 11, 169-182. PMID:16007238&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zvejniece L et al. (2011) Investigation into Stereoselective Pharmacological Activity of Phenotropil. Basic &amp;amp; Clinical Pharmacology &amp;amp; Toxicology 109, 407–412. doi: 10.1111/j.1742-7843.2011.00742.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogers PJ (2007) Caffeine, mood and mental performance in everyday life. Nutrition Bulletin 32, 84–89. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-3010.2007.00607.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camfield DA et al. (2014) Acute effects of tea constituents L-theanine, caffeine, and epigallocatechin gallate on cognitive function and mood: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev 72, 507-522. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/nure.12120&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/nure.12120&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Pexels-2286921/&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">NIH section chief with 19 retractions is no longer running a lab</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/nih-section-chief-19-retractions-no-longer-running-lab/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51156</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T15:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A former section chief at the National Institutes of Health who has had 19 papers retracted is no longer running a lab, Retraction Watch has learned. In the last three years, Stanley Rapoport, who is based at the U.S. National Institute on Aging (NIA), has lost 19 papers due to the misconduct of three different […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/nih-section-chief-19-retractions-no-longer-running-lab/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NIH section chief with 19 retractions is no longer running a lab&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fewer big rogue planets roam the galaxy, recount shows</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fewer-big-rogue-planets-roam-galaxy-recount-shows"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fewer-big-rogue-planets-roam-galaxy-recount-shows</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T15:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Jupiter-mass planets without parent solar systems are less common than astronomers thought, a new study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T11:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A Publishing Milestone to Celebrate: 200,000 PLOS Research Articles and Counting</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/0EQ7vKTIN-4/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7673</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T15:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/200K-blog-post-image-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2003, PLOS published its first research article and this month we’re proud to announce that we have now published more than 200,000 research articles across our seven Open Access journals. It has been an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;amazing journey &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;to reach this milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In only 14 years of existence, PLOS has helped catalyze the rapid growth of the Open Access literature. The 200,000th article is a remarkable milestone for PLOS and for the scientific community that has supported the Open Access movement.”-Veronique Kiermer, PLOS Executive Editor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d like to take this opportunity to thank those who have helped rapidly create this large corpus of diverse, Open Access research:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nearly 1,000,000 authors who trusted PLOS to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/why-publish-with-plos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;maximize the accessibility and readership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of their research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/03/thank-you-from-plos/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7,000 editorial board members and 70,000+ volunteer peer reviewers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;each year for their contribution to making PLOS journals’ content strong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thousands of journalists who &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/press-kit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report on trusted PLOS content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online readers of our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/innovation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;organization’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who have made &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; one of the 50 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexa.com/topsites/category/Science&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most-visited science websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, creating a global audience for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/2016-research-highlights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS journal content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/open-access-funds&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Funders and institutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; all over the world who supported publication of this rich body of research under a model that provides unrestriced access to all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS was incorporated in 2001 as an Open Access advocacy organization and became a publisher to prove the value of Open Access, beginning with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in 2003 and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in 2004 as open alternatives to prestigious subscription journals. In 2005, PLOS launched &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as proof of concept to show that research communities built around and across specific areas and disciplines could thrive with an Open Access model. In late December 2006, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; spearheaded the innovative editorial approach focused on evaluation of research independent of perceived impact; this editorial approach has now been adopted by journals from nearly every scientific publisher. Since its founding, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; has published more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/search?filterJournals=PLoSONE&amp;amp;filterArticleTypes=Research+Article&amp;amp;q=publication_date%3A%5B2001-01-01T00%3A00%3A00Z%20TO%202017-07-19T23%3A59%3A59Z%5D&amp;amp;page=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;175,000 research articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; based on three compelling features: advancing quality science for everyone, moving publication forward in all scientific disciplines, and favoring speed to publication over subjective assessment of significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, with the support of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, PLOS launched a fourth community journal, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;. Together with the journal’s leadership and global community, we now proudly celebrate the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ntds-10th-anniversary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;10th Anniversary of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ntds-10th-anniversary&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS NTDs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/search?filterJournals=PLoSNTD&amp;amp;filterArticleTypes=Research+Article&amp;amp;q=publication_date%3A%5B2001-01-01T00%3A00%3A00Z%20TO%202017-07-19T23%3A59%3A59Z%5D&amp;amp;page=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4,500 research articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that contribute to advances in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Access continues to gain momentum but there is further work to be done. At PLOS, we are constantly looking for ways to use emerging technology and new ideas to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/04/placing-authors-at-the-center-of-the-scientific-endeavor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open up scientific communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;—to make it faster, more efficient, more connected and more useful. We look forward to the next 200,000 articles and continued involvement with the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/0EQ7vKTIN-4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T23:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s a clever demonstration of how we simulate the mental experiences of story characters</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/24/heres-a-clever-demonstration-of-how-we-simulate-the-mental-experiences-of-story-characters/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27197</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T12:40:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-629579800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27286&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27286&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman, 30s, at home,reading, book, resting, one person,  bedroom&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1481718820&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Eva Katalin Kondoros&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Beautiful young woman at home&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Beautiful young woman at home&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/24/heres-a-clever-demonstration-of-how-we-simulate-the-mental-experiences-of-story-characters/beautiful-young-woman-at-home/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avid readers of novels know that they often take the perspective of the characters they read about. But just how far does this mental role-playing go? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0749596X16300997?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Memory and Language&lt;/em&gt; has provided a clever demonstration of how readily we simulate the thoughts of fictional characters. Borrowing a method from research into the psychology of deliberate forgetting, the researchers at Binghamton University, USA, show that when a story character needs to focus on remembering one series of words rather than another, the reader simulates this same memory process in their own minds. The character’s mental experience becomes the reader’s mental experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27197&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experiment, Danielle Gunraj and her colleagues asked about 100 undergrads to read a vignette about Nadia and Lyle, who’d just moved from New York to North Dakota. Nadia decides to go shopping for their new place and makes a list of 15 items to buy from an emporium (the vignette then details the list of items). Half the participants then read that Nadia changed her mind and that she drew up a new list of items (again these are listed) to buy at Walmart. The other half the participants read that Nadia decided to go to both the emporium and Walmart to buy both lists of items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively, this is an implicit version of an established memory test used in research into deliberate forgetting: half the participants had been cued that Nadia needed to forget the first list and focus on remembering the second; the other participants had been cued that both lists should be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the vignette, Gunraj’s team gave the participants a surprise test of their memory for the two lists of items. They wanted to see how much they had simulated Nadia’s thought processes, depending on the version of the story they read. The key finding was that participants who read the version in which Nadia decided not to go the emporium and to only get the items at Walmart showed superior memory for the Walmart list compared with the participants who read the other story version. Although they didn’t show forgetting of the first, emporium list, it’s as if the Walmart-only participants had deliberately focused on remembering the second, Walmart list, just as their version of Nadia needed to do. “We conclude that Nadia’s memory experience influenced readers’ mental experience,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A follow-up experiment was similar but this time undergrads read one of two versions of a vignette about a Frenchman Pierre who was learning English and had to study a list of 15 English words for an exam. In one version, he realises he has studied the wrong list and must study a new list of 15 more words instead. In the other version, he suddenly realises he needs to study the new list as well as the old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, when the participants were given a surprise memory test for both the lists, their performance again depended on the story version they’d read. The participants who read the version in which Pierre realised he’d initially studied the wrong list showed superior memory for the second list as compared with the participants who read the other story version. Again, the participants seem to have simulated the memory processes of the fictional character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are intriguing effects, although reading a short vignette in a psychology lab is of course quite different from being immersed in a literary novel. However, arguably we should expect the memory simulation effects uncovered in this research to be even more powerful for engrossing novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another potential caveat relates to the task instructions. Although participants were surprised by the specific nature of the memory tests, and they weren’t given any explicit instructions to remember or forget the two lists, they were told to “read the passage from Nadia’s (or Pierre’s) perspective. Try to imagine what she is thinking and doing as you read. Furthermore, try to keep track of the details that are important to Nadia (Pierre). After reading the passage you will be asked to recall details from Nadia’s experience”. It’s not clear how much readers would have spontaneously simulated the characters’ memory processes without these instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Regardless of the exact mechanisms involved, we can conclude that readers’ mental representation was influenced by their understanding of the story character’s cognitive processes,” the researchers said. Their findings add to past research that’s shown how we automatically simulate the content of the stories we read: for instance, we are better at &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BF03194927&quot;&gt;remembering a story character’s current location compared with their past location&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BF03196313&quot;&gt;we’re quicker to make bodily movements that resemble character’s actions&lt;/a&gt; described in written sentences, as if we simulate their described actions in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0749596X16300997?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Simulating a story character’s thoughts: Evidence from the directed forgetting task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27197/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27197/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27197&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-07-31T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Work by group at Australian university faces scrutiny</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/work-group-australian-university-faces-scrutiny/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51139</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T12:00:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A journal is investigating research by a group in Australia, after receiving “serious allegations” regarding a 2017 paper about treating eye burns. The journal, Frontiers in Pharmacology, has issued an expression of concern (EOC) for the 2017 paper while it investigates. The notice does not specify the nature of the allegations.  Meanwhile, several other papers […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/work-group-australian-university-faces-scrutiny/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Work by group at Australian university faces scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Radioactive substances leave electron ‘fingerprints’ behind</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/radioactive-substances-leave-electron-fingerprints-behind"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/radioactive-substances-leave-electron-fingerprints-behind</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new method of nuclear forensics could make it harder to handle radioactive material in secret.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_5419294436825012=0.5367889236834835</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Channel opening and gating mechanism in AMPA-subtype glutamate receptors</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ioavAfp-1V8/nature23479"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23479</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 AMPA-subtype ionotropic glutamate receptors mediate fast excitatory neurotransmission throughout the central nervous system. Gated by the neurotransmitter glutamate, AMPA receptors are critical for synaptic strength and dysregulation of AMPA receptor-mediated signalling is linked to numerous neurological diseases. Here, we use cryo-electron microscopy to solve the structures of AMPA receptor-auxiliary subunit complexes in the apo, antagonist and agonist-bound states and elucidate the iris-like mechanism of ion channel opening. The ion channel selectivity filter is formed by the extended portions of the re-entrant M2 loops, while the helical portions of M2 contribute to extensive hydrophobic interfaces between AMPA receptor subunits in the ion channel. We show how the permeation pathway changes upon channel opening and identify conformational changes throughout the entire AMPA receptor that accompany activation and desensitization. Our findings provide a framework for understanding gating across the family of ionotropic glutamate receptors and the role of AMPA receptors in excitatory neurotransmission. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23479&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ioavAfp-1V8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edward C. Twomey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Glutamate receptor-like channels are essential for chemotaxis and reproduction in mosses</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/7CUiwVn0_9Q/nature23478"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23478</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Glutamate receptors are well characterized channels that mediate cell-to-cell communication during neurotransmission in animals. Nevertheless, information regarding their functional role in organisms without nervous systems is still limited. In plants, Glutamate Receptor-like (GLR) genes have been implicated in defence against pathogens, reproduction, control of stomata aperture and light signal transduction1–5. However, the numerous GLR genes present in angiosperm genomes (20 to 70)6 has prevented the observation of strong phenotypes in loss-of-function mutants. Here, we show that in the moss Physcomitrella patens, a basal land plant, mutation of GLR genes cause sperm failure in targeting the female reproductive organs. In addition, we show that GLR genes encode non-selective Ca2+ permeable channels that can regulate cytoplasmic Ca2+ and are needed to induce the expression of a BELL1-like transcription factor essential for zygote development. Our work reveals novel functions for GLRs in sperm chemotaxis and transcriptional regulation. Sperm chemotaxis is essential for fertilization in both animals and early land plants like bryophytes and pteridophytes. Therefore, our results are suggestive that ionotropic glutamate receptors may have been conserved throughout plant evolution to mediate cell-to-cell communication during sexual reproduction. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23478&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23478&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/7CUiwVn0_9Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carlos Ortiz-Ramírez</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">cGAS surveillance of micronuclei links genome instability to innate immunity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/AlgcIhmiC88/nature23449"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23449</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 DNA is strictly compartmentalized within the nucleus to prevent autoimmunity; despite this, cyclic GMP–AMP synthase (cGAS), a cytosolic sensor of double-stranded DNA, is activated in autoinflammatory disorders and by DNA damage. Precisely how cellular DNA gains access to the cytoplasm remains to be determined. Here, we report that cGAS localizes to micronuclei arising from genome instability in a mouse model of monogenic autoinflammation, after exogenous DNA damage and spontaneously in human cancer cells. Such micronuclei occur after mis-segregation of DNA during cell division and consist of chromatin surrounded by its own nuclear membrane. Breakdown of the micronuclear envelope, a process associated with chromothripsis, leads to rapid accumulation of cGAS, providing a mechanism by which self-DNA becomes exposed to the cytosol. cGAS is activated by chromatin, and consistent with a mitotic origin, micronuclei formation and the proinflammatory response following DNA damage are cell-cycle dependent. By combining live-cell laser microdissection with single cell transcriptomics, we establish that interferon-stimulated gene expression is induced in micronucleated cells. We therefore conclude that micronuclei represent an important source of immunostimulatory DNA. As micronuclei formed from lagging chromosomes also activate this pathway, recognition of micronuclei by cGAS may act as a cell-intrinsic immune surveillance mechanism that detects a range of neoplasia-inducing processes. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23449&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23449&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/AlgcIhmiC88&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Karen J. Mackenzie</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Elements of Eoarchean life trapped in mineral inclusions</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/IvTz3P-RsEM/nature23261"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23261</id>
		<updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Metasedimentary rocks from Isua, West Greenland (over 3,700 million years old) contain 13C-depleted carbonaceous compounds, with isotopic ratios that are compatible with a biogenic origin. Metamorphic garnet crystals in these rocks contain trails of carbonaceous inclusions that are contiguous with carbon-rich sedimentary beds in the host rock, where carbon is fully graphitized. Previous studies have not been able to document other elements of life (mainly hydrogen, oxygen, nitrogen and phosphorus) structurally bound to this carbonaceous material. Here we study carbonaceous inclusions armoured within garnet porphyroblasts, by in situ infrared absorption on approximately 10−21 m3 domains within these inclusions. We show that the absorption spectra are consistent with carbon bonded to nitrogen and oxygen, and probably also to phosphate. The levels of C–H or O–H bonds were found to be low. These results are consistent with biogenic organic material isolated for billions of years and thermally matured at temperatures of around 500 °C. They therefore provide spatial characterization for potentially the oldest biogenic carbon relics in Earth’s geological record. The preservation of Eoarchean organic residues within sedimentary material corroborates earlier claims for the biogenic origins of carbon in Isua metasediments. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23261&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23261&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/IvTz3P-RsEM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>T. Hassenkam</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-07-28T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This history book offers excellent images but skimps on modern science</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/history-book-offers-excellent-images-skimps-modern-science"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/history-book-offers-excellent-images-skimps-modern-science</id>
		<updated>2017-07-23T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 For an accessible account of mostly pre-20th century science, check out The Oxford Illustrated History of Science.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2247</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: 10 rules for research misconduct; peer review’s black box; the rich get richer</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/22/weekend-reads-10-rules-research-misconduct-peer-reviews-black-box-rich-get-richer/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51152</id>
		<updated>2017-07-22T13:36:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured authors making a difficult decision to retract once-promising findings about gliobastoma, and sanctions for a researcher in whose lab image manipulations were found. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “So, here we are! You’ve decided to join the dark side of Science. That’s great!” Ten Simple Rules for Scientific Fraud &amp;amp; […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/22/weekend-reads-10-rules-research-misconduct-peer-reviews-black-box-rich-get-richer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: 10 rules for research misconduct; peer review’s black box; the rich get richer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T17:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Predatory Journals Hit By 'Star Wars' Sting</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8981"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8981</id>
		<updated>2017-07-22T09:57:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A number of so-called scientific journals have accepted a Star Wars-themed spoof paper. The manuscript is an absurd mess of factual errors, plagiarism and movie quotes. I know because I wrote it.

Inspired by previous publishing &quot;stings&quot;, I wanted to test whether 'predatory' journals would publish an obviously absurd paper. So I created a spoof manuscript about &quot;midi-chlorians&quot; - the fictional entities which live inside cells and give Jedi their powers in Star Wars. I filled it with other refe</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-07-29T23:00:23+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fire ants build towers with three simple rules</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/fire-ants-build-towers-three-simple-rules"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/fire-ants-build-towers-three-simple-rules</id>
		<updated>2017-07-21T18:54:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fire ants use the same set of simple rules to produce static rafts and perpetually moving towers.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Zielinski</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2247</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-07-27T17:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Months after neuroscientist flagged errors, Nature journal corrects them — and more</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/months-neuroscientist-flagged-errors-nature-journal-corrects/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51143</id>
		<updated>2017-07-21T14:30:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When a neuroscientist noticed there were problems with his January 2017 paper in Nature Neuroscience, he didn’t wait for the journal to take action — instead, he published his concerns about four figures on PubMed Commons. Months later, the journal has issued formal corrections to those figures — along with several more.    In February […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/months-neuroscientist-flagged-errors-nature-journal-corrects/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Months after neuroscientist flagged errors, Nature journal corrects them — and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-07-26T17:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">“I was skeptical at first, but now I firmly believe in agile”</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/i-was-skeptical-at-first-but-now-i-firmly-believe-in-agile"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/i-was-skeptical-at-first-but-now-i-firmly-believe-in-agile</id>
		<updated>2017-07-21T13:51:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Two years after Newsflo joined Elsevier, its small team has been expanding its technology and influence in a big way</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-07-30T17:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
