<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Supreme Court nominee Gorsuch lifted from earlier works in his scholarly papers: Report</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/supreme-court-nominee-gorsuch-lifted-earlier-works-scholarly-papers-report/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49200</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T18:00:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;U.S. Supreme Court nominee Neil Gorsuch appears to have borrowed material from multiple authors in his 2006 book, according to a new analysis by Politico. This week, U.S. lawmakers are going head-to-head over the nomination of Gorsuch to the highest court in the land. Although the book is only one snippet of Gorsuch’s vast portfolio […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/supreme-court-nominee-gorsuch-lifted-earlier-works-scholarly-papers-report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Supreme Court nominee Gorsuch lifted from earlier works in his scholarly papers: Report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Language heard, but never spoken, by young babies bestows a hidden benefit</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/language-heard-never-spoken-young-babies-bestows-hidden-benefit"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/language-heard-never-spoken-young-babies-bestows-hidden-benefit</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Adults who as babies heard but never spoke Korean benefited from their latent language knowledge decades later, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Y Combinator launches Science Exchange-powered marketplace to support its companies’ research and development</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/04/y-combinator-launches-science-exchange-powered-marketplace-to-support-its-companies-research-and-development/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1042</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T17:14:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;MOUNTAIN VIEW, CA, USA, 5 March 2017– &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading marketplace for outsourced research and development, today announced a strategic partnership with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycombinator.com/about/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; (YC). YC-backed companies will now have exclusive access to the Science Exchange-powered YC marketplace, where they can instantly order experimental services from a network of over 2,500 qualified scientific service providers, all with pre-established contracts that protect companies’ IP and confidentiality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;YC, best known for its investments in tech giants including Airbnb, Dropbox, and Stripe, began investing in life sciences companies in 2014 as the need and opportunity to fund early stage companies in this space became increasingly apparent. The Science Exchange partnership addresses the unique needs of these R&amp;amp;D-focused companies, enabling them to compete on an equal footing with Science Exchange’s established global pharmaceutical and biotechnology clients by readily accessing the expertise and infrastructure housed in the Science Exchange network of service providers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Science Exchange marketplace will help YC companies:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expand access to qualified service providers. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Life science and biotech entrepreneurs must balance the need to access new, innovative service providers with the time-consuming process required to vet each potential service provider for quality and capability. Science Exchange streamlines this process with a network of over 2,500 service providers that have been pre-qualified through a stringent, ISO 9001-certified evaluation process that includes metrics tied to performance on past projects. Science Exchange additionally supports researchers with an expert Sourcing Team that can recommend the best service providers for each scope of work, further minimizing the risks inherent in outsourcing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eliminate administrative overhead.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Each service provider relationship typically requires a standalone contract that may take months to negotiate and implement. Under the partnership, all service providers on the YC-Science Exchange network are available under a single contract that protects IP and confidentiality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange also eliminates the need for YC-funded companies to conduct costly and time-consuming regulatory audits of service providers. Science Exchange’s in-house audit team conducts on-site inspections of service providers and facilities to ensure regulatory compliance, ensuring that contracted service providers possess necessary certifications, licenses, informed consent of subjects, and data security.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Save money. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Science Exchange-powered YC marketplace enables companies to quickly identify cost-competitive options and provides access to special offers exclusive to YC-funded companies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;YC is the latest organization to choose to partner with Science Exchange, and joins over 30 enterprise clients using Science Exchange-powered marketplaces to manage their outsourced R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“In the last decade, the landscape for biotech firms has changed dramatically,” said Michael Seibel, CEO of Y Combinator. “Bringing a drug to market, which once took millions of dollars and several years of work because of infrastructure costs involved in building a lab, can now happen in a fraction of the time and funding required because of the ability to outsource R&amp;amp;D. YC invested in Science Exchange years ago because we saw the promise of what they were doing to help companies innovate faster, get important products to market quickly, and reduce the friction inherent in starting a business. Now we are excited to offer these benefits to our companies who have brilliant ideas and are meeting urgent market demands, but need the administrative and cost barriers removed so they can focus on their innovations.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“The Science Exchange platform solves the challenge of R&amp;amp;D outsourcing: we provide scientists with efficient access to a network of highly qualified service providers,” said Dr. Elizabeth Iorns, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Science Exchange. “We believe, like Y Combinator, that key to advancing groundbreaking research is eliminating the barriers to innovation, and we are thrilled to help YC-funded companies bring potentially life-saving products to market faster.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Science Exchange&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange is the world’s leading marketplace for outsourced research. Science Exchange provides an efficient procure-to-pay platform for ordering services from the world’s largest network of scientific service providers. Through Science Exchange, clients gain access to over 2,500 qualified service providers, all with pre-established contracts in place that protect client intellectual property and confidentiality. This increases scientists access to innovation and significantly improves their productivity because they are freed up from the administrative tasks and delays associated with sourcing, establishing and managing service provider contracts. At an organizational level, the Science Exchange enterprise program enables organizations to consolidate the long tail of research outsourcing spend into a single strategic relationship driving significant efficiency and cost savings. To date, Science Exchange has raised over $30 million from Maverick Capital Ventures, Union Square Ventures, Index Ventures, OATV, the YC Continuity Fund, and others. For more information visit www.scienceexchange.com.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Y Combinator&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Y Combinator is a startup fund based in Mountain View, CA. In 2005, Y Combinator developed a new model of startup funding. Twice a year they invest a small amount of money in a large number of startups. The startups move to Silicon Valley for 3 months, and the YC partners work closely with each company to get them into the best possible shape and refine their pitch to investors. Each batch culminates in Demo Day, when the startups present their companies to a carefully selected audience of investors. Y Combinator has invested in over 1,464 companies including Airbnb, Dropbox, Stripe, Reddit, Instacart, Docker and Gusto. The combined valuation of YC companies is over $80B.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Diana Truong</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Transforming Scientific Collaboration: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Massive red, dead galaxy spotted in young universe</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/massive-red-dead-galaxy-spotted-young-universe"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/massive-red-dead-galaxy-spotted-young-universe</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A hefty red, dead galaxy may raise questions about how galaxies formed in the early universe.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Star pediatric oncologist committed misconduct, ethical violations: reports</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/star-pediatric-oncologist-committed-misconduct-ethical-violations-reports/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49071</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T15:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A high-profile pediatric oncologist quietly left his former institution in 2015 after it concluded his clinical trials had been affected by significant “administrative problems.” But now the results of the university’s investigations and what followed have become public, after a paper in Belgium published a series of news reports last month. We’re still hazy on some details […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/star-pediatric-oncologist-committed-misconduct-ethical-violations-reports/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Star pediatric oncologist committed misconduct, ethical violations: reports&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">If there are curious young minds, science will survive</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-there-are-curious-young-minds-science-will-survive"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-there-are-curious-young-minds-science-will-survive</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T14:40:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses the unending search for scientific knowledge.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers question mental health research</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-mental-health-research"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-mental-health-research</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T14:39:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Maintaining mental health, protecting ocean critters and more in reader feedback.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The ways that student samples differ from the public varies around the world</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/05/the-ways-that-student-samples-differ-from-the-public-varies-around-the-world/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=22127</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T13:53:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Students sit facing camera in a modern university classroom&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-22252&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;22252&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Students sit facing camera in a modern university classroom&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1470065920&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;monkeybusinessimages&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;24&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Students sit facing camera in a modern university classroom&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Students sit facing camera in a modern university classroom&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-597959396.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-597959396.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-597959396.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/05/the-ways-that-student-samples-differ-from-the-public-varies-around-the-world/students-sit-facing-camera-in-a-modern-university-classroom/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-597959396.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biologists have their fruit flies and rats, psychologists have students. An overwhelming amount of behavioral science is conducted with young people at universities on the assumption that it’s safe to generalise from this species of human to people more generally. There are some common-sense reasons for thinking this might be a problem and also some more specific issues, which we’ve documented before, such as that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/06/10/how-burnt-out-students-could-be-skewing-psychology-research/&quot;&gt;burnt out students could be skewing the findings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0168354&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;PLOS One&lt;/em&gt; shows that the ways students differ from the public is different depending on which country you’re in, meaning it’s extra complicated to figure out if and when it’s appropriate to extrapolate student-based findings to people as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-22127&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers Paul Hanel and Katia Vione at Cardiff University used data collected from over 86,000 people (including 6,352 students) in 59 countries as part of the World Values Survey.  They wanted to see if students differed from the general population on various measures, such as personality and trust in strangers, and if so, whether this was fairly constant across countries or varied according to whether a country was more individualistic or collectivist (either of which would make it easier to anticipate and account any for student-public differences when conducting research).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers indeed found some notable differences between students and the general public, but perplexingly these differences often varied between countries and they weren’t explained by the key country characteristic of being individualistic vs. collectivist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, in Colombia students tended to score higher on Conscientiousness than the public, but in Brazil, the reverse was true. On the trait of Openness to Experience, students in China scored higher than the public, but in Pakistan students scored lower. The picture was similarly complex with people’s personal values and attitudes. For example, in New Zealand students showed heightened respect for the elderly compared with the public, but in Australia the opposite was found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanel and Vione said their results “further support the claim that generalizing from students to the general public within personal and social psychology is problematic, at least while we do not know what predicts those differences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings are somewhat disconcerting, but studies of this kind are also very welcome given that psychology’s dependence on student samples is unlikely to end any time soon. Crucially, the more we know about how students tend to differ from the public, the better placed we will be to interpret new student-based findings in an informed and considered way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0168354&quot;&gt;Do Student Samples Provide An Accurate Estimate of The General Public?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image under licence via gettyimages.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/22127/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/22127/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=22127&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Most citations to retracted papers don’t note they’re problematic, authors say</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/citations-retracted-papers-dont-note-theyre-problematic-authors-say/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49194</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T13:30:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;We’ve known for a while that too many researchers cite retracted papers. But in what context do those citations occur? Are some authors citing a retracted paper as an example of problematic findings, or do most citing authors treat the findings as legitimate, failing to realize they are no longer valid? In a new paper […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/05/citations-retracted-papers-dont-note-theyre-problematic-authors-say/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Most citations to retracted papers don’t note they’re problematic, authors say&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">CRISPR had a life before it became a gene-editing tool</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-had-life-it-became-gene-editing-tool"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-had-life-it-became-gene-editing-tool</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Before it was a tool, CRISPR was a weapon in the never-ending war between microbes and viruses</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rosie Mestel</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">The Trouble With The &quot;Journal of Stem Cells&quot;</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8674"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8674</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T11:36:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A couple of weeks ago, I wrote about a paper describing possibly unethical stem cell injection treatments for children with autism. That paper was published in 2015 in the Journal of Stem Cells.



I've since discovered additional problems with this journal.

It's important to note at the outset that the Journal of Stem Cells is not some obscure operation. It's indexed in MEDLINE, something that the vast majority of 'predatory' journals could only dream of. MEDLINE is the gold standard, or</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Event Horizon Telescope to try to capture images of elusive black hole edge</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/event-horizon-telescope-try-capture-images-elusive-black-hole-edge"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/event-horizon-telescope-try-capture-images-elusive-black-hole-edge</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T09:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Network of radio observatories will attempt a first-ever glimpse at an event horizon.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">What is computational neuroscience? (XXVI) Is optimization a good metaphor of evolution?</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxvi-is-optimization-a-good-metaphor-of-evolution/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1401</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T08:50:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;Is the brain the result of optimization, and if so, what is the optimization criterion? The popular argument in favor of the optimization view goes as follows. The brain is the result of Darwinian evolution, and therefore is optimally adapted to its environment, ensuring maximum survival and reproduction rates. In this view, to understand the brain is primarily to understand what “adapted” means for a brain, that is, what is the criterion to be optimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxiii-on-optimality-principles-in-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;I have pointed out a few difficulties in optimality arguments&lt;/a&gt; used in neuroscience, in particular the problem of specification (what is being optimized) and the fact that evolution is a history-dependent process, unlike a global optimization procedure. An example of this history dependence is the fascinating case of &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/feed/mitochondria&quot;&gt;mitochondria&lt;/a&gt;. Mitochondria are organelles in all eukaryotes cells that produce most of the cellular energy in the form of ATP. At this date, the main view is that these organelles are a case of symbiosis: mitochondria were once prokaryote cells that have been captured and farmed. This symbiosis has been selected and conserved through evolution, but optimization does not seem to be the most appropriate metaphor in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the optimization metaphor can be useful when applied to circumscribed problems that a biological organism might face, for example the energy consumption of action potential propagation. We can claim for example that, everything else being equal, an efficient axon is better than an inefficient one (with the caveat that in practice, not everything else can be made equal). But when applied at the scale of an entire organism, the optimization metaphor starts facing more serious difficulties, which I will discuss now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When considering an entire organism, or perhaps an organ like the brain, then what criterion can we possibly choose? Recently, I started reading “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Guitar-Zero-Musician-Science-Learning/dp/B006ZGO09U&quot;&gt;Guitar Zero&lt;/a&gt;” by Gary Marcus. The author points out that learning music is difficult, and argues that the brain has evolved for language, not music. This statement is deeply problematic. What does it mean that the brain has evolved &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; language? Language does not preexist to speakers, so it cannot be that language was an evolutionary (“optimization”) criterion for the brain, unless we have a more religious view of evolution. Rather, evolutionary change can create opportunities, which might be beneficial for the survival of the species, but there is no predetermined optimization criterion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is the color visual system of bees (see for example &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfu.ca/~kathleea/colour/docs/Ways%20of%20Colouring.pdf&quot;&gt;Ways of coloring&lt;/a&gt; by Thompson et al.). A case can be made that the visual system of bees is adapted to the color of flowers they are interested in. But conversely, the color of flowers is adapted to the visual system of bees. This is a case of co-evolution, where the “optimization criterion” changes during the evolutionary process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the optimization criterion does not preexist to the optimization process, and this makes the optimization metaphor weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A possible objection is that there is a preexisting optimization criterion, which is survival or reproduction rate. While this might be correct, it makes the optimization metaphor not very useful. In particular, it applies equally to all living species. The point is, there are species and they are different even though the optimization criterion is the same. Not all have a brain. Thus, optimization does not explain why we have a brain. Species that have a brain have different brains. The nervous system of a nematode is not the same as that of a human, even though they are all equally well adapted, and have evolved for exactly the same amount of time. Therefore, the optimization view does not explain why we speak and nematodes don’t, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that “fitness” is a completely contextual notion, which depends both on the environment and on the species itself. In a previous post where I discussed an &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/outline-of-an-existentialist-theory-of-evolution/&quot;&gt;“existentialist” view of evolution&lt;/a&gt;, I proposed the following thought experiment. Imagine a very ancient Earth with a bunch of living organisms that do not reproduce but can survive for an indefinite amount of time. By definition, they are adapted since they exist. Then at some point, an accident occurs such that one organism starts multiplying. It multiplies until it occupies the entire Earth and resources become scarce. At this point of saturation, organisms start dying. The probability of dying being the same for both non-reproducing organisms and reproducing ones, at some point there will be only reproducing organisms. Thus in this new environment, reproducing organisms are adapted, whereas non-reproducing ones are not. If we look at the history of evolution, we note that the world of species constantly changes. Species do not appear to converge to some optimal state, because as they evolve, the environment changes and so does the notion of fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the optimization criterion does not preexist to the optimization process, unless we consider a broad existentialist criterion such as survival, but then the optimization metaphor loses its usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>romain</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Why more highly educated people are less into conspiracy theories</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/05/why-more-highly-educated-people-are-less-into-conspiracy-theories/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=22052</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T07:31:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Moon Landing Conspiracy Concept&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-22119&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;22119&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cartoon illustration of the famous Moon Landing. Some people think it was a conspiracy. This image may shed some new light!&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Joe Peragino&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Moon Landing Conspiracy Concept&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Moon Landing Conspiracy Concept&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-164325167.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-164325167.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-164325167.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1988,1508&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/05/why-more-highly-educated-people-are-less-into-conspiracy-theories/moon-landing-conspiracy-concept/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-164325167.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this era of “fake news” and rising populism, encountering conspiracy theories is becoming a daily phenomenon. Some people usually shrug them off – they find them too simplistic, biased or far-fetched – but others are taken in. And if a person believes one kind of conspiracy theory, they usually believe others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologists are very interested in why some people are more inclined to believe in conspiracy theories, especially since the consequences can be harmful: for example, by avoiding getting their kids vaccinated, believers in vaccination conspiracies can harm wider public health; in other cases, a belief in a conspiracy against one’s own ethnic or religious group can foment radicalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main differences between conspiracy believers and nonbelievers that’s cropped up in multiple studies is that nonbelievers tend to be more highly educated. For a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/acp.3301/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Applied Cognitive Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, Jan-Willem Van Prooijen at VU Amsterdam has conducted two large surveys to try to dig into just what it is about being more educated that seems to inoculate against belief in conspiracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-22052&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first survey, Van Prooijen recruited over 4000 readers of a popular science journal in the Netherlands, with an average age of 32. He asked them about their formal education level and their belief in various well-known conspiracy theories, such as that the moon landings were hoax; he tested their feelings of powerlessness; their subjective sense of their social class (they located their position on a social ladder); and their belief in simple solutions, such as that “most problems in society are easy to solve”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more highly educated a participant, the less likely they were to endorse the conspiracy theories. Importantly, several of the other measures were linked to education and contributed to the association between education and less belief in conspiracy: feeling less powerlessness (or more in control), feelings of higher social status, and being sceptical of simple solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second survey was similar, but this time Van Prooijen quizzed nearly 1000 participants, average age 50, selected to be representative of the wider Dutch population. Also, there were two phases: for the first, participants answered questions about their education level; feelings of power; subjective social class; belief in simple solutions; and they took some basic tests of their analytical thinking skills. Then two weeks later, the participants rated their belief in various conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, more education was associated with less belief in conspiracy theories, and this seemed to be explained in part by more educated participants feeling more in control, having less belief in simple solutions, and having stronger analytical skills. Subjective social class wasn’t relevant in this survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, Van Prooijen said the results suggest that “the relationship between education and belief in conspiracy theories cannot be reduced to a single psychological mechanism but is the product of the complex interplay of multiple psychological processes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of his study means we can’t infer that education or the related factors he measured actually cause less belief in conspiracies. But it makes theoretical sense that they might be involved: for example, more education usually increases people’s sense of control over their lives (though there are exceptions, for instance among people from marginalized groups), while it is feelings of powerlessness that is one of the things that often attracts people to conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, Van Prooijen said his findings help make sense of why education can contribute to “a less paranoid society” even when conspiracy theories are not explicitly challenged. “By teaching children analytic thinking skills along with the insight that societal problems often have no simple solutions, by stimulating a sense of control, and by promoting a sense that one is a valued member of society, education is likely to install the mental tools that are needed to approach far-fetched conspiracy theories with a healthy dose of skepticism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/acp.3301/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;Why Education Predicts Decreased Belief in Conspiracy Theories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image under licence via Gettyimages.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/22052/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/22052/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=22052&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">What are the Big Ideas in Cognitive Neuroscience?</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/8pK71LcGK2c/what-are-big-ideas-in-cognitive.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-3886926264265091433</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:19:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HSNIGJfOEDo/WNdxjmjEhVI/AAAAAAAAMGI/9GCHvXdCSaYAOnjub8MINjvaZRycZ980QCLcB/s1600/BIG%2BIDEAS%2BCNS%2B2017%2Bwhite.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HSNIGJfOEDo/WNdxjmjEhVI/AAAAAAAAMGI/9GCHvXdCSaYAOnjub8MINjvaZRycZ980QCLcB/s320/BIG%2BIDEAS%2BCNS%2B2017%2Bwhite.png&quot; width=&quot;305&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This year, the Cognitive Neuroscience Institute (CNI) and the Max-Planck-Society organized a symposium on Big Ideas in Cognitive Neuroscience. I enjoyed this fun forum organized by David Poeppel and Mike Gazzaniga. The format included three pairs of speakers on the topics of memory, language, and action/motor who “consider[ed] some major challenges and cutting-edge advances, from molecular mechanisms to decoding approaches to network computations.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Co-host Marcus Raichle recalled his inspiration for the symposium: a similar Big Ideas session at the Society for Neuroscience meeting. But human neuroscience was absent from all SFN Big Ideas, so Dr. Raichle contacted Dr. Gazzaniga, who “made it happen” (along with Dr. Poeppel). The popular event was standing room only, and many couldn't even get into the Bayview Room (which was too small a venue). More context:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;“Recent discussions in the neurosciences have been relentlessly reductionist. The guiding principle of this symposium is that there is no privileged level of analysis that can yield special explanatory insight into the mind/brain on its own, so ideas and techniques across levels will be necessary.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The two hour symposium was a welcome addition to hundreds of posters and talks on highly specific empirical findings. Sometimes we must take a step back and look at the big picture. But since I'm The Neurocritic, I'll start out with some modest suggestions for next time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There was no time for questions or discussion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There were too many talks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It would be nice for all speakers to try to bridge different levels of analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This is a small point, but ironically the first two speakers (Gallistel, Ryan) did not talk about human neuroscience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So my idea is to have four speakers on one topic (memory, let's say) with two at the level of Gallistel and Ryan&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and two who approach human neuroscience using different techniques. Talks are strictly limited to 20 minutes. Then there is a 20 minute panel discussion where everyone tries to consider the implications of the other levels for their own work. Then (ideally) there is time for 20 minutes of questions from the audience. However, since I'm not an expert in organizing such events, allotting 20 minutes for the audience could be excessive. So the timing could be restructured to 25 min for talks, 10-15 min panel, 5-10 min audience. Or combine the round table with audience participation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20160611055236/http://www.cogneurosociety.org/mycns/?page=symposium_sessions#7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Symposium Session 7&lt;/a&gt; on Human Intracranial Electrophysiology (which included the &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2016/04/dont-lose-your-head-over-tdcs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Studies of transcranial electrical stimulation in human cadaver heads showed a 90% loss of current when delivered through the skin&quot;&gt;incendiary tDCS challenge&lt;/a&gt; by György Buzsáki) had a round table discussion as Talk 5, which I thought was very successful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Video of the Big Ideas symposium is now available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlFDiU2PVB8DQ1Qf7cGNvRV2HSMOWUBMf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, but in case you don't want to watch the entire two hours, I'll present a brief summary below.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big Box Neuroscience&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's an idiosyncratic distillation of some major points from the symposium.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The brain is an information processing device in the sense of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_theory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;'information' is thought of as a set of possible messages, where the goal is to send these messages over a noisy channel, and then to have the receiver reconstruct the message with low probability of error&quot;&gt;Shannon information theory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The brain does &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; use Shannon information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Memories (”engrams”) are not stored at synapses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We learn entirely through spike trains.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The engram is inter-spike interval.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The engram is an emergent property.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emergent properties are for losers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Language is genetically predetermined.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There is something called mirror neural ensembles.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Recursion is big.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Architectures are important.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build a bridge from networks to models of behavior.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use generative models to construct theories.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Machine learning will save us.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go back to behavioral neuroscience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Maybe I'll explain what this all means in the next post. You can also check out the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cogneurosociety.org/memory-language-action-watch-big-ideas-in-cognitive-neuroscience/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@CogNeuroNews coverage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnote&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Controversy is always entertaining, and these two had diametrically opposed views.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=8pK71LcGK2c:fnLtmkFPDJY:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/8pK71LcGK2c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T19:00:55+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Machine learning predicts the look of stem cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MqeMIWEjhYs/nature.2017.21769"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21769</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Website contains thousands of 3D stem cell images and could help with better understanding diseases like cancer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21769&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21769&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MqeMIWEjhYs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Maxmen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">CRISPR studies muddy results of older gene research</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/j0STHTX2S2E/nature.2017.21763"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21763</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientists face tough decisions when the latest gene-editing findings don’t match up with the results of other techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21763&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21763&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/j0STHTX2S2E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Heidi Ledford</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The DIY electronics transforming research</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Qyoj3Lyox30/544125a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544125a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Cheap, stripped-down microcontrollers are allowing users to pack huge amounts of computing power into tiny spaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 125 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544125a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544125a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Qyoj3Lyox30&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Cressey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Smart manufacturing must embrace big data</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/roUgtorGLqw/544023a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544023a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Study and model industrial processes to save money, energy and materials, urges Andrew Kusiak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544023a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544023a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/roUgtorGLqw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew Kusiak</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How the genomics revolution could finally help Africa</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/W7NbLx2awFw/544020a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544020a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;New investments promise to get precision medicine and precision public health off the ground. But experts debate how much work needs to be done first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 20 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544020a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544020a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/W7NbLx2awFw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Linda Nordling</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brazilian budget woes, negative results and botany in the digital era</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oNw-cUmno7M/544010a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544010a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 31 March–6 April 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 10 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544010a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544010a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oNw-cUmno7M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How to judge a book by its network</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/U6vXqdVUmOY/544005b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544005b</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A breakdown of purchasing habits shows where science books fall on the political spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 5 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/544005b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544005b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/U6vXqdVUmOY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structural basis for selectivity and diversity in angiotensin II receptors</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Mkq1NH1zoK4/nature22035"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22035</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The angiotensin II receptors AT1R and AT2R serve as key components of the renin–angiotensin–aldosterone system. AT1R has a central role in the regulation of blood pressure, but the function of AT2R is unclear and it has a variety of reported effects. To identify the mechanisms that underlie the differences in function and ligand selectivity between these receptors, here we report crystal structures of human AT2R bound to an AT2R-selective ligand and to an AT1R/AT2R dual ligand, capturing the receptor in an active-like conformation. Unexpectedly, helix VIII was found in a non-canonical position, stabilizing the active-like state, but at the same time preventing the recruitment of G proteins or β-arrestins, in agreement with the lack of signalling responses in standard cellular assays. Structure–activity relationship, docking and mutagenesis studies revealed the crucial interactions for ligand binding and selectivity. Our results thus provide insights into the structural basis of the distinct functions of the angiotensin receptors, and may guide the design of new selective ligands. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22035&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22035&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Mkq1NH1zoK4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Haitao Zhang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The crown-of-thorns starfish genome as a guide for biocontrol of this coral reef pest</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/mCeeGGkKGmA/nature22033"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22033</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The crown-of-thorns starfish (COTS, the Acanthaster planci species group) is a highly fecund predator of reef-building corals throughout the Indo-Pacific region. COTS population outbreaks cause substantial loss of coral cover, diminishing the integrity and resilience of reef ecosystems. Here we sequenced genomes of COTS from the Great Barrier Reef, Australia and Okinawa, Japan to identify gene products that underlie species-specific communication and could potentially be used in biocontrol strategies. We focused on water-borne chemical plumes released from aggregating COTS, which make the normally sedentary starfish become highly active. Peptide sequences detected in these plumes by mass spectrometry are encoded in the COTS genome and expressed in external tissues. The exoproteome released by aggregating COTS consists largely of signalling factors and hydrolytic enzymes, and includes an expanded and rapidly evolving set of starfish-specific ependymin-related proteins. These secreted proteins may be detected by members of a large family of olfactory-receptor-like G-protein-coupled receptors that are expressed externally, sometimes in a sex-specific manner. This study provides insights into COTS-specific communication that may guide the generation of peptide mimetics for use on reefs with COTS outbreaks. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22033&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22033&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/mCeeGGkKGmA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael R. Hall</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Large historical growth in global terrestrial gross primary production</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/z55wpthvj3g/nature22030"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22030</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Growth in terrestrial gross primary production (GPP)—the amount of carbon dioxide that is ‘fixed’ into organic material through the photosynthesis of land plants—may provide a negative feedback for climate change. It remains uncertain, however, to what extent biogeochemical processes can suppress global GPP growth. As a consequence, modelling estimates of terrestrial carbon storage, and of feedbacks between the carbon cycle and climate, remain poorly constrained. Here we present a global, measurement-based estimate of GPP growth during the twentieth century that is based on long-term atmospheric carbonyl sulfide (COS) records, derived from ice-core, firn and ambient air samples. We interpret these records using a model that simulates changes in COS concentration according to changes in its sources and sinks—including a large sink that is related to GPP. We find that the observation-based COS record is most consistent with simulations of climate and the carbon cycle that assume large GPP growth during the twentieth century (31% ± 5% growth; mean ± 95% confidence interval). Although this COS analysis does not directly constrain models of future GPP growth, it does provide a global-scale benchmark for historical carbon-cycle simulations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 84 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22030&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/z55wpthvj3g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>J. E. Campbell</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structural biology: A receptor that might block itself</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4-dH9npItng/nature21907"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21907</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The structure of the angiotensin II type 2 receptor reveals a potential mode of self-blocking action. This might explain its lack of signalling, and opens up avenues of investigation into its function and role in disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21907&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21907&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4-dH9npItng&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christopher G. Tate</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Marine conservation: The race to fish slows down</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jtPrRv3OqHc/nature21906"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21906</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A fishery can allow participants to fish as hard as they can until its quota is reached, or allocate quota shares that can be caught at any time. A comparison of the systems in action reveals that shares slow the race to fish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21906&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21906&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jtPrRv3OqHc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew A. Rosenberg</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Biocontrol: Crown-of-thorns no more</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/mCmFy2mrgcg/nature21905"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21905</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The starfish  Acanthaster planci  destroys coral reefs. Whole- genome sequences provide clues to the proteins that mediate  A. planci  outbreaks — information that might be used to help protect coral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21905&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21905&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/mCmFy2mrgcg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mónica Medina</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Myt1l safeguards neuronal identity by actively repressing many non-neuronal fates</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/aM5Xj0YQYIk/nature21722"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21722</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Normal differentiation and induced reprogramming require the activation of target cell programs and silencing of donor cell programs. In reprogramming, the same factors are often used to reprogram many different donor cell types. As most developmental repressors, such as RE1-silencing transcription factor (REST) and Groucho (also known as TLE), are considered lineage-specific repressors, it remains unclear how identical combinations of transcription factors can silence so many different donor programs. Distinct lineage repressors would have to be induced in different donor cell types. Here, by studying the reprogramming of mouse fibroblasts to neurons, we found that the pan neuron-specific transcription factor Myt1-like (Myt1l) exerts its pro-neuronal function by direct repression of many different somatic lineage programs except the neuronal program. The repressive function of Myt1l is mediated via recruitment of a complex containing Sin3b by binding to a previously uncharacterized N-terminal domain. In agreement with its repressive function, the genomic binding sites of Myt1l are similar in neurons and fibroblasts and are preferentially in an open chromatin configuration. The Notch signalling pathway is repressed by Myt1l through silencing of several members, including Hes1. Acute knockdown of Myt1l in the developing mouse brain mimicked a Notch gain-of-function phenotype, suggesting that Myt1l allows newborn neurons to escape Notch activation during normal development. Depletion of Myt1l in primary postmitotic neurons de-repressed non-neuronal programs and impaired neuronal gene expression and function, indicating that many somatic lineage programs are actively and persistently repressed by Myt1l to maintain neuronal identity. It is now tempting to speculate that similar ‘many-but-one’ lineage repressors exist for other cell fates; such repressors, in combination with lineage-specific activators, would be prime candidates for use in reprogramming additional cell types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21722&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21722&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/aM5Xj0YQYIk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Moritz Mall</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Re-evaluation of learned information in Drosophila</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/eR4i4QvBULs/nature21716"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21716</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Animals constantly assess the reliability of learned information to optimize their behaviour. On retrieval, consolidated long-term memory can be neutralized by extinction if the learned prediction was inaccurate. Alternatively, retrieved memory can be maintained, following a period of reconsolidation during which it is labile. Although extinction and reconsolidation provide opportunities to alleviate problematic human memories, we lack a detailed mechanistic understanding of memory updating. Here we identify neural operations underpinning the re-evaluation of memory in Drosophila. Reactivation of reward-reinforced olfactory memory can lead to either extinction or reconsolidation, depending on prediction accuracy. Each process recruits activity in specific parts of the mushroom body output network and distinct subsets of reinforcing dopaminergic neurons. Memory extinction requires output neurons with dendrites in the α and α′ lobes of the mushroom body, which drive negatively reinforcing dopaminergic neurons that innervate neighbouring zones. The aversive valence of these new extinction memories neutralizes previously learned odour preference. Memory reconsolidation requires the γ2α′1 mushroom body output neurons. This pathway recruits negatively reinforcing dopaminergic neurons innervating the same compartment and re-engages positively reinforcing dopaminergic neurons to reconsolidate the original reward memory. These data establish that recurrent and hierarchical connectivity between mushroom body output neurons and dopaminergic neurons enables memory re-evaluation driven by reward-prediction error. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21716&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/eR4i4QvBULs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Johannes Felsenberg</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mono-unsaturated fatty acids link H3K4me3 modifiers to C. elegans lifespan</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/M7R3ng8vIHk/nature21686"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21686</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Chromatin and metabolic states both influence lifespan, but how they interact in lifespan regulation is largely unknown. The COMPASS chromatin complex, which trimethylates lysine 4 on histone H3 (H3K4me3), regulates lifespan in Caenorhabditis elegans. However, the mechanism by which H3K4me3 modifiers affect longevity, and whether this mechanism involves metabolic changes, remain unclear. Here we show that a deficiency in H3K4me3 methyltransferase, which extends lifespan, promotes fat accumulation in worms with a specific enrichment of mono-unsaturated fatty acids (MUFAs). This fat metabolism switch in H3K4me3 methyltransferase-deficient worms is mediated at least in part by the downregulation of germline targets, including S6 kinase, and by the activation of an intestinal transcriptional network that upregulates delta-9 fatty acid desaturases. Notably, the accumulation of MUFAs is necessary for the lifespan extension of H3K4me3 methyltransferase-deficient worms, and dietary MUFAs are sufficient to extend lifespan. Given the conservation of lipid metabolism, dietary or endogenous MUFAs could extend lifespan and healthspan in other species, including mammals. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21686&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21686&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/M7R3ng8vIHk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shuo Han</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cold comforts</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/vsl_QlKFrR8/544132a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544132a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Message from the abyss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 132 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544132a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544132a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/vsl_QlKFrR8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Graham Robert Scott</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 &amp;amp; 100 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/j2BoezdX_JI/544043a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544043a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 43 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544043a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544043a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/j2BoezdX_JI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature Biological Sciences Research</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Outreach: Local problems are a low research priority</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bALHrwf7G-U/544035e"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035e</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 35 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544035e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bALHrwf7G-U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ole John Nielsen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Socio-economics: Reduce inequality to reduce abortion</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/uPNdsvGvXng/544035d"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035d</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 35 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544035d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/uPNdsvGvXng&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chika E. Uzoigwe</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brexit: UK universities and European industry</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Sw0CvVgCB0I/544035c"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035c</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 35 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544035c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Sw0CvVgCB0I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Robert Tijssen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ivory ban: Close Hong Kong's ivory-trade window</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/wZYYn9qexM4/544035b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035b</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 35 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544035b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/wZYYn9qexM4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Hubert Cheung</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Gene editing: Debate is failing Europe's geneticists</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/9OLNgtH6t1Y/544035a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 35 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544035a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544035a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/9OLNgtH6t1Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthias Fladung</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Physics: Revelations of fundamental science</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/QtMOI3fMxdo/544034a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544034a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Robert P. Crease wonders at a physics history with more than a hint of the biblical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 34 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544034a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544034a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/QtMOI3fMxdo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Robert P. Crease</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Meteorology: Weather makers</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/gIwhEKulM44/544032a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544032a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Jim Fleming assesses a history of US governmental intervention in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 32 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544032a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544032a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/gIwhEKulM44&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jim Fleming</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Philanthropy: The politics of giving</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/k2_f9Vemj3I/544031a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544031a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Anne-Emanuelle Birn reviews a survey of the new megaphilanthropy and its impact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 31 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544031a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544031a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/k2_f9Vemj3I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anne-Emanuelle Birn</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Energy: Muscle, steam and combustion</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0fifC9vql_4/544029a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544029a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Roger Fouquet applauds Vaclav Smil's vast survey of the technologies powering human progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 29 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544029a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544029a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0fifC9vql_4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Roger Fouquet</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New in Paperback</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CrVNTavS1yo/544028b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544028b</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Highlights of this season's releases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 28 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544028b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544028b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CrVNTavS1yo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rosalind Metcalfe</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Medical history: A surgeon for all seasons</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/QWOeSW7mpVA/544028a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544028a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Tilli Tansey extols a biography of the radical who gave his name to Parkinson's disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 28 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544028a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544028a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/QWOeSW7mpVA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tilli Tansey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Migration: Refugee economics</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6jo2Hdawm0s/544026a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544026a</id>
		<updated>2017-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Heaven Crawley questions a call for enterprise zones as a solution to forced migration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 544 26 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/544026a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/544026a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6jo2Hdawm0s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Heaven Crawley</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Protocols.io Tools for PLOS Authors: Reproducibility and Recognition</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/4f1A5xUoxx4/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7491</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T22:11:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;Protocol.io_opt2&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/Protocol.io_opt2-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solutions to the challenges of reproducibility in experimental science should be as diverse as the challenges themselves. Inconsistent reagents, barriers to the open sharing of supporting data, experimental variation that goes unrecorded and researcher’s concerns for lack of recognition and credit for novel and meticulously created experimental methods all contribute to the challenges of reproducibility in biomedical research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS now partners directly with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protocols.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;protocols.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to provide authors better ways to share methodological details about their work, practical tools to reduce wasted research efforts and persistent, citable identifiers for laboratory methods. For PLOS, this is a step forward on commitments to address reproducibility and provide improved recognition and credit for all contributions to a work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to be associated with a like-minded partner such as PLOS,” says protocols.io CEO Lenny Teytelman. “We are aligned in our Open Access ethos, and we strive to facilitate the communication of research in an effective, accessible and reusable way.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new offering complements PLOS’ already robust &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/data-availability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;data availability policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, requiring that data underlying the conclusions of an article be made available at the time of publication. Since the strengthening of this policy in 2014, about 60,000 articles have been published that contain a Data Availability Statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to engage with protocols.io,” says PLOS Executive Editor Veronique Kiermer. “This is another step towards &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/11/a-plos-response-to-open-in-action-with-open-science/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, facilitating access not only to the data but now also to the laboratory methodology that generated these data.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How It Works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are encouraged, at their discretion, to deposit their laboratory protocols on the protocols.io site, obtain a unique DOI and link directly to these from the Methods section of their articles. The unique link allows reviewers and editors access to the protocols during peer review. At the time of publication, the partnership between PLOS and protocols.io ensures that links to and from the published article are established and protocols are automatically made publicly available under a CC BY license for anyone to access, use and cite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_7492&quot; style=&quot;width: 202px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002538&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;protocol.io_app&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7492&quot; height=&quot;396&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/protocol.io_app-153x300.png&quot; title=&quot;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pbio.1002538&quot; width=&quot;202&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;DOI: 10.1371/journal.pbio.1002538&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Archived and linked permanently to and from the article, protocols become part of the scientific record. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002538&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;protocols.io application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; allows scientists to create, copy, modify and evolve laboratory protocols, describing the critical details of experimental procedures that are often overlooked in articles Methods sections. While detailed steps in a protocol may evolve and improve over time, the version that relates to the published article remains accessible to help explain experimental nuances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;“Methods sections that describe laboratory experiments are narratives that tend to omit subtle variations that may affect the experiments,” says Kiermer. “I hope that scientists will take up the opportunity to describe their methods in a way that is much more useful to others.”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuanced methodological details can be shared in new ways, that in time can integrate seamlessly into the research cycle, from bench to publication and back. “It is not merely a tool for publication,” says Teytelman, “it can be useful as a lab tool, at the bench, for record keeping and for sharing expertise within and outside a laboratory.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engaged &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protocols.io/view/diatom-transformation-via-bacterial-conjugation-hgpb3vn?comments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;commenting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the protocols.io website allows interested readers to clarify and discuss deeper with others using an article’s methodology. “This partnership will improve reproducibility of published research while fostering scientists’ collaborative engagement with our content,” adds Kiermer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A DOI for methods, citable by others, provides more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/07/author-credit-plos-and-credit-update/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;granular credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to those individuals contributing to methodological development.&lt;/strong&gt; It also enables researchers to compare methodological details between laboratories pursuing similar approaches or between published experimental methods and those subtly revised by users. In this respect, protocols.io helps bridge an information gap between published experimental methods and methods refined over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS looks forward to authors’ participation in this novel approach to enhancing Methods sections—an Open Access tool to record and share detailed protocols. We hope you try it and let us know your experience via comment below or email to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:communications@plos.org?subject=protocols.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;communications@plos.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hero image inset credit (CC BY): Bandage plot of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.17504/protocols.io.ghebt3e&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transcripts assembled by J. Mamrot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/4f1A5xUoxx4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Engineered immune cells boost leukemia survival for some</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/engineered-immune-cells-boost-leukemia-survival-some"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/engineered-immune-cells-boost-leukemia-survival-some</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T19:30:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Engineered immune cells can extend life for some leukemia patients.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">When coal replaces a cleaner energy source, health is on the line</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/when-coal-replaces-cleaner-energy-source-health-line"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/when-coal-replaces-cleaner-energy-source-health-line</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T18:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Health concerns prompted a shift from nuclear power to coal. But that shift came with its own health troubles, a new study suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Once-prominent researcher logs retraction following misconduct finding</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/prominent-researcher-logs-retraction-following-misconduct-finding/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49143</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T18:00:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher who resigned from the University of Dundee in Scotland after it concluded he was guilty of misconduct has issued his first retraction. According to an internal email to staff forwarded to us last year, the university concluded that Robert Ryan had misrepresented clinical data and images in 12 different publications. The first retraction, published […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/prominent-researcher-logs-retraction-following-misconduct-finding/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Once-prominent researcher logs retraction following misconduct finding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Predictive analytics based student intervention</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/04/04/predictive-analytics-based-student-intervention.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-04-04:/2017/04/04/predictive-analytics-based-student-intervention.html</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T15:33:18+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The field of Learning Analytics is beginning to gain traction in educational institutions, with perhaps the main driver being the prediction of student outcomes in order to identify students at risk.  This is not just key to improving the student experience, but critical to institutional budgets, where student withdrawals can cause significant damage to revenue streams.  However, the identification of students at risk is only useful when positive and successful interventions are made.  Currently, institutional interventions are ad-hoc and usually based upon the experience and style/approach of the individual tutor or course leader, with supporting institutional processes arguably focussed upon protecting the establishment.  An emerging area is that of using intelligent techniques to provide evidential input and specific intelligent support to the intervention process itself.  In addition to describing the relevant issues and methods I will describe the approach taken by the Open University, a leader in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 07/04/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edward Wakelam</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T15:33:18+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">For problematic papers, don’t retract or correct, say publishing experts: Amend</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/problematic-papers-dont-retract-correct-say-publishing-experts-amend/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49152</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T15:30:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A group of publishing experts have proposed a somewhat radical idea: Instead of retracting papers, or issuing corrections that address problems, authors should amend published articles. Here’s how it would work – any post-publication changes would be added as amendments labeled “insubstantial,” “substantial,” or “complete” (equivalent to a retraction). Is this a better way? We […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/problematic-papers-dont-retract-correct-say-publishing-experts-amend/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;For problematic papers, don’t retract or correct, say publishing experts: Amend&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Bone-inspired steel cracks less under pressure</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bone-inspired-steel-cracks-less-under-pressure"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bone-inspired-steel-cracks-less-under-pressure</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Steel that’s structured like bone resists cracks better that the traditional form of the heavy-duty building material.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Failure is an essential part of science:” A Q&amp;amp;A with the author of a new book on reproducibility</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/failure-essential-part-science-qa-author-new-book-reproducibility/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49162</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T13:23:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Reproducibility is everywhere recently, from the pages of scientific journals to the halls of the National Academy of Sciences, and today it lands in bookstores across the U.S. Longtime NPR correspondent Richard Harris has written Rigor Mortis (Basic Books), which is published today. (Full disclosure: I blurbed the book, writing that “Harris deftly weaves gripping tales […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/04/failure-essential-part-science-qa-author-new-book-reproducibility/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Failure is an essential part of science:” A Q&amp;amp;A with the author of a new book on reproducibility&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">The many faces of accessibility</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-many-faces-of-accessibility"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-many-faces-of-accessibility</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T10:24:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier colleagues across the company work to ensure that our content is accessible to people with disabilities</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Competing ideas abound for how Earth got its moon</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-moon-formation-impact"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-moon-formation-impact</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T10:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The moon may have formed from one giant impact or from about 20 small ones.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thomas Sumner</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cold symptoms feel worse when you’re lonely</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/04/cold-symptoms-feel-worse-when-youre-lonely/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=21936</id>
		<updated>2017-04-04T08:56:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Young sick African woman in bed&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-22029&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;22029&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young sick African woman in bed&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1475249293&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LaraBelova&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young sick African woman in bed&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young sick African woman in bed&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-611100194.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-611100194.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-611100194.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/04/cold-symptoms-feel-worse-when-youre-lonely/young-sick-african-woman-in-bed/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-611100194.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already substantial evidence suggests that &lt;em&gt;feeling&lt;/em&gt; lonely – regardless of whether we actually are socially isolated based on our number of relationships – is &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/11/12/loneliness-is-a-disease-that-changes-the-brains-structure-and-function/&quot;&gt;bad for our health&lt;/a&gt;, affecting our odds of developing heart disease and other chronic conditions. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-14291-001/&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; extends this literature by showing that feelings of loneliness, but not levels of social isolation, seem to increase the toll of acute illness, in this case by worsening the subjective experience of having a cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, led by Angie LeRoy at the University of Houston and Rice University, said their findings could be useful for helping doctors understand their patients’ different experiences of short-term illnesses. It also provides yet more evidence for why interventions aimed at reducing loneliness need to focus on quality not quantity of social interaction – after all, it’s perfectly possible to feel intensely alone in a crowded room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-21936&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the kind of study you’d consider volunteering for lightly: the researchers used viral nasal drops to try to infect 159 healthy US participants, average age 30, with a cold (75 per cent became infected) and then they holed them up in quarantine in a hotel for five days. Thankfully for the participants, they received just over $1000 in compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day, the participants answered questions about their mood and the severity of eight different cold symptoms, from congestion to chills. They also filled out a loneliness questionnaire at the start, which tapped their subjective sense of loneliness (typical items included “In general, how often do you feel left out?”), and an objective measure of their social isolation based on the number of people they had contact with every two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling lonely didn’t affect risk of infection by the cold virus, but of the participants who were infected, the more lonely they said they felt, the worse they reported their cold symptoms to be. This remained true when factoring out the influence of negative mood, which was also associated with experiencing more severe symptoms. Social isolation, measured objectively, was not associated with the subjective severity of cold symptoms. “Put simply,” the researchers said, “lonelier people feel worse when they are sick than less lonely people”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_22012&quot; style=&quot;width: 645px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-04-03 at 16.49.25&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-22012&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;22012&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-04-03 at 16.49.25&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/screen-shot-2017-04-03-at-16-49-25.png?w=845?w=645&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/screen-shot-2017-04-03-at-16-49-25.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/screen-shot-2017-04-03-at-16-49-25.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;645,346&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/04/cold-symptoms-feel-worse-when-youre-lonely/screen-shot-2017-04-03-at-16-49-25/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/screen-shot-2017-04-03-at-16-49-25.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;Figure via &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-14291-001/&quot;&gt;LeRoy et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some study limitations to be aware of: for instance, loneliness was only measured once, rather than as a dynamic state; deliberate infection isn’t exactly the same process as being infected in everyday life; and we can’t tell from these findings that loneliness causes worse subjective symptoms: some other unmeasured factor, such as lack of sleep, might be the key causal factor (loneliness tends to lead to sleep disruption).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the results hint at how subjective feelings of loneliness can become self-fulfilling through increasing the sense of feeling unwell after catching a cold, thus driving yet further social withdrawal. This form of negative spiral is in addition to &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/scienceofus/2015/08/lonely-peoples-brains-work-differently.html&quot;&gt;self-perpetuating psychological processes&lt;/a&gt; identified by prior research, such as the increased sensitivity lonely people have for social threat. The good news is that by becoming aware of these self-perpetuating mechanisms we can hopefully intervene more effectively and with greater understanding, either to help ourselves or others who  feel alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-14291-001/&quot;&gt;Loneliness predicts self-reported cold symptoms after a viral challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image under licence via Gettyimages.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21936/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21936/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=21936&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Out-of-body experiments show kids’ budding sense of self</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/out-body-experiments-show-kids-budding-sense-self"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/out-body-experiments-show-kids-budding-sense-self</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T20:15:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sensing that “my body is me” starts early and develops over many years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journals retract paper, flag two others by cancer doc under investigation</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/journals-retract-paper-flag-two-others-cancer-doc-investigation/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49129</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T19:00:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This weekend, Carlo Croce had some reprieve from the misconduct accusations that have followed him for years (recently described in a lengthy article in the New York Times) and that have prompted his university to re-open an investigation. On Sunday, he received a prestigious award from the American Association for Cancer Research, honoring his work. But the moment […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/journals-retract-paper-flag-two-others-cancer-doc-investigation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journals retract paper, flag two others by cancer doc under investigation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Can Alzheimer’s disease steal one’s consciousness?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/xHbB15r7cKw/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19250</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T18:46:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;Old Man Time Kahl Care Dementia Tree Clock Age&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/04/Old-Man-Time-Kahl-Care-Dementia-Tree-Clock-Age-97986-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer’s disease (AD) has been characterized as a “&lt;a href=&quot;http://ajp.psychiatryonline.org/doi/abs/10.1176/ajp.145.6.760&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;complete loss of self&lt;/a&gt;.” Early on when memory begins to fade, the victim has difficulty recalling names, their grocery list or where they put their keys. As the disease progresses, they have trouble staying focused, planning and performing basic daily activities. From the exterior, dementia appears to ravage one’s intellect and personality; yet as mere observers, it’s impossible to ascertain how consciousness of the self and environment is transformed by dementia. The celebrated late neurologist Oliver Sacks once suggested that, “Style, neurologically, is the deepest part of one’s being and may be preserved, almost to the last, in dementia.” Is this remaining neurological “style” sufficient to preserve consciousness? Is the AD patient aware of their deteriorating cognition, retaining a sense of identity or morality, or can they still connect with friends and loved ones? Emerging advances in neuroscience have enabled researchers to more precisely probe the AD brain, suggesting that although some aspects of consciousness are compromised by dementia, others are remarkably spared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manifestations of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists are beginning to piece together how the selective loss of some functions, but the preservation of others, alters consciousness in AD. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11696024&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; found that the severity of cognitive impairment strongly relates to “meta-cognition” (reflecting on one’s own condition), moral judgments and thinking about the future, whereas basic personal identity and body awareness remain. Perhaps the most widely observed deficit in consciousness is “anosognosia,” impaired awareness of one’s own illness; whereas individuals with mild cognitive impairment (MCI; considered a precursor to full AD) are aware of their declining memory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15802909&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AD patients may be unaware of their impairments&lt;/a&gt;. These behavioral signs suggest that only some aspects of consciousness and self-awareness are truly lost in AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although basic perceptual, sensory, and communication skills are relatively spared, the defining feature of AD is memory loss. The unique nature of these memory deficits provides clues to why sub-components of consciousness deteriorate in dementia. Memory for experiences (episodic memory; e.g., &lt;em&gt;I went for a walk in the park yesterday&lt;/em&gt;) and recollection of their associated details are impaired, while memory for facts and meaning (semantic memory; e.g., &lt;em&gt;Paris is the capital of France&lt;/em&gt;) is preserved. Recollection of episodic memories demands that the rememberer engage with the memory, searching for context and reflecting upon the memory after it’s recalled. In contrast, semantic memory can be automatic and doesn’t require this level of attention or personal involvement. Impairment in personal meta-cognition may lie at the heart of these memory deficits. For instance, AD patients can accurately predict how well they’ll later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/S1355617700001375&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recall semantic information&lt;/a&gt;, but cannot predict how they’ll &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12417467&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recall episodic memory&lt;/a&gt;, pointing to a specific impairment in &lt;em&gt;awareness&lt;/em&gt; of their personal memories. Perhaps then, loss of consciousness in AD stems from impaired control over attention to memory. Indeed, AD has been considered a disorder of “impaired attention to life.” This is supported by reports that the feelings surrounding a memory and re-experiencing an episode during recollection are absent in AD. Unable to engage with a memory, the individual loses their conscious awareness of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenpinker.com/publications/how-mind-works&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steven Pinker&lt;/a&gt; defines consciousness as the sum of sentience, access to information, and self-knowledge. While the first two are relatively intact in AD, episodic memories are heavily dependent on the last. In addition to problems with episodic memory, some AD patients have difficulty remembering semantic information when it’s personal, suggesting that hindered access to personal details of a memory may, to some extent, account for impairments in consciousness. As dementia often warps one’s sense of time continuity, this temporal disconnect could further degrade one’s ability to accurately place themself in the context of past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neural underpinnings of altered consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unique pattern of brain pathology in AD might explain the resulting partial loss of consciousness in its victims. Since consciousness requires the coordination of distributed brain networks that support sensation, memory, attention and emotion, dysfunction of this system could lead to changes in cognition and awareness. In AD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2904350/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brain atrophy&lt;/a&gt; begins in the medial temporal lobe, followed by lateral temporal, parietal and frontal areas. These regions may engender consciousness by supporting recall of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12372291&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source of a memory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15784441&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-referential processing&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11459919&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-identification&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1002987&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Metabolism is reduced&lt;/a&gt; in temporal and parietal regions, and these changes are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16189724&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;associated with the severity of cognitive impairment&lt;/a&gt; and changes in awareness. Furthermore, in line with the finding that AD patients have trouble understanding another’s personality, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/25/3/550.short&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stimulating the temporoparietal junction&lt;/a&gt; can induce an “out-of-body experience,” where the person perceives themself as someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deficits in meta-cognitive ability could further stem from &lt;em&gt;disconnect&lt;/em&gt; among key brain hubs. The pathways connecting the frontal, parietal and temporal cortices, which integrate information across the brain, become compromised in AD. Although these widespread brain networks aren’t affected until late in the disease, the earliest target of AD-related neurodegeneration, the medial temporal lobe, lies at the core of this system. In the medial temporal lobe, the hippocampus binds contextual information about an experience into memory, but must communicate across the brain to store these details into long-term memory. Therefore, early damage to the medial temporal lobe might be a first step towards a disrupted sense of awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preserving consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research linking the select deficits in self-awareness and meta-cognition with the characteristic pattern of neurodegeneration in AD is invaluable for informing about the neurobiological origins of consciousness. Perhaps more importantly, understanding which aspects of consciousness go awry in AD could theoretically promote the development of more effective treatment strategies. If attention to one’s inner mental landscape, and awareness of one’s personal state, are targets of AD, there’s hope that training these skills could confer resilience against the neuropathology degrading these functions. Although in its infancy, studies testing this possibility have shown promise. Older adults who are experienced mediators were more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17655980&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;resilient to the detrimental effects of age&lt;/a&gt; on cognitive function than non-meditators, and an intervention of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20164557&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eight weeks of meditation training&lt;/a&gt; increased brain blood flow and improved cognitive function in individuals with MCI and AD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it’s tempting to attribute changes in awareness to strictly biological aberrations, we cannot overlook the physical and social interactions that mold our mental state. Being labeled “demented”, infantilized or treated as incapable, as can be done to AD victims, would be damaging to anyone’s self-esteem and sense of dignity. Perhaps then, by nurturing the AD mind by reinforcing their human worth, we could dampen the pathological fire working to degrade their personhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blanke O et al. (2005). Linking Out-of-Body Experience and Self Processing to Mental Own-Body Imagery at the Temporoparietal Junction. &lt;em&gt;J Neurosci&lt;/em&gt;. 25(3):550-7. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2612-04.2005&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breen N, Caine D, Coltheart M. (2001). Mirrored-self misidentification: two cases of focal onset dementia. &lt;em&gt;Neurocase&lt;/em&gt;. 7(3):239-54. doi: 10.1093/neucas/7.3.239&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D’Argembeau A et al. (2005). Self-referential reflective activity and its relationship with rest: a PET study. &lt;em&gt;Neuroimage&lt;/em&gt;. 25(2):616-24. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2004.11.048&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dobbins IG, Foley H, Schacter DL, Wagner AD. Executive control during episodic retrieval: multiple prefrontal processes subserve source memory. &lt;em&gt;Neuron&lt;/em&gt;. 35(5):989-96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dukart J et al (2013). Generative FDG-PET and MRI Model of Aging and Disease Progression in Alzheimer’s Disease. &lt;em&gt;PLOS Comp Biol&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1371/journal.pcbi.1002987&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gil R et al. (2001). Self-consciouness and Alzheimer’s disease. &lt;em&gt;Acta Neurol Scand. &lt;/em&gt;104(5):296-300&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalbe E et al. (2005). Anosognosia in very mild Alzheimer’s disease but not in mild cognitive impairment. &lt;em&gt;Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord&lt;/em&gt;. 19(5-6):349-56. doi:10.1159/000084704&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipinksa B, Backman L. (1996). Feeling-of-knowing in fact retrieval: Further evidence for preservation in early Alzheimer’s disease. &lt;em&gt;J Int Neurospcyh Soc&lt;/em&gt;. 2(4):350-8. doi:10.1017/S1355617700001375&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newberg AB, Wintering N, Khasla DS, Roggenkamp H, Waldman MR. (2010). Meditation effects on cognitive function and cerebral blood flow in subjects with memory loss: a preliminary study. &lt;em&gt;J Alzheimers Dis&lt;/em&gt;. 20(2):517-26. doi:10.3233/JAD-2010-1391&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pagnoni G, Cekic M. (2007). Age effects on gray matter volume and attentional performance in Zen meditation. &lt;em&gt;Neurobiol Aging&lt;/em&gt;. 28(10):1623-7. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2007.06.008&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinker S. (1997). How the mind works. New York, NY: W.W. Norton &amp;amp; Company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reynolds CF. (1998) The Loss of Self: A Family Resource for the Care of Alzheimer’s Disease and Related Disorders.” &lt;em&gt;Am J Psychiatr&lt;/em&gt;. 145(6):760 doi:10.1176/ajp.145.6.760&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risacher SL et al. (2010). Longitudinal MRI atrophy biomarkers: Relationship to conversion in the ADNI cohort. &lt;em&gt;Neurobiol Aging&lt;/em&gt;. 31(8):1401-18. doi:10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.04.029&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salmon E et al. (2005). Cerebral metabolic correlates of four dementia scales in Alzheimer’s disease. &lt;em&gt;J Neurol&lt;/em&gt;. 252(3):283-90. doi:10.1007/s00415-005-0551-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Souchay C, Isingrini M, Gil R. (2002). Alzheimer’s disease and feeling-of-knowing in episodic memory. &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;. 40(13):2386-96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-17356&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emilie Reas&lt;/strong&gt; received her PhD in Neuroscience from UC San Diego, where she used fMRI to study memory. As a postdoc at UCSD, she currently studies how the brain changes with aging and disease. In addition to her tweets for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PLOSNeuro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@PLOSNeuro&lt;/a&gt; she is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/etreas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@etreas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/xHbB15r7cKw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emilie Reas</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2017-04-03T23:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Five retractions for engineering duo in South Korea over duplication, fraudulent data</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/five-retractions-engineering-duo-south-korea-duplication-fraudulent-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49035</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T15:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;An engineering student in South Korea and a professor have retracted five papers from four different journals for reasons ranging from figure duplication to manipulated or fraudulent data. Jae Hyo Park, who is pursuing his PhD, and Seung Ki Joo, a professor in the department of material science and engineering at Seoul National University in South […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/five-retractions-engineering-duo-south-korea-duplication-fraudulent-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Five retractions for engineering duo in South Korea over duplication, fraudulent data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">First fluorescent frogs might see each others’ glow</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-fluorescent-frogs-might-see-each-others-glow"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/first-fluorescent-frogs-might-see-each-others-glow</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A polka dot frog, the first known fluorescent amphibian, may get a visibility boost in twilight and moonlight.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">German funder bans researcher for five years following misconduct probe</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/german-funder-bans-researcher-five-years-following-misconduct-probe/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49092</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T12:36:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A researcher in Germany has been banned from seeking money from the largest independent research funder in the country for five years after an investigation by her former employer found her guilty of misconduct. According to a recent announcement from the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), scientist Tina Wenz cannot apply for any DFG funding for five years, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/03/german-funder-bans-researcher-five-years-following-misconduct-probe/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;German funder bans researcher for five years following misconduct probe&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Specimens’ goes behind the scenes of Chicago’s Field Museum</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/specimens-goes-behind-scenes-chicago-field-museum"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/specimens-goes-behind-scenes-chicago-field-museum</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The Field Museum of Natural History in Chicago puts seldom-seen specimens on display in a new exhibit to highlight the crucial role of museum objects in scientific research.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Howard Wolinsky</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A five-minute chat with preschoolers about their past or future selves helps them make better decisions</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/03/talking-to-preschoolers-about-the-near-past-or-future-helps-them-make-better-decisions/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=21849</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T09:21:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Little girl's legs in glitter shoes on snow&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-21911&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;21911&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;18&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D90&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1233458152&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;nbkimages&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;95&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Little girl's legs in glitter shoes on snow&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Little girl’s legs in glitter shoes on snow&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-95019984.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-95019984.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-95019984.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2600,2135&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/03/talking-to-preschoolers-about-the-near-past-or-future-helps-them-make-better-decisions/little-girls-legs-in-glitter-shoes-on-snow/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/gettyimages-95019984.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There could be an Arctic blizzard blowing outside for all little Mary cares. The fact is, she’s hot from running around indoors, and no matter how much you try to explain to Mary that her future self – the one that’s about to go walking in the cold – would really appreciate that she put her coat on, Mary, like most kids aged under five, finds it very difficult to step outside of the present and consider her future needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While psychologists have already spent a lot of time demonstrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/11/09/when-anticipating-their-future-needs-children-cant-see-past-their-current-state/&quot;&gt;the limitations of young children’s ability to plan for the future&lt;/a&gt;, until now they’ve not looked much at whether it’s possible to target these “prospective abilities”. However, &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/index.cfm?fa=buy.optionToBuy&amp;amp;id=2017-09886-001&quot;&gt;a new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Developmental Psychology&lt;/em&gt; has done that, showing that a mere five-minute chat about their recent past or future selves seems to help preschoolers remember to do things in the future, and to “time travel” mentally, so that they make better decisions about their forthcoming needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-21849&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadia Chernyak at Boston University and her colleagues allocated 81 children, aged three to five, to one of four training conditions. Each child spent five minutes alone with a researcher talking and thinking about either: their self in the near past (for example, what they’d been doing earlier that day, and drawing a picture of themselves going to bed the previous night); their near future (such as what they would be doing later that day; drawing a picture of themselves going to bed that night); their distant future (such as in the coming weeks, and even when they are adult); or, finally, the present (including drawing a picture of what they were doing “right now”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they’d finished their training phase, a different researcher tested each child on their ability to make future-related decisions. Importantly, this researcher didn’t know which training condition each child had completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were several tests, including a “prospective memory” challenge, which involved remembering to remind the researcher to open a box at the end of the tests; a “mental time travel” test that involved selecting appropriate items to take on a trek through the forest or snow; a “temporal discounting task” that gave the opportunity to forego a sticker “right now”, for the chance to have two at the end of the day; and a “saving task” that involved showing patience and waiting for a better play opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children who’d spent time thinking about their near-past or future outperformed the others (the children in the distant future and present training conditions) on the prospective memory task and on the mental time travel task. There were no group differences in performance on the temporal discounting task or saving task, perhaps because improvement in these skills takes practice as well as progress in conceptual understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children in the near-past or future conditions had used more personal pronouns when chatting compared with the other children, and Chernyak and her colleagues think this offers a clue to why these conditions were apparently more beneficial to prospective memory and mental time travel. “Our work suggests that experience communicating and thinking about one’s extended self promotes the ability to make decisions on behalf of the extended self,” the researchers said. They added that children in the distant future condition may have found distant events and talk of their distant selves less self-relevant and more abstract (just as adults do).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not clear how long the apparent benefits of the near-past and future training conditions would last; ideally future studies would also provide some kind of before and after comparison of abilities rather than simply looking for between-group differences in ability after training. Nonetheless, the researchers believe they’ve highlighted an important principle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These results have implications for caregivers’ day-to-day interactions with preschoolers,” they concluded, “because even brief conversations with adults can help scaffold, shape, and activate concepts about one’s extended self. Critically engaging young children in conversations where they are provided with opportunities to cognitize, remember, and discuss their extended selves may ultimately help them make future-oriented decisions that benefit those extended selves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/index.cfm?fa=buy.optionToBuy&amp;amp;id=2017-09886-001&quot;&gt;Training preschoolers’ prospective abilities through conversation about the extended self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21849/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21849/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=21849&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Using Discourse Analysis to Assess Cognitive Decline</title>
		<link href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/tYYDadX2k1g/using-discourse-analysis-to-assess.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-6283119004927853198</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T00:12:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mT-NB1kp71M/WKlJKRrlx3I/AAAAAAAAMBk/qACWmxtPnfweLr2JF4poTAcEFOKaZRBEQCLcB/s1600/outline%2Bof%2BMCI.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mT-NB1kp71M/WKlJKRrlx3I/AAAAAAAAMBk/qACWmxtPnfweLr2JF4poTAcEFOKaZRBEQCLcB/s400/outline%2Bof%2BMCI.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Figure from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673606685425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gauthier et al. (2005)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alzheimer's Disease (AD) and other dementias are progressive neurodegenerative conditions that unfold over time. Subtle symptoms such as forgetfulness and word finding problems may progress to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673606685425&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mild cognitive impairment&lt;/a&gt; (MCI), and then escalate to full-blown dementia. Recent efforts to classify &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2881320/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Defining 'Prodromal' Alzheimer’s Disease, Frontotemporal Dementia, and Lewy Body Dementia: Are we there yet?&quot;&gt;prodromal states&lt;/a&gt; have included automated analysis of spontaneous speech, which loses complexity as the disease progresses.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In one study, &lt;strike&gt;Frazier&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3233/JAD-150520&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fraser et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt; applied machine learning methods to speech transcripts and audio files from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.talkbank.org/DementiaBank/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DementiaBank&lt;/a&gt; database. The participants were 167 patients with probable AD and 97 controls. The authors considered a total of 370 linguistic features, and found that a subset of 35 was able to classify patients vs. controls with 82% accuracy.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; While an advance over previous studies, this is not yet useful for diagnostic purposes. Another limitation was the relatively short length of the speech samples.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Using factor analysis, the researchers found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://alzheimersnewstoday.com/2015/12/15/alzheimers-disease-markers-found-speech-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;four dimensions of speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;were most indicative of dementia: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Semantic impairment&lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt; – &lt;/span&gt;using overly simple words&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acoustic impairment &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;e.g., speaking more  slowly &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Syntactic impairment  &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;using less complex grammar &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Information impairment &lt;span class=&quot;_Tgc&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;not clearly identifying the main aspects  of a picture they were told to describe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Public figures who give repeated interviews leave a searchable record of spontaneous speech that can be analyzed for changes over time. Presidential press conferences provide another rich source of data for linguistic analysis. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25633673&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Berisha et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt; examined &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transcripts&lt;/a&gt; from the press conferences given by Ronald Reagan (1981-1989) and George H.W. Bush (1989-1993). We know that President Reagan received a formal diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease in 1994, five years after leaving office. And as far as we know, the elder Bush is still cognitively intact for his age (he's 92 now).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The quantified linguistic features included:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Number of unique words&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Non-specific nouns – e.g., &lt;i&gt;thing, something, anything&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filler words – &lt;i&gt;well, so, basically, actually, literally, um, ah&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low-imageability, high frequency verbs &lt;i&gt;– e.g., &lt;i&gt;get, give, go, have, do&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reagan showed a significant decline in the number of unique words over the course of his presidency, but Bush did not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-W3MMHZEZQqg/WKloZbS7jEI/AAAAAAAAMB4/oJKTD80k2o0HFZLiepXi0dVUEKS43k6YACLcB/s1600/unique%2Bwords_linked%2Bto%2BAD%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-W3MMHZEZQqg/WKloZbS7jEI/AAAAAAAAMB4/oJKTD80k2o0HFZLiepXi0dVUEKS43k6YACLcB/s400/unique%2Bwords_linked%2Bto%2BAD%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Likewise, Reagan showed a significant &lt;i&gt;increase&lt;/i&gt; in the use of non-specific nouns and fillers, but Bush did not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2r3dyRDBak/WKloZfPjJ4I/AAAAAAAAMB0/fbUHrn28BPgSlF1ZKIMXycTB1fMrDZN_wCLcB/s1600/non-specific%2Bnouns%2Band%2Bfillers%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L2r3dyRDBak/WKloZfPjJ4I/AAAAAAAAMB0/fbUHrn28BPgSlF1ZKIMXycTB1fMrDZN_wCLcB/s400/non-specific%2Bnouns%2Band%2Bfillers%2Bfor%2BReagan%2Band%2BGHW%2BBush.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are several caveats here. Reagan was 69 when he was elected, while Bush was 64. Reagan was president for eight years and Bush for only four years; yet Bush held over twice as many press conferences as Reagan. Nonetheless, the results are consistent with a decline in cognitive function (which is not uncommon when aging from 69 to 77). Can we can classify Reagan as having MCI on the basis of these results? I don't think so. We'd really need comparable data from a population of demographically matched elderly participants.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;President Donald Trump&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2017/02/16/remarks-president-trump-press-conference&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feb. 16 press conference&lt;/a&gt;, the public debate over whether President Trump is mentally unbalanced has intensified. Much of the current and past discussion has centered on the possibility of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Narcissistic_personality_disorder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narcissistic Personality Disorder&lt;/a&gt; (NPD), as speculated in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/06/the-mind-of-donald-trump/480771/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vanityfair.com/news/2015/11/donald-trump-narcissism-therapists&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2017/feb/17/donald-trump-narcisissm-mentally-ill-personality?CMP=share_btn_tw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, Trump has many of these qualities (that predate his &lt;i&gt;actual&lt;/i&gt; grandiose status as POTUS): &lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grandiosity with expectations of superior treatment from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fixated on fantasies of power, success, intelligence, attractiveness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Self-perception of being unique, superior and associated with high-status people and institutions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Needing constant admiration from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sense of entitlement to special treatment and to obedience from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exploitative of others to achieve personal gain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unwilling to empathize with others' feelings, wishes, or needs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Intensely envious of others and the belief that others are equally envious of them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pompous and arrogant demeanor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;And we can call him &lt;b&gt;narcissistic&lt;/b&gt; in the generic sense of the word. But do we need to diagnose him with a quasi-psychiatric disorder, as in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/13/opinion/mental-health-professionals-warn-about-trump.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;NY Times&lt;/i&gt; letter&lt;/a&gt; signed by 35 mental health professionals?&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Mr. Trump’s speech and actions demonstrate an inability to tolerate views different from his own, leading to rage reactions. His words and behavior suggest a profound inability to empathize. Individuals with these traits distort reality to suit their psychological state, attacking facts and those who convey them (journalists, scientists).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a powerful leader, these attacks are likely to increase, as his personal myth of greatness appears to be confirmed. We believe that the grave emotional instability indicated by Mr. Trump’s speech and actions makes him incapable of serving safely as president.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Allen Frances, chair of the DSM-IV task force, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/14/opinion/an-eminent-psychiatrist-demurs-on-trumps-mental-state.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forcefully argued&lt;/a&gt; that Trump does not meet criteria for NPD, because he is not distressed by his behavior:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Mr. Trump causes severe distress rather than experiencing it and has  been richly rewarded, rather than punished, for his grandiosity,  self-absorption and lack of empathy. It is a stigmatizing insult to the  mentally ill (who are mostly well behaved and well meaning) to be lumped  with Mr. Trump (who is neither).&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Discourse Analysis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here I'll suggest a different approach: can we quantify age-related neurological change using spontaneous speech?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;This is probably my favorite part so far &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/n61y5I8UrN&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/n61y5I8UrN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;— Rachel Riederer (@readerer) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/readerer/status/832303185826033664&quot;&gt;February 16, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;“You know what uranium is, right?  It's this &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;thing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; called nuclear weapons  and other &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Like&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, lots of &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;done&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with uranium,  including some bad &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;things&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Nobody talks about that.  I didn't &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;do&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; anything&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for Russia.  I've &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;done&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;nothing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; for Russia.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the most egregious example in the one hour, 17 minute &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ct0H_ndjavM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;train wreck&lt;/a&gt;. But there are other signs. He used the construction “very, very” 20 times. The word “thing” (and its variants) was uttered 102 times.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Am I going to diagnose him with anything? Of course not. That's unethical!&lt;/b&gt; But I will say that since Mr. Trump has been a public figure for nearly 40 years, we can objectively analyze his spontaneous speech and quantify any changes over time. I must emphasize that there is no magical scale to use for classification or comparison purposes (at least not yet). We don't know what's normal age-related decline and what's pathological.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I suggest that the best corpus of spontaneous speech data is the collection of Trump interviews/conversations with David Letterman. I believe they're unscripted, and there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9-mWCMiytLi0RV53IHrGXA/search?query=donald+trump&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; of them on YouTube (I've linked to eight below). Letterman has aged too, so you might as well analyze his speech as well.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnotes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The authors performed... &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;...a 10-fold cross-validation procedure in which a unique 10% of the data (i.e., the ‘test set’) are used in each iteration for evaluation, and the remaining 90% (i.e., the ‘training set’) are used to select the most useful features (of the 370 available as described in “Features” above) and construct our models. The reported accuracy is an average across the 10 folds. In a given fold, data from any individual speaker can occur in the test set or the training set, but not both.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; A show-stopping limitation is that the two groups were not matched for age or education. The mean age was 71.8 for AD vs. 65.2 for controls, and years of education 12.5 vs. 14.1 yrs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://alzheimersnewstoday.com/2015/12/15/alzheimers-disease-markers-found-speech-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alzheimer’s Disease Markers Found in Speech Patterns&lt;/a&gt; (link via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aholdenj/status/824801091007115268&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@aholdenj&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;BTW, they're not supposed to diagnose non-patients, that's unethical.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Alzheimer%27s+Disease&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F25633673&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Tracking+discourse+complexity+preceding+Alzheimer%27s+disease+diagnosis%3A+a+case+study+comparing+the+press+conferences+of+Presidents+Ronald+Reagan+and+George+Herbert+Walker+Bush.&amp;amp;rft.issn=1387-2877&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=45&amp;amp;rft.issue=3&amp;amp;rft.spage=959&amp;amp;rft.epage=63&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Berisha+V&amp;amp;rft.au=Wang+S&amp;amp;rft.au=LaCross+A&amp;amp;rft.au=Liss+J&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CNeuroscience%2CCognitive+Psychology%2C+Language&quot;&gt;Berisha V, Wang S, LaCross A, &amp;amp; Liss J (2015). Tracking discourse complexity preceding Alzheimer's disease diagnosis: a case study comparing the press conferences of Presidents Ronald Reagan and George Herbert Walker Bush. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 45&lt;/span&gt; (3), 959-63 PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25633673&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;25633673&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Alzheimer%27s+Disease&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.3233%2FJAD-150520&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Linguistic+Features+Identify+Alzheimer%E2%80%99s+Disease+in+Narrative+Speech&amp;amp;rft.issn=13872877&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=49&amp;amp;rft.issue=2&amp;amp;rft.spage=407&amp;amp;rft.epage=422&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.medra.org%2Fservlet%2FaliasResolver%3Falias%3Diospress%26doi%3D10.3233%2FJAD-150520&amp;amp;rft.au=Fraser%2C+K.&amp;amp;rft.au=Meltzer%2C+J.&amp;amp;rft.au=Rudzicz%2C+F.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CNeuroscience%2CLanguage&quot;&gt;Fraser, K., Meltzer, J., &amp;amp; Rudzicz, F. (2015). Linguistic Features Identify Alzheimer’s Disease in Narrative Speech. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 49&lt;/span&gt; (2), 407-422 DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3233/JAD-150520&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.3233/JAD-150520&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gs_citr&quot; id=&quot;gs_cit4&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Gauthier S, Reisberg B,  Zaudig M, Petersen RC, Ritchie K, Broich K, Belleville S, Brodaty H,  Bennett D, Chertkow H, Cummings JL. (2006). Mild cognitive impairment. &lt;i&gt;The  Lancet&lt;/i&gt;  367:1262-70.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=IEEE+International+Conference&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3A%2F10.1109%2FICMA.2005.1626789&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Automatic+detection+and+rating+of+dementia+of+Alzheimer+type+through+lexical+analysis+of+spontaneous+speech&amp;amp;rft.issn=&amp;amp;rft.date=2005&amp;amp;rft.volume=3&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=1569&amp;amp;rft.epage=1574&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fieeexplore.ieee.org%2Fdocument%2F1626789%2F&amp;amp;rft.au=Thomas%2C+C.%2C+Keselj%2C+V.%2C+Cercone%2C+N.%2C+Rockwood%2C+K.%2C+%26+Asp%2C+E.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Computer+Science+%2F+Engineering%2CLanguage&quot;&gt;Thomas, C., Keselj, V., Cercone, N., Rockwood, K., &amp;amp; Asp, E. (2005). Automatic detection and rating of dementia of Alzheimer type through lexical analysis of spontaneous speech. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;IEEE International Conference, 3&lt;/span&gt;, 1569-1574. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1626789/&quot;&gt;10.1109/ICMA.2005.1626789&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Donald Trump on the David Letterman Show&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GmNN2MCJ-7U&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;11-10-1988 Letterman Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=diIU9TH8Dq8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump Interview on Letterman Show (1997)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8JEhHvnGRNQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump Interview on David Letterman Show (1998)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qrNRX5SEsOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman Show (2008-08-08)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PP8CO61hlgk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump talks business and banks on David Letterman Show (2009-02-18)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUpabQGL_KA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman Show (2010) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PR_SoJpWzOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman 17 October, 2013 Full Interview &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/lYpsrstfx8o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump on David Letterman January 8th 2015 Full Interview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can find them all &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9-mWCMiytLi0RV53IHrGXA/search?query=donald+trump&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;other Trump&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.org/details/trumparchive?&amp;amp;sort=date&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Trump Archive&lt;/a&gt; - over 900&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; televised speeches, interviews, debates, and other news broadcasts related to President Donald Trump. See post &lt;/span&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.archive.org/2017/01/05/internet-archives-trump-archive-launches-today/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lYpsrstfx8o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donald Trump 1980 Interview (Brokaw)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ronald Reagan videos&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dCl5FG9Kl7s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - 1/29/81&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ySHtDHrLJY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - 8/12/86 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n8gN-GxiRD8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Iran/Contra Excerpt from 11/19/86&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n8gN-GxiRD8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The President's News Conference - late Oct 1987&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/tYYDadX2k1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>The Neurocritic</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Neurocritic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Deconstructing the most sensationalistic recent findings in Human Brain Imaging, Cognitive Neuroscience, and Psychopharmacology.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T19:00:55+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Early Career Researchers and Forbes 30 Under 30 Innovators Have What It Takes</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/6Yf4ryB3ptU/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7446</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;728x90_ECR 2017 R1&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;90&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/728x90_ECR-2017-R1-150x90.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is part one of a two-part blog series. Visit the PLOS ECR Community for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/thestudentblog/2017/04/03/ecrsand30under30prt1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;part two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In advance of the third &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/ecr-travel-awards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Early Career Researcher Travel Award Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; launching today, PLOS reached out to recipients of Forbes 30 Under 30 in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/30-under-30-2017/healthcare/#16f55d454f78&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Healthcare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/30-under-30-2017/science/#8e5684927fa6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; who were also PLOS authors at the time of the awards (scroll down on the Forbes pages to see individual honorees). Five leading Early Career Researchers (ECRs) working in genetics, pathogens, virology and the intersection of medicine and policy shared their views with PLOS on Open Access, open data and communicating scientific results. Below are their responses that we hope will inspire and motivate ECRs in all disciplines. At the end of this post, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Chief Editor Larry Peiperl specifically responds to the importance of data sharing and publishing all valid results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When asked, “Do you and your colleagues discuss publishing in Open Access journals, or making data openly available?” these stellar scientists replied:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0096788&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gymrek&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-7456 size-medium alignleft&quot; height=&quot;185&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/Gymrek2-1-300x185.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a computational group, we rely almost exclusively on publicly available datasets. &lt;/strong&gt;Making data openly available is critical to moving science forward, and it’s really frustrating that it is still far from ubiquitous. But I think we need to go even a step forward, and make all parts of publications, including the code and pipelines, easily available as well. I have been actively involved in discussions about why and how to do this. Luckily, I think the field of human genomics has been quite pioneering in moving toward a more “open” culture. Among my colleagues, it is just assumed that everyone puts their papers on preprint servers as soon as they’re submitted. We give people a hard time if their data is not available. Increasingly, software is getting &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mgymrek&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;posted on github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or similar repositories. Unfortunately, this is not the case in every field. —Melissa Gymrek, Assistant Professor, UC San Diego. Read Gymrek’s work in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0096788&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/article?id=10.1371/journal.pntd.0004820&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cowardin&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-7458 &quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/Cowardin2-271x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;244&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s incredibly important for data to be shared in a way that promotes collaboration and the advancement of knowledge.&lt;/strong&gt; I think in general the more diverse ways you can examine a problem, or a data set, the more likely you are to reach surprising and meaningful conclusions. As biomedical researchers, our major goal should always be to improve human health, and open access seems to be an essential part of that effort. —Carrie Cowardin, Postdoctoral fellow, Washington University. Read Cowardin’s work in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/article?id=10.1371/journal.pntd.0004820&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making data openly available is an approach we highlight and discuss in our recent analysis of alternative mechanisms of research and development on our Re:route microsite.&lt;/strong&gt; Open data platforms are one way we can make biomedical R&amp;amp;D help more people, by increasing scientific discovery output, sharing negative results, increasing competition and decreasing the cost of medicines, vaccines and diagnostics. This model is already being used to some extent by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dndi.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Drugs for Neglected Diseases &lt;em&gt;initiative&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (DND&lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mmv.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medicines for Malaria Venture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (MMV), among others. But it is not enough. This has to be implemented more broadly. —Gloria Tavera, President of the board, Universities Allied for Essential Medicines. Read Tavera’s work in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/article?id=10.1371/journal.pntd.0000635&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;When asked, as one of the new generation of influencers in their respective fields, what changes do they foresee or would like to see related to the way research findings make their way to the greater scientific community, these innovators described preprints, linked data and code, the role of politics in the direction of scientific research and new forms of media as communication tools.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.1003701&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;He&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-7463 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;121&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/He2-300x121.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the many things I’d like to see in the future is to get the science spread to the general public more often.&lt;/strong&gt; As a scientist, we’ve more often just focused on exchanging our ideas or findings within our close circle, while the general public have little idea of what we are doing. I think it will be really great for the next generation of scientists to become better communicators, and try to bridge what we know to the others, and with the use of new forms of media, I am pretty sure there will be many endeavors taken pretty soon. —Jiang He, Postdoctoral fellow, Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Read He’s work in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/article?id=10.1371/journal.ppat.1003701&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0121644&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Raj&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-7464 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;249&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/04/Raj2-300x249.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If current trends continue, the most recent scientific developments will continue to be communicated to the greater scientific community digitally, through many different open access platforms. &lt;/strong&gt;The advantage is that this information can reach a wider audience than we could have ever imagined. However, we need to make sure that this dissemination mitigates sensationalism and only communicates good, accurate science. We will need well-trained science journalists and editors to lead these changes. —Srilakshmi Raj, Postdoctoral fellow, Cornell University. Read Raj’s work &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plos.io/2okMrQp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;published in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preprints and open access will become the norm.&lt;/strong&gt;…I am particularly inspired by the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atgu.mgh.harvard.edu/PubPolicy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ATGU’s eloquent publication policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. They sum it up: “We believe that it is only a matter of time before the concept of restricted access to the products of scientific research becomes an anachronism.” …In principle, a publication should include everything needed to reproduce the main findings of the study. That has to include software as well! I am frustrated with how many times I have to reinvent the wheel by redoing an analysis that was already done in another paper. My dream is that every figure, table, and result in a paper will be linked directly to the code and data used to produce them. —Melissa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We live in an interconnected world, and as technology advances, it becomes ever more pressing to share data openly and in an expedient way.&lt;/strong&gt; The methods put in place by the WHO for sharing data on Zika virus come to mind. It’s incredibly important to maintain the quality of work we do while improving our ability to share it with others, and part of that means timely publication of results. I also hope for more acceptance of negative data, which can be just as important to be aware of as interesting positive results. Better communication and recognition of negative results would make current research much more efficient and productive. —Carrie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt; Chief Editor Larry Pieperl responds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encouraging data sharing became a priority for many during the West Africa Ebola outbreak 2-3 years ago. WHO called a consultation on data sharing and invited several journal editors to join the researchers and funding agencies for discussions in Geneva. The evidence presented there included an analysis that showed most of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1000272&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research from the 2003 SARS outbreaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; were not even submitted for publication until after the crisis was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think some people had the idea that editors presented a barrier by refusing to publish research if the data had been previously shared, and wanted us to account for ourselves. What happened may have surprised them: journal editors had no problem &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001949&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;endorsing data sharing in public health emergencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This statement of editorial policy turned out to be timely, as the first studies on Zika came soon after, and data sharing quickly became an expectation. Of course, many of us believe that data sharing shouldn’t require an international emergency. Requirements by major funding agencies that researchers share data as a condition of their grant award are an interesting recent development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding negative results, they may not win awards, but their publication is unquestionably a contribution to the research community. Think of a forest where a few well-known paths appear on a published map, but most paths are not marked at all, even though some of them have already been explored for long distances only to find they lead nowhere. Surely a signpost should be added to keep others from wasting time and resources. In clinical research, a conclusive negative result can have the immediate benefit of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1000152&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preventing futile, costly or hazardous interventions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in subsequent patients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now PLOS invites all ECRs who meet the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/ecr-travel-awards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Early Career Researcher Travel Award guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to share their views. For an opportunity to obtain support to attend a professional meeting, let us know your thoughts on the below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Considering new and modern ways of communicating science, describe the role the community can play in changing the way science is judged and assessed to accelerate science and discovery.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing your vision of the future. For more on the Forbes 30 Under 30 honorees, their backgrounds, greatest challenges and advice for success, head to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/thestudentblog/2017/04/03/ecrsand30under30prt1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS ECR Community&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;for the second part of this two-part blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/6Yf4ryB3ptU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:37+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mutual regulation of tumour vessel normalization and immunostimulatory reprogramming</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/aHBpNlZqXOM/nature21724"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21724</id>
		<updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Blockade of angiogenesis can retard tumour growth, but may also paradoxically increase metastasis. This paradox may be resolved by vessel normalization, which involves increased pericyte coverage, improved tumour vessel perfusion, reduced vascular permeability, and consequently mitigated hypoxia. Although these processes alter tumour progression, their regulation is poorly understood. Here we show that type 1 T helper (TH1) cells play a crucial role in vessel normalization. Bioinformatic analyses revealed that gene expression features related to vessel normalization correlate with immunostimulatory pathways, especially T lymphocyte infiltration or activity. To delineate the causal relationship, we used various mouse models with vessel normalization or T lymphocyte deficiencies. Although disruption of vessel normalization reduced T lymphocyte infiltration as expected, reciprocal depletion or inactivation of CD4+ T lymphocytes decreased vessel normalization, indicating a mutually regulatory loop. In addition, activation of CD4+ T lymphocytes by immune checkpoint blockade increased vessel normalization. TH1 cells that secrete interferon-γ are a major population of cells associated with vessel normalization. Patient-derived xenograft tumours growing in immunodeficient mice exhibited enhanced hypoxia compared to the original tumours in immunocompetent humans, and hypoxia was reduced by adoptive TH1 transfer. Our findings elucidate an unexpected role of TH1 cells in vasculature and immune reprogramming. TH1 cells may be a marker and a determinant of both immune checkpoint blockade and anti-angiogenesis efficacy. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21724&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21724&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/aHBpNlZqXOM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lin Tian</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Food odors are more enticing to sleep-deprived brains</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/food-odors-are-more-enticing-sleep-deprived-brains"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/food-odors-are-more-enticing-sleep-deprived-brains</id>
		<updated>2017-04-02T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sleep deprivation makes the brain more sensitive to food smells.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“Publications of questionable scientific value:” A scientist models a potential prom date</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/01/publications-questionable-scientific-value-scientist-models-potential-prom-date/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49102</id>
		<updated>2017-04-01T15:24:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Eve Armstrong had an important question: How would things have turned out if she had summoned the nerve to ask a certain Barry Cottonfield to her high school’s junior prom in 1997? Cottonfield, for those readers unfamiliar, “was a brash, unprincipled individual (private communications 1983-1998; Lunch Ladies’ Assoc. v. Cottonfield 1995) with slightly below-average learning […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/01/publications-questionable-scientific-value-scientist-models-potential-prom-date/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Publications of questionable scientific value:” A scientist models a potential prom date&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: What’s the real rate of misconduct?; research parasites win awards; preprints’ watershed moment</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/01/weekend-reads-whats-real-rate-misconduct-research-parasites-win-awards-preprints-watershed-moment/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49095</id>
		<updated>2017-04-01T13:28:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the strange story of a reappearing retracted study, and the retraction of a study showing a link between watching violent cartoons and verbal skills. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: So how much misconduct is there, anyway? The muddled testimony of a senior National Science Foundation official to the US House […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/04/01/weekend-reads-whats-real-rate-misconduct-research-parasites-win-awards-preprints-watershed-moment/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: What’s the real rate of misconduct?; research parasites win awards; preprints’ watershed moment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Book Review: &quot;The Brain Defense&quot;, Kevin Davis</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8641"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8641</id>
		<updated>2017-04-01T12:00:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Can neuroscience help courts to decide how criminals should be punished? Is moral responsibility, or the lack of it, visible on a brain scan?

In The Brain Defense (Penguin, 2017, on sale now), author Kevin Davis explores the growing use of brain images as evidence in American courtrooms. What Davis calls the &quot;brain defense&quot; is the strategy of using evidence of apparent brain abnormalities as a mitigating factor when defendants are convicted of violent crimes. If someone's brain isn't work</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">More brain differences seen between girls, boys with ADHD</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-brain-differences-seen-between-girls-boys-adhd"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-brain-differences-seen-between-girls-boys-adhd</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T16:35:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 ADHD looks different in the cerebellums of girls and boys with the condition.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Two researchers guilty of misconduct, says university investigation</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/31/two-biologists-guilty-misconduct-says-university-investigation/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49081</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T15:30:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A Swedish university has concluded that two professors studying tissue engineering are guilty of misconduct in two published papers, including a 2012 study in The Lancet. The two researchers are  Suchitra Sumitran-Holgersson and Michael Olausson, both based at the University of Gothenburg. The university investigation — launched after several of Holgersson’s papers were questioned on PubPeer — has […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/31/two-biologists-guilty-misconduct-says-university-investigation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Two researchers guilty of misconduct, says university investigation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Camera trap catches a badger burying a cow</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/camera-trap-catches-badger-burying-cow"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/camera-trap-catches-badger-burying-cow</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T15:00:30+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Badgers are known to bury small animals to save them for future eating. Now researchers have caught them caching something much bigger: young cows.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Zielinski</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Temple Grandin on the kinds of minds science desperately needs</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/temple-grandin-on-the-kinds-of-minds-science-desperately-needs"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/temple-grandin-on-the-kinds-of-minds-science-desperately-needs</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T14:26:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Renowned animal scientist and autism advocate talks about “turning on young students” to science – and not just the obvious candidates</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How many scientists admit to questionable research practices?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/31/many-researchers-admit-questionable-research-practices/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49051</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T13:30:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Sure, everyone knows it’s not a good idea to falsify data. But what about somewhat lesser offenses that also undermine the reproducibility of your findings, such as only publishing studies that “work,” and reporting an unexpected finding as something you had predicted from the beginning? In 2012, a survey of more than 2,000 psychologists based […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/31/many-researchers-admit-questionable-research-practices/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How many scientists admit to questionable research practices?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">The latest research for #AutismAwareness</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-latest-research-for-autismawareness"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-latest-research-for-autismawareness</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T11:00:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A special collection of research articles for Autism Awareness Day and Month</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">For glass frogs, moms matter after all</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/glass-frogs-moms-matter-after-all"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/glass-frogs-moms-matter-after-all</id>
		<updated>2017-03-31T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Brief but important maternal care may have evolved before the elaborate egg-tending of glass frog dads.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">SpaceX launches and lands its first reused rocket</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/spacex-launches-and-lands-its-first-reused-rocket"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/spacex-launches-and-lands-its-first-reused-rocket</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T22:42:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Aerospace company SpaceX has successfully reused a Falcon 9 rocket’s booster section for the first time.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily DeMarco</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Getting dengue first may make Zika infection much worse</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/getting-dengue-first-may-make-zika-infection-much-worse"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/getting-dengue-first-may-make-zika-infection-much-worse</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T20:26:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Experiments in cells and mice suggest that a previous exposure to dengue or West Nile can make a Zika virus infection worse.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Extreme gas loss dried out Mars, MAVEN data suggest</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-gas-loss-dried-out-mars-maven-data-suggest"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-gas-loss-dried-out-mars-maven-data-suggest</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T18:46:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Over the planet’s history, the Martian atmosphere has lost 66 percent of its argon and a majority of its carbon dioxide, according to data from NASA’s MAVEN spacecraft.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=1582</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Cancer org bestows award on scientist under investigation</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/30/cancer-org-bestows-award-scientist-investigation/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49044</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T16:06:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This month hasn’t been all bad for Carlo Croce. Despite issuing two corrections and being the subject of a lengthy New York Times article about how he’s dodged misconduct accusations for years (prompting his institution to re-open an investigation), Croce is now the recipient of a prestigious award from the American Association for Cancer Research. In a recent […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/30/cancer-org-bestows-award-scientist-investigation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cancer org bestows award on scientist under investigation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">#HeForShe in science and research</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/heforshe-in-science-and-research"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/heforshe-in-science-and-research</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T14:10:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A growing number of men are joining the movement to boost gender equality for the benefit of society</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Group whose findings support video game-violence link loses another paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/30/group-whose-findings-support-video-game-violence-link-lose-another-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49002</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T14:00:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last July, Joseph Hilgard, a postdoctoral fellow at the Annenberg Public Policy Center at the University of Pennsylvania, saw an article in Gifted Child Quarterly that made him do a double take. Hilgard, who is studying the effects of violent media on aggressive behavior, said the results of the 2016 paper “caused me some alarm.” The […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/30/group-whose-findings-support-video-game-violence-link-lose-another-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Group whose findings support video game-violence link loses another paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-03T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New tyrannosaur had a sensitive side</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-tyrannosaur-had-sensitive-side"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-tyrannosaur-had-sensitive-side</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T13:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Tyrannosaurs may have had sensitive snouts that detected temperature and touch.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Eaton</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">For kids, daily juice probably won’t pack on the pounds</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/kids-daily-juice-probably-wont-pack-pounds"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/kids-daily-juice-probably-wont-pack-pounds</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An analysis of existing studies suggests that regular juice drinking isn’t linked to much weight gain in kids.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">You’re in my space! How preferred interpersonal distance varies across the world</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/30/youre-in-my-space-how-preferred-interpersonal-distance-varies-across-the-world/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=21711</id>
		<updated>2017-03-30T09:52:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_21840&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Obama Meets With European Leaders In Berlin&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-21840&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;21840&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;BERLIN, GERMANY - NOVEMBER 18:  German Chancellor Angela Merkel (R) greets British Prime Minister Theresa May upon her arrival for talks between U.S. President Barack Obama and western European leaders at the Chancellery on November 18, 2016 in Berlin, Germany.Obama and Merkel will hold talks with British Prime Minister Theresa May, French President Francois Hollande, Italian Prime Minister Matteo Renzi and Spanish Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy today on Obama's last trip to Europe as U.S. President.  (Photo by Sean Gallup\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1479466398&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2016 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1600&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Obama Meets With European Leaders In Berlin&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Obama Meets With European Leaders In Berlin&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-624089046.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-624089046.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-624089046.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,683&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/30/youre-in-my-space-how-preferred-interpersonal-distance-varies-across-the-world/obama-meets-with-european-leaders-in-berlin-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-624089046.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Compared with English participants, Germans were comfortable with a smaller interpersonal space when chatting to an acquaintance&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s really awkward when you’re chatting to someone whose sense of appropriate interpersonal space is way too close. There’s the option of performing a subtle backward shuffle, but what if they simply close the gap again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our judgments about such things obviously vary with individual personality – people with more social anxiety tend to prefer a greater distance – and also on the nature of the relationship we have with the other person. But culture must surely play a part too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out how preferred interpersonal distances vary across the world, the authors of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0022022117698039&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cross-Cultural Psychology&lt;/em&gt; approached – not too close, presumably – nearly 9,000 participants in 42 countries and asked them to indicate on a simple graphic how close another person – either a stranger, friend or more intimate relation – could get to them during a conversation for things to remain comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-21711&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three countries where participants’ preferred minimal distance from a stranger was largest were Romania (approximately 140cm), Hungary and Saudi Arabia; conversely the three countries where participants were happiest being most up close with a stranger were Argentina (80cm), Peru and Bulgaria. The UK was represented by England, with participants here coming out near the middle (approximately 1 metre) in terms of the spread of international preferences for when talking with a stranger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The averaged preferred minimal distances from a friend or acquaintance during conversation were smaller, as you’d expect, but the rank order across countries was fairly similar to the order for stranger distance. So, in countries where people tended to prefer a greater distance from strangers during conversation, they also tended to prefer a greater distance from friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intriguingly, this wasn’t so much the case for preferred minimal distance when conversing with a close or more intimate other person. For instance, Romanians, who you remember liked the largest distance from a stranger, actually came out as having among the smallest preferred minimal distances from an intimate relation (about 50cm). Likewise, Norwegians came out near the middle in the distribution of preferred minimal distances from a stranger, but were happy with the smallest amount of physical distance (approx 40cm) from a close other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead author Agnieszka Sorokowska and her dozens of colleagues around the world also looked to see if international differences in climate and vulnerability to parasites might correlate with preferred interpersonal differences. The parasite measure wasn’t relevant, but average temperature was: in warmer countries, participants tended to be happier with smaller distances when chatting to strangers, perhaps because &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2009/10/23/a-warm-room-makes-people-feel-socially-closer/&quot;&gt;people feel socially closer in warmer climes&lt;/a&gt;, the researchers speculated; in contrast, when it came to intimate relationships, it was colder countries that were happier with smaller distances, perhaps as a way to stay cosy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across countries, women tended to prefer greater distances from the other person, as did older participants. An obvious limitation of the study is that it was based on participants’ judgments of the interpersonal distances they think they would prefer, not on actual observations of their behaviour. Still, the researchers collected an impressive amount of data from a huge range of countries, providing a fascinating global perspective on an everyday personal experience: just how close is too close when you’re chatting to another person?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0022022117698039&quot;&gt;Preferred Interpersonal Distances A Global Comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via gettyimages.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21711/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21711/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=21711&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mosquito flight is unlike that of any other insect</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mosquito-flight-unlike-any-other-insect"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mosquito-flight-unlike-any-other-insect</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T19:00:25+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 High-speed video and modeling reveal a more complex understanding of mosquito flight.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?paged=2</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">“A Course In Deception:” Scientist’s novel takes on research misconduct</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/course-deception-scientists-novel-takes-research-misconduct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=49016</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T18:00:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Jana Rieger is a researcher in Edmonton, Alberta. And now, she’s also a novelist. Her new book, “A Course in Deception,” draws on her experiences in science, and weaves a tale of how greed and pressures to publish can lead to even worse outcomes than the sort we write about at Retraction Watch. We interviewed Rieger […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/course-deception-scientists-novel-takes-research-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“A Course In Deception:” Scientist’s novel takes on research misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-03T23:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neandertals had an eye for patterns</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/neandertals-had-eye-patterns"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/neandertals-had-eye-patterns</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T18:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Neandertals carved notches in a raven bone, possibly to produce a pleasing or symbolic pattern, scientists say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?paged=2</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Thinning ice creates undersea Arctic greenhouses</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/thinning-ice-creates-undersea-arctic-greenhouses"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/thinning-ice-creates-undersea-arctic-greenhouses</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T18:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Arctic sea ice thinned by climate change increasingly produces conditions favorable for phytoplankton blooms in the waters below, new research suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thomas Sumner</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?paged=2</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T11:00:39+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Asteroid in Jupiter's orbit goes its own way</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/asteroid-jupiters-orbit-goes-its-own-way"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/asteroid-jupiters-orbit-goes-its-own-way</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Asteroid shares Jupiter’s orbit around the sun but travels in the opposite direction as the planet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=517</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T05:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Gene editing of human embryos yields early results</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gene-editing-human-embryos-yields-early-results"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gene-editing-human-embryos-yields-early-results</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T15:30:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Gene editing in embryos has started in labs, but isn’t ready for the clinic.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_6094559487893296=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Automated validation and comparison of neurophysiological biomarkers of psychiatric disorders</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/03/29/automated-validation-and-comparison-of-neurophysiological-biomarkers-of-psychiatric-disorders.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-03-29:/2017/03/29/automated-validation-and-comparison-of-neurophysiological-biomarkers-of-psychiatric-disorders.html</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T14:22:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Research on psychiatric disorders has gradually shifted its focus from complex clinical phenotypes towards the identification of biomarkers and endophenotypic measures. Computational approaches have gained significantly more attention over the last years, and this has led to the emergence of 'Computational Psychiatry' as an independent discipline. Computational modelling of biomarkers promises to more readily shed light on the mechanisms underlying disorders and to facilitate the discovery of novel medications [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in order to develop a computational model, scientists need to have an in-depth understanding of the current, relevant experimental data, the current state of computational modeling and the state-of-the-art of statistical testing. Based on this knowledge, they have to choose the appropriate criteria with which the model predictions and experimental observations will be compared [2]. In a field where both the number of experimental and computational studies grows rapidly, as is the case for psychiatry, this becomes more and more impracticable. Omar et al. therefore proposed a framework for automated validation of scientific models, SciUnit [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we propose to adopt this framework for the computational psychiatry community and to collaboratively build common repositories of experimental observations, computational models, test suites and tools. As a case in point, we have implemented test suites for auditory steady-state response deficits in schizophrenic patients, which are based on observations from several experimental studies [4,5,6], and we demonstrate how existing computational models [6,7] can be validated against these observations and compared against each other. We have included sets of observations from three experimental studies, which concur on most findings but also disagree on some. This allows us to demonstrate the usefulness of our approach in highlighting and clarifying existing, potentially conflicting, experimental data. We have included computational models that not only comprise biophysically detailed as well as abstract models, but that also differ in implementation (native Python vs. Genesis vs NeuroML2), in order to demonstrate the flexibility of the approach. Furthermore, this additionally allows us to showcase the ability of the framework to compare models against each other based on a set of experimental observations. Furthermore, our approach enables us to assess the variability of the produced model output, and therefore the robustness of the findings, by generating a distribution of model instances where certain parameters, such as the precise timing of noise inputs (however, not the strength and type of noise) or the precise connectivity (however, not the underlying distribution of connections) vary, which then are used to produce a distribution of model outputs. This can inform on the robustness of the findings and can also be compared against the variability of experimental observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;arabic simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siekmeier, P.: Computational modeling of psychiatric illnesses via well-defined neurophysiological and neurocognitive biomarkers. Neuroscience &amp;amp; Biobehavioral Reviews 57: 365-380, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gerkin, R.C. and Omar, C.: NeuroUnit: Validation Tests for Neuroscience Models. Front. Neuroinform. Conference Abstract: Neuroinformatics 2013. doi: 10.3389/conf.fninf.2013.09.00013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omar, C., Aldrich, J., and Gerkin, R.C.: Collaborative infrastructure for test-driven scientific model validation. In CompanionProceedings of the 36th International Conference on Software Engineering, ACM, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kwon J.S., O’Donnell B.F., Wallenstein G.V., Greene R.W., Hirayasu Y., Nestor P.G., Hasselmo M.E., Potts G.F., Shenton M.E., and McCarley R.W..: Gamma frequency–range abnormalities to auditory stimulation in schizophrenia. Archives of General Psychiatry, 56(11):1001–1005, 1999.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krishnan, G.P., Hetrick, W.P., Brenner, C.A., Shekhar, A., Steffen, A.N., and O’Donnell, B.F.: Steady state and induced auditory gamma deficits in schizophrenia. Neuroimage, 47(4):1711–1719, 2009.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vierling-Claassen, D., Siekmeier, P., Stufflebeam, S., and Kopell, N.: Modeling GABA alterations in schizophrenia: a link between impaired inhibition and altered gamma and beta range auditory entrainment. Journal of Neurophysiology, 99(5):2656–2671, 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metzner, C., Schweikard, A. and Zurowski, B.: Multi-factorial modeling of impairment of evoked gamma range oscillations in schizophrenia. Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, 10, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 31/03/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christoph Metzner</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T15:33:18+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Research misconduct finding — which university won’t discuss — leads to second retraction for prominent physicist</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/research-misconduct-finding-university-wont-discuss-leads-second-retraction-prominent-physicist/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48995</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T13:30:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A rising star in nanotechnology, Dmitri Lapotko, has received his second retraction within a month over “a finding of research misconduct” that the university will apparently only disclose on a need-to-know basis. According to the notice, the journal’s editor and publisher issued the retraction after Lapotko’s former institution—Rice University in Houston—notified them of research misconduct and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/research-misconduct-finding-university-wont-discuss-leads-second-retraction-prominent-physicist/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Research misconduct finding — which university won’t discuss — leads to second retraction for prominent physicist&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-03T17:00:41+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author duplicated a figure in three papers; two get retracted</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/author-duplicated-figure-three-papers-two-get-retracted/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48740</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T13:30:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Two journals have retracted two papers by the same group within months of each other, after editors were independently tipped off that they contained duplicated figures representing different experiments. The two papers were published by PLOS ONE and The Egyptian Journal of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (EJBMB) in 2015 and 2014, respectively. According to the PLOS ONE paper’s corresponding author, last […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/29/author-duplicated-figure-three-papers-two-get-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author duplicated a figure in three papers; two get retracted&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-04-01T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">People who feel connected to nature are more prone to “electrosensitivity”</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/29/people-who-feel-connected-to-nature-are-more-prone-to-electrosensitivity/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=21633</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T11:35:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Radiation from mobile phone lead to brain damage.&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-21702 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;21702&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Radiation from mobile phone lead to brain damage. Medical illustration.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;solar22&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Radiation from mobile phone lead to brain damage.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Radiation from mobile phone lead to brain damage.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-543199034.jpg?w=730&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-543199034.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=197&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-543199034.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;730,479&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/29/people-who-feel-connected-to-nature-are-more-prone-to-electrosensitivity/radiation-from-mobile-phone-lead-to-brain-damage/&quot; height=&quot;197&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-543199034.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=197&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the TV series &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;, Saul’s brother Chuck believes that electromagnetic signals from mobile phones and other devices make him seriously ill. He lives as a recluse and uses a foil blanket to protect himself. By some estimates, millions of people – around 5 per cent of the population – believe that they too suffer from “electrosensitivity” or “electromagnetic hypersensitivity”. Though they may not suffer as much as Chuck, these individuals claim that wi-fi and other signals make them ill, triggering headaches and other symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical consensus based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bmj.com/content/332/7546/886.full&quot;&gt;double-blind trials&lt;/a&gt; (in which neither researcher nor test subject knows when a test device is real or pretend) is that while the experience of electrosensitivity-related symptoms may be real, they are not caused by electromagnetic fields. More likely is that the symptoms arise from a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nocebo&quot;&gt;nocebebo effect&lt;/a&gt;” – a strong belief that the fields are harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1359105317699681&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; sheds new light on electrosensitivity by suggesting that it is people who feel especially connected to nature – normally considered a positive trait – who may be particularly likely to suffer from electrosensitivity, probably because their love of nature is accompanied by a heightened negative attitude to anything they consider artificial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zsuzsanna Dömötör and her colleagues surveyed 510 people online, 74 of whom described themselves as electrosensitive. The electrosensitive participants tended to score higher than the others on modern health worries in general (related to things like pollution and tainted food), on sensitivity to bodily symptoms, and nature relatedness (measured by agreement with items like “I always think about how my actions affect the environment” and “My ideal vacation spot would be a remote, wilderness area”). What’s more, nature connectedness interacted with the other variables: people prone to modern health worries were especially likely to complain of electrosensitivity if they also felt a connection with nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1359105317699681&quot;&gt;Nature relatedness is connected with modern health worries and electromagnetic hypersensitivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21633/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21633/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=21633&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A scientific measure of our visual imagination suggests it is surprisingly limited</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/29/a-scientific-measure-of-our-visual-imagination-shows-it-is-surprisingly-limited/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=21595</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T09:08:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Thinker&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-21626&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;21626&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Beyond Human series. Collage of human, geometric and natural forms on the subject of inner reality, mental health, imagination, mysticism, thinking and dreaming.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1384437086&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;agsandrew&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Thinker&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The Thinker&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-457796625.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-457796625.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-457796625.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3600,2700&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/29/a-scientific-measure-of-our-visual-imagination-shows-it-is-surprisingly-limited/the-thinker/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/gettyimages-457796625.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human mind has been so successful in transforming the material world that it is easy to forget that it too is subject to its own constraints. From biases in our judgment to the imperfection of our memory, psychology has done useful work mapping out many of these limits, yet when it comes to the human imagination, most of us still like to see it as something boundless. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010027717300367&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt;, on the capacity of our visual imagination, suggests that we soon hit its limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-21595&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Keogh and Joel Pearson from the University of New South Wales conducted a series of tightly controlled experiments involving 72 participants, mostly students from the university. In every experiment, participants donned special glasses and sat before a computer screen to view dozens or hundreds of trials each composed of two phases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first phase, the screen was lit up with dotted outlines marking out “imagination spaces”. The participants had to mentally “fill-in” between one and seven of these spaces with a simple pattern, either red with horizontal stripes or green with vertical stripes (similar to those pictured below). Cues in the dotted outlines indicated which pattern to visualize in which space. Participants attempted to keep the imagination spaces appropriately coloured in their minds for six seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-03-29 at 09.43.15&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-21608&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;21608&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2017-03-29 at 09.43.15&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/screen-shot-2017-03-29-at-09-43-15.png?w=845?w=789&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/screen-shot-2017-03-29-at-09-43-15.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/screen-shot-2017-03-29-at-09-43-15.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;789,390&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/29/a-scientific-measure-of-our-visual-imagination-shows-it-is-surprisingly-limited/screen-shot-2017-03-29-at-09-43-15/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/screen-shot-2017-03-29-at-09-43-15.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately afterwards, the second phase of each trial determined how successfully the participants had pictured the patterns, and this is where the glasses came into play. They beamed the red pattern into one eye, and the green into the other. When faced with two competing images presented to each eye in this way, the human mind quickly settles on just one image, banishing the other from conscious awareness in a well-known phenomenon called “binocular rivalry”. All things being equal, the battle between competing images is random: half the time one will dominate our perception, half the time the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But crucially, the outcome of this process can be influenced by the content of our imagination, especially when the real and imagined share the same location. The researchers took advantage of this and, each trial, always targeted the real images at one of the imagination spaces that had been triggered in the first phase, to see whether the mental pattern in that location was strong enough to tip the binocular battle one way or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When participants only had to fill one imagination space, and the two rival real patterns were beamed to this location, the mental image there strongly influenced the rivalry phase: participants were swayed towards seeing whichever real pattern corresponded with the imagined pattern seventy per cent of the time (fifty per cent would mean no influence).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But once participants were tasked with filling two imagination spaces, the biasing effect of beaming the real patterns onto either one of those imagined patterns dropped to sixty per cent. Imagining three or more patterns led to a further drop-off in the influence of imagined patterns on the process of binocular rivalry. In fact, the experimenters quickly adjusted their design to avoid trials with six or more imagination spaces as it was clear participants couldn’t handle it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doubling the imagination phase duration to 12 seconds didn’t improve success for multiple imagination spaces, ruling out the possibility that more imagining just takes more time to get going. Further experiments revealed how the mind deals with greater demands on the imagination: trying to fill more imagination spaces led to rougher mental images at every location, rather than a few filled vividly with others more or less abandoned. This tallies with participants’ descriptions: they said vividness of the imagined patterns suffered as demand increased. This quantity-quality trade-off suggests some kind of resolution issue: think of limited pixels on a screen, or the space available on an artist’s canvas. These two-dimensional examples may be more than an analogy, as visual brain areas have limited anatomical space to represent information, and often do so across two-dimensional maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keogh and Pearson said their results are beginning to map out the “severe capacity limits” of internal representation, and demonstrate how much the architecture of thought depends on the foundations of perception. This is truly important work in understanding the mind, and how much of the world we can truly grasp. Yet, contrasting the effortful yet arbitrary visualisation investigated in this study with the rich, spontaneously arising visions I’ve personally experienced during meditation – or the overwhelming sense of reality we’ve all experienced in dreams – I’m left wondering how these limits may vary according to our states and motivations. That’s worthy of future research, because feeling out the firmament of the imagination is a most worthwhile goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010027717300367&quot;&gt;The perceptual and phenomenal capacity of mental imagery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gettyimages.co.uk&quot;&gt;gettyimages.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21595/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/21595/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=21595&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Will the ‘4th Industrial Revolution’ be gender-blind?</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/will-the-4th-industrial-revolution-be-gender-blind"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/will-the-4th-industrial-revolution-be-gender-blind</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T08:23:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 More women in engineering and computing will help focus technological progress on societal needs</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-04-04T11:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">A mother’s love can’t cure it all: No benefits of maternal care on immunity in a group-living insect</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/29/mothers-love-cant-cure-no-benefits-maternal-care-immunity-group-living-insect/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8782</id>
		<updated>2017-03-29T06:00:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;An earwig family&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/Earwig-family-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During their life, animals encounter many different threats, from predators to parasites, which can weaken or even kill them. To limit the costs of pathogen infections, hosts typically rely on their body’s immune system. But personal immunity is not the only way to be protected from pathogens. In group-living animals, social immunity describes the cooperative actions of group members to fight together against parasites and pathogens. These actions can take many different forms such as reciprocal grooming to remove external parasites, or the sanitary disposal of waste to prevent the growth of pathogenic microbes, as found in ant and bee colonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social immunity is also important for species living in family groups (i.e. parents and offspring), in which parents care for their young. Not only humans have been documented to improve the immunity of their children, but also mice and rats. However, it is less clear whether such beneficial effects of parental care exist in insects and whether these benefits could have contributed to the evolution of social life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the influence of the mother on offspring immunity, we studied the European earwig &lt;em&gt;Forficula auricularia. &lt;/em&gt;This insect is an interesting model to address this kind of question because earwig mothers provide multiple forms of care to their young such as food provisioning, grooming and protection against predators. Young earwigs are nevertheless mobile, can forage on their own and are thus able to develop and survive in the absence of a tending mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these unique aspects of their lifestyle, we were able to investigate the effect of the mother on offspring immunity by experimentally manipulating maternal presence and parasite exposure. Based on the findings in social vertebrates, we predicted that maternal presence will improve the short- and long-term survival of offspring when exposed to a pathogen. Moreover, we expected that maternal presence either increases offspring immunity, when the resources provided by the mother facilitate the development of the immune system, or alternatively decrease offspring immunity, when young earwigs invest less in immune defenses because of the protection provided by the mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8785&quot; style=&quot;width: 2830px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Earwig mother moving her nymphs&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8785&quot; height=&quot;1969&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/Earwig_mother-moving-nymphs.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2820&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Earwig mother moving her nymphs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Joël Meunier&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, we found that maternal presence did not affect offspring immunity in the short- or in the long-term, even when exposed to pathogens. Moreover, maternal presence appears to generally reduce offspring survival, independently of pathogen exposure. The fact that maternal presence does not influence pathogen resistance of their young indicates that while unable to ward off disease, care provided by earwig mothers might be useful in other contexts such as protection against predators or adverse climatic conditions. This also suggests that pathogen pressure does not appear to be a universal promoter for the evolution of parental care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surprisingly negative effect of maternal presence on offspring survival supports earlier work on earwigs, which reported that the mothers’ influence on the well-being of their offspring also depends on food availability. This highlights the complex nature of mother-offspring interactions, but also indicates that interactions among siblings might be crucial for the evolution of family life, an aspect that deserves more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, our findings reveal that the benefits of family interactions in terms of protection against pathogen infection are unlikely to be driven by the mother. Instead, we propose that such benefits could come from the young themselves. In earwigs, mothers and siblings line their nest with their own feces, which exhibits antimicrobial properties. That way, they possibly reduce the need of investing into their personal immunity as their habitat is largely pathogen-free. This investment in social immunity might be an important way to ensure family health. Hence, our findings show that the role of sibling behavior may be an underestimated factor in the evolution and maintenance of family life in the face of pathogen pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fanny Vogelweith &lt;a href=&quot;http://fanny-vogelweith.com/&quot;&gt;http://fanny-vogelweith.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maximilian Körner &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bio.uni-mainz.de/zoo/evobio/453_DEU_HTML.php&quot;&gt;http://www.bio.uni-mainz.de/zoo/evobio/453_DEU_HTML.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susanne Foitzik &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bio.uni-mainz.de/zoo/evobio/51_DEU_HTML.php&quot;&gt;http://www.bio.uni-mainz.de/zoo/evobio/51_DEU_HTML.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joel Meunier &lt;a href=&quot;http://joelmeunier.wixsite.com/researchpage&quot;&gt;http://joelmeunier.wixsite.com/researchpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/29/mothers-love-cant-cure-no-benefits-maternal-care-immunity-group-living-insect/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A mother’s love can’t cure it all: No benefits of maternal care on immunity in a group-living insect&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr Fanny Vogelweith</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-04-05T23:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
