<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:39+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Can a reasoning test predict who will make a good detective?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/28/can-a-reasoning-test-predict-who-will-make-a-good-detective/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33367</id>
		<updated>2018-02-28T09:35:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-118096569.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33371&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33371&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Peter Sellers as Inspector Clouseau is disguised as a mountain climber, while hiding in  a trash can, in a scene from the film 'The Pink Panther Strikes Again', 1976. (Photo by United Artists\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2011 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Peter Sellers In 'The Pink Panther Strikes Again'&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Peter Sellers In ‘The Pink Panther Strikes Again’&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-118096569.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-118096569.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-118096569.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;5985,4684&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/28/can-a-reasoning-test-predict-who-will-make-a-good-detective/peter-sellers-in-the-pink-panther-strikes-again/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-118096569.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although criminal investigation has been transformed through technological developments in DNA, phone tracking, and online data, the way a detective works through a crime has remained much the same. The first suspect is often the true perpetrator, but not always, and snowballing biases continue to lead to miscarriages of justice. Proficient detectives need the ability to generate and evaluate different explanations and keep an open mind. New &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11896-017-9231-3&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Police and Criminal Psychology&lt;/i&gt; investigates whether it’s possible to use established tests of reasoning ability to identify who has the skills necessary for thinking this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33367&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Gothenburg psychologists Ivar Fahsing and Karl Ask asked 166 recruits (60 women, aged around 23) from the Norwegian Police University College to complete two tests of reasoning ability. One involved deductive reasoning – the ability to apply rules to reach a correct conclusion, in this case, combining shapes to form a new target shape. The other involved inductive reasoning –  viewing different images, and using these to figure out the rule that is governing them all. These tests already feature in Norwegian police recruitment but it’s not clear whether they are useful for predicting detective skills, which are more dependent on abductive reasoning, which is much harder to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas deduction seeks linear, definitive conclusions, and induction tries to identify a category based on the available clues (“all birds, none fly”  therefore the category must be “flightless birds”), abduction amplifies the known information to generate imaginative possibilities (“an open wine bottle and smashed glasses could suggest a thwarted seduction… or a failed reconciliation with his wife?”). It requires a leap of logic, a creative act, hard to measure but known to differentiate stronger investigators, whether criminal or scientific. The ability to make many such leaps helps avoid premature foreclosure on the possibilities of a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fahsing and Ask were hopeful that measures of deductive and inductive reasoning would help identify better detectives because investigation isn’t rooted solely in abduction, and because different forms of reasoning ability are known to correlate (so a candidate skilful at deduction and induction ought to be skilled at abduction and therefore detective thinking too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assess detection nous, the researchers asked their participants to review two case vignettes, each describing a woman missing under ambiguous circumstances, and some versions also mentioned the arrest of a suspect. The participants’ task was to outline all the possible explanations that could account for the facts. Both vignettes had been reviewed by an expert panel of detectives, who generated a “gold standard” of 9 viable hypotheses for the first and 11 for the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants tended to neglect the non-criminal hypotheses, such as the possibility the missing woman had suffered an accident. More importantly, scores on the reasoning ability tests didn’t predict their detective performance. Nor did they predict immunity to a commonly observed detecting error: becoming more narrow-minded (generating fewer hypotheses) after reading that a suspect had been arrested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current data suggest that commonly used cognitive assessments are unlikely to help identify candidates with the best aptitude for becoming a detective. It seems police forces will need to think more inventively about the actual skills that contribute to good detection if they are to succeed in separating the Maigrets from the Clouseaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11896-017-9231-3&quot;&gt;In Search of Indicators of Detective Aptitude: Police Recruits’ Logical Reasoning and Ability to Generate Investigative Hypotheses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Peter Sellers In ‘The Pink Panther Strikes Again’ is disguised as a mountain climber, while hiding in a trash can, in a scene from the film ‘The Pink Panther Strikes Again’, 1976. (Photo by United Artists/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Watch an experimental space shield shred a speeding bullet</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/space-debris-shield-bullet"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/space-debris-shield-bullet</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T20:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Engineers tested how well a prototype shield for spacecraft would stand up to space debris by shooting it with a solid aluminum pellet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Remembering Joe Polchinski, the modest physicist who conceived a multiverse</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/remembering-joe-polchinski-modest-physicist-who-conceived-multiverse"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/remembering-joe-polchinski-modest-physicist-who-conceived-multiverse</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T20:01:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 String theorists lament the death of Joe Polchinski, one of their field’s most esteemed and respected thinkers.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Siegfried</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A rare rainstorm wakes undead microbes in Chile’s Atacama Desert</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rain-wakes-undead-microbes-chile-atacama-desert"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rain-wakes-undead-microbes-chile-atacama-desert</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T19:33:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Microbial life in Chile’s Atacama Desert bursts into bloom when moisture is available.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">These giant viruses have more protein-making gear than any known virus</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-giant-viruses-have-more-protein-making-gear-any-known-virus"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-giant-viruses-have-more-protein-making-gear-any-known-virus</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T19:06:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists have found two more giant viruses in extreme environments in Brazil.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Cancer researcher under cloud of suspicion wins $300,000 science prize</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/cancer-researcher-under-cloud-of-suspicion-wins-300000-science-prize/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62132</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T18:56:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Carlo Croce, who has had numerous papers retracted and corrected for issues including image manipulation, has received an award for more than $300,000 for his achievements in personalized medicine. The Dan David Prize, awarded earlier this month by a charitable organization based at Tel Aviv University, bestowed $1 million to three researchers who have “made pioneering … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/cancer-researcher-under-cloud-of-suspicion-wins-300000-science-prize/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Cancer researcher under cloud of suspicion wins $300,000 science prize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS Collaborates on Recommendations to Improve Transparency for Author Contributions</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/hMjMgXXat38/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8076</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T18:30:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/02/Dichroic_filters_690x320px-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/orcid.org/0000-0001-8771-7239&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;orcid.org/0000-0001-8771-7239&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a new report, a group convened by the US National Academy of Sciences and including a dozen journal editors reflects on authorship guidelines and recommends new ways to make author contributions more transparent. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What does it mean to be author number seven on a twenty-five–author article?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing transparency for each author’s role in a research study is one of the recommendations in a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/02/26/1715374115&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report published today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PNAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) by a group led by Marcia McNutt, President of the National Academy of Sciences. The recommendations issued by this group, which included one of us, were adapted based on community feedback and peer review from an original draft presented as a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/05/20/140228&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. PLOS supports the recommendations for increased transparency and has already put some of them in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more systematic description of author contributions is a prerequisite to providing due credit for roles that are instrumental to the research enterprise, especially those roles that are too often ignored or devalued. For example, collecting, curating and sharing a dataset or developing a new methodological approach that can be reused by others are key contributions that may not always land a ‘first author position’ but have applications beyond a single article and deserve recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency also brings more accountability to a system where questionable and even detrimental practices (such as guest, ghost or conscripted authorship) have been documented. While transparency requirements cannot entirely eliminate abuse, transparent description of individual author contributions can deter inaccurate representations and can expose institutionalized authorship practices that should be questioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, a concern often heard about emphasizing contributions is that they risk diluting individual author responsibility for the overall integrity of a study. The recommendations address this concern by stipulating authorship standards that require each author to be “personally accountable for [their] own contributions and to ensure that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work, even ones in which the author was not personally involved, are appropriately investigated, resolved, and the resolution documented in the literature.” Thus, having one’s contributions precisely described does not absolve any author of responsibility for the accuracy and rigor of the entire study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper also recommends mechanisms by which publishers can bring a minimum level of standardization to the description of author contributions. In particular, the group advocates for the implementation of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://orcid.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ORCID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; identifiers and the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dictionary.casrai.org/Contributor_Roles&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CRediT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; taxonomy as emerging standards in the industry. While many journals already require specification of author contributions, a more fully integrated system of persistent identifiers (like ORCID iDs for authors and DOIs for articles) connected via a standardized vocabulary of relationships (like the CRediT taxonomy for contributions) will make the information both human- and machine-readable and allow it to be surfaced more easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS journals have adopted both &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/01/author-credit-plos-orcid-update/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ORCID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/07/author-credit-plos-and-credit-update/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CRediT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; since 2016; the roles and ORCID iDs provided by authors are now visible with one click on the author name in the by-line. ORCID information is passed on to CrossRef, which updates ORCID records with authors’ permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our experience, the CRediT taxonomy has worked well, but the definition of some individual terms could be improved. In particular, those related to data may benefit from some refinement to distinguish generation of data from its subsequent curation. As others examine the possibility of using the taxonomy, we encourage a collaborative approach with CASRAI’s CRediT Committee, the taxonomy steward, to match the needs of different communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all roles in the CRediT taxonomy immediately qualify a participant for authorship; that qualification is determined by journal policy. To determine who should be an author, PLOS currently follows the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icmje.org/recommendations/browse/roles-and-responsibilities/defining-the-role-of-authors-and-contributors.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recommendation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; established by the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icmje.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ICMJE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) for medical journals which posits that authorship should be associated with a substantive intellectual contribution as well as participation in drafting or revising the manuscript. While &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/s/authorship&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; checks that all four ICMJE criteria are met by all authors, the experience at other PLOS journals indicates that in fields outside medicine, not all authors state they have participated in the drafting or revising of the manuscript. The proposed adaptation of authorship criteria in the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2018/02/26/1715374115&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;current PNAS report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which includes writing as a &lt;em&gt;qualification&lt;/em&gt; for authorship but does not &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; it, aims not to exclude important contributors from authorship. Conversely, the inclusion of writing without other intellectual contribution to a study as a role worthy of authorship may not find acceptance in all disciplines. The intent is not to impose a monolithic approach to authorship, but to accommodate a broad range of community standards transparently. When contributors do not meet authorship criteria, CRediT can also serve to document their precise contributions as acknowledged colleagues, supported by other means of credit like citations of protocols and datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasonline.org/about-nas/Transparency_Author_Contributions.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the report’s authors commit to reflect upon and improve current authorship guidelines and practices at the journals they represent, and they encourage other journals to do the same. Such introspection and subsequent discussion are timely, as research studies are increasingly large-scale and multi-disciplinary affairs. As more work goes into providing due credit for scholarly contributions like methods development, data collection and data sharing, transparency in authorship roles should advance in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Competing Interests Disclosure: Veronique Kiermer is an author of the recommendations discussed and Chair of the ORCID Board. Larry Peiperl serves on the ICMJE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dichroic_filter&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/hMjMgXXat38&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Veronique Kiermer</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Should publicly funded research tools be free for researchers to use?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/caught-our-notice-so-publicly-funded-research-tools-arent-always-free-to-the-public/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62077</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T16:00:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Title: Adherence to Adjuvant Neuropathic Pain Medications in a Palliative Care Clinic What Caught Our Attention: We’ve found a fourth retraction for the unlicensed use of a common research tool, an issue we explored in depth for Science last year. Quick recap: When researchers use a copyrighted questionnaire (MMAS-8) without permission, they get a call … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/caught-our-notice-so-publicly-funded-research-tools-arent-always-free-to-the-public/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Should publicly funded research tools be free for researchers to use?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">After “considerable intellectual agony,” journal retracts Wansink paper</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/after-considerable-intellectual-agony-journal-retracts-wansink-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62116</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T13:02:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ever since critics began raising concerns about high-profile food scientist Brian Wansink’s work, he’s had to issue a series of high-profile retractions — and now has his seventh (including one paper that was retracted twice, after the journal removed a revised version, along with 14 corrections). The latest notice — first reported by BuzzFeed — … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/27/after-considerable-intellectual-agony-journal-retracts-wansink-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;After “considerable intellectual agony,” journal retracts Wansink paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How radiologists and pathologists can win at the game of Clue</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-radiologists-and-pathologists-can-win-at-the-game-of-clue"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-radiologists-and-pathologists-can-win-at-the-game-of-clue</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T10:21:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A radiology professor and Medical Director for Elsevier’s Clinical Solutions writes about two award-winning systems she helped develop</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T12:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Smart or determined? Examining the influence of motivation on IQ test performance</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/27/smart-or-determined-examining-the-role-of-motivation-in-iq-tests/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33349</id>
		<updated>2018-02-27T10:14:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-918364616.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33352&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33352&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 6D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired businessman squinting eyes looking at laptop screen trying to focus concentrate, office employee thinking of online problem suffering from fatigue, headache or bad sight, computer syndrome&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1500031464&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1600&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Businessman squinting eyes trying to focus looking at laptop screen&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Businessman squinting eyes trying to focus looking at laptop screen&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-918364616.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-918364616.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-918364616.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/27/smart-or-determined-examining-the-role-of-motivation-in-iq-tests/businessman-squinting-eyes-trying-to-focus-looking-at-laptop-screen/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-918364616.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligence tests are meant to tell you something about a person’s inherent abilities. But what if the results are distorted by the motivation to perform well? That would undermine the tests’ validity and have important implications for their use in education and recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple way to find out whether motivation affects intelligence test performance is to offer people a financial incentive for doing well and see if this helps them get a higher score. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjop.12288/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;British Journal of Psychology&lt;/i&gt; has done this, finding that while a financial incentive boosted people’s self-declared effort levels, it failed to lift their performance. This result is good news for the validity of intelligence testing. Or as the paper’s author, Gilles Gignac at the University of Western Australia, put it: “The position of a causal effect of test-taking motivation on intelligence test performance in adults does not, yet, appear to be clearly tenable”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33349&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background to this research is a controversial &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2011/04/19/1018601108&quot;&gt;meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; published in 2011 by Angela Duckworth (of Grit fame) and her colleagues which suggested that motivation distorts IQ test performance, thereby challenging the validity of IQ tests as a pure measure of ability. However, only 2 of the 46 samples included in that meta-analysis featured adults, and the findings from those adult samples were inconclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To plug this gap, Gignac recruited 99 undergrads and asked them to complete various intelligence tests, including of basic “processing speed”, working memory, fluid intelligence (measured using Raven’s progressive matrices) and crystallised intelligence (based on a vocab test).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gignac split the tests in half so that the participants completed two very similar testing sessions in succession: one without any financial incentive and one with the chance to win $75 if they were among the top 10 per cent of performers (some participants did the session with this incentive first, others did it second). After each session, the participants completed a survey about how much effort they had put in and how important they thought the tests were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The financial incentive didn’t affect the participants’ perception of the importance of the tests. However it affected their effort levels, at least according to their self-reports. Those participants who had the financial incentive session in their first session subsequently reported less effort in their second session. In contrast, those who had the financial incentive in the second session managed to sustain their effort levels. “It may be claimed with some confidence that financial incentives can, on average, increase the amount of effort testees apply to complete cognitive tasks,” Gignac said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, however, this effect on effort did not translate into any difference in performance. Participants’ actual performance on all the various tests was the same across both sessions, suggesting that the financial incentive failed to boost their results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many prior studies, in children and adults, have found that people’s self-reported effort correlates with their IQ. That is, people who are more intelligent – at least according to their higher test results – tend to say that they tried harder. Of course this doesn’t mean that greater effort is causing the superior performance. And the new results are among the first in adults to suggest strongly that it does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this study makes a useful contribution, it doesn’t settle the matter. Remember the financial incentive did not affect participants’ belief in the importance of the tests. Perhaps a bigger or different kind of incentive may affect test performance, especially if it manages to harness people’s intrinsic motivation by making them think it is very important to do well (for instance, imagine feeling highly motivated after being told that your test performance would be used to rate the ability of your country or your university). Another thing is that the participants in the new study all scored fairly high in terms of their effort levels, even without financial incentive. It remains possible that financial incentives may affect intelligence test performance but only among people who have very low motivation to start with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, it is safe to say there is little evidence that differences in motivation undermine the validity of intelligence tests taken by adults. However, Gignac concluded, “as absence of evidence is not evidence of absence, we encourage more research to help understand precisely why test-taking motivation and intelligence test scores are correlated positively in both children and adults.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjop.12288/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;A moderate financial incentive can increase effort, but not intelligence test performance in adult volunteers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This scratchy hiss is the closest thing yet to caterpillar vocalization</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scratchy-hiss-closest-thing-yet-caterpillar-vocalization"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scratchy-hiss-closest-thing-yet-caterpillar-vocalization</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T23:33:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new way that caterpillars make noise may involve (tiny) teakettle‒style turbulence.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Rare Disease Day Spotlight on PLOS Authors: Open Data Repositories in Practice</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/frgJf61zACA/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8056</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T20:20:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/02/Rare-Diesase-Open-Data_blog-image2-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Science increasingly involves collaborative research groups, program partnerships and shared learnings to encourage transparency, reproducibility and a responsible transition to a more open way of doing science. Open Science policies and best practices are currently under discussion, definition and development across the wide spectrum of activities that make up the research cycle, from open notebooks, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/open-data&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and transparent peer review to the interoperability of meta-data and digital identifiers. In particular for open research practices, adoption of emergent and recent policies (i.e. PLOS Data Policy) could be strengthened if accompanied by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2017/05/08/making-progress-toward-open-data/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;examples of successful implementation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Examples can serve as a powerful motivator for improved understanding and behavioral change for those confronted with the uncertainties of a more open landscape for the practice and communication of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s a question of making clear to the broad stakeholder community, at all stages and across multiple disciplines, the practical benefit of these polices moving us all toward a more Open Science. It’s not just a theoretical pursuit of Open Science for the sake of being open. The current energy behind Open Science in the European Union, as well as in the United States, stems also from a frustration over wasted resources, time and talent. Practicing Open Science well does enhance reproducibility through improved clarity of methods and reagents, and accelerated reuse of data and code by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Celebration of Open Data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major benefit of open data is that data can be reused, not only for validation work but also for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006945&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pushing science forward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Teams of scientists with diverse expertise collaborated to explore&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/up-for-a-challenge&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preexisting data sets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to advance breast cancer research, in the US National Cancer Institute’s Up For A Challenge (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synapse.org/#!Synapse:syn3157598/wiki/232604&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U4C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) Contest. Finalists in the US National Institutes of Health, Howard Hughes Medical Institute and Wellcome Trust &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/04/open-data-projects-win-wellcome-trust-nih-and-hhmi-open-science-prize/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Science Prize competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (which included projects by PLOS authors and their related publications) “demonstrated the huge potential for data to be reused to develop new applications and uncover new knowledge,” wrote Robert Kiley, Head of Open Research, and David Carr, Programme Manager, Wellcome Trust, in Figshare’s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://figshare.com/articles/_/5481187&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;State of Open Data Report 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The report provided insight into how researchers approach publishing their data. In response to surveys asking where they published their data, researchers most commonly did so as an appendix to an article (slightly over 30%) or in a data repository (slightly under 30%), with 20% having published data in a data journal (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://figshare.com/articles/The_State_of_Open_Data_2017_Report_-_Infographic/5519155&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;see the summary infographic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opendataday.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (March 3, 2018) is an opportunity to showcase the benefits of open data and open data systems, and, according to the grassroots collective’s website, “to encourage the adoption of open data policies in government, business and civil society around the world.” This year, the focus is on four key areas where open data can help solve universal problems: opening research data, tracking public money flows, informing open mapping projects and providing open data for equal development. In Copenhagen, Open Data Day will include announcement of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dk.okfn.org/2018/02/13/join-us-for-open-data-day-2018-in-copenhagen/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Danish Open Data Award&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and in London activities are planned related to Open Science and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goldsmiths.tech/data&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Participants in The Philippines will benefit from a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ilead.ph/2018/02/20/open-data-day-rtd-on-open-research-in-the-philippines/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;roundtable discussion on open research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as it applies locally and globally. There are no shortage of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opendataday.org/#resources&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ideas and data &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opendataday.org/#resources&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for Open Data Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Publisher Actions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS took a leadership position in open data in 2014 with our strengthened Data Policy, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2015/07/02/plos-recommended-data-repositories/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;since 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; our journals maintain a list of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/data-availability#loc-recommended-repositories&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recommended repositories&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to help authors share their data. When we assess repositories for inclusion in our list we are guided by criteria that meet the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.force11.org/group/fairgroup/fairprinciples&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FAIR principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on open data. We consider this our responsibility as a publisher. The FAIR guiding principles state that beyond making data open as an important component in the data ecosystem, data also need to be Findable, Accessible, Interoperable and Reusable. For inclusion on PLOS’ list of recommended repositories, several criteria were developed, some of which are listed below. For a more complete description of repository criteria, visit the EveryONE blog on Open Data Day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasets should be available at no cost. &lt;/strong&gt;All PLOS articles are available to readers free of charge and we believe cost should not be a barrier to access either the scientific literature or accompanying datasets. Repositories are not considered for our recommended list if they charge readers access or subscription fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repository with stated licensing policies should offer &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CC 0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CC BY&lt;/a&gt; licenses (or equivalents&lt;/strong&gt;), for maximum reproducibility and reuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To ensure that datasets will be permanently accessible at the specified location, repositories must &lt;strong&gt;issue a stable identifier at publication, such as a digital object identifier (DOI) or an equally robust accession number&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FAIRsharing.org works with a community of 70 journals, funders and databases in support of standards, polices and educational material to enable funders, librarians, journals, researchers and developers to thrive in the open data world. &lt;strong&gt;The repository chosen by PLOS authors should have an entry created in the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fairsharing.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAIRsharing database&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, to allow it to be linked to the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fairsharing.org/recommendation/PLOS&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLOS entry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to considering the PLOS Data Policy and providing a Data Availability Statement for their individual data and datasets, selecting the appropriate data repository is an important part of a researcher’s overall experimental and data plan. To assist authors in choosing the best repository, in addition to the current list of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/data-availability#loc-recommended-repositories&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recommended repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the complete list of repository criteria will soon be available on PLOS journal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Researcher Participation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the practical importance of open data? As one specific example we can look to a coincidence of timing: February 28 is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rarediseaseday.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rare Disease Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Rare diseases constitute a group of more than 6,000 different diseases and affect more than 300 million people worldwide. To put this number in perspective, 1 in 20 people live with a rare disease in their life, according to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurordis.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EURORDIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, an alliance of over 700 patient organizations from nearly 70 countries in Europe. In light of Rare Disease Day’s close temporal alignment with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opendataday.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Data Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, we highlight a selection of articles on rare diseases published at PLOS that utilize a variety of repository options to best make their associated data available. These are examples of authors doing the right thing to advance rare disease research, collective knowledge, and future therapeutic interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0176562&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sorenson et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; used the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) Gene Expression Omnibus (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) repository to store their genomic and transcriptomic data relating to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fibrolamellar_hepatocellular_carcinoma&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fibrolamellar hepatocellular carcinoma&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(a rare variant of liver cancer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0188943&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Guilhem et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;used the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://easy.dans.knaw.nl/ui/home&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Data Archiving and Networking Services (DANS) EASY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; repository to deposit data files from their research on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hereditary_hemorrhagic_telangiectasia&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;hereditary hemorrhagic telangiectasia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (a disease leading to abnormal blood vessel formation). The EASY repository is one of PLOS’ recommended repositories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0116966&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andersen et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;carried out a bibliometric analysis on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiple_myeloma&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;multiple myeloma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; research (a cancer of white blood cells). Few, if any, dedicated repositories exist exclusively for bibliometric work, so data underlying work like this can be deposited to a discipline-independent repository—in this case &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://figshare.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Figshare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. While subject-specific repositories are preferred, in cases where they are not available authors may use a cross-disciplinary repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006037&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hytönen et al. (2016)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;published genome data relating to their work on three rare bone diseases in the European Nucleotide Archive (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ENA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) hosted by EMBL-EBI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0133607&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Piersanti et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; also used the GEO repository to store their microarray data on gene expression changes in brain cells following infection with viral vectors. This work contributes to the development of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gene_therapy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;gene therapy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that could be used in the treatment of several rare diseases affecting the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme for Rare Disease Day this year is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/02/optimism-on-rare-disease-day-with-research-possibilities-are-limitless/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;carry-over from last year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;—research. If scientists working in these disease areas make their data open and available for reuse and re-examination, they can extend the impact of their efforts and may open a window to unrealized diagnoses, therapies and perhaps even cures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pursuit of Open Science, practical and even incremental change has the power and potential to bolster momentum and encourage a spirit of collaboration that ultimately brings about large-scale cultural shift. We have seen evidence of this most recently with the preprint movement in biomedical and life sciences. Making open data the norm, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2017/06/05/new-icmje-requirements-and-the-plos-data-policy/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;whenever possible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and following FAIR sharing principles are additional practices that, like preprints, have the capacity to transform the work and culture of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/frgJf61zACA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>PLOS</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Some flu strains can make mice forgetful</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flu-virus-brain-memory-mice"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flu-virus-brain-memory-mice</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mice infected with influenza had memory problems a month later, a result that hints at a link between infections and brain performance.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">New Nature Neuroscience paper!</title>
		<link href="http://blog.ketyov.com/2015/08/new-nature-neuroscience-paper.html"/>
		<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545.post-4611040478364219479</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T16:32:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 I wrote a detailed piece about my new &lt;i&gt;Nature Neuroscience&lt;/i&gt; paper, &quot;Oscillatory dynamics coordinating human frontal networks in support of goal maintenance&quot; over at my lab blog.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;http://voyteklab.com/nature-neuroscience-paper-oscillatory-dynamics-coordinating-human-frontal-networks-in-support-of-goal-maintenance/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;float: left; padding: 5px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ResearchBlogging.org&quot; src=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/public/citation_icons/rb2_large_gray.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Nature+neuroscience&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F26214371&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Oscillatory+dynamics+coordinating+human+frontal+networks+in+support+of+goal+maintenance.&amp;amp;rft.issn=1097-6256&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=&amp;amp;rft.epage=&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Voytek+B&amp;amp;rft.au=Kayser+AS&amp;amp;rft.au=Badre+D&amp;amp;rft.au=Fegen+D&amp;amp;rft.au=Chang+EF&amp;amp;rft.au=Crone+NE&amp;amp;rft.au=Parvizi+J&amp;amp;rft.au=Knight+RT&amp;amp;rft.au=D%27Esposito+M&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Neuroscience&quot;&gt;Voytek B, Kayser AS, Badre D, Fegen D, Chang EF, Crone NE, Parvizi J, Knight RT, &amp;amp; D'Esposito M (2015). Oscillatory dynamics coordinating human frontal networks in support of goal maintenance. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nature neuroscience&lt;/span&gt; PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26214371&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;26214371&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bradley Voytek</name>
			<email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
			<uri>http://blog.ketyov.com/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Oscillatory Thoughts</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Thoughts of a Neuroscientist</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/5648062351012720545/posts/default"/>
			<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T15:52:52+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Florida investigation can’t ID culprit who falsified data in retracted PNAS paper</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/26/florida-investigation-cant-id-culprit-who-falsified-data-in-retracted-pnas-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61808</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T16:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 When the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences retracted a gene therapy paper in December, it declared that some of the data had been falsified and mentioned a research misconduct investigation. But the notice said nothing about who was responsible. Via a public records request, Retraction Watch has obtained investigation documents from the University … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/26/florida-investigation-cant-id-culprit-who-falsified-data-in-retracted-pnas-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Florida investigation can’t ID culprit who falsified data in retracted PNAS paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Chemistry journal retracts highly criticized paper</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/26/chemistry-journal-retracts-highly-criticized-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61820</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T13:00:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A chemistry journal has retracted a nanoparticle paper following heavy outcry from readers, who alleged the paper contained signs of obvious manipulation. After the paper appeared in 2017, one critic lamented it contained “obviously fabricated” images, and asked the journal to retract it. Another suggested the presence of one image merited “an instant lifetime ban.” … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/26/chemistry-journal-retracts-highly-criticized-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Chemistry journal retracts highly criticized paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The quest to identify the nature of the neutrino’s alter ego is heating up</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quest-identify-nature-neutrinos-alter-ego-heating"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quest-identify-nature-neutrinos-alter-ego-heating</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The search is on for a rare nuclear decay that could prove neutrinos are their own antiparticles and shed light on the universe’s antimatter mystery.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brainwave evidence hints at benefits from a school mindfulness programme</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/26/brainwave-evidence-hints-at-benefits-from-a-school-mindfulness-programme/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33326</id>
		<updated>2018-02-26T09:13:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-143176827.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33327&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33327&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/Vetta&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D3X&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Group of teens with closed eyes sitting on the desks and meditating.  The focus is on the teenage girls in the second row. \r\r[url=http:\/\/www.istockphoto.com\/search\/lightbox\/9786738][img]http:\/\/dl.dropbox.com\/u\/40117171\/group.jpg[\/img][\/url]&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1331818508&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;kristian sekulic&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Group of teenagers sitting on the desk in lotus position.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Group of teenagers sitting on the desk in lotus position.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-143176827.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-143176827.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-143176827.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/26/brainwave-evidence-hints-at-benefits-from-a-school-mindfulness-programme/group-of-teenagers-sitting-on-the-desk-in-lotus-position/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-143176827.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies of mindfulness schools programmes for teenagers have produced mixed results, with some failing to find benefits, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/26/perhaps-teens-are-too-cynical-to-benefit-from-mindfulness-say-authors-of-latest-negative-school-trial/&quot;&gt;even when extra features were added&lt;/a&gt; to try to make them more effective. But given the demonstrated benefits of mindfulness training on stress and wellbeing in adults – and the urgent need to find ways to reduce stress and prevent depression in teenagers – it’s not surprising that researchers are pursuing work in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advocates of mindfulness for kids may, then, take some comfort from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12646/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;a new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Developmental Science&lt;/em&gt; that found an 8-week training programme improved emotion processing in 16-18-year-olds. In theory, this might reduce their vulnerability to depression, write the researchers, from Bangor University, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33326&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study was not large: it involved just 40 sixth-form pupils (aged 16 to 18) from north Wales. Twenty-one pupils from two schools acted as controls, while 19 from two other schools formed the training group. Regular teachers from these schools delivered the “Foundations” version of the .b mindfulness curriculum, originally developed by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mindfulnessinschools.org&quot;&gt;Mindfulness in Schools Project&lt;/a&gt; for busy adults, and which consists of eight 50-minute sessions (the researchers said they chose this programme to “reflect the maturity of the age group targeted for this intervention”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start and end of the study period, all the pupils completed a number of questionnaires, including the Perceived Stress Scale, a self-assessment of empathy, and a version of the WHO Well-Being Index. The researchers also used electroencephalography (EEG) to provide a brainwave measure of the teenagers’ sensitivity to happy, sad and neutral male and female faces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the training, the mindfulness group did not score higher for empathy or lower for stress than the controls. But they did report feeling greater well-being. And the EEG data showed that, unlike the controls, they sustained their sensitivity to the faces that had happy or sad expressions, rather than becoming habituated to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tentatively, we can interpret the findings as suggesting that mindfulness practice, which encourages curiosity and exposure to emotion without judgement or reactivity, can help maintain attention on socially relevant stimuli,” the researchers write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the so-called Emotion Content Insensitivity model, depression is characterised by a lack of response to both positive and negative emotional stimuli. So, in theory, maintaining a sensitivity to happy and sad faces may reduce these pupils’ vulnerability to depression, the researchers argue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has to be said that there are a quite a lot of “maybes” in the conclusions of this study. And while there were some potentially encouraging trends in the data (in relation to empathy, for example), only a few of the positive results were statistically significant. Also, the final assessments came soon after the training finished, so there’s no way of knowing how long the slight improvements shown by the mindfulness group would have lasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, “we hope that future work will build on these initial findings and explore the long-term effects of mindfulness training on adolescents,” the researchers write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, every teacher and parent would like to see effective interventions to reduce stress and the risk of depression in teenagers. But whether mindfulness is the answer is yet to be demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12646/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;Effects of school-based mindfulness training on emotion processing and well-being in adolescents: evidence from event-related potentials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Retraction Watch is back at full speed. Here’s what you need to do to make sure you’re seeing our content.</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/25/retraction-watch-is-back-at-full-speed-heres-what-you-need-to-do-to-make-sure-youre-seeing-our-content/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62062</id>
		<updated>2018-02-25T13:50:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Our readers will likely know that the site has been having significant trouble for more than two weeks. Thanks for your patience, your offers to help, and for sticking with us during that time. We’re happy to say that we seem to have identified all of the various issues involved, and have solved them. Some … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/25/retraction-watch-is-back-at-full-speed-heres-what-you-need-to-do-to-make-sure-youre-seeing-our-content/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch is back at full speed. Here’s what you need to do to make sure you’re seeing our content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Automated image duplication detection?; journal editor frustrations; cash for catching errors</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/24/weekend-reads-automated-image-duplication-journal-editor-frustrations-cash-for-catching-errors/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61838</id>
		<updated>2018-02-24T14:44:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 We seem to be past the worst of our technical issues, so thanks for your patience with us over the past few weeks. (Some of the fixes came at a cost, so we would be remiss if we did not ask readers to consider a donation to support our work.) The week at Retraction Watch featured … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/24/weekend-reads-automated-image-duplication-journal-editor-frustrations-cash-for-catching-errors/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Automated image duplication detection?; journal editor frustrations; cash for catching errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">About that New Antidepressant Study</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9376"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9376</id>
		<updated>2018-02-24T13:52:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new Lancet paper about antidepressants caused quite a stir this week. Headlines proclaimed that &quot;It's official - antidepressants work&quot;, &quot;Study proves anti-depressants are effective&quot;, and &quot;Antidepressants work. Period.&quot;



Wew.

The truth is that while the Lancet paper is a nice piece of work, it tells us very little that we didn't already know, and it has a number of limitations. The media reaction to the paper is frankly bananas, as we'll see below.

Here's why the new study doesn't t</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-02-24T18:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Prof who just dropped $10M suit against PNAS: “I was expecting them to settle”</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/prof-who-just-dropped-10m-suit-against-pnas-i-was-expecting-them-to-settle/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61831</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T22:26:10+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Yesterday, Mark Jacobson, a researcher at Stanford University who studies the future of renewable energy, announced he would drop a $10 million defamation suit over a paper published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences that was critical of his work. As we reported, the announcement came just two days after the District … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/prof-who-just-dropped-10m-suit-against-pnas-i-was-expecting-them-to-settle/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Prof who just dropped $10M suit against PNAS: “I was expecting them to settle”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Big journal, big correction</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/caught-our-notice-big-journal-big-correction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61792</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T16:30:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Title: Tranexamic Acid in Patients Undergoing Coronary-Artery Surgery What Caught Our Attention: When the New England Journal of Medicine (NEJM) publishes a correction that is more than a misspelling of a name, we take a look. When NEJM publishes a 500-word correction to the data in a highly cited article, we take notice. This study … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/caught-our-notice-big-journal-big-correction/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Big journal, big correction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 142 Michael Graziano explores Peripersonal Neurons</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-142-michael-graziano-explores-peripersonal-neurons"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/0b6d58e61f533124e7b5e6675cefcce4</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T15:14:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;BS 142 is an interview with neuroscientist Michael Graziano about his latest book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2BfNO4G&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;amazon link&quot;&gt;The Spaces Between Us: A Story of Neuroscience, Evolution, and Human Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. We explore the discovery of peripersonal neurons and discover how deeply they are imbedded in our daily lives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For show notes and complete transcripts go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainscience&quot;&gt;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Send email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&quot;&gt;brainsciencepodcast@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or submit audio feedback at &lt;a href=&quot;http://speakpipe.com/docartemis&quot;&gt;http://speakpipe.com/docartemis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This episode will be discussed on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/brainsciencepodcast&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Brain Science Podcast Fan Page&lt;/a&gt; via Facebook live on  Thursday April 12 at 8PM Central Time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T21:15:21+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Two-way communication is possible with a single quantum particle</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-way-communication-possible-single-quantum-particle"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-way-communication-possible-single-quantum-particle</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T15:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 One photon can transmit information in two directions at once.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Conover</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Stanford prof plans to drop $10m suit against PNAS and critic</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/stanford-prof-plans-to-drop-10m-suit-against-pnas-and-critic/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61810</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T14:39:34+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A professor who is suing a journal publisher and critic for defamation has announced he plans to drop the case. Yesterday, Stanford University professor Mark Jacobson announced on Twitter that he plans to “voluntarily dismiss the lawsuit” he filed last year in the District of Columbia, in which he alleged he was defamed when the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/23/stanford-prof-plans-to-drop-10m-suit-against-pnas-and-critic/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Stanford prof plans to drop $10m suit against PNAS and critic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">In memoriam: Jimmie C. Holland, MD</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/528121437/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=136634</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T12:30:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;Jimmie C. Holland, MD, internationally recognized as the founder of the field of Psycho-oncology, died suddenly on 24 December 2017 at the age of 89. Dr. Holland, who was affectionately known by her first name, “Jimmie,” had a profound global influence on the fields of Psycho-oncology, Psychosomatic Medicine, and Oncology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Holland was the Attending Psychiatrist and Wayne E. Chapman Chair at Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSK) and Professor of Psychiatry, Weill Medical College of Cornell University in New York. In 1977, she was appointed Chief of the Psychiatry Service in the Department of Neurology at MSK. The Psychiatry Service at MSK was the first such clinical, research, and training service established in any cancer center in the world. In 1996, Dr. Holland was named the inaugural Chairwoman of the Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences at MSK Cancer Center, also the first such department created in any cancer center in the world. Over 25 years ago, Dr. Holland founded and co-edited the international &lt;em&gt;Psycho-Oncology &lt;/em&gt;journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; style=&quot;width: 450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;557&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DRU-367eCmE.jpg&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;Dr. Jimmie Holland. &lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Dr. William Breitbart. Not to be reused without permission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Holland edited the first major textbooks of Psycho-oncology, and in 1989 edited the &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Psychooncology: Psychological care of the patient with cancer&lt;/em&gt;. This landmark textbook was notable for several reasons; it established a “new” field, a subspecialty of both Psychosomatics and oncology. I remember being a young faculty member in Dr. Holland’s service and the very real sense that we were creating something that had not existed before. I remember her asking me to write multiple chapters, including several in which I had very little expertise. I expressed my concern, “I’m not an expert on the psychiatric complications of head and neck cancer!” She calmly reassured me, “Well, Bill, no one is. So when you finish researching and writing the chapter I suppose then you’ll be the world’s expert!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psycho-oncology was born and named with the publication of this textbook and with Dr. Holland’s founding of the International Psycho-oncology Society (IPOS) in 1984, then the American Psychosocial Oncology Society in 1986. Subsequently, Dr. Holland edited, with a group of co-editors, what became known as the “Bible” of Psycho-oncology; &lt;em&gt;Psycho-oncology&lt;/em&gt; was published in 1998, and represented the most comprehensive, multidisciplinary, and international encyclopedia of a field entering its adolescence. 2010 saw the publication of the second edition followed by the third edition in 2015. Every card-carrying “psycho-oncologist” (in 57 countries with national psycho-oncology societies) had to have the latest edition in their library to demonstrate their link to Jimmie Holland. Dr. Holland also co-wrote two well received books for the public: &lt;em&gt;The Human Side of Cancer&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Lighter as We Go: Virtues, Character Strengths, and Aging&lt;/em&gt;, the latter reflecting her interests in Geriatric Oncology as she approached her 90th birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Holland was born in the small farming community of Nevada, Texas in 1928. She credits the local family physician in that community for her interest in medicine and caring for those who were suffering. She was one of only three women in her class at Baylor College of Medicine. In 1956, Dr. Holland married the renowned oncology pioneer James Holland, MD, who was then Chief of Medical Oncology at Roswell Park in Buffalo, NY. She would chide James, complaining that cancer patients were asked every conceivable question about their physical functioning but never, “How do you feel emotionally?” Dr. Holland pioneered the inclusion of psychological and emotional well-being patient-reported outcomes in quality of life measures and as a component of clinical outcomes in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; style=&quot;width: 450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DRU_EERGI14.jpg&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;Dr. Jimmie C. Holland. Image courtesy of Dr. William Breitbart. Not to be reused without permission&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Holland has received too many awards to list, however some notable ones include: The Medal of Honor for Clinical Research from the American Cancer Society, The Marie Curie Award from the Government of France, and the Margaret L. Kripke Legend Award for contributions to the advancement of women in cancer medicine and cancer science from the MD Anderson Cancer Center. She served as President of the Academy of Psychosomatic Medicine (APM) in 1996 and was the recipient of the APM’s Hackett Lifetime Achievement Award in 1994. She was also the inaugural recipient of the Arthur Sutherland Award for Lifetime Achievement from IPOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a 40-year career at MSK Cancer Center, Dr. Holland created and nurtured the field of Psycho-oncology, established its clinical practice, advanced its clinical research agenda, and through her pioneering efforts, launched the careers of the leaders of a national and worldwide field who mourn her passing and continue to work in what has become a shared mission to emphasize the &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt; in cancer care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After stepping down as Chairman of the MSK Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences in 2003, she kept working full time, seeing patients, conducting research, training and supervising fellows, and traveling the world lecturing and teaching. She also helped bring Psycho-oncology to Africa through her work with the African Organization for Cancer Research &amp;amp; Training in Cancer (AORTIC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born in a humble farming community with a one room school house, Dr. Holland created a life that led her to New York and the capitals of the world, honored by so many organizations and societies. She was teaching and seeing patients up until two days before her death. I think we’ll all remember her for various reasons. I certainly have many memories from a 34 year career working beside her. But on that list was her generosity and loving attitude towards her family, her patients, her colleagues, trainees, and everyone who crossed her path. Those who worked alongside her in medicine have made her mission our mission. We will continue this mission’s work, always remembering and honoring Dr. Jimmie Holland. Her death is a profound loss for all of Psychiatry, Psychosomatic Medicine, Psycho-oncology, and Oncology. We’ve lost a pioneer, a remarkable woman, a once-in-a-generation influencer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Sunflower by Conner Baker. Public Domain via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://unsplash.com/photos/sIjMLE3TX0A&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/memoriam-jimmie-c-holland-md/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;In memoriam: Jimmie C. Holland, MD&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/528121437/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/528121437/oupblogpsychology,https%3a%2f%2fblog.oup.com%2fwp-content%2fuploads%2f2018%2f02%2fDRU-367eCmE.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/528121437/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/dr-victor-sidel-leader-health-peace-social-justice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Dr. Victor Sidel: a leader for health, peace, and social justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/fungus-worth-900-billion/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The fungus that’s worth $900 billion a year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/excessive-gambling-gaming-addictive-disorders/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Excessive gambling and gaming recognised as addictive disorders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>DanP</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T00:00:33+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">(c) Oxford University Press</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Using SymPy in exploratory research</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/02/23/using-sympy-in-exploratory-research.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-02-23:/2018/02/23/using-sympy-in-exploratory-research.html</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T12:04:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.sympy.org/en/index.html&quot;&gt;SymPy&lt;/a&gt; is an open source computer algebra system (CAS) implemented as a Python
library. Besides providing the usual CAS features such as solving equations and
performing symbolic integration and differentiations, it has the added benefit
that it can be used seamlessly as a part of regular Python programs. I will
show how the features of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.sympy.org/en/index.html&quot;&gt;SymPy&lt;/a&gt; help our research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 23/02/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrei D. Robu</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:04:15+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Adopting a more active lifestyle today could have benefits for your personality decades from now</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/23/adopting-a-more-active-lifestyle-today-could-have-benefits-for-your-personality-decades-from-now/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33331</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T08:45:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-76724501.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33335&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33335&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Senior man in-line skating in a surfing pose&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Senior man in-line skating in a surfing pose&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-76724501.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-76724501.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-76724501.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2118,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/23/adopting-a-more-active-lifestyle-today-could-have-benefits-for-your-personality-decades-from-now/senior-man-in-line-skating-in-a-surfing-pose/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-76724501.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bhf.org.uk/publications/statistics/physical-inactivity-report-2017&quot;&gt;statistics&lt;/a&gt; published by the British Heart Foundation, we spend 76 days per year, on average, sitting. The World Health Organisation describes physical inactivity as a “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/dietphysicalactivity/factsheet_inactivity/en/&quot;&gt;global public health problem&lt;/a&gt;” that contributes to millions of deaths each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might not be surprised to hear about the harmful health consequences of a sedentary lifestyle, but perhaps less obvious is that physical inactivity is also associated with unwelcome changes in personality over time. Previous research has documented these effects over periods of four and ten years. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092656618300175&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Research in Personality&lt;/em&gt; has extended this, finding that greater physical inactivity at baseline is associated with deterioration in personality two decades later, even after accounting for any differences in initial personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers, led by Yannick Stephan at Université de Montpellier, point out, there is an upside: the findings suggest that even a moderate increase in your activity levels today could have positive implications for your personality decades from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33331&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers combined data from three long-running survey studies. Two involved over 6000 participants in Wisconsin, first recruited between 1992 and 1994, aged 53 on average, when they completed a personality questionnaire and answered questions about their physical activity levels. These same participants then repeated the personality questionnaire in 2011. The other study was US-wide and involved over 2500 participants who first took part between 1995 to 1996, aged 46, on average, when they answered questions about their personality and physical activity. The same participants then provided follow-up personality data in 2013-2014. All the studies also recorded extensive information about the participants’ health and any illnesses or psychological problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main take-away is that greater physical inactivity at baseline was associated with sharper declines in conscientiousness, extraversion, agreeableness and openness, as measured two decades later, even after factoring out baseline personality and any differences in health. The pattern also wasn’t moderated by race, age, education or sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a sense of perspective about the size of these links: the associations between physical inactivity and personality change were mostly either as great as, or even greater than, the associations between demographic factors and personality change, and between disease burden and personality change (in a multiple regression on data combined from the three studies, and controlling for other factors like health, the β value for the inactivity and personality correlations was between -.03 and -.06).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These patterns generally held across different intensities of physical activity (the researchers were able to look separately at light physical activity, such as gardening; moderate physical activity, such as brisk walking; and vigorous activity, such as running or lifting weights). However, for extraversion and agreeableness, there was a suggestion that a lack of moderate physical activity might be especially relevant in terms of later declines in these traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we may not usually think of physical activity as contributing to our personalities, in fact &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20180221-the-hidden-side-to-your-personality&quot;&gt;there is a close association between personality and our basic physiology&lt;/a&gt;, including our responsiveness to stress. Another part of the reason that lower physical activity may have such long-term links with personality may be due to knock-on consequences of inactivity for our physical capabilities, which will impact the kind of lives we are able to lead. Being less active may also contribute to us becoming less self-disciplined, less curious and adventurous. We will have fewer opportunities for socialising and also miss the mood-enhancing effects of exercise, a detriment that may accumulate over time and potentially contribute to our lower agreeability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat unexpected, but consistent with previous research, was the relative lack of an association between inactivity and later higher trait neuroticism (or emotional instability). However there was one exception: lower vigorous physical activity at baseline was associated with higher neuroticism two decades later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper includes a large number of participants and covers an impressive time span. However, it’s far from perfect. It mostly pertains to changes between mid-life and older age. There is also no data on what happened earlier in the participants’ lives – perhaps the participants’ personalities in their youth influenced both their later activity levels and the later trajectories of their trait changes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/18/hate-sport-maybe-its-because-you-have-the-genes-that-make-exercise-feel-awful/&quot;&gt;Genetic differences&lt;/a&gt; between the participants could be another major confound, potentially influencing personality trajectories and activity levels. It’s worth noting too that we don’t know how the participants’ activity levels changed over the course of the studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these limitations, the findings reinforce the increasingly well-established idea that personality and health are closely interwoven, and that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/07/longest-ever-personality-study-finds-no-correlation-between-measures-taken-at-age-14-and-age-77/&quot;&gt;personality is relatively malleable across the life-span&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already know that being more active is good for our health, this new paper brings home that it’s probably good for our personalities too. Something to ponder when you next decide whether to walk or drive to the shops. “It is likely that the benefits of even a small increase in physical activity may accumulate over time, resulting in significant [positive] personality change,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092656618300175&quot;&gt;Physical activity and personality development over twenty years: Evidence from three longitudinal samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth:  Highlights of 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/23/bmc-pregnancy-childbirth-highlights-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9938</id>
		<updated>2018-02-23T07:37:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/pregnant-1-e1518712534422-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12884-017-1279-7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factors Influencing Choice of Birth Place Setting from the Perspective of Healthy Women in the UK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maternity care policy in England has opened the doors for women to choose their birth setting. With this change in policy, women now have the options to give birth in a hospital obstetrics unit, a freestanding midwifery unit, with a midwife affiliated with an obstetric unit, or plan a home birth. Despite the options provided, in recent years it has been observed that only 13% of women take advantage of non-obstetric unit settings. Previous studies have suggested that women chose one birth option over another due to the perceived level of safety in hospitals, a lack of information related to non-obstetric birth units, or sociodemographic factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this systematic review, 20 research articles were assessed using the best fit framework, delving into what influences women’s decisions based on their perspective. This study found women were influenced by the level of information they received regarding each birth setting, the opinions of healthcare providers, family and friends, the characteristics of the services provided, perceived level of associated risk, and experiences with previous births.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study found that each birth setting had its positive attributes and factors that concerned women. Women often relied on hospitals due to access to facilities in the event something went wrong as well as access to pain relief. Conversely, women often felt that hospitals were not as personal as other birthing options. Women who decided to deliver at home or use a midwifery affiliated unit felt that it was a more relaxed setting and that they had a greater sense of control and a relationship with the person caring for them.  Alternatively, women in this setting felt they had to do extra research to gain the appropriate information outside of what was provided to them and worried about what would happen in the event they needed to transfer to a hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study concluded that women with a low-risk pregnancy found giving birth in a hospital more straightforward than non-hospitals births. Overall, these opinions were shaped by each woman’s personal experience and pre-existing opinion, despite the access to multiple forms of care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12884-017-1566-3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements for safe obstetric anesthesia are rarely met in hospitals in Uganda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9940 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/surgery-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safe surgery and anesthesia are critical to comprehensive emergency obstetric care.  International standards of safe practice have been formulated to address the needs of low- and middle-income countries to improve the quality and safety of surgical procedures using anesthesia.  However, small studies across East Africa have shown that these standards are not being met by hospitals offering obstetric anesthesia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epiu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; conducted a large, cross-sectional survey of 64 hospitals in Uganda, both public and private, to assess adherence to guidelines for safe anesthesia. They found that only 5% met all the requirements set out by the international guidelines while 8% had no trained providers for anesthesia at all. Many hospitals lacked some of the equipment necessary for monitoring of anesthesia and the authors noted that much of the equipment present was obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results highlight the need to strengthen obstetric and general anesthesia services in Uganda by increasing training and access to equipment. These improvements would play an important role in meeting United Nations goals for reducing the maternal mortality ratio by providing safe cesarean section services when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12884-017-1319-3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Mind in Labor (MIL): Working with Pain in Childbirth”: A promising new tool to reduce Fear of Childbirth in First Time Mothers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9941 alignright&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/meditation-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Past research suggests th&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;at fear of childbirth is highest among first-time mothers. This fear not only predicts the use of pain medication, but it is linked to perinatal and postpartum depression, puts women at a higher risk for poor postpartum adjustment, and can act as a predictor of poor outcomes for labor and birth. In order to provide first time mothers with a resource to combat fear of childbirth, Duncan &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt; conducted a randomized controlled trial implementing a mindfulness-based childbirth workshop. In the trial, the intervention group utilized the workshop while the control group underwent standard preparations for childbirth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop, titled “Mind in Labor (MIL): Working with Pain in Childbirth,” was an 18-hour program, utilized in the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; trimester for both the mothers and their partners. The MIL workshop taught the participants yoga, walking meditation, partner touch, mindful breathing, and instruction grounded in mindfulness as strategies to cope with labor-related stress. The mindfulness strategies used in the study are based on a nine-week Mindfulness-based Childbirth and Parenting program which in turn is based on Mindfulness-Based Stress Reduction. The overall goal of the workshop was to teach women the traditional topics needed for childbirth preparation, how to become more aware of their bodies, separate the cognitive and emotional aspects of pain and replace it with the goal to decrease fear, and show participants ways to cope and support each other throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this trial found that there was a reduced rate of opioid analgesia in the MIL group as compared to controls, but no reduction in the overall rate of epidural or perceived pain retrospectively. The results also suggested that participants in the MIL group had marginally fewer perinatal and postpartum depression symptoms as compared to the controls. Most notably, participants in the MIL group were significantly more likely to feel confident in their behaviors throughout labor. In conclusion, a mindfulness based approach to childbirth preparation is promising avenue for continued research in reducing fear of childbirth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpregnancychildbirth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12884-016-1197-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The role of care providers in birth trauma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birth trauma, an extreme negative experience during childbirth that can result from a number of factors, can lead to ongoing poor mental health, affecting the woman herself, her relationship to her family, and her ability to bond with her child. A number of studies have identified a perceived lack of control of decision-making as a major factor in the experience of birth trauma.  Additionally, a lack of emotional support of women during birth has also been identified as a risk factor for birth trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this qualitative study by Reed, Sharman, and Inglis, from our collection ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biomedcentral.com/collections/SVWomen&quot;&gt;The Role of Structural and Interpersonal Violence in the Lives of Women&lt;/a&gt;,’ nearly 750 women out of over 900 who completed an online survey answered an open-ended question about birth trauma. While one third of them described birth trauma related to medical concerns or adverse events, the other two thirds described trauma relating to care provider actions and how they were treated during labor and birth. Accounts of trauma included care providers disregarding or not seeking women’s preferences regarding interventions, women not being believed regarding onset of labor or timing of pushing, outright lies and threats to coerce women into consenting to interventions, and physical violations such as internal examinations on women who had explicitly not consented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These experiences were common across cultural contexts and birth settings.  This highlights the global nature of the problem and the need for maternity services to comply with recommendations from the World Health Organization and others regarding women-centered maternity services and potentially unnecessary medical interventions. In addition, it contributes to ongoing debate about the accuracy and efficacy of standards and assessments used during labor and birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/23/bmc-pregnancy-childbirth-highlights-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth&lt;/i&gt;:  Highlights of 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tovah Honor Aronin &amp;#38; Janelle Coore</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New mapping shows just how much fishing impacts the world’s seas</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-mapping-shows-just-how-much-fishing-impacts-world-seas"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-mapping-shows-just-how-much-fishing-impacts-world-seas</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T20:40:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Industrial fishing now occurs across 55 percent of the world’s ocean area while only 34 percent of Earth’s land area is used for agriculture or grazing.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ed Stern PhD</title>
		<link href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Entries/2018/2/22_Ed_Stern,_PhD.html"/>
		<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/210d1a45-30a6-4105-b6d2-e614feff403d</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T20:06:33+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 Ed Stern (Bar-Ilan University, Israel) discusses corticostriatal networks in mouse models of Alzheimer’s disease. 

Duration: 42 minutes

Discussants:(in alphabetical order)
Alfonso Apicella (Asst Prof, UTSA) 
Salma Quraishi (Res Asst Prof, UTSA)
Charles Wilson (Ewing Halsell Chair, UTSA)

acknowledgement: JM Tepper for original music.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dwight Bergles PhD</name>
			<uri>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">NEUROSCIENTISTS TALK SHOP</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Neuroscientists Talk Shop is the University of Texas at San Antonio's (UTSA) Neurobiology Podcast, showcasing the current research of internationally renowned guest Neuroscientists. Each episode features a moderated discussion with a cross section of UTSA</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/rss.xml"/>
			<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T18:00:53+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Salma Quraishi</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Global Virome Project is hunting for more than 1 million unknown viruses</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-virome-project-unknown-virus-outbreak"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-virome-project-unknown-virus-outbreak</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T19:53:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists are searching for viruses lurking in animals that could threaten human health.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cave art suggests Neandertals were ancient humans’ mental equals</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cave-art-suggests-neandertals-were-ancient-humans-mental-equals"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cave-art-suggests-neandertals-were-ancient-humans-mental-equals</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T19:12:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Ancient humans’ close relatives also created rock art and shell ornaments, studies assert.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The last wild horses aren’t truly wild</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/last-wild-horses-arent-truly-wild"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/last-wild-horses-arent-truly-wild</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T19:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The ancestor of today’s domesticated horses remains a mystery after a new analysis of ancient horse DNA.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Erika Engelhaupt</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">BMJ journal pulls case report after UK tabloids publish graphic photos</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/22/bmj-journal-pulls-case-report-after-uk-tabloids-publish-graphic-photos/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61747</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T16:20:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A BMJ journal has retracted a medical case report about a couple in the United Kingdom who were infected by parasitic worms while on a Caribbean cruise. The paper in BMJ Case Reports included graphic photos of the patients’ buttocks, the site of the infection, which were republished within a week by UK tabloids. Specifics … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/22/bmj-journal-pulls-case-report-after-uk-tabloids-publish-graphic-photos/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;BMJ journal pulls case report after UK tabloids publish graphic photos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Building a bright future for science journalism</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/building-bright-future-science-journalism"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/building-bright-future-science-journalism</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T15:46:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Editor in Chief Nancy Shute is ready to produce top-quality science journalism and investigate digital innovations.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nancy Shute</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers weigh in on human gene editing and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-weigh-human-gene-editing-and-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-weigh-human-gene-editing-and-more</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T15:39:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers debated feeling morally obligated to edit their kid's genes and had questions about exoplanets.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Psst…Need a PhD thesis? That’ll be $63,000</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/22/psst-need-a-phd-thesis-thatll-be-63000/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61770</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T13:00:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Many readers may have heard whisper of companies that offer a range of writing services — some more ethical than others. Although some companies offer to edit and polish writing, others can write PhD research proposals, masters’ theses, or even a dissertation. In other words, the students engage in so-called “contract cheating” — paying someone … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/22/psst-need-a-phd-thesis-thatll-be-63000/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Psst…Need a PhD thesis? That’ll be $63,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, early organ transplants brought triumph and tragedy</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-early-organ-transplants-brought-triumph-and-tragedy"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-early-organ-transplants-brought-triumph-and-tragedy</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T12:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 In 1968, the liver transplant field had its first small successes. Now, more than 30,000 patients in the U.S. receive a donated liver each year.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Wisdom is a journey</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/22/wisdom-is-a-journey/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33322</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T09:30:13+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-856291670.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33323&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33323&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;E-M5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;No turning back.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1502795839&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;17&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;From A to B. Life's journey, concept. Travelling woman by rising road.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;From A to B. Life’s journey, concept. Travelling woman by rising road.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-856291670.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-856291670.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-856291670.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/22/wisdom-is-a-journey/from-a-to-b-lifes-journey-concept-travelling-woman-by-rising-road/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-856291670.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of recorded time, humanity has been fascinated by the figure of the wise person, wending their path through the tribulations of life, and informing those willing to learn. What sets them apart? Maybe that’s the wrong question. In a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-02884-003&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;European Psychologist&lt;/i&gt;, Igor Grossman of the University of Waterloo argues that understanding wisdom involves taking the wise off their pedestal, and seeing wisdom as a set of processes that we can all tap into, with the right attitude, and in the right context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33322&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wisdom might seem to be a difficult concept for psychologists to study, but Grossman says there is some agreement now that it comprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/23/something-we-could-use-a-little-more-of-studies-link-intellectual-humility-with-openness-to-other-viewpoints/&quot;&gt;Intellectual humility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appreciating broader perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing that social relations can change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A willingness to compromise or integrate different opinions together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen this way, wisdom is distinct from things like creativity and intelligence, while being associated with related phenomena like emotion regulation, cooperative intentions, and political even-handedness (e.g. not condemning an opponent’s change of view as flip-flopping).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologists who research wisdom tend to use questionnaires administered at one point in time to measure it, treating it as a static property. But Grossman argues that this doesn’t fit with the variability with which wisdom manifests. Experiments in the lab that asked participants to work through hypothetical situations, have found that people’s wisdom on one topic (say, the “Meaning of Life”) only gave a limited indication of their wisdom in another, like adjudicating a family issue. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/08/31/wisdom-is-more-of-a-state-than-a-trait/&quot;&gt;diary studies&lt;/a&gt; where participants reflect on the most difficult issue they faced each day show that wise thinking can fluctuate wildly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Grossman’s view, this suggests that although wisdom has some stability, the context is king. And changing the context of thinking can encourage more wise outcomes. For instance, researchers observe wiser thinking when participants are asked to consider a problem as if it occurred a year ago, rather than now, or if it’s occurring to a third party, rather than themselves. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/03/01/how-thinking-for-others-can-boost-your-creativity/&quot;&gt;distancing techniques&lt;/a&gt; help us take a less egocentric approach, trapped in the urgent “here, now, me” which pushes us to look for certainty and closure, often prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, explaining an issue you care deeply about is done in a more wise, balanced manner when you imagine that the recipient is a 12-year old, casting you as a teacher. It seems that again, seeing yourself as a teacher of someone in need of insight (rather than facing a peer in need of convincing) leads us to be less egocentric and more focused on the other, allowing us to disinvest in static certainties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If different contexts can encourage wisdom, does this mean that wisdom can be taught? There’s good reason to be skeptical: in &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/1973-31215-001&quot;&gt;a classic study&lt;/a&gt;, John Darley and Daniel Batson found that seminary students who had been preparing a talk about the Good Samaritan were no more likely to stop and help someone in need, suggesting that learning about a wise approach to living doesn’t mean that we will internalise it. And we know that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/22/expert-philosophers-are-just-as-irrational-as-the-rest-of-us/&quot;&gt;moral philosophers are no more moral&lt;/a&gt; than the rest of us, suggesting that even deep training doesn’t add up to real world practical wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Grossman is optimistic, citing the fact that even undergraduate study – including in psychology – can lead to better reasoning about statistics, methodology, and practical aspects of logic. While these don’t map directly onto wisdom, they share something in their recognition of uncertainty and error in the ways we know the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proponents of teaching wisdom suggest that this teaching could be framed around exemplars – wise figures from the past. Grossman is in favour of this, but suggests that the road to wisdom comes not from treating these figures as peerless exemplars, but as successes within a social context, and by comparing and contrasting where their wisdom apparently reached its limits and why. This is captured by the Solomon Paradox, named after the great Jewish king who also boasted of his riches and ill-prepared his son to succeed him. Grossman argues that exploring these foibles and failings – and whether, in their historical context, they were as great a failing as we now assume – leads to intellectual humility and a sense of a bigger, more complicated picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting the social context into wisdom isn’t an entirely new idea. Taoism teaches us to go beyond an individual point of view, and the Socratic method involves gaining wisdom through discussion, rather than solitary rumination. So consider this new paper a reminder of what these traditions have said: that wisdom is a way, a path along which our thinking becomes proportionate, balanced and expansive, and that it’s a journey enriched by company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-02884-003&quot;&gt;Wisdom and how to cultivate it: Review of emerging evidence for a constructivist model of wise thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">How does the microbiome influence our health? (Part 2)</title>
		<link href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/microbiome-influence-brain-health-part-2/"/>
		<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5282</id>
		<updated>2018-02-22T05:41:40+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-5296 size-full&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/bacteria-108898_1280-e1519278029540.jpg&quot; width=&quot;675&quot; /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second post in a series exploring the neurobiology of the gut-brain connection published in partnership with neuroscientist &lt;a href=&quot;http://amyreichelt.com/&quot;&gt;Dr Amy Reichelt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our intestines are home to an ecosystem of trillions of microbes including bacteria, viruses, phages, fungi, protists, and nematodes. Dominant are bacteria from the families &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt; and&lt;em&gt; Bacteriodetes.&lt;/em&gt; As I talked about in &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/neuroscience-gut-brain-connection-part-1/&quot;&gt;my last blog&lt;/a&gt;, the collective community of these microbes in the intestines is the gut ‘microbiome’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we’ll consider the gut microbiome from the perspective of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Cristina_Torres-Fuentes/publication/319296336_The_microbiota-gut-brain_axis_in_obesity/links/59a6ffc0aca272895c169c9a/The-microbiota-gut-brain-axis-in-obesity.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;obesity research&lt;/a&gt;. Changes in the gut microbiome are associated with several disease states including obesity. Obesity-associated microbes affect insulin resistance, inflammation, fat deposition, metabolism, and appetite. And the gut microbiome is becoming a target for new anti-obesity therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does the microbiome influence our health?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome responds to its surrounding environment including to the foods we eat. Healthy versus unhealthy diets have a profound effect on the microbiome including which species dominate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, eating an unhealthy diet full of sugar and saturated fat alters the balance between ‘good’ &lt;em&gt;Bactereoides&lt;/em&gt; and ‘bad’ &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt; bacterial species. &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt; are needed to digest fats, and eating a high-fat diet encourages their population to increase, leading in turn to weight gain. &lt;em&gt;Bactereoides&lt;/em&gt; digest soluble fibre, so people who consume fibre-rich diets have more &lt;em&gt;Bactereoides&lt;/em&gt; than &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20508158&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; in germ-free mice, which lack gut microbes, found altering the balance between &lt;em&gt;Bactereoides&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Firmicutes&lt;/em&gt; dictated how obese or lean mice became. And a propensity for obesity or leanness could be transmitted from mouse to mouse via gut microbes alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain regulates appetite, feeding behaviours, and energy balance, and although the gut microbiome &lt;em&gt;contributes&lt;/em&gt; to obesity and metabolic syndromes such as diabetes, the exact mechanisms underlying this relationship are uncertain. To date, the link between the microbiome and obesity &lt;a href=&quot;http://mbio.asm.org/content/7/4/e01018-16&quot;&gt;in humans is “weak”.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How might gut bugs speak to the brain?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut provides an environment for bacteria to ferment digested food into all kinds of chemicals and molecules that inform the brain of our current nutritional state. As mentioned in the previous blog, the microbiome signals to the brain via pathways such as vagus nerve, immune and hormone systems, and also via the production of bioactive microbial metabolites released into the bloodstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short-chain fatty acids (SCFAs) are metabolites produced in the gut by microbial fermentation of undigested dietary fibre and complex carbohydrates. SFCAs can cross the blood-brain barrier and modulate brain activity to regulate appetite and food intake. In the brain, SCFAs are neuroprotective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such SCFA is butyric acid or butyrate.  Butyrate is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27346602&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anti-inflammatory agent in the brain and the gut&lt;/a&gt; and reduces levels of harmful toxins that can damage neurons. Butyrate also fortifies the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/science/articles/2013/07/23/3808471.htm&quot;&gt;blood–brain barrier&lt;/a&gt; by tightening connections between cells, which prevents harmful toxins entering the brain causing neuron-damaging inflammation. A leaky blood-brain barrier is often seen in obesity and neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer’s disease. Butyrate also boosts the production of molecules that are important for neuroplasticity including brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF). Boosted levels of BDNF leads to enhanced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5277010/#B130&quot;&gt;memory performance&lt;/a&gt; in lab rats. Scientists have found that eating a junk food diets reduces SCFA levels so it is important to eat a healthy diet to maintain optimal brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How can we change our gut microbiome?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of the microbiome like the different soils that plants grow in — certain plants grow well in nutrient-rich compost, but they won’t survive in dry, sandy soil. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature16504&quot;&gt;Western diets&lt;/a&gt;, especially those with low levels of fibre, have possibly reduced the diversity of microbiota over generations. By contrast, traditional diets high in fibre and low in sugar and fat increase microbiome diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can we do to ensure our microbiome supports our health?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers suggest the diversity and function of microbiome are established by your genetic background and external factors, including way you were delivered at birth and how you exercise. It’s suggested the key determinant affecting the composition and activity of the gut microbiome is your diet —  explaining about 57% of variations in total gut microbiota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can influence the populations of gut microbes by making our gut environment hospitable to them by eating &lt;em&gt;probiotic&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;prebiotic &lt;/em&gt;foods&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probiotics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are foods or dietary supplements containing specific gut-beneficial microbes (such as &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt;) to stimulate the growth of these microorganisms in the gut. Probiotic-rich foods include live yoghurt, kombucha, kimchi, and fermented vegetables such as sauerkraut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prebiotics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are foods stimulate the growth of beneficial bacteria. I think of them as the nutrient-rich fertiliser that helps plants grow. Prebiotic-rich foods include bananas, onions, wheat, flaxseeds, legumes and leafy green vegetables, e.g. spinach, kale, and broccoli. Fermented foods contain microbes that aid gut health and are also prebiotic. The live microbes have already worked on digesting these foods, unlocking extra nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Harnessing the gut microbiome to boost the brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthy gut microbiota is crucial for proper metabolic function and homoeostasis. It’s a win-win for us and our microbes — in exchange for living and proliferating in the gut, they keep us healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing our gut microbiome using probiotics and prebiotics has exciting potential to improve brain function. In my next blog, I’ll talk about a whole new field called ‘psychobiotics’ that could provide a novel therapy for people suffering from mood disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/microbiome-influence-brain-health-part-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How does the microbiome influence our health? (Part 2)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah McKay</name>
			<uri>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Your Brain Health</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Discover neuroscience. Explore the brain. Understand your mind.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/"/>
			<id>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au</id>
			<updated>2018-02-25T12:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Human Chains: &quot;Prayer Camp&quot; Psychiatry Study Raises Ethical Questions</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9367"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9367</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T21:12:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new medical paper raises complex questions over ethics and human rights, as it reports on a study that took place in a religious camp where mentally ill patients were chained up for long periods.

The paper's called Joining psychiatric care and faith healing in a prayer camp in Ghana and it's out now in the British Journal of Psychiatry. The authors are a Ghanian-British-American team led by Dr Angela Ofori-Atta.



In Ghana, the authors explain, there are just 25 psychiatrists to cater</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-02-24T18:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New fossils are redefining what makes a dinosaur</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-fossils-are-redefining-what-makes-dinosaur"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-fossils-are-redefining-what-makes-dinosaur</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T21:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 While some researchers question what characteristics define the dinosaurs, others are uprooting the dino family tree altogether.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">An amateur astronomer caught a supernova explosion on camera</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/supernova-amateur-astronomer-camera"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/supernova-amateur-astronomer-camera</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T18:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 An amateur astronomer has caught a supernova explosion on camera.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Retracted letter about vaccine safety made potentially “slanderous” claims</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/21/retracted-letter-about-vaccine-safety-made-potentially-slanderous-claims/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=61686</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T16:30:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Last October, David Hawkes read a letter to the editor that shocked him: It alleged Hawkes and a colleague had lied about their professional affiliations. Hawkes told Retraction Watch that he contacted the journal Toxicology on October 19 to complain that the letter contained “numerous factual errors that could adversely affect our professional standing,” and … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/21/retracted-letter-about-vaccine-safety-made-potentially-slanderous-claims/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retracted letter about vaccine safety made potentially “slanderous” claims&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T06:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Ecology Highlights</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/21/bmc-ecology-highlights/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9958</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T15:01:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/feature-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0140-1&quot;&gt;The Effects of Stress on Survival in Grey Mouse Lemurs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9959&quot; style=&quot;width: 274px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9959 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/e1-264x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;264&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;By photographer: Gabriella Skollar; editor: Rebecca Lewis (Own work) [GFDL (http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/fdl.html) or CC-BY-SA-3.0 (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/)], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;The relationship between glucocorticoid levels and survival in the grey mouse lemur were studied by Rakotoniaina &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;Through the implementation of a capture-mark-recapture model and hair cortisol concentration (a type of glucocorticoid) as a stress indicator, the effects of stress on survival in a natural setting were assessed.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High levels of cortisol and reduced survival appeared to have an association. It was also found that very good body condition was associated with an increased survival semi-annually, but not during the reproductive season. Variations in parasitism did not predict survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study indicates that long-term increased glucocorticoid levels may be negatively associated with survival. These results highlight the need to consider environmental pressures that may affect glucocorticoid levels, thereby influencing survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Population decline is often hard to measure, and this study demonstrates how an individual health indicator, such as long-term stress levels, may provide an alternate and easier method for detecting issues at a population level, thereby predicting wild populations’ responses to environmental challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0121-4&quot;&gt;Flycatchers in the Cold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9960&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9960&quot; height=&quot;199&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/e2-300x199.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;By Ivan Medenica (Own work) [CC BY-SA 4.0 (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0)], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;Briedis &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; investigated the effect of extreme weather changes on migrating semi-collared flycatchers. They found that the flycatchers delayed the last phase of their spring migration and the population experienced low return rates to breeding sites while enduring a severe cold spell &lt;em&gt;en route&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also found that the start of the spring migration in Africa, and timing of crossing the Sahara were consistent between late and early springs. However, breeding site arrival was dependent on spring phenology at the stopover points in each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study progresses our understanding of how a species biological rhythms and their external environmental stimuli interact. This enables us to greater understand how climate change may impact on migratory animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0134-z&quot;&gt;A Citizen Science Approach to Investigating Road-kill Hotspots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9961&quot; style=&quot;width: 284px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9961&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/e3-274x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;274&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;© Kellergassen Niederösterreich 2016 / Wikimedia Commons / , via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heigl &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;. studied the spatial patterns of road-killed reptiles and amphibians on tertiary roads using a citizen science approach. Open-access remote sensing data was obtained through the use of a citizen science app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors monitored the reptile and amphibian road-kills along 97.5km of tertiary roads, stretching across interurban, municipal and agricultural roads as well as cycling paths. The data was collected in eastern Austria across two seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;72 reptile and 180 amphibian road-kills comprising eight species were recorded, mainly along agricultural roads. It was found that the highest concentrations of road-kills were located next to vineyards, suburban areas and arable land. Green toads, common toads and grass snakes were the most often found road-killed species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was found that a citizen science approach was more cost-efficient than monitoring by professional researchers in instances where more than 400km of road are studied. This information may help authorities aiming to reduce road-kills and other researchers to implement large-scale monitoring of road-kill hotspots in a cost-effective manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0135-y&quot;&gt;Which Frogs Will Reign in an Altered Tropical Forest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0135-y&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-9962&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/e4-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mareike Hirschfeld and Mark-Oliver Rödel investigated which traits make a species more tolerant to disturbances, thereby enabling their success and survival in altered tropical forests as well as pristine ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through analyzing published data in 243 frog species, they identified which traits enabled these amphibians to cope most effectively to modifications of their natural environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those that coped with modifications to their natural habitat best were; indirect developing species with a wide elevational distribution and large range size, which were independent of streams and inhabited leaf litter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study helps to predict future frog communities in altered tropical forests by identifying the traits which are likely to persist in these new environments. These traits found in frogs are also linked with traits found in species with a low extinction risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0147-7&quot;&gt;Habitat Destruction by Crayfish to Access Prey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9963&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9963&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/e5-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;By Andrew C (Red Swamp Crayfish (Procambarus clarkii)) [CC BY 2.0 (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0)], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;In their study, Nishijima &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; examined whether invasive crayfish deliberately destroy submerged vegetation which houses its prey in order to increase their feeding efficiency and therefore their growth rate.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that increasing crayfish density decreased vegetation and animal prey density whilst also increasing the rate of growth of individual crayfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the vegetation was replaced with an increased amount of artificial vegetation, the crayfish growth rate decreased and the survival of animal prey increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experiments determine that the aquatic vegetation strengthens the bottom-up control of crayfish, but this effect is relaxed when the density of crayfish is increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study contributes towards ecosystem restoration knowledge, as the introduction of submerged plants which are tolerant to crayfish destruction may assist in the rebuilding of other aquatic plants and therefore invertebrate populations at small scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/21/bmc-ecology-highlights/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Ecology Highlights&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Stephanie Martin</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Author: Journal’s unapproved edits distorted my ideas</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/21/author-journals-unapproved-edits-distorted-my-ideas/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=54637</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T13:00:48+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researcher Floribert Patrick Endong had been looking forward to seeing his paper in print. Several months after he submitted it to Gender Studies, the journal told him in March that it was online. But when he read it, Endong was disappointed to see some changes he had not approved, which he believed “deformed much of … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/21/author-journals-unapproved-edits-distorted-my-ideas/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Author: Journal’s unapproved edits distorted my ideas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T12:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A new study eases fears of a link between autism and prenatal ultrasounds</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/autism-prenatal-ultrasound-study"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/autism-prenatal-ultrasound-study</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 On almost every measure, prenatal ultrasounds doesn’t appear to be related to a risk of developing autism, a recent study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Episode 11: How to Get a Good Night’s Sleep</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/21/episode-11-how-to-get-a-good-nights-sleep/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33305</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T09:46:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-506725379.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33306&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33306&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;vector of sleep concept with brain. info graphic paper cut style.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;thanaphiphat&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;vectorof sleep concept with brain.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;vectorof sleep concept with brain.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-506725379.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-506725379.jpg?w=845?w=263&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-506725379.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1622,1849&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/21/episode-11-how-to-get-a-good-nights-sleep/vectorof-sleep-concept-with-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-506725379.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;Episode 11 of PsychCrunch&lt;/strong&gt; the podcast from the British Psychological Society’s Research Digest, sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;. Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20180208_PsychCrunch_Ep11_Mx1.mp3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio class=&quot;wp-audio-shortcode&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; id=&quot;audio-33305-1&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20180208_PsychCrunch_Ep11_Mx1.mp3?_=1&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20180208_PsychCrunch_Ep11_Mx1.mp3&quot;&gt;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20180208_PsychCrunch_Ep11_Mx1.mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Can psychology help us get a better night’s sleep?&lt;/strong&gt; Our presenter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ginnysmithscience.com&quot;&gt;Ginny Smith&lt;/a&gt; hears how worry about sleep is sometimes more of a problem than lack of sleep itself. She gives us some evidence-backed sleep tips and finds out about “sleep engineering” – deliberately manipulating the sleep process to aid memory and enhance its health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guests are &lt;a href=&quot;http://lichstein.people.ua.edu&quot;&gt;Professor Kenneth Lichstein&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Alabama and &lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/lewisp8.php&quot;&gt;Professor Penny Lewis&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Cardiff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Background reading for this episode&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/26/insomnia-identity-misbelieving-youve-got-sleep-problems-can-be-more-harmful-than-actual-lack-of-sleep/&quot;&gt;“Insomnia identity” – misbelieving you’ve got sleep problems can be more harmful than actual lack of sleep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-wales-37168752&quot;&gt;BBC News: Sleep engineering: Cardiff scientists working on designer rest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1074742716303240?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;Targeted memory reactivation of newly learned words during sleep triggers REM-mediated integration of new memories and existing knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, find many more &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/?s=procrastination+&quot;&gt;studies on sleep and dreaming&lt;/a&gt; in our archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Episode credits&lt;/b&gt;: Presented and produced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ginnysmithscience.com/&quot;&gt;Ginny Smith&lt;/a&gt;. Mixing &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffknowler.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Jeff Knowler&lt;/a&gt;. PsychCrunch theme music Catherine Loveday and Jeff Knowler. Art work Tim Grimshaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20180208_PsychCrunch_Ep11_Mx1.mp3&quot;&gt;Check out this episode!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/psychcrunch/id966578696?mt=2&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=75970&amp;amp;refid=stpr&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/3FGoC927WmEteiFzdepSrR&quot;&gt;Subscribe and listen on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Past episodes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/episode-one.html&quot;&gt;Episode one: Dating and Attraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/episode-two.html&quot;&gt;Episode two: Breaking Bad Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/10/episode-three.html&quot;&gt;Episode three: How to Win an Argument&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/12/episode-4.html&quot;&gt;Episode four: The Psychology of Gift Giving&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/03/episode-5.html&quot;&gt;Episode five: How To Learn a New Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/06/episode-6.html&quot;&gt;Episode six: How To Be Sarcastic &lt;img alt=&quot;😉&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/08/episode-7.html&quot;&gt;Episode seven: Use Psychology To Compete Like an Olympian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Episode eight: Can We Trust Psychological Studies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/21/episode-9-how-to-get-the-best-from-your-team/&quot;&gt;Episode nine: How To Get The Best From Your Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/01/episode-10-how-to-stop-procrastinating/&quot;&gt;Episode ten: How To Stop Procrastinating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PsychCrunch is sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-10617&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10617&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;936,120&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/podcast/psychcrunch-banner-april-16/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Routledge &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SAGCtSOZXn&quot;&gt;interviewed PsychCrunch presenter Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt; about the aims of the podcast and engaging with the public about psychology research.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How the world responded to Cell Press’s cloned monkey paper</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-the-world-responded-to-cell-presss-cloned-monkey-paper"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-the-world-responded-to-cell-presss-cloned-monkey-paper</id>
		<updated>2018-02-21T06:33:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Highlights from social media and the press – and an overview of how media mentions are gathered and tracked</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T12:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A fake organ mimics what happens in the blink of an eye</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fake-organ-mimics-what-happens-blink-eye"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fake-organ-mimics-what-happens-blink-eye</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T22:15:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A newly crafted artificial eye could help researchers study treatments for dry eye disease and other ailments.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PNAS asks D.C. court to dismiss $10 million defamation lawsuit</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/20/pnas-asks-d-c-court-to-dismiss-10-million-defamation-lawsuit/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=54643</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T22:02:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 WASHINGTON, DC — Lawyers for the National Academy of Sciences have asked a District of Columbia court to dismiss a $10 million defamation suit brought by a Stanford University professor. Mark Jacobson, an engineering professor at Stanford who has published research about the future of renewable energy, alleged he was defamed in a June 2017 … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/20/pnas-asks-d-c-court-to-dismiss-10-million-defamation-lawsuit/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;PNAS asks D.C. court to dismiss $10 million defamation lawsuit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T12:00:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How to build a human brain</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-build-human-brain"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-build-human-brain</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T20:30:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Organoids, made from human stem cells, are growing into brains and other miniorgans to help researchers study development</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ingfei Chen</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T06:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Target of $2M recruitment grant falsified several images: ORI</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/20/target-of-2m-recruitment-grant-falsified-several-images-ori/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=54531</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T14:35:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A former NIH postdoc recruited to a tenure-track position last year committed multiple acts of misconduct in two papers, according to the U.S. Office of Research Integrity. According to the new notice, issued by the ORI, Colleen Skau altered results and multiple figures across the papers, published in Cell and PNAS. The misconduct occurred while … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/20/target-of-2m-recruitment-grant-falsified-several-images-ori/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Target of $2M recruitment grant falsified several images: ORI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-25T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are computers better than people at predicting who will commit another crime?</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/are-computers-better-people-predicting-who-will-commit-another-crime"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/are-computers-better-people-predicting-who-will-commit-another-crime</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T14:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 If crime-predicting computer programs aren’t any more accurate than human guesswork, do they still have a place in the criminal justice system?</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The flowers that give us chocolate are ridiculously hard to pollinate</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flowers-give-us-chocolate-are-ridiculously-hard-pollinate"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flowers-give-us-chocolate-are-ridiculously-hard-pollinate</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T12:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Cacao trees are really fussy about pollination.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Study conducted during war finds one symptom that is especially indicative of PTSD vulnerability</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/20/unprecedented-study-of-conflict-situation-finds-one-symptom-that-is-especially-indicative-of-ptsd-vulnerability/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33293</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T09:53:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-452430810.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33294&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33294&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ASHKELON, ISRAEL - JULY 20:  A wounded Israeli soldier arrives at a hospital for treatment on July 20, 2014 in Ashkelon, Israel. Today marked the deadliest day yet for operation \&amp;quot;Protective Edge,\&amp;quot; with 13 Israeli soldiers being killed and 87 Palestinians.  (Photo by Andrew Burton\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1405838810&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2014 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;27&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.000125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tensions Remain High At Israeli Gaza Border&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tensions Remain High At Israeli Gaza Border&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-452430810.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-452430810.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-452430810.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,2000&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/20/unprecedented-study-of-conflict-situation-finds-one-symptom-that-is-especially-indicative-of-ptsd-vulnerability/tensions-remain-high-at-israeli-gaza-border/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-452430810.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a traumatic event, some people develop post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) – generally within about a month – while others don’t. Identifying those most at risk could allow for targeted interventions, aimed at stopping the disorder developing. So how do you spot these people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way of exploring this question involves viewing PTSD as a dynamic process in which symptoms interact over time to cause the disorder, and some symptoms likely play a bigger causal role than others. So if you can identify the most problematic symptoms, and the people displaying them, at an early stage, then you can work out not only who to target but which symptoms to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a new paper due for publication in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Medicine&lt;/i&gt; and released as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/hv5ts/&quot;&gt;pre-print&lt;/a&gt; at the Open Science Framework, a team of researchers from Israel and Amsterdam conducted just such an analysis on data collected from Israeli civilians during the 50-day Israeli-Gaza war of 2014. “It is important to note that collecting [this kind of] data regarding traumatic stress symptoms during a conflict situation is unparalleled in the literature,” the researchers write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33293&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talya Greene at the University of Haifa led the study of 96 people who were living in communities that were exposed to rocket fire. The participants were recruited via adverts and entered the study between eight and 24 days into the conflict. Twice a day, for 30 days, they received a personalised email link to an online version of a 20-item diagnostic checklist for PTSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This checklist asks people to self-report on four categories of symptoms: intrusions (such as nightmares and flashbacks); avoidance (of thoughts about and reminders of the  traumatic event); negative alterations in mood and thoughts (such as amnesia, blame of self and others, and reduced emotion); and alterations in arousal and reactivity (which measures, among other things, irritability and anger, sleep problems, hyper-vigilance, difficulties in concentrating, and the startle response – an involuntary reaction to a flash of light, a loud noise, or a sudden, potentially threatening movement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every morning, and every evening, the participants recorded any symptoms that they had experienced since completing the previous checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that showing the startle response was clearly the most important predictor of future PTSD symptoms. Reduced emotion, blame, negative emotions and an avoidance of thoughts relating to the conflict were also, in order of decreasing importance, predictive of future symptoms. Participants who showed any of these five symptoms earlier in the study (but the startle response, especially) were more likely to show even more PTSD-related symptoms later on – and those who had more of these predictive symptoms early on developed even more of the other symptoms of PTSD over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers believe this means these are the specific symptoms that could indicate PTSD vulnerability and that targeting them early on could have a preventative benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some limitations to the study. One is that it began during the conflict period, and in fact for many participants the conflict was still unfolding by the time they completed their final checklist. PTSD usually develops in the month after a trauma, but in some cases, it takes much longer to appear. These findings may not apply, then, after a trauma. Also, as the researchers themselves point out, they didn’t take some potentially relevant variables – such as gender, trauma history and severity of exposure to the conflict – into account in their analysis. And it would have been interesting to know which – if any – of the participants would have met the criteria for a diagnosis of PTSD (a process that requires more than completion of a symptom checklist.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, as the researchers conclude: “More studies in this vein can elucidate the complex processes by which PTSD symptoms crystallise into disorder and indicate possible causal mechanisms that drive the development of PTSD. This in turn could have clinical implications for identifying the relevant importance of symptoms as targets for interventions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/hv5ts/&quot;&gt;Dynamic networks of PTSD symptoms during conflict&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: A wounded Israeli soldier arrives at a hospital for treatment on July 20, 2014 in Ashkelon, Israel. (Photo by Andrew Burton/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Cool the planet: drink tap water and eat less meat at dinner time</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/20/cool-planet-drink-tap-water-eat-less-meat-dinner-time/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9825</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T09:30:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/steak-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global food system, from fertilizer manufacture to food storage and packaging, is responsible for up to a staggering one-third of all human-caused GHG emissions. Although there is a need to make food systems more efficient and sustainable, this in itself is not adequate to bring GHG emissions down to acceptable levels; changes also need to be made to our diets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what changes are required? Elisabeth Temme and colleagues at The National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM) set out to answer this question by looking at food consumption in the Netherlands, where the intake of fruits and vegetables is very low and where the intake of saturated fatty acids and sodium is very high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumption data was obtained from the most recent food consumption survey in the Netherlands, the Dutch National Food Consumption Survey (DNFCS) 2007-2010. All consumptions were labelled as one of seven food consumption occasions, distinguishing between the three main meals (breakfast, lunch, dinner) and all moments in between meals (before breakfast, in between breakfast and lunch, in between lunch and dinner, after dinner). Socio-demographic and lifestyle data such as physical activity and educational level was also obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to estimate GHG emissions associated with different foods, life cycle assessments were performed; these look at the entire life cycle of a product from primary production, processing, use of packaging and transport to storage as well as the preparation of the food. The GHG emissions associated with the preparation of foods in the consumer phase was based on the average cooking time for each product . Food waste was also included by using food group specific percentages for avoidable and unavoidable food losses throughout the food chain, including the consumer phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that, in the Dutch diet, the GHG emission varies per consumption occasion. In the highest tertile of dietary GHG emission, dinner was associated with the highest GHG emissions, and consumptions in between meals were associated with the second-to-highest emissions. Meat consumption contributed most to the GHG emission of dinner, while beverages contributed most to the GHG emission of consumptions in between meals. Dairy (including cheese) was an important contributor to total daily dietary GHG emission throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9838&quot; style=&quot;width: 791px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9838&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/graph.jpg&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Mean daily GHG emission (kg CO2-eq) of food groups per consumption occasion in reference scenario.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Source: Temme, van de Kampe and Seves, 2018&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors also developed various scenarios to lower GHG emissions of people in the highest tertile of dietary GHG emission: 1) reduce red and processed meat consumed during dinner by 50% and 75%, 2) replace 50% and 100% of alcoholic and soft drinks (including fruit and vegetable juice and mineral water) by tap water, 3) replace cheese consumed in between meals by plant-based alternatives and 4) two combinations of these scenarios. Effects on GHG emission as well as nutrient content of the diet were assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9828&quot; style=&quot;width: 220px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9828 size-full&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/01/water.jpg&quot; width=&quot;210&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Flickr: Government of Prince Edward Island&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most effective single dietary change was to reduce the consumption of meat, with a 75% reduction in red and/or processed meat during dinner resulting in a 24% reduction in GHG emissions for men and a 22% reduction for women. Furthermore, replacing the consumption of all alcoholic drinks and soft drinks (including mineral water and fruit and vegetable juices) with tap water was also successful in reducing dietary GHG emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dietary changes are also beneficial for health as they are more in line with dietary guidelines and reduce saturated fatty acids and sugar intake. For those who may not meet energy or iron requirements with these changes in diet, low GHG emission and nutritious replacement foods might be needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the scenarios in this study were focused on people in the highest tertile of GHG emissions, it is expected that the dietary changes proposed here will also lead to reductions in GHG emissions for people in the lowest or intermediate tertiles. However, further research is required to determine whether this is indeed the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/20/cool-planet-drink-tap-water-eat-less-meat-dinner-time/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cool the planet: drink tap water and eat less meat at dinner time&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Natalie Pafitis</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Science Suffers from Harassment</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/lQ0wijLAiMY/scientificamerican0318-8"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-8</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 8 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-8&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-8&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leading organization has said that sexual harassment is scientific misconduct. Where are the others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/lQ0wijLAiMY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Case for Daylight Saving Time</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/RNMs9K605oo/scientificamerican0318-76"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-76</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 76 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-76&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-76&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Katie Peek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that the benefits may outweigh the drawbacks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/RNMs9K605oo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Katie Peek</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50, 100 &amp;amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/G7q5JPE6Hyw/scientificamerican0318-75"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-75</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 75 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-75&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-75&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/G7q5JPE6Hyw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel C. Schlenoff</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Factiness</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/x3fqpSXPc0A/scientificamerican0318-73"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-73</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 73 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-73&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-73&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we living in a post-truth world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/x3fqpSXPc0A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michael Shermer</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Recommended</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/wLd6QFmtxC4/scientificamerican0318-72"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-72</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 72 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/wLd6QFmtxC4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Building a Backup Bee</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/7h_q75Osulk/scientificamerican0318-66"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-66</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 66 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-66&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-66&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Paige Embry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world's largest almond grower is creating a novel replacement for the embattled honeybee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/7h_q75Osulk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Paige Embry</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Means of Reproduction</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/P4Z9Im4gBhA/scientificamerican0318-60"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-60</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 60 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-60&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-60&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Karen Weintraub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could scientists one day use blood and skin cells to replace sperm and eggs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/P4Z9Im4gBhA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Karen Weintraub</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Letters</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/L9g_b8FNRtc/scientificamerican0318-6"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-6</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/L9g_b8FNRtc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Scientific American</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Look Within</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/CQbrWCbC7FM/scientificamerican0318-54"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-54</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 54 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-54&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-54&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John Gabrieli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imaging technologies could find the best treatments for depression and addiction—and could even reshape education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/CQbrWCbC7FM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>John Gabrieli</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Island of Heavyweights</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/q8ehqpa20_s/scientificamerican0318-46"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-46</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 46 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-46&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-46&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Christoph E. Düllmann &amp;amp; Michael Block&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A race is on to create the world's heaviest elements—and to explore the periodic table's “island of stability,” where these elements exist for more than a moment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/q8ehqpa20_s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christoph E. Düllmann</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Baddest Bite</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8U01JcRP6Ko/scientificamerican0318-40"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-40</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 40 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-40&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-40&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Gregory M. Erickson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adrenaline-fueled studies of the bite forces of crocodiles and their relatives reveal secrets of the group's evolutionary success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8U01JcRP6Ko&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gregory M. Erickson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Child's Play</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/I8n5Qr6Hgtc/scientificamerican0318-4"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-4</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 4 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/I8n5Qr6Hgtc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariette DiChristina</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Shadows of Other Worlds</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/78OUqnkBzfM/scientificamerican0318-32"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-32</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 32 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-32&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-32&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Joshua N. Winn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two telescopes due to launch this year should reveal a host of new exoplanets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/78OUqnkBzfM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Joshua N. Winn</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Self-Taught Robots</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/yF_WXXBwzHk/scientificamerican0318-26"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-26</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 26 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-26&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-26&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Diana Kwon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machines that learn like children provide deep insights into how the mind and body act together to bootstrap knowledge and skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/yF_WXXBwzHk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Diana Kwon</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Video Disorientation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/-NafgTedpLc/scientificamerican0318-25"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-25</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 25 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-25&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-25&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see horizontally but tend to hold our phones vertically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/-NafgTedpLc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Pogue</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A Perfectly Avoidable Crisis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8RUbycEgsGY/scientificamerican0318-24"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-24</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bone fractures are rife after age 50. Can't we do more about osteoporosis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8RUbycEgsGY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Claudia Wallis</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quick Hits</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/FLeS6bfK26c/scientificamerican0318-22"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-22</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Yasemin Saplakoglu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/FLeS6bfK26c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Yasemin Saplakoglu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fishy Behemoth</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/iOJcv7fhgSk/scientificamerican0318-21"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-21</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 21 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-21&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-21&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Doug Main&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World's largest bony fish was previously misidentified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/iOJcv7fhgSk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Doug Main</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">“I'm Sorry, Dave”</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/B51vjFZJeqo/scientificamerican0318-20b"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20b</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20b&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20b&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Charles Q. Choi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debugging software spots AI's mistakes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/B51vjFZJeqo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Charles Q. Choi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ineffective Geniuses?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/F3JHfG6WG6E/scientificamerican0318-20a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20a</id>
		<updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20a&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0318-20a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Matthew Hutson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with very high IQs can be perceived as worse leaders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/F3JHfG6WG6E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Matthew Hutson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Scientific American is the world's premier magazine of scientific discovery and technological innovation for the general public. Readers turn to it for a deep understanding of how science and technology can influence human affairs and illuminate the natural world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/scientificamerican/current_issue/</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T00:00:30+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© 2018 Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">When — and how — should journals flag papers that don’t quite meet retraction criteria?</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/19/when-and-how-should-journals-flag-papers-that-dont-quite-meet-retraction-criteria/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=54438</id>
		<updated>2018-02-19T13:00:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers of Retraction Watch will be no strangers to the practice of issuing Expressions of Concern — editorial notices from journals that indicate a paper’s results may not be valid. While a good idea in theory — so readers can be aware of potential issues while an investigation is underway — in practice, it’s a […]</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Modern tech unravels mysteries of Egyptian mummy portraits</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/modern-tech-unravels-mysteries-egyptian-mummy-portraits"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/modern-tech-unravels-mysteries-egyptian-mummy-portraits</id>
		<updated>2018-02-19T13:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A museum exhibit showcases what modern analytical tools can reveal about ancient Egyptian funerary portraits and mummies.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Howard Wolinsky</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mix of metals in this Picasso sculpture provides clues to its mysterious origins</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/metals-picasso-bronze-sculptures"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/metals-picasso-bronze-sculptures</id>
		<updated>2018-02-19T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The alloys used to cast Picasso’s bronze sculptures provide a valuable piece of the puzzle in reconstructing the histories of the works of art.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kate Travis</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-27T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Nature vs Nurture: Mothers with multiple children have an intuitive grasp of behavioural genetics</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/19/nature-vs-nurture-mothers-with-multiple-children-have-an-intuitive-grasp-of-behavioural-genetics/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33267</id>
		<updated>2018-02-19T10:50:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33279&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-02-19 10.37.35.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33279&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33279&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-02-19 10.37.35&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/screenshot-2018-02-19-10-37-351.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/screenshot-2018-02-19-10-37-351.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/screenshot-2018-02-19-10-37-351.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1950,1480&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/19/nature-vs-nurture-mothers-with-multiple-children-have-an-intuitive-grasp-of-behavioural-genetics/screenshot-2018-02-19-10-37-35-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/screenshot-2018-02-19-10-37-351.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lower scores equals more accurate estimates of genetic inheritance. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/ezg2j/&quot;&gt;Willoughby et al 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several prominent psychologists &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2015/09/the-coddling-of-the-american-mind/399356/&quot;&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chronicle.com/article/The-Intellectual-War-on/242538?key=VUoegFJonv4-gPdfGkNzjwL5cdI9L5prPSDsTd4xWZnsCQwj9m-Tmvk0CWWLCS24dzg1cnFobUpLZ3lBQjBrOVF0UzBlS29rX0NjWWtHRzEwN084YTM1MXMwQQ&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt; raised concerns that the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dr.jordan.b.peterson/posts/10155096812587657&quot;&gt;radical left&lt;/a&gt;” has a stranglehold on free speech and thought in our universities. The psychologists argue this includes biological denialism: claims that differences between individuals and groups are entirely the result of the biased system or mere social constructions. More generally, many commentators are horrified by the apparent &lt;a href=&quot;http://harvardpolitics.com/world/rise-of-far-right/&quot;&gt;resurgence of far-right ideologies&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/article/the-alt-right-still-wears-the-same-old-brown-shirts-dclwcggw3&quot;&gt;twisted interpretation of genetic science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s timely, then, that a team of researchers, led by psychologist Emily Willoughby at the University of Minnesota Twin Cities, recently surveyed over 1000 online US participants, asking them about their personal circumstances, education, political orientation, and also to estimate the relative contribution of genes and the environment to variation in 21 different human traits, from eye colour to intelligence. This is probably the most detailed study to date of people’s insights into behavioural genetics, and the findings have just been published &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/ezg2j/&quot;&gt;as a pre-print at the Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33267&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing participants’ judgments against the best estimates from the behavioural genetics literature, the researchers found a surprisingly high correlation of .77 (where 1 would be a perfect score). “People’s observations and intuitions about the genetic contributions to human traits are relatively informed,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants’ estimates tended to group into four main categories: physical traits (height, eye colour etc); psychological (intelligence, personality); lifestyle (obesity, blood pressure); and psychiatric (depression, ADHD etc). One interpretation of this is that when making nature/nurture judgments, people tend think in terms of these approximate categories and they infer that traits within a category are subject to a similar level of genetic influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General educational level, and specifically participants’ genetic knowledge were related to the accuracy of their estimates, but only to a surprisingly modest degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about political orientation? Left-leaning liberals estimated a greater genetic contribution to psychiatric disorders and sexual orientation compared with conservatives, while conservatives assumed a relatively greater contribution of genes to traits like intelligence and musical ability. This led to what the researchers called “a surprising sort of ‘balancing out’,” meaning that individuals’ accuracy did not differ by political persuasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers believe this pattern is consistent with the idea that moral judgments are central to the political split in the USA. Right-wing participants more strongly endorsed the idea that some people have more innate aptitude than others, while the left-wing participants more strongly endorsed the idea that many stigmatised traits are largely innate and should therefore be treated with fairness and compassion, not judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there was no greater biological denialism or “blank slatism” by one political wing than the other, but rather a genetic cherry-picking to suit one’s own world view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, sexual orientation was something of an outlier in the study and the trait for which participants’ intuitions diverged the most from the published literature. The researchers do not offer any speculation for why this might be. Most participants strongly overestimated the genetic contribution to this trait, but conservatives did so less than liberals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly perhaps, more strongly related to overall accuracy than education, politics or genetic knowledge, were gender and having children. Women were more accurate in their estimations than men, and participants with non-adopted children were more accurate than those without. The most accurate judges of all were women with multiple non-adopted children. “Mothers may be uniquely observant of their children’s abilities, needs, and attributes,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willoughby and her colleagues took heart from these findings. “While it is clear that social and political biases do inform the magnitude of heritability judgments, the best predictors of these judgments are education and parenthood – an encouraging prospect indeed for the public understanding of findings from behaviour genetics.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more sceptical note, however, this survey was based entirely on myriad correlations and can’t tell us too much about what influences people’s beliefs about behavioural genetics, nor how these beliefs develop through life. For instance, it’s plausible that beliefs about genetic heritability shape people’s political views, as much as the other way around. There may even be genetic influences on people’s insights into genetic inheritance, perhaps manifested through personality, intelligence and political leanings (only the last was measured in this survey).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of better understanding the roots of some of the scientifically dubious beliefs on display on our college campuses and elsewhere, we probably need studies that follow people over time and that are focused at the more extreme ends of the political spectrum – only around 4 to 5 per cent of the current participants identified as very conservative and around 16 per cent as very liberal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues aside, this study makes a novel contribution to a little studied topic, and the idea that mothers have a unique insight into behavioural genetics gained through the experience of parenting will surely resonate with many readers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/ezg2j/&quot;&gt;Free will, determinism, and intuitive judgments about the heritability of behavior&lt;/a&gt; [this paper is a pre-print that has not yet been subjected to peer review]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Babies can recover language skills after a left-side stroke</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/babies-language-brain-stroke"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/babies-language-brain-stroke</id>
		<updated>2018-02-18T20:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Very young babies who have strokes in the language centers of their brain can recover normal language function — in the other side of their brain.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T18:00:52+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Disability Bias in Peer Review?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9359"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9359</id>
		<updated>2018-02-18T15:05:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Writing in the journal Medical Care, researcher Lisa I. Iezzoni says that a peer reviewer on a paper she previously submitted to that journal displayed &quot;explicitly disparaging language and erroneous derogatory assumptions&quot; about disabled people.





Iezzoni's paper, which was eventually rejected, was about a survey of Massachusetts Medicaid recipients with either serious mental illness or significant physical disability. The survey involved a questionnaire asking about their experiences w</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2018-02-24T18:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This stick-on patch could keep tabs on stroke patients at home</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wearable-sensor-patch-stroke-patients"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wearable-sensor-patch-stroke-patients</id>
		<updated>2018-02-17T21:00:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 New wearable electronics that monitor swallowing and speech could aid rehabilitation therapy for stroke patients.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: We’re back! (We hope); the data thugs; heroes of retraction</title>
		<link href="https://retractionwatch.com/2018/02/17/weekend-reads-were-back-we-hope-the-data-thugs-heroes-of-retraction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=54141</id>
		<updated>2018-02-17T14:00:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 As many of our readers will know, we’ve been having serious technical issues with the site. We’re cautiously optimistic that they’ve been solved, so although we’re still working on fixes, we’re going to try posting again. Thanks for your ongoing patience. This week, we posted at our sister site, Embargo Watch. Here are those posts: […]</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>https://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Americans would welcome alien life rather than fear it</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/americans-would-welcome-alien-life-rather-fear-it"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/americans-would-welcome-alien-life-rather-fear-it</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T22:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Americans would probably take the discovery of extraterrestrial microbes pretty well.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-26T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ants practice combat triage and nurse their injured</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ants-practice-combat-triage-and-nurse-their-injured"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ants-practice-combat-triage-and-nurse-their-injured</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T19:14:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Termite-hunting ants have their own version of combat medicine for injured nest mates.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:41+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">James Webb Space Telescope challenges artists to see in infrared</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/james-webb-space-telescope-challenges-artists-see-infrared"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/james-webb-space-telescope-challenges-artists-see-infrared</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T17:58:38+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Astronomy artists face new challenges in translating James Webb’s invisible data into visuals.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">To hear the beat, your brain may think about moving to it</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hear-beat-your-brain-may-think-about-moving-it"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hear-beat-your-brain-may-think-about-moving-it</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T15:49:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 To keep time to a song, the brain relies on a region used to plan movement — even when you’re not tapping along.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dan Garisto</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">BMC Veterinary Research: editor picks of 2017</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/16/bmc-veterinary-research-editor-picks-of-2017/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9945</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T14:00:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/dog_veterinary_pet_animal_clinic_vet_veterinarian_care-1161946-140x110.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Editor, Dr. Hayley Henderson:&lt;em&gt;“It was a successful year, and we would like to thank all of our authors, referees and our dedicated editorial board for their support and contribution. There is a greater push for more complete and transparent reporting in veterinary research, and for effective collaboration between human and veterinary healthcare professionals. Some of our 2017 publications highlight the importance of these endeavors, and we have used these papers to help create our 2018 objectives to improve veterinary and animal research reporting. We look forward to sharing our plans with our readers soon.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12917-017-0987-6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental enrichment for captive cats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-9948 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/catnip-225x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;225&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cats kept exclusively indoors may become bored or stressed which can exacerbate negative behaviors such as being aggressive or destructive. Catnip (&lt;em&gt;Nepeta cataria&lt;/em&gt;) is a well known olfactory stimulant which causes a euphoric response in some domestic cats and is used by some cat owners to enrich their pet’s environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bol &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; aimed to test catnip and other plants with anecdotal evidence of causing euphoric responses in cats. The researchers tested catnip, silver vine, Tatarian honeysuckle and valerian root on 100 domestic cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their results showed that most of the sampled cats had a positive response to the olfactory stimulation. One in three cats did not respond to catnip. A much higher percentage of cats responded to the silver vine (80%) and approximately 50% of the cats responded to the honeysuckle and valerian root. Interestingly, 75% of the cats which did not respond to catnip did respond to silver vine, and a third to the honeysuckle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors concluded that silver vine and Tatarian honeysuckle may be good alternatives for cats which do not respond to catnip, and suggest that olfactory stimulation may be effective for improving quality of life for cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12917-017-1207-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring the influence of funding source on the quality of animal randomized control trial reporting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randomized control trials are essential for veterinary evidence-based clinical research and it is important that trial reporting is transparent and complete. Animal trials are often poorly reported compared to human trials, mainly because human trial guidelines are considered more rigorous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wareham &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;reviewed a sample of veterinary randomized control trials published in 2011. Their study looked at the number of outcomes measured, number of animals enrolled, whether primary outcome measures were stated, and sample size calculations were performed before animals were enrolled. The authors also studied whether the trial funding source influenced trial design and delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;They concluded that veterinary clinical trial, design and delivery could be substantially improved and suggested that low quality reporting impedes veterinary evidence-based practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their results showed that in 126 trials, the median number of outcome measures reported was 5 and median number of animals enrolled in each trial was 30, neither of which significantly differed across funding groups. Primary outcomes were stated in 40.5% of the trials studied, and interestingly these were more likely to be stated if the trial was funded by a pharmaceutical company. Only 14.3% of the trials reported their sample size calculation. They concluded that veterinary clinical trial, design and delivery could be substantially improved and suggested that low quality reporting impedes veterinary evidence-based practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12917-017-1258-2&quot;&gt;Searching for the source of “phantom” scratching in canine syringomyelia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syringomyelia is a complex neurological condition which affects some dog and cat breeds. The condition is characterized by a malformation in the spine affecting the flow of cerebrospinal fluid, causing “pockets” of fluid, called syrinx, to accumulate in the spinal cord. A common clinical sign in dogs is phantom scratching, a compulsion to scratch towards the shoulder or neck without actually scratching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nalborczyk &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;performed a retrospective cohort study on the medical records of 37 Cavalier King Charles spaniels with a diagnosis of symptomatic syringomyelia. All dogs’ MRI files were reviewed to determine the maximum perpendicular dimensions of syrinx in the spinal cord quadrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9947&quot; style=&quot;width: 913px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9947&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/spaniel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;903&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Source: Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their results showed that phantom scratching in the dog may be associated with a syrinx located in the C2-C5 vertebrae, which correlates to a section of the spinal cord called the superficial dorsal horn. The authors concluded that phantom scratching in dogs may happen after superficial dorsal horn cervical neurons are damaged. It may be possible that this neuronal damage influences the activity of scratching behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biomedcentral.com/collections/COHACTSA&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outlining quality assurance and best research practices for non-regulated veterinary clinical studies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal clinical trials can generate volumes of useful data which can translate knowledge from clinical research to veterinary and human clinical practice. However, the usefulness of these studies is dependent on the quality of their reporting. Davies &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;outlined quality control and assurance procedures which they believe should be built into all veterinary clinical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors referred to numerous resources for designing and conducting regulated clinical trials as well as suggesting the use of local guidelines to improve trial design and execution. The authors commented that even in non-regulated clinical trials, following trial guidelines would make them more useful for translation into the clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is further discussed that funders, publishers and quality assurance organizations are increasingly exploring ways to improve the quality of reporting including using standardized guidelines and policies. The authors concluded that research outcomes should be constantly scrutinized as new data emerges in regulated and non-regulated research settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12917-017-1072-x&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stimulating collaboration between human and veterinary health care professionals for One Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The One Health approach is a concept which aims to improve health and well-being of humans and animals by using an interdisciplinary approach to address the relationship between health care for humans and animals as well as the environment. The approach requires a collaborative effort between human and veterinary healthcare professionals; however documented collaboration between these groups is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professional associations may develop the One Health approach by acting as a facilitator to increase collaboration between health care professionals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study Eussen &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;explored the social dilemma experienced by health care professionals to help understand how the collaborative effort could be improved. The authors developed a questionnaire  to assess the relationship between collaboration and a common goal. The survey was completed by 368 respondents, 16% were human healthcare professionals 84% were veterinary healthcare professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was found that a common goal stimulates collaboration. The authors suggested that professional associations may develop the One Health approach by acting as a facilitator to increase collaboration between health care professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcvetres.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12917-017-1142-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploring the possibilities of diagnosing adverse food reactions in dogs and cats with &lt;em&gt;in vivo &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;in vitro &lt;/em&gt;tests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adverse food reactions in dogs and cats usually involve eliminating certain foods from the diet and using provocation tests to identify intolerances or allergies, which is a similar method used in human medicine. However this method can be considered laborious by pet owners, and there is a low rate of compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A laboratory test using samples of blood, saliva or hair could be more convenient for pet-owners who have animals showing signs of an adverse food reaction. In this study, Mueller and Olivry systematically reviewed 22 publications reporting data for adverse food reaction tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9946&quot; style=&quot;width: 905px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9946&quot; height=&quot;597&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/dogs-eating.jpg&quot; width=&quot;895&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Source: Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors found articles describing several different tests such as lymphocyte proliferation tests, serum tests for food-specific allergies and colonoscopy tests. Lymphocyte proliferation tests gave the most promising results, but are difficult to perform. Until a more simple protocol can be developed, this test can only be used as a research tool. The other tests reviewed were not considered currently useful so the best diagnostic procedure remains the elimination diet with provocation trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/16/bmc-veterinary-research-editor-picks-of-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Veterinary Research&lt;/em&gt;: editor picks of 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tillie Cryer</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The neurology of the Winter Olympics</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/526774570/0/oupblogpsychology/"/>
		<id>https://blog.oup.com/?p=136513</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T11:30:12+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;The human brain is a wonder and a marvel. At the same time, it is enigma and frustration. Given all it has accomplished, it continues to perplex. This is why I became a neurologist. For me, combining the apex of all organic structures with the vast unknown of cerebral neuroscience produces a daily wonder that is worth dedicating a life’s work to. To that end, I find myself somewhere over the North Pole hurling towards PyeongChang, South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, roughly, I was on a similar flight to Sochi, Russia for my first experience as a physician for the US Olympic Team. Then, despite all of the preparation, work, dedication, and sacrifice it took to be on that flight, I felt a degree of uneasy apprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Olympics!” people would say when they found out why I’d be away from work and family for three weeks, “So amazing… what an honor!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, mid-flight jitters were created, mainly on the backs of others’ vicarious attestations. In the end, when faced with that same dichotomy of known vs. unknown and the responsibility of caring for the brain of another human, I fell back on what I first learned as a medical student and intern at Charity Hospital in New Orleans. Stay within yourself. Adjust to the unknown. First, do no harm. You may not have every answer in front of you or on the internet (which didn’t exist when I was at Tulane)… so solve the problem as best you can! These are valuable lessons for all physicians, to be sure, but even more so for neurologists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These lessons served me well in Sochi, as a foundation wrapped in the premise that it doesn’t matter to the person you’re caring for whether they were hurt in an Olympic halfpipe, a neighborhood skate park, or a French Quarter misstep. In the end, it comes down to the same thing: understanding the brain well enough to appreciate the scope of its complexities while simultaneously having the humility and perspective to admit what you don’t know, expect to be challenged, yet still find a way to provide medical care to the best of your abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_136518&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-136518&quot; height=&quot;333&quot; src=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Stephanie_Beckert_-_5000m_speed_skating_-_Vancouver_2010-744x496.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;Stephanie Beckert at the Women’s 5000m final by Robert Scoble. CC BY 2.0 via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Stephanie_Beckert_-_5000m_speed_skating_-_Vancouver_2010.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past week, you may have already had the chance to watch some of the world’s best athletes do some truly amazing things. In the days to come, hopefully you can watch some more. When you do, take a moment to appreciate what is allowing them to perform, at the brain level. Wonder at how many neurons it takes to twist and flip an athlete while first they go skyward, their skis launching them up, and then continue their contortions as they come down again when gravity wins the day. Consider the cerebral networks involved in an ice-hockey game: the visuospatial, motor, cognitive, proprioceptive, balance networks (to name a few!). Marvel at what it takes to land a quad jump, have the reaction time and attention to navigate a downhill course at 90 mph, produce the fluidity of movement to win a gold medal in ice dancing. Dancing… on millimeters-thick razor blades!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then stop and consider what happens when any one of those brains experiences a sudden stop, a deceleration caused by ice, or snow, or an opponent’s elbow. Normal physiological function is impaired if not temporarily halted. The eloquent firing of neurons, allowing each to participate in the formation of a purposeful network, is replaced by sluggish, inefficient recruitment. Inside the brain, the injury is obvious… if only one could be there or measure it! In the outside world, however, we rely on the clinical manifestations of the injury to guide diagnosis and management. Sometimes the clinical effect is obvious; other times it’s subtle. Still for others, although the injury is present, there is simply no clinical effect at all. The marveled married with the unknown. This is why I love what I do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, from the Olympics standpoint, I have the advantage of experience and perspective, so no in-flight uneasiness this time around! From the medical perspective, however, in the weeks to come I’ll really be where I always am, practicing medicine in the intersection of reverence for human accomplishment and respect for the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Ivica Kostelić at the 2010 Winter Olympic downhill by Jon Wick. CC BY 2.0 via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ivica_Kosteli%C4%87_at_the_2010_Winter_Olympic_downhill.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/neurology-winter-olympics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The neurology of the Winter Olympics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/526774570/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/526774570/oupblogpsychology,https%3a%2f%2fblog.oup.com%2fwp-content%2fuploads%2f2018%2f02%2fStephanie_Beckert_-_5000m_speed_skating_-_Vancouver_2010-744x496.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/526774570/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitzstatic.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/dr-victor-sidel-leader-health-peace-social-justice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Dr. Victor Sidel: a leader for health, peace, and social justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/memoriam-jimmie-c-holland-md/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;In memoriam: Jimmie C. Holland, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/02/fungus-worth-900-billion/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The fungus that’s worth $900 billion a year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>DanP</name>
			<uri>https://blog.oup.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">OUPblog » Psychology</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Academic insights for the thinking world.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.oup.com</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T00:00:34+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">(c) Oxford University Press</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What are the psychological dynamics when a couple tries to change a habit together?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/16/what-are-the-psychological-dynamics-when-a-couple-tries-to-change-a-habit-together/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33265</id>
		<updated>2018-02-16T09:05:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-650384784.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33266&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33266&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 6D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Wife is very angry because her husband doesn't want to stop smoking.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1476302954&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;90&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Angry wife because of her husband addiction&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Angry wife because of her husband addiction&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-650384784.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-650384784.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-650384784.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/02/16/what-are-the-psychological-dynamics-when-a-couple-tries-to-change-a-habit-together/angry-wife-because-of-her-husband-addiction/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-650384784.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing an unhealthy habit depends a lot on your belief that you can do it, something psychologists call self-efficacy. Take smoking, for example. Your belief that you are capable of quitting will influence the likelihood you will decide to quit in the first place, the amount your smoking reduces, and your chances of staying smoke-free in the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This self-belief doesn’t come out of nowhere. Besides seeing ourselves make progress (called “mastery”), health psychologists will tell you that one of the most important inspirations is seeing others successfully make the changes that you desire. To test how true this is, Lisa Warner from the Freie Universität Berlin and her colleagues looked at the impact on smokers of having a partner whose own attempt to quit is going well. Their findings, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12293/full?hootPostID=12e380b4e3af49ac3082c8cfa7d2241d&quot;&gt;published in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, didn’t fit the expected pattern – but there’s news that co-quitting couples can help each other make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33265&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warner’s team asked 85 couples, made up of partners who had chosen to quit together, to keep a diary of their progress. At the end of each day, every participant recorded whether they had smoked any cigarettes that day (to indicate their mastery) and also their feelings of self-efficacy regarding the challenge of quitting, rating their agreement with items such as “I am confident that I can refrain from smoking tomorrow even if it is difficult”. The researchers expected that when one partner improved their mastery, this should boost their other half’s self-efficacy the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t quite what the researchers found, but partners certainly mattered. The day-by-day analysis showed that a participant’s self-efficacy was more likely to go up when their partner had shown increases in their own self-efficacy the day before. So partner confidence was contagious. The same was true for mastery: one partner’s success predicted their other half’s next-day success (or another way to see this: when one person gave in, it was more likely that their partner would succumb on the next day). Intriguingly, however,  partner mastery didn’t seem to affect a participant’s next-day self-efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that witnessing success in a close other wasn’t a driver of self-efficacy is a puzzle for the researchers, but overall this is still important news for couples trying to make healthy changes together – one way or another, a determined partner can be a source of support for finding your way out of smoking – a habit that kills around six million people a year. So put your mind to it, lean into that success cycle, and know that your efforts are feeding those of the person you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12293/full?hootPostID=12e380b4e3af49ac3082c8cfa7d2241d&quot;&gt;Day-to-day mastery and self-efficacy changes during a smoking quit attempt: Two studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2018-02-28T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Strong winds send migrating seal pups on lengthier trips</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/strong-winds-send-migrating-seal-pups-lengthier-trips"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/strong-winds-send-migrating-seal-pups-lengthier-trips</id>
		<updated>2018-02-15T21:32:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Prevailing winds can send northern fur seal pups on an epic journey.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Household products make surprisingly large contributions to air pollution</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/household-products-make-surprisingly-large-contributions-air-pollution"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/household-products-make-surprisingly-large-contributions-air-pollution</id>
		<updated>2018-02-15T19:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A study of smog in the Los Angeles valley finds that paints, fragrances and other everyday items are a growing component of the problem.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T18:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fossil footprints may put lizards on two feet 110 million years ago</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-footprints-may-put-lizards-two-feet-110-million-years-ago"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-footprints-may-put-lizards-two-feet-110-million-years-ago</id>
		<updated>2018-02-15T18:19:54+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fossilized footprints found in South Korea could be the earliest evidence of two-legged running in lizards.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">In Borneo, hunting emerges as a key threat to endangered orangutans</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borneo-hunting-emerges-key-threat-endangered-orangutans"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borneo-hunting-emerges-key-threat-endangered-orangutans</id>
		<updated>2018-02-15T17:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Only small numbers of Bornean orangutans will survive coming decades, researchers say.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2018-02-22T00:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Higher cigarette taxes may increase use of chewing tobacco and cigars in adolescents</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/15/higher-cigarette-taxes-may-increase-use-of-chewing-tobacco-and-cigars-in-adolescents/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9920</id>
		<updated>2018-02-15T09:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/E-Cigarette-E-Cigar-Electronic_Cigarette-E-Cigs-E-Liquid-Vaping_16088078247-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the continued decline of adolescent cigarette use has been celebrated as a public health &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2014/p0612-YRBS.html&quot;&gt;success&lt;/a&gt;, we should put away our party hats when we consider that overall tobacco use has remained relatively stable in recent years. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/66/wr/mm6623a1.htm&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, 20% of adolescents used tobacco products while 8% used cigarettes. Is that how we want to define success?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing cigarette taxes has been a major policy driver to decrease smoking, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4877221/&quot;&gt;adolescent smoking&lt;/a&gt;, while taxes on other tobacco products have received less attention. Taxes on cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, and cigars are all fiscal policies, but they are not all equal. While state taxes on cigarettes have increased substantially over the past decade, there has been little change in policies governing alternative tobacco products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examining the impacts of tobacco taxes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of our study published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; was to evaluate the impact of chewing tobacco and cigar taxes, cigarette taxes, and smoke-free legislation on adolescent use of smokeless tobacco and cigars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in tobacco control policies across and within US states created a natural experiment, which we were able to examine using data on 499,381 adolescents from 36 US states. In the Youth Risk Behavior Survey, adolescents’ self-report on how many days they used smokeless tobacco, cigars, and cigarettes over the past month. We linked information on state chewing tobacco taxes, cigar taxes, cigarette taxes and smoke-free restaurant legislation to each adolescent based on the year the survey was completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that chewing tobacco taxes had no effect on smokeless tobacco use and cigar taxes had no effect on cigar use. In contrast, a 10% increase in cigarette taxes was associated with a 1.0 percentage point increase in smokeless tobacco use among adolescent males. A 10% increase in cigarette taxes was also associated with a 1.5 percentage point increase in cigar use among adolescent males and a 0.7 percentage point increase in cigar use among adolescent females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also found some evidence that smoke-free legislation, such as a restaurant smoking ban, was associated with a 1.1 percentage point increase in smokeless tobacco use among adolescents, but only in males. There was no effect of smoke-free legislation on cigar use for males or females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taxes may be driving adolescents to cheaper alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When developing tobacco control policies, we need to think beyond the conventional cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that higher state cigarette taxes are associated with adolescents’ use of cheaper, alternative tobacco products such as smokeless tobacco and cigars. In our data, from 1999 through 2013, 30/33 states increased their cigarette taxes while 16/33 states increased their taxes on chewing tobacco or cigars. As a percent of the retail price, this translates to a 73% and 58% average increase in chewing tobacco and cigar taxes, respectively. In contrast, combined with the federal cigarette tax increase of $1.01 in 2009, cigarette taxes ($/pack) increased by 141% in real terms over the study period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless taxes on tobacco products are inflation-adjusted, their impact diminishes over time. If taxes on alternative tobacco products are not increased in line with cigarette taxes, some of the decrease in cigarette use reflects adolescents switching to other products. This would not be considered a public health success as health risks from alternative products are the same or greater than cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developing tobacco control policies, we need to think beyond the conventional cigarette. Adolescents are price sensitive and look to experiment with tobacco. Unfortunately the Youth Risk Behavior Survey did not ask about e-cigarettes or hookahs—two products that continue to gain in popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing adolescent tobacco use will require comprehensive tobacco control policies that are applied equally to and inclusive of all tobacco products, including chewing tobacco and cigars. If we can align our policies so populations that are more price-sensitive cannot easily substitute products, we may begin to see overall reductions in tobacco use. If that’s the case, then we’re ready for a celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/02/15/higher-cigarette-taxes-may-increase-use-of-chewing-tobacco-and-cigars-in-adolescents/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Higher cigarette taxes may increase use of chewing tobacco and cigars in adolescents&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Summer Sherburne Hawkins, Ph.D., M.S.</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2018-02-23T12:00:38+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
