<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:36+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This talk is based on the article &quot;Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants&quot; by Bernd Noack; Research Director CNRS (Centre Nationnal de la Recherche Scientifique), LIMSI-CNRS, France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk Anuradha will summarise the article and attempt to explain some fundamental features of human speech.
In particular, she will show the range of frequencies typically used by men and women.
She will also explain the role of formants (concentration of energy at particular frequency) in speech communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vowels play an important part in the formation of words and how they are vocalised.
In fact, as will be shown much of the energy in human speech is used in the production of vowels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anuradha will also demonstrate how the human voice can be heard against the background of a full orchestra, even though the total sound from the orchestra is much louder than the singer (typically a soprano).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, she will show the relationship between distance and received speech level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 10/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anuradha Sulane</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This deep-sea fish uses weird eyes to see in dark and light</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T20:25:19+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The eyes of deep-sea fish called pearlsides contain cells that look like rods but act like cones.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Firing patterns in the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model</title>
		<link href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html"/>
		<id>tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T19:20:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Julia will present the paper by Naud et al (2008) 'Firing patterns in the AdEx IF model'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article the authors explore the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model as a good tool to simulate large-scale spiking neuron networks.
They show that the AdEx model generates multiple firing patterns in response to the parameter values.
In order to describe the transition from one pattern to another, the phase diagrams are analysed in the article.
To further classify the firing patterns, the transient response to step current is studied.
The analytical solutions are given for continuous adaptation, initial bursting, regular bursting, tonic spiking and irregular spiking as a response to the constant current.
It is also concluded, that the network simulations of a large systems, such as thalamocortical, require the description of different neuron types.
Parameter sets for three neuron types are provided, but further work is needed to extend this to a larger number of neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full article could be found here: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Julia Goncharenko</name>
			<uri>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">UH Biocomputation Group</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml"/>
			<id>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T23:26:35+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crested pigeons sound the alarm with their wings</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T18:28:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Crested pigeons have specialized feathers that signal danger when they flee from an apparent threat.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helen Thompson</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52537</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T15:57:05+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;This week, we received a press release that caught our attention: A company is releasing software it claims will write manuscripts using researchers’ data.  The program, dubbed “Manuscript Writer,” uses artificial intelligence (AI) to generate papers, according to the company that created it, sciNote LLC. A spokesperson explained the software generates a first draft the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Honeybees fumble their way to blueberry pollination</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T14:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Blueberry flowers drive honeybees to grappling, even stomping a leg or two down a bloom throat, to reach pollen.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52531</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T13:37:01+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Carlo Croce, a cancer researcher who has faced numerous research misconduct allegations, recently accused a former lab member of misconduct. Although an institutional probe did not support that allegation, Croce’s efforts have led to a retraction. In November 2015, Croce and another cancer researcher at Ohio State University (OSU), Ramiro Garzon, contacted PLOS ONE, alleging […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Can evolutionary psychology and personality theory explain Trump’s popular appeal?</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32297</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T12:30:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-632198430.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32369&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32369&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;WASHINGTON, DC - JANUARY 20:  U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on the West Front of the U.S. Capitol on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. In today's inauguration ceremony Donald J. Trump becomes the 45th president of the United States.  (Photo by Chip Somodevilla\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1484914722&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;840&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2500&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,683&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/donald-trump-is-sworn-in-as-45th-president-of-the-united-states/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago today, Donald J Trump, a man with no political or military experience, defied expectations, winning the election to become the 45th president of the United States. Nearly 63 million voted for him, including, and in spite of his reputation for sexism, over half of all white women. In an &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;open-access paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Evolutionary Studies in Imaginative Culture&lt;/em&gt;, Dan McAdams, one of the world’s leading experts in personality psychology, proposes an explanation for Trump’s popular appeal that is grounded in evolutionary psychology, personality theory and the social psychology of leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32297&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump encapsulates, and his personality is perfectly suited to, “dominance-oriented leadership”, McAdams explains, in contrast to “prestige leadership”, as exemplified by Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prestige leadership emerged more recently in our evolutionary history and is grounded in the cultural transmission of ideas and skills. Individuals who acquire expertise, and who have the ability to effectively organize other experts, are respected for their knowledge and wisdom and seen as legitimate leaders for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, dominant leadership is based on fear and power and dates farther back in our evolutionary past. To many Americans, Trump’s bombastic style and persona and proclamations have a “primal appeal”. Describing Trump as more “overtly aggressive” than any other political figure, “physically big and dynamic”, “insulting” and “egregiously self-promoting”, McAdams likens Trump’s “incendiary tweets” to the “charging displays” of an alpha male chimp, “designed to intimidate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to the dominance approach to leadership is the derogation of experts – Trump has previously stated he knows more than military generals and has no need for economists. Related to this is the espousal of an essentialist view that sees some individuals as inherently superior to others. Trump consistently boasts about his superior intelligence and abilities over others. He displays what social psychologists call “hubristic pride” – celebrating who he is (brilliant and powerful, in his view), rather than the work and effort he has invested (upon which “authentic pride” is based).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominant leader is especially appealing in a climate of fear. Trump has pushed this view – highlighting the dangers of outsiders, be they Mexican immigrants or Islamist terrorists, while also speaking of the economic “carnage” afflicting the country. Throughout his life, Trump has advocated a Hobbesian view of human culture. Even as long ago as 1981, he said “Man is the most vicious of all animals, and life is a series of battles ending in victory or defeat”. Against the enemies he invokes, and in these dangerous times, Trump “confidently assures Americans that he will deliver them from the chaos,” McAdams writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s personality is perfectly suited to this particular approach to leadership, McAdams observes. He has an unusual mix of extremely high extraversion, low agreeableness, and extreme narcissism. The first two traits contribute to his ability and willingness to forge opportunistic, short-term coalitions, but then to drop them as soon as they no longer fulfill his needs, just as alpha chimpanzees do with their potential rivals. Indeed, McAdams observes that “the case of Donald Trump shows how much humans turn out to be like chimps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Trump’s narcissism (and his essentialist view of ability and status) is likely appealing to voters who crave authoritarian rule – that is, submission to a strong leader, adherence to strict rules, and an aggressive, intolerant approach to outsiders and liberals (polls suggest authoritarianism has risen in the US over the last decade). A leader who believes confidently in, and frequently brags about, his own abilities, and strength and power, is highly appealing to these voters who have what social psychologists call a right-wing authoritarian attitude and social dominance orientation, meaning they believe strongly in the superiority of their own group over others, and who want a leader who endorses and represents this superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McAdams concludes by writing that he does not wish to dismiss or denigrate the many other explanations put forward for the rise of a man described by people from all political persuasions as “a serial liar, a sexual predator, a swindler, a narcissist, and a bully”. There are “many reasons” McAdams writes, [but] “the view advanced here is that Trump holds a deep and primal appeal for millions of Americans at this time in our history because of how effectively he channels the psychology of dominance – a way of thinking and feeling about leadership in groups that traces back many millions of years in human evolution, to our primate heritage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;The Appeal of the Primal Leader: Human Evolution and Donald J. Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32297&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">See these first-of-a-kind views of living human nerve cells</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A catalog of live brain cells reveals stunning diversity and intricate shapes, and may help scientists understand the abilities of the human brain.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How text mining is changing the way we tackle chronic disease</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T11:02:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers are working with Pathway Studio to design innovative treatments using simulations of complex diseases</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Physicists shrink plans for next major collider</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xmPIEmDBp1I/nature.2017.22983"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983</id>
		<updated>2017-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Large Hadron Collider’s failure to detect new particles beyond the Higgs has eroded the case for Japan’s proposed linear accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22983&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xmPIEmDBp1I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edwin Cartlidge</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">EPA OKs first living pest-control mosquito for use in United States</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T23:58:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Feds approve non-GM male tiger mosquitoes for sale as fake dads to suppress local pests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52498</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T19:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Nobel Prize Physiology 2017 (for their discoveries of molecular mechanisms controlling the circadian rhythm) is On Fiction as There Is No Molecular Mechanisms of Biological Clock Controlling the Circadian Rhythm. Circadian Rhythm Is Triggered and Controlled By Divine Mechanism (CCP – Time Mindness (TM) Real Biological Clock) in Life Sciences  What Caught Our Attention: This isn’t a retraction — rather, it’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists replaced 80 percent of a ‘butterfly’ boy’s skin</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T18:35:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 By correcting genes in stem cells and growing new skin in the lab, a new therapy repaired a genetic skin disease.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This star cheated death, exploding again and again</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:44+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The weirdest supernova ever has lasted more than three years, and may be the third outburst from the same star.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52505</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T16:00:51+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Last week, a Swedish government funding agency announced 325 recipients of grants in Natural and Engineering Sciences. We don’t normally write about grant announcements, but we’re flagging this one because one recipient may be familiar to our readers. It is Peter Eklöv of Uppsala University, a co-author of a now-retracted Science paper about the potential […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">Is a thermostat conscious?</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/is-a-thermostat-conscious/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1464</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T14:23:23+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;A theory of consciousness initially proposed by David Chalmers (in his book the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Conscious-Mind-Search-Fundamental-Philosophy/dp/0195117891&quot;&gt;Conscious Mind&lt;/a&gt;) is that consciousness (or experience) is a property of information processing systems. It is an additional property, not logically implied by physical laws; a new law of nature. The theory was later formalized by Giulio Tononi into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_information_theory&quot;&gt;Integrated Information Theory&lt;/a&gt;, based on Shannon’s mathematical concept of information. One important feature of this theory is it is a radical form of panpsychism: it assigns consciousness (to different degrees) to virtually anything in the world, including a thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bewitched experiment of thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/modern-panpsychism-about-the-integrated-information-theory-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;I have criticized IIT previously&lt;/a&gt; on the grounds that it fails to define in a sensible way what makes a conscious subject (eg a subsystem of a conscious entity would be another conscious entity, so for example your brain would produce an infinite number of minds). But here I want to comment specifically on the example of the thermostat. It is an interesting example &lt;a href=&quot;https://annakaharris.com/chalmers/&quot;&gt;brought up by Chalmers in his book&lt;/a&gt;. The reasoning is as follows: a human brain is conscious; a mouse brain is probably conscious, but with a somewhat lower degree (for example, no self-consciousness). As we go down the scale of information-processing systems, the system might be less and less conscious, but why would it be that there is a definite threshold for consciousness? Why would a billion neurons be conscious but not a million? Why would a million neurons be conscious but not one thousand? And how about just one neuron? How about a thermostat? A thermostat is an elementary information-processing system with just two states, so maybe, Chalmers argue, the thermostat has a very elementary form of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To claim that a thermostat is conscious defies intuition, but I would not follow Searle on insisting that the theory must be wrong because it assigns consciousness to things that we wouldn’t intuitively think are conscious. As I argued in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/the-substrate-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, to claim that biology tells us that only brains are conscious is to use circular arguments. We don’t know whether anything else than a brain is conscious, and since consciousness is subjective, to decide whether anything is conscious is going to involve some theoretical aspects. Nonetheless, I am skeptical that a thermostat is conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to examine the Bewitched experiment of thought. In the TV series Bewitched, Samantha the housewife twitches her nose and everyone freezes except her. Then she twitches her nose and everyone unfreezes, without noticing that anything happened. For them, time has effectively stopped. The question is: was anyone experiencing anything during that time? To me, it is clear that no one can experience anything if time is frozen. In fact, that whole time has not existed at all for the conscious subject. It follows that a substrate with a fixed state (e.g. hot/cold) cannot experience anything, because time is effectively frozen for that substrate. Experience requires a flow of time, a change in structure through time. I leave it open whether the interaction of the thermostat with the room might produce experience for that coupled system (see below for some further thoughts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is “information”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my view, the fallacy in the initial reasoning is to put the thermostat and the brain in the same scale. That scale is the set of information-processing systems. But as I have argued before (mostly following Gibson’s arguments), &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xix-does-the-brain-process-information/&quot;&gt;it is misleading to see the brain an information-processing system&lt;/a&gt;. The brain can only be seen to transform information of one kind into information of another kind by an external observer, because the very concept of information is something that makes sense to a cognitive/perceptual system. The notion of information used by IIT is Shannon information, a notion from communication theory. This is an extrinsic notion of information: for example, neural activity is informative about objects in the world in the sense that properties of those objects can be inferred from neural activity. But this is totally unhelpful to understand how the brain, which only ever gets to deal with neural signals and not things in the world, sees the world (see this argument in more detail in my paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/07/31/168237&quot;&gt;Is coding a relevant metaphor for the brain?&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s clarify with a concrete case: does the thermostat perceive temperature? The thermostat can be in different states depending on temperature, but from its perspective, there is no temperature. There are changes in state that seems to be unrelated to anything else (there is literally nothing else for the thermostat). One could replace the temperature sensor with some other sensor, or with a random number generator, and there would be literally no functional change in the thermostat itself. Only an external observer can link the thermostat’s state with temperature, so the thermostat cannot possibly be conscious of temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, Shannon’s notion of information is inappropriate to understand consciousness. Instead of extracting information in the sense of communication theory, what the brain might do is build models of sensory (sensorimotor) signals from its subjective perspective, in the same way as scientists make models of the world with observations (=sensory signals) and experiments (=actions). But this intrinsic notion of information, which corresponds eg to laws of physics, is crucially not what Shannon’s notion of information is. And it is also not the kind of information that a thermostat is dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inappropriate notion of information leads to what in my view is a rather absurd quantitative scale of consciousness, according to which entities are more or less conscious along a graded scale (phi). Differences in consciousness are qualitative, not quantitative: there is dreaming, being awake, being self-conscious or not, etc. These are not different numbers. This odd analog scale arises because Shannon information is counted in bits. But information in the sense of knowledge (science) is not counted in bits; there are different kinds of knowledge, they have different structure, relations between them etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subjective physics of a thermostat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let us not throw away Chalmers’ interesting experiment of thought just now. Let us ask, following Chalmers: what does it feel like to be a thermostat? We will examine it not with Shannon’s unhelpful notion of information but with what I called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;subjective physics&lt;/a&gt;”: the laws that govern sensory signals and their relations to actions, from the perspective of the subject. This will define my world from a functional viewpoint. Let’s say I am a conscious thermostat; a homunculus inside the thermostat. All I can observe is a binary signal. Then there is a binary action that I can make, which for an external observer corresponds to turning on the heat. What kind of world does that make to me? Let’s say I’m a scientist homunculus, what kind of laws about the world can I infer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m a conventional thermostat, then the action will be automatically triggered when the signal is in a given state (“cold”). After some time, the binary signal will switch and so will the action. So in fact there is an identity between signal and action, which means that all I really observe is just the one binary signal, switching on and off, probably with some kind of periodicity. This is the world I might experience, as a homunculus inside the thermostat (note that to experience the periodicity requires memory, which a normal thermostat doesn’t have). In a way, I’m a “locked-in” thermostat: I can make observations, but I cannot freely act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that I am not locked-in and have a little more free will, so I can decide whether to act (heat) or not. If I can, then my world is a little bit more interesting: my action can trigger a switch of the binary signal, after some latency (again requiring some memory), and then when I stop, the binary signal switches back, after a time that depends on how much time my previous action lasted. So here I have a world that is much more structured, with relatively complex laws which in a way defines the concept of “temperature” from the perspective of the thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if a thermostat were conscious, then we have a rough idea of the kind of world it might experience (although not how it feels like), and even in this elementary example, you can’t measure these experiences in bits - let alone the fact that a thermostat is not conscious anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>admin</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52488</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T13:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When examining the roles of conflicts of interest in academic publishing, most research focuses on transparency around the payments authors receive. But what about journal editors? According to a new Peer J preprint, two-thirds of editors at prominent journals received some type of industry payment over the last few years – which, at many journals, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A 30-minute lesson in the malleability of personality has long-term benefits for anxious, depressed teenagers</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32165</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T12:24:07+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-155427885.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32264&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32264&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This series aims to portrait tattooed people in their professional and private lives.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;alvarez&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2000,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/portrait-of-a-tattooed-person/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many effective psychological therapies to help teenagers with depression, anxiety or other mental health problems. Unfortunately, for various reasons, most teenagers never get access to a professional therapist. To overcome this problem, some researchers are exploring the potential of brief, “single-session” interventions that can be delivered cheaply and easily to many at-risk teenagers outside of a clinical context. In &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, Jessica Schleider and John Weisz at Harvard University &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;present extremely promising results&lt;/a&gt; from their trial of a 30-minute computer session teaching depressed and anxious teenagers that personality is malleable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32165&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible, the participating teenagers needed to have problematic anxiety and/or depression. Ninety-six teenagers took part, aged 12 to 15, mostly White American. Forty-eight of them were assigned to the 20-to-30-minute session about the malleability of personality. The others, who had the same baseline symptom levels, acted as controls and spent an equal amount of time in a computer-based session of “supportive therapy” learning about emotions and how it’s helpful to talk about them. The idea was this would match the experience of being enrolled in the personality change session in all ways except for the all-important content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personality session was self-administered on computer and taught the teenagers about neuroplasticity and the idea that behaviours arise from thoughts and feelings in their brains, and that brains are always changing. They heard from older youths saying they believe people can change, and from others saying how they’d used belief in our capacity for change (a “growth mindset”) to cope with problems like embarrassment or rejection. The teenagers learned strategies for applying these principles to themselves and they wrote notes to younger children about the malleability of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary message of the intervention, the researchers said, is that “personal attributes are malleable if we systematically – and with appropriate supports – act to change them. Essentially it reinforces beliefs in &lt;em&gt;behavioral&lt;/em&gt; control over the kinds of people we are can can become.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the teens completed a series of psychological measures before and immediately after whichever session they took part in, and then they took the same measures again three, six, and nine-months later. Their parents also completed some of the same measures about their child. To avoid their own expectations affecting the results, the researchers were kept unaware of which teens were in which condition until the end of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promising findings include that the teens in the personality change session showed more rapid declines in depression, and nine months later their depression scores had declined more than the control participants’ scores (33 per cent fewer of them now had clinically severe levels of depression, compared with 11 per cent fewer among the control group). These benefits were mirrored in parents’ ratings of their children’s depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results for anxiety weren’t as good, but still showed promise – the personality change intervention led to greater declines in symptoms at nine months based on parents’ reports, although not based on the teenagers’ self-reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hoped, compared with the controls, the teenagers in the personality change intervention reported a stronger increase in their belief that your personality is something you can change. Further clues as to how the personality change intervention helped the teenagers come from measures of their belief in their ability to deal with adversity by controlling their own behavior (e.g. whether they agreed with statements like “I can be popular with kids my age, if I really try”; “I can do well on tests if I try really hard”) and their own emotions (e.g. “I can usually find something good to like, even in a bad situation” or ““When I have a problem that I can’t change, I can do something to take my mind off it.”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the follow-up period, the teens in the personality change intervention showed larger increases in their sense of control over their own behavior, as compared with the control participants (there was no difference in their sense of control over their emotions). This makes sense given the personality intervention’s focus on behavioral control as a means to influence our personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleider and Weisz said their “mindset” intervention teaching that personality is malleable is “highly cost-effective and scalable”, meaning it could be delivered to all new pupils arriving at a secondary school, for example. They added “these are the first findings we know of suggesting that a 30-minute, self-administered program may help reduce depression, and to a lesser degree, anxiety, in high-symptom and high-risk youths.” They believe the intervention may have such strong and enduring effects because it focuses on “‘keystone beliefs’ of high developmental relevance to adolescents”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage is that for any teens who end up in therapy, the brief personality change session could help lay the groundwork in terms of motivation and helpful beliefs about personal control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the results are encouraging, larger trials are needed, the researchers noted, including with teenagers from more ethnically diverse and less affluent backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;A single-session growth mindset intervention for adolescent anxiety and depression: 9-month outcomes of a randomized trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Psych_Writer/status/818794319385690113&quot;&gt;currently writing a book about personality change&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32165&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Human study supports theory on why dengue can be worse the next time around</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The amount of dengue antibodies leftover in the blood may up the chances of a severe second dengue infection, a study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Q&amp;amp;A: German pharma start-up leader on the importance of knowledge in a fast-changing industry</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T09:24:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Till Erdmann, Managing Director Myelo Therapeutics, on the challenges for young businesses in healthcare and how to tackle them</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">How to increase your grant success rates with insights, discovery and decisions</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T08:37:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Elsevier’s VP of Academic and Government Strategic Alliances examines the challenges of research funding – and introduces a new solution</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Face it: Sheep are just like us when it comes to recognizing people</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:09:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Sheep trained to recognize celebrity faces demonstrate that the animals have face-recognition capabilities similar to humans and other primates.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">UK government appoints next chief scientific adviser</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/O3Ylql2RgSw/nature.2017.22956"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22956</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A former pharmaceutical boss will help navigate the UK's exit from the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22956&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22956&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/O3Ylql2RgSw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The catalogue that made metrics, and changed science</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6mV2dBaf2NE/551163a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551163a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As new ways emerge to assess research, Alex Csiszar recalls how the first one transformed the practice and place of science in society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 163 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551163a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551163a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6mV2dBaf2NE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alex Csiszar</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Four ethical priorities for neurotechnologies and AI</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/A5H-Jeo28uM/551159a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551159a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and brain–computer interfaces must respect and preserve people's privacy, identity, agency and equality, say Rafael Yuste, Sara Goering and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 159 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551159a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551159a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/A5H-Jeo28uM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rafael Yuste</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The bitter battle over the world’s most popular insecticides</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/y1H1Dfi1b0s/551156a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551156a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As regulators consider a ban on neonicotinoids, debate rages over the harm they cause to bees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 156 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551156a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551156a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/y1H1Dfi1b0s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Cressey</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dark-matter hunt fails to find the elusive particles</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Z0791HB-KBA/551153a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551153a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Physicists begin to embrace alternative explanations for the missing material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551153a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551153a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Z0791HB-KBA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Rohingya refugees, Bulgarian protests and a prize for negative results</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3nMPj_0gx2U/551146a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551146a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The week in science: 3–9 November 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 146 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551146a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551146a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3nMPj_0gx2U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Grant recipients can still give objective advice</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oNHGz7KGPgM/551142a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551142a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The US environment agency should not ban researchers it funds from its advisory boards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551142a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551142a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oNHGz7KGPgM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Too many academics study the same people</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/FQ9aHM9zyLg/551141b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141b</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers should recognize communities that feel over-researched and under-rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 141 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551141b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/FQ9aHM9zyLg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Skin regeneration with insights</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_xxO-kIw2-o/551141a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A feat in stem-cell therapy highlights what can be achieved when basic and clinical research combine to advance biological understanding and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 141 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551141a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551141a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_xxO-kIw2-o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Gene therapy: Transgenic stem cells replace skin</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/X-lqwYnUihg/nature24753"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24753</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The treatment of a patient affected by an incurable genetic skin disease demonstrates the efficacy, feasibility and safety of replacing almost the whole skin using genetically corrected stem cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24753&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24753&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/X-lqwYnUihg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariaceleste Aragona</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Astrocytic neuroligins control astrocyte morphogenesis and synaptogenesis</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WqIv855oAf8/nature24638"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24638</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Astrocytes are complex glial cells with numerous fine cellular processes that infiltrate the neuropil and interact with synapses. The mechanisms that control the establishment of astrocyte morphology are unknown, and it is unclear whether impairing astrocytic infiltration of the neuropil alters synaptic connectivity. Here we show that astrocyte morphogenesis in the mouse cortex depends on direct contact with neuronal processes and occurs in parallel with the growth and activity of synaptic circuits. The neuroligin family cell adhesion proteins NL1, NL2, and NL3, which are expressed by cortical astrocytes, control astrocyte morphogenesis through interactions with neuronal neurexins. Furthermore, in the absence of astrocytic NL2, the formation and function of cortical excitatory synapses are diminished, whereas inhibitory synaptic function is enhanced. Our findings highlight a previously undescribed mechanism of action for neuroligins and link astrocyte morphogenesis to synaptogenesis. Because neuroligin mutations have been implicated in various neurological disorders, these findings also point towards an astrocyte-based mechanism of neural pathology. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 192 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24638&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24638&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WqIv855oAf8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff A. Stogsdill</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Fully integrated silicon probes for high-density recording of neural activity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/fi-MLl9S27I/nature24636"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24636</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Sensory, motor and cognitive operations involve the coordinated action of large neuronal populations across multiple brain regions in both superficial and deep structures. Existing extracellular probes record neural activity with excellent spatial and temporal (sub-millisecond) resolution, but from only a few dozen neurons per shank. Optical Ca2+ imaging offers more coverage but lacks the temporal resolution needed to distinguish individual spikes reliably and does not measure local field potentials. Until now, no technology compatible with use in unrestrained animals has combined high spatiotemporal resolution with large volume coverage. Here we design, fabricate and test a new silicon probe known as Neuropixels to meet this need. Each probe has 384 recording channels that can programmably address 960 complementary metal–oxide–semiconductor (CMOS) processing-compatible low-impedance TiN sites that tile a single 10-mm long, 70 × 20-μm cross-section shank. The 6 × 9-mm probe base is fabricated with the shank on a single chip. Voltage signals are filtered, amplified, multiplexed and digitized on the base, allowing the direct transmission of noise-free digital data from the probe. The combination of dense recording sites and high channel count yielded well-isolated spiking activity from hundreds of neurons per probe implanted in mice and rats. Using two probes, more than 700 well-isolated single neurons were recorded simultaneously from five brain structures in an awake mouse. The fully integrated functionality and small size of Neuropixels probes allowed large populations of neurons from several brain structures to be recorded in freely moving animals. This combination of high-performance electrode technology and scalable chip fabrication methods opens a path towards recording of brain-wide neural activity during behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 232 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24636&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24636&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/fi-MLl9S27I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>James J. Jun</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ultra-selective looming detection from radial motion opponency</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/pma6qLrOVNY/nature24626"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24626</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Nervous systems combine lower-level sensory signals to detect higher-order stimulus features critical to survival, such as the visual looming motion created by an imminent collision or approaching predator. Looming-sensitive neurons have been identified in diverse animal species. Different large-scale visual features such as looming often share local cues, which means loom-detecting neurons face the challenge of rejecting confounding stimuli. Here we report the discovery of an ultra-selective looming detecting neuron, lobula plate/lobula columnar, type II (LPLC2) in Drosophila, and show how its selectivity is established by radial motion opponency. In the fly visual system, directionally selective small-field neurons called T4 and T5 form a spatial map in the lobula plate, where they each terminate in one of four retinotopic layers, such that each layer responds to motion in a different cardinal direction. Single-cell anatomical analysis reveals that each arm of the LPLC2 cross-shaped primary dendrites ramifies in one of these layers and extends along that layer’s preferred motion direction. In vivo calcium imaging demonstrates that, as their shape predicts, individual LPLC2 neurons respond strongly to outward motion emanating from the centre of the neuron’s receptive field. Each dendritic arm also receives local inhibitory inputs directionally selective for inward motion opposing the excitation. This radial motion opponency generates a balance of excitation and inhibition that makes LPLC2 non-responsive to related patterns of motion such as contraction, wide-field rotation or luminance change. As a population, LPLC2 neurons densely cover visual space and terminate onto the giant fibre descending neurons, which drive the jump muscle motor neuron to trigger an escape take off. Our findings provide a mechanistic description of the selective feature detection that flies use to discern and escape looming threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 237 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24626&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24626&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/pma6qLrOVNY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nathan C. Klapoetke</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure and assembly of the Ebola virus nucleocapsid</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/f0xxw1BINHI/nature24490"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24490</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ebola and Marburg viruses are filoviruses: filamentous, enveloped viruses that cause haemorrhagic fever. Filoviruses are within the order Mononegavirales, which also includes rabies virus, measles virus, and respiratory syncytial virus. Mononegaviruses have non-segmented, single-stranded negative-sense RNA genomes that are encapsidated by nucleoprotein and other viral proteins to form a helical nucleocapsid. The nucleocapsid acts as a scaffold for virus assembly and as a template for genome transcription and replication. Insights into nucleoprotein–nucleoprotein interactions have been derived from structural studies of oligomerized, RNA-encapsidating nucleoprotein, and cryo-electron microscopy of nucleocapsid or nucleocapsid-like structures. There have been no high-resolution reconstructions of complete mononegavirus nucleocapsids. Here we apply cryo-electron tomography and subtomogram averaging to determine the structure of Ebola virus nucleocapsid within intact viruses and recombinant nucleocapsid-like assemblies. These structures reveal the identity and arrangement of the nucleocapsid components, and suggest that the formation of an extended α-helix from the disordered carboxy-terminal region of nucleoprotein-core links nucleoprotein oligomerization, nucleocapsid condensation, RNA encapsidation, and accessory protein recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24490&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24490&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/f0xxw1BINHI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>William Wan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A single-cell survey of the small intestinal epithelium</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MVaQv3dg3tI/nature24489"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24489</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Intestinal epithelial cells absorb nutrients, respond to microbes, function as a barrier and help to coordinate immune responses. Here we report profiling of 53,193 individual epithelial cells from the small intestine and organoids of mice, which enabled the identification and characterization of previously unknown subtypes of intestinal epithelial cell and their gene signatures. We found unexpected diversity in hormone-secreting enteroendocrine cells and constructed the taxonomy of newly identified subtypes, and distinguished between two subtypes of tuft cell, one of which expresses the epithelial cytokine Tslp and the pan-immune marker CD45, which was not previously associated with non-haematopoietic cells. We also characterized the ways in which cell-intrinsic states and the proportions of different cell types respond to bacterial and helminth infections: Salmonella infection caused an increase in the abundance of Paneth cells and enterocytes, and broad activation of an antimicrobial program; Heligmosomoides polygyrus caused an increase in the abundance of goblet and tuft cells. Our survey highlights previously unidentified markers and programs, associates sensory molecules with cell types, and uncovers principles of gut homeostasis and response to pathogens. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24489&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24489&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MVaQv3dg3tI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Adam L. Haber</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Regeneration of the entire human epidermis using transgenic stem cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/SRXKhF2JIAw/nature24487"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24487</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Junctional epidermolysis bullosa (JEB) is a severe and often lethal genetic disease caused by mutations in genes encoding the basement membrane component laminin-332. Surviving patients with JEB develop chronic wounds to the skin and mucosa, which impair their quality of life and lead to skin cancer. Here we show that autologous transgenic keratinocyte cultures regenerated an entire, fully functional epidermis on a seven-year-old child suffering from a devastating, life-threatening form of JEB. The proviral integration pattern was maintained in vivo and epidermal renewal did not cause any clonal selection. Clonal tracing showed that the human epidermis is sustained not by equipotent progenitors, but by a limited number of long-lived stem cells, detected as holoclones, that can extensively self-renew in vitro and in vivo and produce progenitors that replenish terminally differentiated keratinocytes. This study provides a blueprint that can be applied to other stem cell-mediated combined ex vivo cell and gene therapies. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24487&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24487&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/SRXKhF2JIAw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tobias Hirsch</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A ubiquitin-dependent signalling axis specific for ALKBH-mediated DNA dealkylation repair</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/_5xuJLZMxk8/nature24484"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24484</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 DNA repair is essential to prevent the cytotoxic or mutagenic effects of various types of DNA lesions, which are sensed by distinct pathways to recruit repair factors specific to the damage type. Although biochemical mechanisms for repairing several forms of genomic insults are well understood, the upstream signalling pathways that trigger repair are established for only certain types of damage, such as double-stranded breaks and interstrand crosslinks. Understanding the upstream signalling events that mediate recognition and repair of DNA alkylation damage is particularly important, since alkylation chemotherapy is one of the most widely used systemic modalities for cancer treatment and because environmental chemicals may trigger DNA alkylation. Here we demonstrate that human cells have a previously unrecognized signalling mechanism for sensing damage induced by alkylation. We find that the alkylation repair complex ASCC (activating signal cointegrator complex) relocalizes to distinct nuclear foci specifically upon exposure of cells to alkylating agents. These foci associate with alkylated nucleotides, and coincide spatially with elongating RNA polymerase II and splicing components. Proper recruitment of the repair complex requires recognition of K63-linked polyubiquitin by the CUE (coupling of ubiquitin conjugation to ER degradation) domain of the subunit ASCC2. Loss of this subunit impedes alkylation adduct repair kinetics and increases sensitivity to alkylating agents, but not other forms of DNA damage. We identify RING finger protein 113A (RNF113A) as the E3 ligase responsible for upstream ubiquitin signalling in the ASCC pathway. Cells from patients with X-linked trichothiodystrophy, which harbour a mutation in RNF113A, are defective in ASCC foci formation and are hypersensitive to alkylating agents. Together, our work reveals a previously unrecognized ubiquitin-dependent pathway induced specifically to repair alkylation damage, shedding light on the molecular mechanism of X-linked trichothiodystrophy. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24484&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/_5xuJLZMxk8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Joshua R. Brickner</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Parallel palaeogenomic transects reveal complex genetic history of early European farmers</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tXosyiVuYOk/nature24476"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24476</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ancient DNA studies have established that Neolithic European populations were descended from Anatolian migrants who received a limited amount of admixture from resident hunter-gatherers. Many open questions remain, however, about the spatial and temporal dynamics of population interactions and admixture during the Neolithic period. Here we investigate the population dynamics of Neolithization across Europe using a high-resolution genome-wide ancient DNA dataset with a total of 180 samples, of which 130 are newly reported here, from the Neolithic and Chalcolithic periods of Hungary (6000–2900 bc, n = 100), Germany (5500–3000 bc, n = 42) and Spain (5500–2200 bc, n = 38). We find that genetic diversity was shaped predominantly by local processes, with varied sources and proportions of hunter-gatherer ancestry among the three regions and through time. Admixture between groups with different ancestry profiles was pervasive and resulted in observable population transformation across almost all cultural transitions. Our results shed new light on the ways in which gene flow reshaped European populations throughout the Neolithic period and demonstrate the potential of time-series-based sampling and modelling approaches to elucidate multiple dimensions of historical population interactions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24476&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24476&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tXosyiVuYOk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mark Lipson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A neoantigen fitness model predicts tumour response to checkpoint blockade immunotherapy</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gwCTz9AgNOw/nature24473"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24473</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Checkpoint blockade immunotherapies enable the host immune system to recognize and destroy tumour cells. Their clinical activity has been correlated with activated T-cell recognition of neoantigens, which are tumour-specific, mutated peptides presented on the surface of cancer cells. Here we present a fitness model for tumours based on immune interactions of neoantigens that predicts response to immunotherapy. Two main factors determine neoantigen fitness: the likelihood of neoantigen presentation by the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) and subsequent recognition by T cells. We estimate these components using the relative MHC binding affinity of each neoantigen to its wild type and a nonlinear dependence on sequence similarity of neoantigens to known antigens. To describe the evolution of a heterogeneous tumour, we evaluate its fitness as a weighted effect of dominant neoantigens in the subclones of the tumour. Our model predicts survival in anti-CTLA-4-treated patients with melanoma and anti-PD-1-treated patients with lung cancer. Importantly, low-fitness neoantigens identified by our method may be leveraged for developing novel immunotherapies. By using an immune fitness model to study immunotherapy, we reveal broad similarities between the evolution of tumours and rapidly evolving pathogens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24473&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24473&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gwCTz9AgNOw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Marta Łuksza</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genetic variation in glia–neuron signalling modulates ageing rate</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tUF9CiN1FwI/nature24463"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24463</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The rate of behavioural decline in the ageing population is remarkably variable among individuals. Despite the considerable interest in studying natural variation in ageing rate to identify factors that control healthy ageing, no such factor has yet been found. Here we report a genetic basis for variation in ageing rates in Caenorhabditis elegans. We find that C. elegans isolates show diverse lifespan and age-related declines in virility, pharyngeal pumping, and locomotion. DNA polymorphisms in a novel peptide-coding gene, named regulatory-gene-for-behavioural-ageing-1 (rgba-1), and the neuropeptide receptor gene npr-28 influence the rate of age-related decline of worm mating behaviour; these two genes might have been subjected to recent selective sweeps. Glia-derived RGBA-1 activates NPR-28 signalling, which acts in serotonergic and dopaminergic neurons to accelerate behavioural deterioration. This signalling involves the SIR-2.1-dependent activation of the mitochondrial unfolded protein response, a pathway that modulates ageing. Thus, natural variation in neuropeptide-mediated glia–neuron signalling modulates the rate of ageing in C. elegans. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 198 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24463&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24463&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tUF9CiN1FwI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jiang-An Yin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Identification of unique neoantigen qualities in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/HW2E_H4heFY/nature24462"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24462</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma is a lethal cancer with fewer than 7% of patients surviving past 5 years. T-cell immunity has been linked to the exceptional outcome of the few long-term survivors, yet the relevant antigens remain unknown. Here we use genetic, immunohistochemical and transcriptional immunoprofiling, computational biophysics, and functional assays to identify T-cell antigens in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer. Using whole-exome sequencing and in silico neoantigen prediction, we found that tumours with both the highest neoantigen number and the most abundant CD8+ T-cell infiltrates, but neither alone, stratified patients with the longest survival. Investigating the specific neoantigen qualities promoting T-cell activation in long-term survivors, we discovered that these individuals were enriched in neoantigen qualities defined by a fitness model, and neoantigens in the tumour antigen MUC16 (also known as CA125). A neoantigen quality fitness model conferring greater immunogenicity to neoantigens with differential presentation and homology to infectious disease-derived peptides identified long-term survivors in two independent datasets, whereas a neoantigen quantity model ascribing greater immunogenicity to increasing neoantigen number alone did not. We detected intratumoural and lasting circulating T-cell reactivity to both high-quality and MUC16 neoantigens in long-term survivors of pancreatic cancer, including clones with specificity to both high-quality neoantigens and predicted cross-reactive microbial epitopes, consistent with neoantigen molecular mimicry. Notably, we observed selective loss of high-quality and MUC16 neoantigenic clones on metastatic progression, suggesting neoantigen immunoediting. Our results identify neoantigens with unique qualities as T-cell targets in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. More broadly, we identify neoantigen quality as a biomarker for immunogenic tumours that may guide the application of immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24462&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24462&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/HW2E_H4heFY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Vinod P. Balachandran</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inflammation-induced IgA+ cells dismantle anti-liver cancer immunity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/6sK2Bc0IpX0/nature24302"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24302</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The role of adaptive immunity in early cancer development is controversial. Here we show that chronic inflammation and fibrosis in humans and mice with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease is accompanied by accumulation of liver-resident immunoglobulin-A-producing (IgA+) cells. These cells also express programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) and interleukin-10, and directly suppress liver cytotoxic CD8+ T lymphocytes, which prevent emergence of hepatocellular carcinoma and express a limited repertoire of T-cell receptors against tumour-associated antigens. Whereas CD8+ T-cell ablation accelerates hepatocellular carcinoma, genetic or pharmacological interference with IgA+ cell generation attenuates liver carcinogenesis and induces cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-mediated regression of established hepatocellular carcinoma. These findings establish the importance of inflammation-induced suppression of cytotoxic CD8+ T-lymphocyte activation as a tumour-promoting mechanism. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24302&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24302&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/6sK2Bc0IpX0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shabnam Shalapour</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dynamics of P-type ATPase transport revealed by single-molecule FRET</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/rHJ4SHZjOWY/nature24296"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24296</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Phosphorylation-type (P-type) ATPases are ubiquitous primary transporters that pump cations across cell membranes through the formation and breakdown of a phosphoenzyme intermediate. Structural investigations suggest that the transport mechanism is defined by conformational changes in the cytoplasmic domains of the protein that are allosterically coupled to transmembrane helices so as to expose ion binding sites to alternate sides of the membrane. Here, we have used single-molecule fluorescence resonance energy transfer to directly observe conformational changes associated with the functional transitions in the Listeria monocytogenes Ca2+-ATPase (LMCA1), an orthologue of eukaryotic Ca2+-ATPases. We identify key intermediates with no known crystal structures and show that Ca2+ efflux by LMCA1 is rate-limited by phosphoenzyme formation. The transport process involves reversible steps and an irreversible step that follows release of ADP and extracellular release of Ca2+. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24296&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/rHJ4SHZjOWY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mateusz Dyla</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BCAT1 restricts αKG levels in AML stem cells leading to IDHmut-like DNA hypermethylation</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/GDDi0cdk-XQ/nature24294"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24294</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The branched-chain amino acid (BCAA) pathway and high levels of BCAA transaminase 1 (BCAT1) have recently been associated with aggressiveness in several cancer entities. However, the mechanistic role of BCAT1 in this process remains largely uncertain. Here, by performing high-resolution proteomic analysis of human acute myeloid leukaemia (AML) stem-cell and non-stem-cell populations, we find the BCAA pathway enriched and BCAT1 protein and transcripts overexpressed in leukaemia stem cells. We show that BCAT1, which transfers α-amino groups from BCAAs to α-ketoglutarate (αKG), is a critical regulator of intracellular αKG homeostasis. Further to its role in the tricarboxylic acid cycle, αKG is an essential cofactor for αKG-dependent dioxygenases such as Egl-9 family hypoxia inducible factor 1 (EGLN1) and the ten-eleven translocation (TET) family of DNA demethylases. Knockdown of BCAT1 in leukaemia cells caused accumulation of αKG, leading to EGLN1-mediated HIF1α protein degradation. This resulted in a growth and survival defect and abrogated leukaemia-initiating potential. By contrast, overexpression of BCAT1 in leukaemia cells decreased intracellular αKG levels and caused DNA hypermethylation through altered TET activity. AML with high levels of BCAT1 (BCAT1high) displayed a DNA hypermethylation phenotype similar to cases carrying a mutant isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDHmut), in which TET2 is inhibited by the oncometabolite 2-hydroxyglutarate. High levels of BCAT1 strongly correlate with shorter overall survival in IDHWTTET2WT, but not IDHmut or TET2mut AML. Gene sets characteristic for IDHmut AML were enriched in samples from patients with an IDHWTTET2WTBCAT1high status. BCAT1high AML showed robust enrichment for leukaemia stem-cell signatures, and paired sample analysis showed a significant increase in BCAT1 levels upon disease relapse. In summary, by limiting intracellular αKG, BCAT1 links BCAA catabolism to HIF1α stability and regulation of the epigenomic landscape, mimicking the effects of IDH mutations. Our results suggest the BCAA–BCAT1–αKG pathway as a therapeutic target to compromise leukaemia stem-cell function in patients with IDHWTTET2WT AML.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24294&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24294&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/GDDi0cdk-XQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Simon Raffel</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Neurobiology: A genetic cause of age-related decline</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/2N7m_3huZ10/551179a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551179a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Genetic variation in a neuropeptide signalling pathway regulates age-related declines in health in nematode worms. This discovery points to a mechanism that influences individual differences in ageing.  See Article    p.198&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 179 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551179a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551179a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/2N7m_3huZ10&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Patrick T. McGrath</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Brain technology: Neurons recorded en masse</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tRvyn1rkY5g/551172a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551172a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;A silicon probe that is inserted into the mouse brain can precisely measure the activity of about 200 individual neurons simultaneously. This tool should improve our ability to study functional neuronal circuitry.  See Letter    p.232&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 172 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551172a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551172a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tRvyn1rkY5g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edward M. Callaway</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Books in brief</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ldr6NzoCcQg/551167a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551167a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 167 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551167a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551167a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ldr6NzoCcQg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew Robinson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Polar exploration: The forgotten journey</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/f51Jjfob5J8/551166a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551166a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Huw Lewis-Jones revisits a pioneering, ill-fated expedition to map the Arctic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 166 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551166a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551166a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/f51Jjfob5J8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Huw Lewis-Jones</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">NASA wants your help naming New Horizons’ next destination</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/nasa-wants-your-help-naming-new-horizons-next-destination"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/nasa-wants-your-help-naming-new-horizons-next-destination</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T19:00:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 NASA’s New Horizons mission team is asking the public to vote on a nickname for the spacecraft’s next destination.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mike Denison</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Let most babies eat food containing peanuts. Really.</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-peanuts-allergy-guidelines"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-peanuts-allergy-guidelines</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Pediatricians are not yet peanut-savvy when it comes to convincing parents to feed babies food containing peanuts, a new survey suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Opioid Epidemic Resource Center</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/opioid-epidemic-resource-center"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/opioid-epidemic-resource-center</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T16:46:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Free access to research, data, analyses and other resources — updated 8 November 2017</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">17 Johns Hopkins researchers resign in protest from ed board at Nature journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/17-johns-hopkins-researchers-resign-protest-ed-board-nature-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52494</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T16:02:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;More than a dozen members of the editorial board at Scientific Reports have resigned after the journal decided not to retract a 2016 paper that a researcher claims plagiarized his work. As of this morning, 19 people — mostly researchers based at Johns Hopkins — had stepped down from the board, according to Hopkins researcher […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/17-johns-hopkins-researchers-resign-protest-ed-board-nature-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;17 Johns Hopkins researchers resign in protest from ed board at Nature journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researchers ask to retract cancer paper five days after it’s flagged by journal</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/researchers-ask-retract-cancer-paper-five-days-flagged-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52480</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T13:00:28+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers from the University of Kansas asked to retract their paper only days after the journal issued an expression of concern related to some of the images. The retraction notice marks the close of an episode that started in June, but it doesn’t provide much closure: Figures in the paper apparently do not match primary […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/07/researchers-ask-retract-cancer-paper-five-days-flagged-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researchers ask to retract cancer paper five days after it’s flagged by journal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Contrary to stereotypes, study of hedge fund managers finds psychopaths make poor investors</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/07/contrary-to-stereotypes-study-of-hedge-fund-managers-finds-psychopaths-make-poor-investors/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32141</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T10:18:17+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-457803795.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32157&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32157&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cindy Ord&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NEW YORK, NY - DECEMBER 18:  A view of atmosphere at the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences Official Academy Members screening of 'The Wolf Of Wall Street' at the Academy Theater at Lighthouse International on December 18, 2013 in New York City.  (Photo by Cindy Ord\/Getty Images for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1387405599&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2013 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;40&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Academy Of Motion Picture Arts And Sciences Hosts An Official Academy Members Screening Of The Wolf Of Wall Street&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;The Academy Of Motion Picture Arts And Sciences Hosts An Official Academy Members Screening Of The Wolf Of Wall Street&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,2147&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/07/contrary-to-stereotypes-study-of-hedge-fund-managers-finds-psychopaths-make-poor-investors/the-academy-of-motion-picture-arts-and-sciences-hosts-an-official-academy-members-screening-of-the-wolf-of-wall-street/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-457803795.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a psychopath who’s good with numbers, you could make the perfect hedge fund manager. Your lack of empathy will allow you to capitalise blithely on the financial losses of others, while your ability to stomach high-risk, but potentially high-return, options will send your fund value soaring…. Well, that’s the story that’s been painted by popular media, folk wisdom and Wall Street insiders alike. The problem, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0146167217733080&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/i&gt;, is that hedge fund managers with psychopathic tendencies actually make &lt;i&gt;less&lt;/i&gt; money for their clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32141&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dacher Keltner at the University of California, Berkeley, and his colleagues analysed videos of semi-structured interviews with 101 hedge fund managers, whose firms each managed between US$40 million and US$1 trillion in assets. This money generally came from institutional investors, such as insurance companies and public and private pension funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The videos had been recorded between 2005 and 2015 by an investment advisory firm, to act as a marketing tool, and to give existing clients market updates. They followed a set format with the interviewer asking questions like, “What is your outlook on opportunities in the current market?” and “What is your philosophy on risk management?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers were looking for non-verbal evidence in the hedge fund managers’ replies of the so-called Dark Triad personality traits of narcissism, Machiavellianism and psychopathy. Erratic emotional expression, for example, was taken as a signal of psychopathy. A dominant positioning of the jaw and posture were among the signals of Machiavellianism. Flashy clothes, coy looks, and excessive use of “I” rather than “We”, were among the indicators of narcissism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keltner and his colleagues also analysed the financial performance of each manager’s so-called “flagship fund” – usually the largest fund offered by the company, and the one considered to most reflect the individual manager’s investment process – during the ten-year period that the videos were recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machiavellianism had no bearing on performance. Narcissistic hedge fund managers had to make riskier decisions to make the same returns over a given period compared with a less narcissistic manager; as far as an investor is concerned, this would manifest as greater volatility in the value of their investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it came to psychopathic tendencies, however, the results were more clear cut. For managers who displayed psychopathic tendencies at a level of one standard deviation above the mean, an investment of US$1 million earned US$1,161,694 (15 per cent) &lt;i&gt;less&lt;/i&gt; over the course of ten years, on average, compared with a manager who ranked average for psychopathy. More extreme psychopathy led to even weaker returns. For example, the same US$1 million investment by a manager who rated two standard deviations above the mean for psychopathy earned 30 per cent less, on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that the Dark Triad traits have been investigated in the context of hedge fund performance, and unfortunately the study doesn’t reveal the reasons for the counterintuitive results. It may be that, while the individual managers led the hedge funds, innovative ideas from team members are important for effective financial investing – and the more bullying style of managers with more psychopathic traits could have stifled this kind of creative, collaborative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the findings suggest that investors would be wise to avoid managers with psychopathic and narcissistic tendencies, there are some limitations to be mindful of. The financial data were from a period that included the Global Financial Crisis and the researchers can’t rule out the possibility that Dark Triad traits may be advantageous in other, less financially disastrous, contexts. Also the non-verbal coding procedure – although it’s a valid measure according to earlier research – provides only a rather coarse indication of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that the results tally with another &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797615611922&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; (on which Dacher Keltner was also a co-author), that found US senators with psychopathic tendencies received less support for bills they had proposed. “These two studies, clear examples of real-world performance, cast doubts upon the efficacy of a Dark Triad-based approach to wielding power,” Keltner and his team concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0146167217733080&quot;&gt;Hedge Fund Managers With Psychopathic Tendencies Make for Worse Investors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Photo by Cindy Ord/Getty Images for Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32141/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32141/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32141&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pirate paper website Sci-Hub dealt another blow by US courts</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yvjU6ZDjMjM/nature.2017.22971"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22971</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;American Chemical Society wins lawsuit against the site, and could seek to block access to the portal in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22971&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22971&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yvjU6ZDjMjM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Quirin Schiermeier</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Indian scientists urged to speak out about pseudoscience</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/r8q67TtQt1g/nature.2017.22957"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22957</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Cancelled astrology workshop prompts calls for researchers to be vigilant about stamping out unscientific beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22957&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22957&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/r8q67TtQt1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>T.V  Padma</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Genetically modified apple reaches US stores, but will consumers bite?</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/OXIRt8W83hM/551149a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551149a</id>
		<updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Success for the ‘Arctic apple’ could herald a new wave of lab-grown foods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 149 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551149a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551149a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/OXIRt8W83hM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Maxmen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Predicting Suicide: Return of a Scandal (Part 1)</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9228"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9228</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T20:19:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 I recently decided to revisit a 2014 case that regular readers might remember.



Back in 2014, I posted about a terrible piece of statistical 'spin' that somehow made it into the peer-reviewed Journal of Psychiatric Research. The offending authors, led by Swedish psychiatrist Lars H. Thorell, had run a study to determine whether an electrodermal hyporeactivity test was able to predict suicide and suicidal behaviour in depressed inpatients.



Now, the standard way to evaluate the perfor</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Crocs take a bite out of claims of ancient stone-tool use</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crocs-take-bite-out-claims-ancient-stone-tool-use"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crocs-take-bite-out-claims-ancient-stone-tool-use</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T20:16:09+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Reptiles with big bites complicate claims of Stone Age butchery.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">PLOS Channels Provide Opportunity for Discovery, Exploration and Contextual Insights</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/-tKIbmRxVKQ/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7839</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:31:11+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/11/flag_channels_opt2-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month, the new &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; joined existing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veterans Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Source Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Channels in providing distinct and cohesive scholarly homes for research communities. These innovative forums increase the visibility of curated, quality research and reliable news and commentary, bridging a gap in relevance that contributes to public misunderstanding of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Channels Program launched with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veterans Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (VDRR), and as Veterans Day in the US approaches it’s an opportunity to take a moment to relay the channels origin story, highlight the latest content and re-introduce the editors behind this program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“It is imperative that scientists and consumers explore novel and innovative strategies to share research findings. Towards this end, as an editor of the PLOS Channel for Veterans Disability and Rehabilitation Research, I look forward to highlighting research aimed at helping Veterans with disability and/or chronic illness increase function and participation in daily life.”—Lisa Brenner, VDRR Channel Editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those intimately involved with the generation, use or reuse of research, channels provide a central information source for the latest developments, whether published in PLOS journals or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Beyond Traditional Journal and Editorial Boundaries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As global forums for research, news and discussion, all PLOS Channels deliver a similar contemporary layout for easy navigation and reading, developed with feedback from multiple audiences in mind: basic and clinical scientists, policymakers, science journalists, educators, students and patients. The Featured Research section pulls from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0179912&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and other &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jcm.asm.org/content/55/10/3057&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; article &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openhardware.metajnl.com/articles/10.5334/joh.4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A Related Content section contains news, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dspo.mil/Conference/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;occasional events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and journal commentary that speak &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/indias-ambitious-new-plan-to-conquer-tb-needs-cash-and-commitment-84821&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;directly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and with integrity to the channel topic. Although not peer reviewed, web articles and commentary in the Related Content section are selected by channel editors for the reliability of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/13/health/tuberculosis-treatment-drugs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, relevance to the topic and when possible, to provide broad perspective on global issues from local journalists. PLOS hopes the mix of quality peer-reviewed research and exploratory journalistic content will help bridge current knowledge and communication gaps between scientists and the lay public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel editors, selected either from existing PLOS Editorial Board members or recruited together with the channel focus, are an integral component of any given channel. Their expertise and ability to bring in supplementary material through commentary, blogs, news and more helps research communities and the public stay up to date with the latest advances, research trends and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/08/23/world/middleeast/yemen-cholera-humanitarian-crisis.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;societal impact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of work in the field of focus. To highlight their foundational work and dedication to this innovative effort in science communication, these editors are profiled at the bottom of the respective channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Stories of Channel Origins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels originate either from community demand or engaged editors or partners. VDRR provides a new home for the community formerly served by the Journal of Rehabilitation Research &amp;amp; Development (JRRD), no longer published by the US Department of Veterans Affairs. VDRR offers international researchers and practitioners a dedicated online space to share and read state-of-the-art research, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=2914&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and resources to assist Veterans with chronic illness and disabilities worldwide. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/the-veteran-disability-rehabilitation-research-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the four editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Channels and Collections blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; exemplify the academic strength, community knowledge and dedication to science and medicine this position provides for each channel. The channel was proposed by Dr. Soumya Swaminathan during her tenure as Secretary, Department of Health Research, Ministry of Health &amp;amp; Family Welfare, Government of India, and Director General of the Indian Council of Medical Research. In October, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehindu.com/news/national/icmr-chief-soumya-swaminathan-appointed-who-deputy-director-general/article19792489.ece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Swaminathan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was appointed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/dg/leadership-team/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Deputy Director-General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the World Health Organization in Geneva, the second-highest position at the health agency. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/plos-tuberculosis-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet both TB Channel editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born as the PLOS Open Source Toolkit: Hardware Collection, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Source Toolkit Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; builds on the success of the Collection and now includes peer-reviewed and web articles addressing software and its &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appropedia.org/Open-source_mobile_water_quality_testing_platform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The dedication of this community to all aspects of open source in advancing science and medicine was a determining factor in transitioning this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to a PLOS Channel. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/the-open-source-toolkit-meet-the-channel-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the two editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recently launched Cholera Channel was proposed by Dr. Andrew Azman, Deputy Editor of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; he is joined as a channel editor by international experts in global health and infectious disease. Those engaged in the fight against cholera include academics, healthcare workers, policymakers, patients and civil society—all sharing a vision that collective action can stop cholera transmission and end cholera deaths through strengthened international collaboration and improved coordination. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2017/10/12/plos-cholera-channel-meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meet the four editors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Speaking of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Supporting this community, until now with no specialist journal or centralized publication venue for their work, is key to PLOS Channels’ mission to serve as resources for research communities.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Current Editor’s Picks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Channel showcases an Editor’s Pick, updated regularly, to bring the latest research front and center to readers. On the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VDRR Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the latest Editor’s Pick covers a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185613&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study for early screening of Parkinson’s disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; using voicing tasks and text-dependent speech options, published in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focus on research that demonstrates an &lt;em&gt;in vitro &lt;/em&gt;diagnostic test commonly used to accurately detect &lt;em&gt;Mycobacterium tuberculosis&lt;/em&gt; complex and rifampin resistance in high-incidence TB settings &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0186139&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;performs comparably&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in low TB-incidence settings. Editors of the Open Source Toolkit Channel chose to feature a &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt; Community Page describing a tool for ethomics, the high-throughput approach to behavioral studies. “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.2003026&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ethoscopes: An open platform for high-throughput ethomics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” originated as a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/08/05/113647.article-info&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprint on bioRxiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and describes open source software and hardware solutions for monitoring animal behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; highlights “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0183100&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Identification of burden hotspots and risk factors for cholera in India: An observational study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” describing disease hotspots and risk factors for transmission. Using district-level data from the Integrated Disease Surveillance Program, the authors offer their open research results to policymakers for development of a cholera prevention and control roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From epidemiological studies using existing census data to translational research and innovations for behavioral studies of experimental model organisms, these diverse choices highlight channel editors’ broad perspective in curating content of interest for their scholarly communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Focus on Cholera: PLOS’ Newest Channel&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While universal access to safe water and appropriate sanitation is the key to cholera prevention, global progress towards these goals has been slow. The disease remains a global public health threat, with ongoing risk factors that include poor sanitation, lack of enough clean drinking water and poverty. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cholera Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; features articles on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185041&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;applied&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006838&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;basic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;research related to the global fight against this disease and spans a range of topics with application to cholera prevention and control, including computational studies exploring the dynamics and spread of cholera; epidemiologic studies and translational science. Also covered is applied field research on the efficacy, effectiveness and impact of cholera control programs such as water and sanitation interventions and oral cholera vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS aspires to put &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/04/where-next-for-plos-working-together-to-make-waves-in-scientific-communication/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;researchers back at the center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of science communication, working in the best interests of all stakeholders—for the benefit of science and the public. Innovations such as the Channels Program, with collaboration from like-minded organizations, push the boundaries of scientific publishing beyond traditional journal, publisher and editorial constraints. Additional channels are currently in planning; bookmark &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://channels.plos.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or your Channel of interest and check back every two weeks for the latest research, news and developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/-tKIbmRxVKQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Senior NOAA appointee calls for retraction of paper on illegal fishing</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/senior-noaa-appointee-calls-retraction-paper-illegal-fishing/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52472</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:00:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A top US official at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who was recently appointed by President Donald Trump, has called for the retraction of a paper that suggests the country exports a significant amount of illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing. The paper, published July 6 in Marine Policy, estimated that in 2015 approximately one-fifth […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/senior-noaa-appointee-calls-retraction-paper-illegal-fishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Senior NOAA appointee calls for retraction of paper on illegal fishing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A sandy core may have kept Enceladus’ ocean warm</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enceladus-core-water-ocean-saturn"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enceladus-core-water-ocean-saturn</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Friction in Enceladus’ porous core could help heat its ocean enough to keep it liquid for billions of years.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Are early interventions effective?</title>
		<link href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/06/are-early-interventions-effective/"/>
		<id>http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=552</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T14:55:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Early years interventions can seem a particularly powerful way to forestall developmental difficulties. The wide-ranging evidence that early cognitive and behavioural difficulties can predict lifelong outcomes&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn1&quot; name=&quot;_ednref1&quot;&gt;[i]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn2&quot; name=&quot;_ednref2&quot;&gt;[ii]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes it seem obvious that if a child is struggling, intervening earlier is better. This has led to considerable interest in intervening within the first few years of a child’s life, and the temptation to seek out earlier indicators of children’s cognitive development and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;However, there are several challenges with choosing effective early interventions. First, reliably identifying which children will require support is a substantial challenge. This is particularly evident in the case of language development. Children’s language is a rich area for research on early intervention, for several reasons: it provides a window onto learning at school entry, and weak language at school entry is a risk factor for poor educational, social and emotional outcomes in subsequent years. There is also a clear socio-economic gradient in children’s language abilities, in which children from lower socio-economic backgrounds tend to have weaker language skills than their peers before they start school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;blog_image2&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-587 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;587&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;blog_image2&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195?w=324&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;324,251&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/06/are-early-interventions-effective/blog_image2/&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/blog_image21-e1509980544954.jpg?w=252&amp;amp;h=195&quot; width=&quot;252&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(But is the story really so simple?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Despite this, children’s language abilities are highly variable and volatile before they are 4-5 years old, which makes the early identification of children who may be in need of intervention non-trivial. This is demonstrated by several studies showing that whilst children’s early vocabulary around 2 years of age &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; predict their later vocabulary and reading skills at school entry, this predictive power is very small. Only about 10-20%&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn3&quot; name=&quot;_ednref3&quot;&gt;[iii]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn4&quot; name=&quot;_ednref4&quot;&gt;[iv]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of the variation in children’s abilities at school is typically predicted by their early language skills, which indicates that there are multiple other factors that shape children’s outcomes. This also suggests that finding a sufficiently sensitive marker of early difficulties is challenging because of how much a child’s abilities can shift and develop over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;This relates to the second challenge: early interventions can struggle to have sustained impacts unless intervention is ongoing. A good example of this comes from a recent study by McGillion and colleagues (2017). The researchers were interested in whether a caregiver intervention to promote talking with their 11-month old child would lead to changes in both parenting approach and children’s language development. Caregivers from a range of socio-economic backgrounds were randomly assigned to one of two conditions: watching a short video about talking with their child, or a control video about dental hygiene. One month later the caregivers in the language video condition talked more with their children than those in the control video condition. This fed into vocabulary improvement in the low socio-economic group: children in the intervention condition had higher vocabularies at 15 and 18 months compared to children in the control condition. However, at 24 months these benefits had disappeared, and there was no effect of the intervention on children’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;These findings demonstrate several important points about early interventions. Interventions &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; have a positive impact: in this case a brief, low-intensity video intervention was able to positively change caregiver behaviour, and this may have helped gains in children’s vocabulary a few months later. However, these effects were not sustained over time: they had faded by the time children were 2 years old. This shows how critical longer-term follow-ups are in intervention studies to understand whether benefits are long lasting. Moreover, this result reminds us that without ongoing support it is difficult for early gains in one area of cognition to offset other challenges children might face. The promise of early interventions means there can be an assumption that they will permanently shift a child’s trajectory. In reality this is often not the case, and initial gains may often require ongoing support to have real long-term effects for children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;It is important to therefore strike a balance between the promises and limitations of early interventions. Whilst endeavouring to find the right areas to target is undoubtedly valuable, the challenge of finding reliable indicators of difficulties early in a child’s life might mean searching for stable predictors at later ages (e.g. from school entry) may be a more fruitful approach&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_edn5&quot; name=&quot;_ednref5&quot;&gt;[v]&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, long-term follow-ups to interventions may be key to understanding the extent to which they are effective. The challenge of early interventions is that development is complex and shaped by multiple factors. Working within these constraints may help us better identify and help children in need of ongoing support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt; This newest article was contributed by our beloved lab member Erin Hawkins. Erin’s research focuses on understanding the mechanisms and interventions of developmental difficulties in children.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;[i] Caspi et al. (2016). Childhood forecast of a small segment of the population with large economic burden. &lt;em&gt;Nature Human Behaviour, &lt;/em&gt;doi:10.1038/s41562-016-0005&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref2&quot; name=&quot;_edn2&quot;&gt;[ii]&lt;/a&gt; The Allen Report (2011). Early Intervention: The Next Steps. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/284086/early-intervention-next-steps2.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/284086/early-intervention-next-steps2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref3&quot; name=&quot;_edn3&quot;&gt;[iii]&lt;/a&gt; Duff, Reen, Plunkett, &amp;amp; Nation (2015). Do infant vocabulary skills predict school-age language and literacy outcomes? &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, &lt;/em&gt;doi:10.1111/jcpp.12378.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref4&quot; name=&quot;_edn4&quot;&gt;[iv]&lt;/a&gt; McGillion, Pine, Herbert &amp;amp; Matthews. (2017). A randomised controlled trial to test the effect of promoting caregiver contingent talk on language development in infants from diverse socioeconomic status backgrounds. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1111/jcpp.12725&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/ #_ednref5&quot; name=&quot;_edn5&quot;&gt;[v]&lt;/a&gt; Norbury, C. (2015). Editorial: Early intervention in response to language delays – is there a danger of putting too many eggs in the wrong basket? &lt;em&gt;Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1111/jcpp.12446&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For further reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Succinct reviews of the evidence and cost effectiveness of different kinds of early years interventions, by the Education Endowment Foundation: &lt;a href=&quot;https://educationendowmentfoundation.org.uk/evidence-summaries/early-years-toolkit&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://educationendowmentfoundation.org.uk/evidence-summaries/early-years-toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Early Intervention Foundation has practical reports on the effectiveness of various interventions: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eif.org.uk/publication/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://www.eif.org.uk/publication/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This report provides a case study of the ‘London effect’ in attainment gaps: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/321969/London_Schools_-_FINAL.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/321969/London_Schools_-_FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/552/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/552/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=552&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>mengyaz</name>
			<uri>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T16:01:42+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The deactivation effect: What 15 minutes device-free solitude does to your emotions</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/06/the-deactivation-effect-what-15-minutes-device-free-solitude-does-to-your-emotions/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32021</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T13:56:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-493659014.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32132&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32132&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter on the beach at sunset&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;AntonioGuillem&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Lonely woman watching sunset alone in winter&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/06/the-deactivation-effect-what-15-minutes-device-free-solitude-does-to-your-emotions/lonely-woman-watching-sunset-alone-in-winter/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-493659014.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology research has tended to portray solitude as an unpleasant experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ac.els-cdn.com/027322979090008R/1-s2.0-027322979090008R-main.pdf?_tid=37436a9e-c2f8-11e7-890f-00000aacb35d&amp;amp;acdnat=1509975879_39d803157dfe7b76706a2d52e725d31e&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-6494.1978.tb00191.x/abstract&quot;&gt;conducted&lt;/a&gt; in the 1970s and 1990s suggested a clear pattern: people usually felt less happy when alone as compared with having company. More recently, researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/03/is-it-the-darkness-within-some-people-would-rather-shock-themselves-with-electricity-than-spend-time-with-their-own-thoughts/&quot;&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; that their volunteers preferred to give themselves mild electric shocks than sit in silence with their own thoughts. However, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0146167217733073&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;, a research team led by They-vy Nguyen at the University of Rochester explains the shortcomings in this earlier research and presents a more nuanced picture, showing how 15 minutes solitude can have beneficial effects on our emotions. Their results suggest that if you want to lower the intensity of your emotions, positive and negative, time spent alone may be just the ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32021&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research from the 70s and 90s measured emotion on a scale from positive to negative, overlooking the possibility that our positive and negative emotions can fluctuate independently, and that both positive and negative emotions can be either high arousal (such as excitement or anger) or low arousal (such as calmness and loneliness). Meanwhile, the electric shock research involved volunteers being instructed that they must actively think, which may have been aversive as compared with simply being in solitude without more specific instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their new paper, Nguyen’s team first asked 75 student participants to spend 15 minutes sitting alone in a comfortable chair at the psych lab, away from their digital devices and without engaging in any activity. For comparison, 39 other students spent the same time chatting with a research assistant. Before and after this 15 minute period, all the students completed a questionnaire measuring their “high arousal” positive and negative emotions (examples being excited, interested, scared, distressed). The results were clear: the participants in the solitude condition, but not the comparison group, showed reductions in their positive and negative emotions – what the researchers described as a “deactivation effect”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A follow-up study with more students found the same deactivating effect of 15 minutes of solitude on high arousal emotions, but also added in a measure of low-arousal positive and negative emotions (such as calm, relaxed, sad, lonely) and found that these were increased by time alone. It seems solitude doesn’t have a simple emotional effect that can be caricatured as good or bad; rather, it changes the intensity of our inner experience, both positive and negative: accentuating low-key emotions, while dialling down our stronger feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same pattern was found for a comparison group who spent the time alone reading a moderately interesting article rather than in their own thoughts, suggesting that complete mental disengagement from an external task is not necessary for solitude to have its emotional effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you think about when you’re alone surely has some bearing on the emotional effects of solitude: the researchers investigated this in another study, as well as looking into whether it matters whether you choose the tone of your thoughts or follow someone else’s instructions. Choosing the content of one’s own thoughts, rather than following instructions, was preferable in terms of reducing high arousal negative emotions and boosting low arousal positive ones. However, it’s also true that time alone with positive thoughts – whether by choice or through following instructions – was advantageous, as compared with having neutral thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the researchers asked 157 students to keep an evening diary for two weeks to track their emotions. Half the students were instructed to spend 15 minutes in device-free solitude daily during the first week; the other half of the students did this in the second week. Again, the de-activation effect was observed: the week that the students spent time in solitude, they tended to show reduced high arousal positive and negative emotions. There was also an apparent deactivation spill-over into the second week for those who completed the solitude exercises in the first week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth clarifying that these findings pertain to relatively brief moments of solitude as distinct from prolonged loneliness, which is known to be associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/11/12/loneliness-is-a-disease-that-changes-the-brains-structure-and-function/&quot;&gt;a host of unwelcome physical and psychological effects&lt;/a&gt;. Also, bear in mind the current findings could vary across cultures and with older volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nguyen and her colleagues said more research needs to be done, but that the “take-home message is that there are benefits and detriments of solitude.” They added their studies suggest “that people can use solitude, or other variations on being alone, to regulate their affective states, becoming quiet after excitement, calm after an angry episode, or centred and peaceful when desired.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new results may also be seen as a complement to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/05/researchers-say-dont-worry-what-other-people-think-going-out-on-your-own-can-be-fun/&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published two years ago that made the case that people generally enjoy going out on their own in public more than they think they will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0146167217733073&quot;&gt;Solitude as an Approach to Affective Self-Regulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32021/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32021/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32021&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: 4th retraction for prominent physicist (with new funding) cites falsification</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/caught-notice-4th-retraction-prominent-physicist-new-funding-cites-falsification/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52449</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T13:00:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Improved Cellular Specificity of Plasmonic Nanobubbles versus Nanoparticles in Heterogeneous Cell Systems What Caught Our Attention: Nanotechnology researcher Dmitri Lapotko, whose work with lasers continues to catch media attention, has earned his fourth retraction.  As with the other three, the latest notice mentions an investigation at Rice University, but provides no specific information other than “data falsification” […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/06/caught-notice-4th-retraction-prominent-physicist-new-funding-cites-falsification/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: 4th retraction for prominent physicist (with new funding) cites falsification&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Why should we care about medical students’ unprofessional behaviour?</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/06/why-should-we-care-about-medical-students-unprofessional-behaviour/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9622</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T11:45:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/Fotolia_75984055_Subscription_Yearly_XXL-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever experienced your doctor behaving unprofessionally? Perhaps you have felt uncomfortable, or worse, have questioned your safety? Did you wonder if doctors are taught how to behave professionally during their training?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, patient safety can indeed be threatened by the unprofessional behavior of physicians. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nejm.org/doi/pdf/10.1056/NEJMsa052596&quot;&gt;Research has shown&lt;/a&gt; that this can be predicted by a physician’s behavior as a medical student. It’s no surprise then, that medical schools all over the world are increasingly paying attention to teaching and assessing professionalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, medical teachers often show a reluctance to fail students behaving unprofessionally, mainly because they do not know what to document or are afraid to be subjective, and therefore hesitate to take action. Professionalism guidelines describe what is expected regarding professional behavior, but do not always specifically describe what constitutes the &lt;em&gt;unprofessional&lt;/em&gt; behavior of undergraduate medical students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professionalism guidelines describe what is expected regarding professional behavior, but do not always specifically describe what constitutes the &lt;em&gt;unprofessional&lt;/em&gt; behavior of undergraduate medical students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, an educational guideline could mention the importance of accountability, but does not make clear what would be the specific manifestation of a lack of accountability by a medical student. Although the General Medical Council has recently updated &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gmc-uk.org/Achieving_good_medical_practice_0816.pdf_66086678.pdf&quot;&gt;their guideline&lt;/a&gt; (previously known as ‘Tomorrow’s doctors’) to now indicate normative domains of concern, an overview of real-life behaviors that are actually seen by teachers and peer students at medical school, or in the hospital, did not yet exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My co-authors and I, all teachers in medical professionalism, are often consulted by colleagues who seek confirmation before denominating certain student behavior as unprofessional. We also notice that medical teachers often use indirect language while describing unprofessional behaviors in assessment forms such as: ‘&lt;em&gt;professional attitude has to improve&lt;/em&gt;’ or ‘&lt;em&gt;needs to read more&lt;/em&gt;’. Such remarks do not make clear what the teacher actually saw, and what aspect he/she thinks that the student must pay attention to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear descriptors providing a common language for unprofessional behavior could offer teachers a tool for recognizing and denominating unprofessional behavior, and could support them in acknowledging it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why we set up a literature search to find descriptors of medical students’ unprofessional behaviors that were actually experienced by medical teachers or students themselves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-017-0997-x&quot;&gt;Findings of this research project&lt;/a&gt; have recently been published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Education&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 4 I’s of unprofessionalism &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We compiled evidence from 46 research papers and found that medical students can behave unprofessionally in at least 205 different ways. We grouped these 205 descriptions into 30 descriptors, and organized them into 4 main themes. These four themes are indicated as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 4 I’s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Involvement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (failure to engage: e.g. being late, poor initiative, avoiding patient contact),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (dishonest behaviors: lying, fraud in exams, data falsification),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interaction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (disrespectful behavior: discrimination, poor communication, lack of sensitivity to another person’s needs) and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (poor self-awareness: not accepting feedback, lack of awareness of another person’s needs, blaming external factors rather than one’s own inadequacies).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;An early transparent discussion among teacher and student about the teacher’s observations can make medical students aware of their (often unintended) unprofessional behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the 4 I’s seemed to appear fairly consistently in research papers coming out of different continents: similar themes of concern exist globally. However, attention for them did not arise everywhere at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temporal trend we found is that, around 1980, North-American researchers started studying unprofessional behavior of medical students, firstly emphasizing &lt;em&gt;Integrity&lt;/em&gt;, followed by attention for &lt;em&gt;Interaction&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Involvement&lt;/em&gt;. From 2000 on, researchers in other parts of the world also started to investigate &lt;em&gt;Integrity &lt;/em&gt;problems. Around 2000, North-American researchers moved forward to study &lt;em&gt;Insight,&lt;/em&gt; quickly followed by their colleagues in Europe and Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if a similar trend will arise in the rapidly growing body of literature on this topic coming from South America, Africa and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical teachers should care about their students’ unprofessional behavior. They should not be afraid to be subjective, but take action by openly discussing their observations with the student. The framework of &lt;em&gt;The 4 I’s&lt;/em&gt; can help them, as it serves as a tool providing a common language for describing students’ unprofessional behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early transparent discussion among teacher and student about the teacher’s observations can make medical students aware of their (often unintended) unprofessional behaviors, and could inform teachers about underlying personal, interpersonal or institutional causes for the behavior. By discussing such behaviors, without blaming the student, but with the goal of offering help, teachers can contribute to the prevention of future professionalism lapses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this research article we hope to help medical students and teachers alike in creating a culture of professionalism in medical school, which is not only beneficial for the aspiring doctors, but ultimately for the safety of their future patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/06/why-should-we-care-about-medical-students-unprofessional-behaviour/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Why should we care about medical students’ unprofessional behaviour?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dr. Marianne Mak-van der Vossen</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T12:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Alzheimer’s protein can travel from blood to build up in the brain</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alzheimers-disease-amyloid-protein-blood-brain"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alzheimers-disease-amyloid-protein-blood-brain</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Experiments in mice show Alzheimer’s protein can travel from the blood of an affected mouse to the brain of a healthy animal.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">What does Gödel's theorem mean ?</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/what-does-godels-theorem-mean/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1460</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T10:01:15+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gödel's_incompleteness_theorems&quot;&gt;Gödel's theorem&lt;/a&gt; is a result in mathematical logic, which is often stated as showing that « there are true things that cannot proved ». It is sometimes used to comment on the limits of science, or the superiority of human intuition. Here I want to clarify what this theorem means and what the epistemological implications are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;First, this phrasing is rather misleading. It makes the result sound almost mystical. If you phrase the result differently, by avoiding the potentially confusing reference to truth, the result is not that mystical anymore. Here is how I would phrase it : you can always add an independent axiom to a finite system of axioms. This is not an obvious mathematical result, but I wouldn't think it defies intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Why is this equivalent to the first phrasing ? If the additional axiom is independent of the set of axioms, then it cannot be proved from them (by definition). Yet as a logical proposition it has to be either true or not true. So it is true, or its negation is true, but it cannot be proved. What is misleading in the first phrasing is that the statement « there are true things » is contextual. I can start from a set of axioms and add one, and that new one will be true (since it's an axiom). Instead I could add its negation, and then that one will be true. That the proposition is true is not a universal truth, as it would seem with the phrasing « there are true things ». It is true in a particular mathematical world, and you can consider another one where it is not true. Famous examples are Euclidean and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-Euclidean_geometry&quot;&gt;non-Euclidean geometries&lt;/a&gt;, which are mutually inconsistent sets of axioms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;So, what Gödel's theorem says is simply that no finite system of axioms is complete, in the sense that you can always add one without making the system inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;What are the epistemological implications ? It does not mean that there are things that science cannot prove. Laws of physics are not proved by deduction anyway. They are hypothesized and empirically tested, and all laws are provisory. Nevertheless, it does raise some deep philosophical questions, which have to do with reductionism. I am generally critical of &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xi-reductionism/&quot;&gt;reductionism&lt;/a&gt;, but more specifically of methodological reductionism, the idea that a system can be understood by understanding the elements that compose it. For example : understand neurons and you will understand the brain. I think this view is wrong, because it is the relations between neurons, at the scale of the organism, which make a brain. The right approach is systemic rather than reductionist. Many scientists frown at criticisms of reductionism, but this is only because they confuse methodological and ontological reductionism. Ontological reductionism means that reality can be reduced to a small number of types of things (eg atoms) and laws, and everything can be understood in these terms. For example, the mind can in principle be understood in terms of interactions of atoms that constitute the brain. Most scientists seem to believe in ontological reductionism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Let us go back now to Gödel's theorem. An interesting remark made by theoretical biologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Rosen_(theoretical_biologist)&quot;&gt;Robert Rosen&lt;/a&gt; is that Gödel's theorem makes ontological reductionism implausible to him. Why ? The theorem says that, whatever system of axioms you choose, it will always be possible to add one which is independent. Let us say we have agreed on a small set of fundamental physical laws, with strong empirical support. To establish each law, we postulate it and test it empirically. At a macroscopic level, scientists postulate and test all sorts of laws. How can we claim that any macroscopic law necessarily derives from the small set of fundamental laws ? Gödel's theorem says that there are laws that you can express but that are independent of the fundamental laws. This means that there are laws that can only be established empirically, not formally, in fact just like the set of fundamental laws. Of course it could be the case that most of what matters to us is captured by a small of set of laws. But maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>romain</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:34+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Language patterns reveal body's hidden response to stress</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/FKQO-i3Krl4/nature.2017.22964"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22964</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Volunteers' use of certain words predicted stress-related changes in gene expression better than their self-reported feelings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22964&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/FKQO-i3Krl4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jo Marchant</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">US government approves 'killer' mosquitoes to fight disease</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/t4gAEDrnNvo/nature.2017.22959"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22959</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;US Environmental Protection Agency will allow release of insects in 20 states and Washington DC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22959&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22959&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/t4gAEDrnNvo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Waltz</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure of the human MHC-I peptide-loading complex</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WVAZLCtj-yk/nature24627"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24627</id>
		<updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The peptide-loading complex (PLC) is a transient, multisubunit membrane complex in the endoplasmic reticulum that is essential for establishing a hierarchical immune response. The PLC coordinates peptide translocation into the endoplasmic reticulum with loading and editing of major histocompatibility complex class I (MHC-I) molecules. After final proofreading in the PLC, stable peptide–MHC-I complexes are released to the cell surface to evoke a T-cell response against infected or malignant cells. Sampling of different MHC-I allomorphs requires the precise coordination of seven different subunits in a single macromolecular assembly, including the transporter associated with antigen processing (TAP1 and TAP2, jointly referred to as TAP), the oxidoreductase ERp57, the MHC-I heterodimer, and the chaperones tapasin and calreticulin. The molecular organization of and mechanistic events that take place in the PLC are unknown owing to the heterogeneous composition and intrinsically dynamic nature of the complex. Here, we isolate human PLC from Burkitt’s lymphoma cells using an engineered viral inhibitor as bait and determine the structure of native PLC by electron cryo-microscopy. Two endoplasmic reticulum-resident editing modules composed of tapasin, calreticulin, ERp57, and MHC-I are centred around TAP in a pseudo-symmetric orientation. A multivalent chaperone network within and across the editing modules establishes the proofreading function at two lateral binding platforms for MHC-I molecules. The lectin-like domain of calreticulin senses the MHC-I glycan, whereas the P domain reaches over the MHC-I peptide-binding pocket towards ERp57. This arrangement allows tapasin to facilitate peptide editing by clamping MHC-I. The translocation pathway of TAP opens out into a large endoplasmic reticulum lumenal cavity, confined by the membrane entry points of tapasin and MHC-I. Two lateral windows channel the antigenic peptides to MHC-I. Structures of PLC captured at distinct assembly states provide mechanistic insight into the recruitment and release of MHC-I. Our work defines the molecular symbiosis of an ABC transporter and an endoplasmic reticulum chaperone network in MHC-I assembly and provides insight into the onset of the adaptive immune response. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24627&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24627&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WVAZLCtj-yk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andreas Blees</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Invasive species are a growing global threat</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/invasive-species-are-growing-global-threat"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/invasive-species-are-growing-global-threat</id>
		<updated>2017-11-05T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 'The Aliens Among Us' describes how invasive species are colonizing — and disrupting — ecosystems worldwide.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sid Perkins</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">&quot;Facephenes&quot;: Brain Stimulation Creates Phantasmal Faces</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9219"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9219</id>
		<updated>2017-11-04T19:45:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Have you ever seen a face on a football?

In a new paper, neuroscientists Gerwin Schalk et al. report that brain stimulation caused a man to experience strange hallucinations. The patient saw faces in everyday objects, including an orange soccer ball and a featureless box. The researchers coined the word &quot;facephenes&quot; to refer to these face-like perceptions.



Schalk et al. studied a 26 year old Japanese man suffering from intractable epilepsy. The patient was implanted with a large number</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: Researcher sues over criticism; how to fire a professor; science by sexual harassers</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/04/weekend-reads-researcher-sues-criticism-fire-professor-science-sexual-harassers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52464</id>
		<updated>2017-11-04T13:54:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a revoked PhD, more news about Paolo Macchiarini, and a head-scratcher about a retraction involving astronauts. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Stanford professor Mark Jacobson has sued a critic and the National Academy of Sciences for $10 million, over a PNAS paper questioning his work. (Mashable) Anna Azvolinksky considers “How to fire a professor” […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/04/weekend-reads-researcher-sues-criticism-fire-professor-science-sexual-harassers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Researcher sues over criticism; how to fire a professor; science by sexual harassers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Humans are driving climate change, federal scientists say</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-climate-change-national-assessment-2017"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-climate-change-national-assessment-2017</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T22:19:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Human influence “extremely likely” to be dominant cause of warming in last 70 years, U.S. climate report finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s why some water striders have fans on their legs</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/water-striders-fans-legs-biophysics"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/water-striders-fans-legs-biophysics</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T18:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A fan of tiny, elegant plumes on their legs helps certain water striders dash across flowing water without getting wet.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Lancet Oncology Commission releases US cancer research report</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/lancet-oncology-commission-releases-us-cancer-research-report"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/lancet-oncology-commission-releases-us-cancer-research-report</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T16:25:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Major report sets out how to accelerate cancer research and care, delivering on US Cancer Moonshot initiative</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Looking at scaffolding proteins to understand addiction</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/dZPrOrHwZB0/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19469</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T16:06:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/11/2714125856_ea52277be4_o-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding cellular and molecular modifications occurring in reward-related behaviors is nowadays an intense field of scientific investigation. The reward system is a complex circuit composed of several interconnected brain structures responsible for incentive salience, associative learning, reinforcement and positive emotions (i.e. pleasure). One of the most critical regions of this system is represented by the nucleus accumbens (NAc), a hub region that receives and sends information. Several cellular and molecular modifications have been observed at the level of the medium spiny neurons (MSNs) of the NAc, but we are still far from having a clear picture of their detailed mechanisms.&lt;br /&gt;
In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0185796&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE article&lt;/a&gt;, Mittal and colleagues (University of California Los Angeles, UCLA) decided to investigate the role of a family of proteins, the β-arrestins, in reward-related behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;β&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-arrestins: how do they work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;β-arrestins are versatile adapter proteins that form complexes with most G-protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) following ligand binding and consequent activation of the receptors. It is well known that they play a critical role in the interrelated processes of GPCR desensitization and sequestration, which in turn lead to the termination of G protein activation and signaling cascades. This causes specific dampening of cellular responses to specific stimuli such as hormones, neurotransmitters, or sensory signals. While β-arrestin 2 (β-arr2) has been implicated in several aspects of reward-related learning and behaviors, very little is known about the behavioral function of β-arrestin 1 (β-arr1). Both isoforms regulate remodeling of the actin cytoskeleton to influence chemotaxis and trafficking of specific G-protein coupled receptors and they are ubiquitously expressed in the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;β&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-arrestins and the brain reward system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their article, Mittal and colleagues hypothesized that β-arr1, “&lt;em&gt;may influence basal glutamatergic signaling and cocaine-induced adaptations of this &lt;/em&gt;[the glutamatergic]&lt;em&gt; excitatory system within the NAc&lt;/em&gt;”. This would alter specific aspects of reward processing. Thus, using β-arr1 knock-out (KO) mice as well as behavioral and electrophysiological assays to examine this hypothesis the authors have defined specific roles of β-arr1 and glutamate receptors NMDA-Rs in reward processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, mice lacking β-arr1 showed a delay in the initial phases of both the acquisition and extinction of cocaine self-administration, a behavioral test that allows researchers to study changes in distinct aspects of drug-taking behavior that model behaviors observed in drug addicts. This first set of behavioral results indicate that β-arr1 is involved in regulating the acquisition and extinction of instrumental cocaine self-administration. To determine whether these impairments induced by β-arr1 deletion could be generalized to other rewarding stimuli, the authors conducted a series of experiments using a battery of food-motivated behaviors. Surprisingly, β-arr1 KO mice also showed an impairment in developing Pavlovian conditioned (goal-directed) behavior and in the amount of efforts needed to obtain palatable food. Altogether these results suggest that β-arr1 may play a central role in driving reward-related behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, in order to fully explore the molecular mechanisms underlying the behavioral performances observed in β-arr1 KO mice, Mittal et al. performed electrophysiological recordings at the level of the excitatory glutamatergic synapses of the NAc. It must be mentioned that glutamatergic transmission within the nucleus accumbens is a central component of reward-related adaptations. The synaptic strength was then measured as the AMPA/NMDA (A/N) ratio. “&lt;em&gt;We found that deleting β-arr1 increased the A/N ratio and reduced GluN2B-NMDARs in NAc shell MSNs&lt;/em&gt;”, say Nitish Mittal, the leading author of the paper.&lt;br /&gt;
Since β-arr1 plays an important role in regulating actin turnover to modulate exocytosis and endocytosis it may be possible that actin dynamics regulate the trafficking of the GluN2B subunit of the NMDA receptors. In fact, pharmacological blockade of actin remodeling was able to alter synaptic strength in wildtype littermates but not in β-arr1 KO mice, thus suggesting a molecular link between β-arr1 and NMDA receptors. “&lt;em&gt;Based on our findings&lt;/em&gt;”, say Wendy Walwyn, the senior author of the study, “&lt;em&gt;it is possible that deleting β-arr1, or inactivating cofilin &lt;/em&gt;[actin dynamics]&lt;em&gt;, disrupts actin turnover and microtubule disassembly to reduce the transport of GluN2B-containing NMDARs to the cell membrane, or stability once in place&lt;/em&gt;”. Given the fact that β-arr1 genetic ablation disrupts GluN2B-NMDA receptor functions, the authors investigated whether chronic inhibition of GluN2B-NMDA receptors in the NAc would produce similar behavioral impairments as observed in β-arr1 KO mice.&lt;br /&gt;
At the behavioral level, pharmacological inactivation of GluN2B subunits significantly inhibited instrumental lever pressing behavior in WT littermates, thus suggesting a potential link between NMDA and β-arr1. However, the same pharmacological strategy was not performed in β-arr1 KO mice, thus making the final assumption not definitively proved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Although further studies are needed to fully define the underlying cellular mechanisms and causal relationships, this study is the first to examine the role of this arrestin isoform in reward-motivated behaviors&lt;/em&gt;”, conclude the authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image credit : SimplyScience &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/simplyscience/2714125856/in/photolist-58QB4o-kYwXWB-8MQAv7-eMgpuE-VMx9X7-bvBq3M-85zpbq-7JBEmG-7yEyUZ-8ZMtbm-4JcJ4G-CbDzgA-bwwdoc-cH9PLm-avYayj-gaVDUw-DGyAke-mH3HRi-dDbn-hMg5qQ-Tm2SQQ-e6Q7iA-epqjXb-bgLcX2-6w9zwS-7o1VEx-UWjjUv-jBsFcB-fnfJ36-m5tLpg-py1r74-e358zq-5ZyuCe-Ktd3-aW18kg-i1V11f-73j1ri-bwwbpp-7fXN5U-Th9kdT-YKrbUe-bxkGLx-ckXcKS-9V3ZcE-VYa6VH-7BFhSv-5gyAHe-hTZRq8-qMxahP-4xQAAw&quot;&gt;Flickr &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Peppe-BW&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-17882 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/10/Peppe-BW-238x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;117&quot; /&gt;Giuseppe Gangarossa &lt;/b&gt;received his PhD in Biomedical Sciences, specialty Neuroscience, from the University of Bologna. He has been a visiting fellow at the Karolinska Institutet (Sotckholm, Sweden), the French Inserm (Montpellier, France) and the Collège de France (Paris, France). Giuseppe is currently Assistant Professor of Physiology at the University Paris Diderot. His main research topic is dopamine-related brain disorders. You can follow him on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peppeganga?lang=en&quot;&gt;@PeppeGanga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/dZPrOrHwZB0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Giuseppe Gangarossa</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">PLOS Neuroscience Community</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Researchers discuss latest brain science</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/neuro</id>
			<updated>2017-11-06T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Artificial insulin-releasing cells may make it easier to manage diabetes</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/artificial-insulin-releasing-cells-may-make-it-easier-manage-diabetes"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/artificial-insulin-releasing-cells-may-make-it-easier-manage-diabetes</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Synthetic cells crafted in the lab could provide a more precise, longer-lasting diabetes treatment.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Cracking the Code–Revealing the Secret Behind Our Perception</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/03/cracking-the-code-revealing-the-secret-behind-our-perception/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23042</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T15:00:55+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;When you’re an eye doctor, and I’ve spent my entire career as one, you learn a lot about how people use, and misuse, the sense of sight to perceive the world around them. As humans, we’re constantly interpreting and occasionally manipulating our experiences to distinguish fantasy from reality. Some people are better at this than others. Some, for example, are consistently taken in by conspiracy theories or fake news stories, whereas others can quickly sniff them out as bogus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I asked myself-what’s the difference between people with keen powers of perception and those with weaker powers? Is it education? Experience? Genetics? I began researching the topic and discovered there isn’t even a term to classify our power of perception, so I adopted one. I call it &lt;em&gt;perceptual intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s the title of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Perceptual-Intelligence-Illusion-Misperception-Self-Deception/dp/160868475X&quot;&gt;my new book&lt;/a&gt; (in bookstores this month).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Perceptual Intelligence,” (or PI), is our ability to interpret sensory data and arrive at a decision.  Just as with other forms of intelligence, some people have higher PI than others. Good decision-makers exhibit a high level of Perceptual Intelligence, whereas bad decision-makers demonstrate weaker PI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PI, I learned, is an acquired skill. We can improve our PI, in fact, through awareness and practice.  You may, for instance, find yourself overreacting to certain situations or circumstances. But with proper knowledge and a different perspective, you can train yourself to arrive at a more appropriate reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this fast-paced digital age, where we’re often forced to make decisions on the fly; we often “leap before we look.”  That might mean handing over your credit card number without verifying a website’s security, or trusting a news story without considering the integrity of the source. People with high PI, however, consistently “look before they leap.” Before making a decision, they ask themselves, instinctively: Am I interpreting this sensory data correctly and making the best choice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every millisecond, our senses take in a massive amount of information, which then travels to the brain.  The brain, in turn, is where our perceptions originate. Those perceptions may accurately reflect reality but may also derail us toward fantasy. The driving question behind my book is: Why do our perceptions sometimes clash with reality? There are many reasons, I discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is medical. For example, a condition known as synesthesia can cause a person to literally see music or taste sounds. (A second form of synesthesia connects objects such as letters and numbers with a sensory perception such as color or taste.) Even the common cold, which affects the eyes, ears, nose, and throat—not to mention the brain, when our heads fill with congestion—has been known to distort our power of perception. When we are under the weather from the flu, our power of perception might seem so foggy that we develop a pessimistic view of situations that we might otherwise view with optimism. Another medical factor influencing perception is sleep deprivation. As any insomniac or parent of a newborn will tell you, a lack of sleep can distort our perception of the world, sometimes even fogging our memory of what happened during our sleepless state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious (and sometimes deadly) influence on our power of perception is drugs and alcohol. We don’t need to review criminal cases and “beer goggle” studies to see how drugs and alcohol impair our senses and affect our judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s also our psychology, biology, genetics, habits, cultural upbringing, and memories, all of which combine to create our unique perceptual filter, influencing our decisions, thoughts and beliefs. The pope’s belief in life after death, for example, is diametrically opposed to that of theoretical physicist Lawrence Krauss’. Yet each is convinced that his view is the correct one. Is the pope blinded by faith? Is Dr. Krauss closed to any idea that isn’t evidence-based? We all create a version of the world unlike anyone else’s. And how could it not be? It is shaped by &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, we mold our perceptions like Play-Doh to suit the story we create of our lives. But sometimes our perceptions work behind the scenes, shaping our thoughts and behaviors without us realizing.  When we have a vague memory of a painful incident, what purpose does it serve? Why do we hold onto an incorrect and hurtful perception when instead we could make something good of it? People with finely-tuned PI can identify and topple faulty ideas that try to sabotage them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of strong perceptual intelligence is recognizing that your mind is more plastic than you think and can be molded. PI can be improved, like any other skill, such as driving a car, playing a sport, or learning an instrument.  Improving PI can have a profound effect on your life. Better decisions can reduce the risk of financial, health, family problems, and other issues that can arise from low perceptual intelligence.  You could say, therefore, that high PI even improves happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Brian Boxer Wachler, M.D., an expert in human perception, is America’s TV Eye Doctor and internationally renowned for his expertise in Keratoconus treatments, LASIK and other vision correction procedures. His book, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Perceptual-Intelligence-Illusion-Misperception-Self-Deception/dp/160868475X&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perceptual Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; (published by New World Library), is available in bookstores October 17, 2017 on Amazon, Barnes &amp;amp; Noble, and Indie Bound.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/PublicDomainPictures-14/&quot;&gt;PublicDomainPictures&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Brian Boxer Wachler, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:32+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: Ethics, data concerns prompt another retraction for convicted researchers</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/03/caught-notice-ethics-data-concerns-prompt-another-retraction-convicted-researchers/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52421</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T15:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Title: Unravelling the influence of mild traumatic brain injury (MTBI) on cognitive-linguistic processing: A comparative group analysis What Caught our Attention: RW readers might already be familiar with Caroline Barwood and Bruce Murdoch, two researchers from Australia who had the rare distinction of being criminally charged for research misconduct. Both Barwood and Murdoch received suspended sentences after being found guilty of multiple […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/03/caught-notice-ethics-data-concerns-prompt-another-retraction-convicted-researchers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Ethics, data concerns prompt another retraction for convicted researchers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Three markers for open science success</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/three-markers-for-open-science-success"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/three-markers-for-open-science-success</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T14:51:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Researchers and society will benefit from more open science; here’s what’s making it happen</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Open science: enabling a more inclusive, collaborative, transparent world of research</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-enabling-a-more-inclusive-collaborative-transparent-world-of-research"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-enabling-a-more-inclusive-collaborative-transparent-world-of-research</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T14:50:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Gemma Hersh, VP of Open Science at Elsevier, shows how Elsevier is laying a foundation</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Exploring open science</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/exploring-open-science"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/exploring-open-science</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T14:21:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 November's theme focuses on how we can make research more open, transparent and collaborative</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Alligators eat sharks — and a whole lot more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/alligators-sharks-saltwater"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/alligators-sharks-saltwater</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T13:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Alligators aren’t just freshwater creatures. They swim to salty waters and back, munching on plenty of foods along the way.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sarah Zielinski</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">A paper about eye damage in astronauts got pulled for “security concerns.” Huh?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/03/paper-eye-damage-astronauts-got-pulled-security-concerns-huh/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52440</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T12:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Here’s a head-scratcher: A 2017 paper examining why long space flights can cause eye damage has been taken down, with a brief note saying NASA, which sponsored the research, asked for the retraction because of “security concerns.” According to the first author, the paper included information that could identify some of the astronauts that took […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/03/paper-eye-damage-astronauts-got-pulled-security-concerns-huh/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A paper about eye damage in astronauts got pulled for “security concerns.” Huh?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T06:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">See a new mosaic of images of comet 67P from the Rosetta mission</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-new-mosaic-images-comet-67p-rosetta-mission"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-new-mosaic-images-comet-67p-rosetta-mission</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A montage of images taken by the Rosetta spacecraft and its lander, Philae, recap the daring mission to comet 67P.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ashley Yeager</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Leafhoppers use tiny light-absorbing balls to conceal their eggs</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/leafhoppers-use-tiny-light-absorbing-balls-conceal-their-eggs"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/leafhoppers-use-tiny-light-absorbing-balls-conceal-their-eggs</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T10:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Leafhoppers produce microscopic balls that absorb light rather than reflect it and help camouflage the insects’ eggs.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viviane Callier</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">New study suggests people with OCD are especially sensitive to the seasons</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/03/new-study-suggests-people-with-ocd-are-especially-sensitive-to-the-seasons/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31914</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T09:25:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-615902386.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31999&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31999&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young woman walking on autumn leaves carpet in misty park. Yellow leaf on ground.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1477049268&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;portishead1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;24&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young woman walking in foggy park&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young woman walking in foggy park&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-615902386.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-615902386.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-615902386.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/03/new-study-suggests-people-with-ocd-are-especially-sensitive-to-the-seasons/young-woman-walking-in-foggy-park/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-615902386.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clocks have gone back and there’s a chill in the air. It’s well known that during these darker months, a significant minority of us experience unwelcome negative changes to our mood (at least if you believe in the notion of Seasonal Affective Disorder or SAD, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/scienceofus/2016/02/debunking-the-myth-of-the-winter-blues.html&quot;&gt;which not all experts do&lt;/a&gt;). Now an intriguing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0165178116307296?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychiatry Research&lt;/em&gt; has explored the link this condition may have with another psychiatric diagnosis, Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results suggest that people with OCD are more likely than average to experience seasonal effects on their mood, and that for these seasonally sensitive people with OCD, their “compulsions” are worse in the colder months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31914&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s already established that some of the underlying neurophysiology of SAD and OCD is the same, involving dysfunction of the neurotransmitter serotonin, note the study authors Oğuz Tan and his colleagues at Uskudar University in Turkey. They also point to past research that has shown &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/aje/article/162/7/654/204611/Seasonal-Variations-in-Mental-Disorders-in-the&quot;&gt;the prevalence of OCD is highest in Autumn&lt;/a&gt;, and that light therapy, used to treat SAD, has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jad-journal.com/article/S0165-0327(03)00003-X/fulltext&quot;&gt;shown to benefit some people with OCD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further study the links between OCD and SAD, Tan and his team recruited 104 people in Istanbul diagnosed with OCD (and most of whom were on drug treatments) and 125 local controls without OCD (controls were included if they had other mental health problems, unless they were considered too severe, such as a diagnosis of schizophrenia or bipolar disorder). All participants completed a comprehensive questionnaire about their sensitivity to seasonal effects on mood and behaviour, including sleep and social activity. The participants diagnosed with OCD also completed a questionnaire about their OCD-related symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants with OCD reported greater seasonal sensitivity (mostly to colder months) – in fact, based on the extremity of their scores and how much they felt the effects were problematic, 19 per cent showed signs of SAD compared with just 9 per cent of the controls. What’s more, among this sub-group who had OCD combined with SAD, their depression symptoms and compulsions (the actions or thoughts they perform to cope with their disturbing thoughts or mental images) were worse when they were tested in their least favoured time of year. Finally, when participants with OCD and Winter/Autumn-related SAD were tested in these cooler months, the severity of their compulsions correlated with the shortness of the daylight hours on the day of testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our results indicate that seasonal changes in mood frequently co-occur with OCD, which denotes that OCD and mood seasonality may share a common etiology,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don’t know why there was a seasonal association with OCD-related compulsions but not “obsessions” (troubling thoughts or mental images). They also acknowledged their study’s drawbacks, including the dependence on participants’ own reports of their OCD and SAD-related symptoms (the measure of seasonal sensitivity in particular is not a true diagnostic test), and the cross-sectional design. More convincing would be to measure people’s OCD-related symptoms over time and see if they fluctuate with the seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tan and his colleagues believe the topic merits further study, especially to determine “the effect of SAD on the quality of life, prognosis, and risk of suicide and treatment response in patients with OCD”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0165178116307296?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Seasonal mood changes in patients with obsessive–compulsive disorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31914/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31914/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31914&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">US government report says that climate change is real — and humans are to blame</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/uEwHMZdg_ak/nature.2017.22958"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22958</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Conclusions of climate-change science analysis are at odds with US President Donald Trump’s policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22958&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22958&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/uEwHMZdg_ak&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jeff Tollefson</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Energy researcher sues the US National Academy of Sciences for millions of dollars</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/b-UJS8zJDiM/nature.2017.22944"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22944</id>
		<updated>2017-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Rare move stems from a conflict over two journal articles about renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 152 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22944&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22944&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/b-UJS8zJDiM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Chris Woolston</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:28+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What male bias in the mammoth fossil record says about the animal’s social groups</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/male-woolly-mammoth-fossils-social-structure"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/male-woolly-mammoth-fossils-social-structure</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T16:15:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Male woolly mammoths were more often caught in natural traps that preserved their remains, DNA evidence suggests.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T18:00:29+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Order in Disorder: a key feature of dendritic organization in the brain</title>
		<link href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/order-in-disorder-a-key-feature-of-dendritic-organization-in-the-brain/"/>
		<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10211</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T16:00:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;h4&gt;Researchers at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience discovered local order of dendritic spine functional properties within global disorder, a key underlying feature of the synaptic architecture of visual space.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurons are the basic information processing structures in the brain and are composed of three main parts: dendrites, axons, and the soma. Dendrites receive and integrate synaptic inputs that are subsequently processed in the soma and relayed to other neurons via axons. A longstanding question has been to understand how synaptic inputs are arranged on the elaborate dendritic structures of individual neurons in order to better comprehend how dendrites process and transform inputs, ultimately influencing how we perceive the world around us. Recent discoveries in the laboratory of David Fitzpatrick, Ph.D., Scientific Director and CEO at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI), have shed more light on this issue and the universal properties of cortical neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Scholl, Ph.D. and Dan Wilson, researchers in the Fitzpatrick lab, have been studying the spatial arrangement of synaptic inputs onto dendrites and how this arrangement impacts computations in visual cortex. Previous work by Wilson et al. (2015) revealed that orientation selectivity and functional clustering of synaptic inputs in visual cortical neurons correlates with localized dendritic events, sharpening somatic tuning. In their recent paper, published in Neuron on November 2nd, Scholl and Wilson examined whether this clustering exists at a finer scale and across the diversity of functional inputs cortical cells receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate fine-scale synaptic clustering, the researchers presented simple visual stimuli to activate individual excitatory inputs onto individual dendritic spines, small mushroom-shaped protrusions on the dendritic arbors. These visual stimuli allowed the authors to map spatial receptive fields – regions in visual space where stimuli elicit responses from particular neurons or synaptic inputs – and polarity – the preference for luminance increments (ON) or decrements (OFF). Large numbers of spines on individual layer 2/3 neurons were mapped and visualized using in vivo two-photon imaging of a genetically encoded calcium indicator, providing a measure of subcellular and cellular activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within individual dendritic branches and across the dendritic field, they found no evidence for a global organization. Upon closer inspection, however, they discovered robust functional synaptic clustering locally. Neighboring spines separated by less than 10 μm share similar functional properties across the diversity of sensory features they encode. Further, neighboring spines exhibit spontaneous and sensory-driven co-activity that can occur independent of global dendritic calcium events, driven largely by action potentials initiated at the soma. Distance-dependent relationships for these features exist at a spatial scale of 5-10 μm, and this omnipresent spatial length constant may indicate a fundamental biological limit to short-range plasticity mechanisms operating within the dendrite. “The clustering of inputs appears more universal than we might have previously thought,” said Scholl. “We are just beginning to appreciate the complexities of the dendritic field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also revealed, via machine learning, that fine-scale functional synaptic clusters exist within the broader population of spines, and these clusters appear to be selective for features both resembling and distinct from the somatic output. Clustered inputs could amplify such functional features, but the role of synaptic clustering in shaping somatic response is more complex. These distributed functional clusters could enhance the computational power of neurons by allowing greater flexibility of responses to a wide range of sensory inputs, increasing dendritic sensitivity without sacrificing dynamic range, and facilitating nonlinear interactions within individual dendrites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appreciating the integration and processing of distributed networks at the subcellular level is key to understanding organization at the cellular level and beyond. “It is critical that we understand how the inputs to a given neuron are arranged within its dendritic field so that we can understand how individual neurons integrate the information arising from thousands of synaptic inputs,” said Fitzpatrick. What are the consequences of such an arrangement for the function of a neuron and for the network in which it’s embedded? Currently, there is a large gap in our scientific knowledge when it comes to perceiving the role that dendrites play in neuronal circuits. “What makes this paper really exciting,” said Fitzpatrick, “is that it bridges that gap, putting cellular principles in the context of how a network operates.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, the lab is interested in exploring the development and maturation of spines and synaptic clusters. Ongoing work involves chronic imaging of the structure and function of individual spines during development and changes to visual experience to determine whether emerging spines adopt the same functional properties of their more adjacent, stable predecessors. Such research could provide greater insight into the role of synaptic clustering during development and plasticity mechanisms throughout an individual’s lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was supported by National Eye Institute (NEI) and Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience. The content of this article is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the funding agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image:&lt;br /&gt;
This image shows the dendritic locations of a subset of spines. Each spine is colored to indicate the group label from k-means clustering; the group label from k-means clustering is also indicated next to each spine. The s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ynaptic clusters convey functionally distinct spatial receptive field properties.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(17)30985-6&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Local order within global disorder: synaptic architecture of visual space.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Scholl, Daniel E. Wilson, David Fitzpatrick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuron, November 02 2017, Advance online publication.&lt;br /&gt;
DOI: doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.10.017&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helena Decker</name>
			<uri>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/"/>
			<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</id>
			<updated>2017-11-10T00:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Science Exchange Announces New Director of Scientific Content,  Gursatya “Guru” Singh</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/science-exchange-announces-new-director-of-scientific-content-gursatya-guru-singh/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1172</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T16:00:37+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/201722-round1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guru Singh Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1173&quot; height=&quot;174&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/201722-round1-300x174.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, November 2, 2017&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; –&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D), announced today that Gursatya “Guru” Singh has joined the company’s management team as Director of Scientific Content. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Adding Guru to our team is part of our ongoing commitment to strengthen the management team with industry experts who are dedicated to disrupting the traditional R&amp;amp;D outsourcing model,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO and co-founder of Science Exchange. “Guru’s experience in this industry will help us better inform the scientific community about the benefits of accessing innovation through the Science Exchange platform.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Singh’s background includes experience as a laboratory researcher and entrepreneur, as he has helped launch several life science startups. This included a previous role where he developed scientific content to promote the innovative services and technologies of scientific service providers. Singh also &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;has published several scientific papers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;A frequent blogger and thought leader in pharma and biotech outsourcing, Singh founded a Facebook group – Mysteries of Biotech – that has amassed nearly 5,000 followers.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;He holds a master’s degree in biotechnology from the University of Delaware and a bachelor’s degree in biotechnology from Sharda University in India.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“I am excited to join Science Exchange — the most trusted outsourcing platform for scientific products and services,” said Singh. “Science Exchange is a trailblazing company that is revolutionizing R&amp;amp;D outsourcing by helping companies around the world bring their innovations to market faster. I can’t think of a better place to be.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-07T18:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">No more than 800 orangutans from this newly identified species remain</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tapanuli-orangutans-endangered-sumatra"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tapanuli-orangutans-endangered-sumatra</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T16:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Endangered population of orangutans is the oldest surviving red ape lineage, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">More duplications for researcher accused of misconduct in lawsuit</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/02/duplications-researcher-accused-misconduct-lawsuit/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52433</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T15:30:16+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Despite losing a lawsuit against his former mentor, a researcher hasn’t stopped his efforts to discredit his mentor’s work. These efforts have led to new editorial notices — including, most recently, a correction and expression of concern for one paper by a former colleague, who wasn’t even the subject of the lawsuit. In the 2014 […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/02/duplications-researcher-accused-misconduct-lawsuit/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;More duplications for researcher accused of misconduct in lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-11-08T18:00:36+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Ants were among the world’s first farmers</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ants-were-among-worlds-first-farmers"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ants-were-among-worlds-first-farmers</id>
		<updated>2017-11-02T15:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 50 years ago, researchers began unraveling the secrets to Attine ants’ green thumbs.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-11-09T12:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
