<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml"/>
	<link href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"/>
	<id>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/atom.xml</id>
	<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:29+00:00</updated>
    <generator uri="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/">http://intertwingly.net/code/venus/</generator>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">What detecting gravitational waves means for the expansion of the universe</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-detecting-gravitational-waves-means-expansion-universe"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-detecting-gravitational-waves-means-expansion-universe</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T21:34:41+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 The latest LIGO signal proves that gravitational waves travel at the speed of light, ruling out a swath of cosmological theories in the process.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A new material may one day keep mussels off piers and boat hulls</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-material-may-one-day-keep-mussels-piers-and-boat-hulls"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-material-may-one-day-keep-mussels-piers-and-boat-hulls</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mussels don’t stick to a new lubricant-infused silicone material.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">iSpecimen and Science Exchange Announce Technology Integration to Allow Instant Access to Human Biospecimens</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/10/ispecimen-and-science-exchange-announce-technology-integration-to-allow-instant-access-to-human-biospecimens/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1158</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T16:13:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scientists in search of human biospecimens can now search the &lt;/em&gt;iSpecimen&lt;em&gt; Marketplace via Science Exchange as part of one seamless experience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xn-location&quot;&gt;LEXINGTON, Mass.&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;xn-location&quot;&gt;PALO ALTO, Calif.&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;xn-chron&quot;&gt;Oct. 24, 2017&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ —&lt;a class=&quot;linkOnClick&quot; data-include=&quot;300541759&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ispecimen.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iSpecimen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;linkOnClick&quot; data-include=&quot;300541759&quot; href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt; today announced a marketplace technology integration that will allow Science Exchange users to directly search for biospecimens available in the &lt;a class=&quot;linkOnClick&quot; data-include=&quot;300541759&quot; href=&quot;https://marketplace.ispecimen.com/signup/loginOrSignUp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iSpecimen Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; via a single user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science Exchange is the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services, and the iSpecimen Marketplace is the premier online platform instantly connecting life science researchers in need of human biospecimens with the healthcare organizations that have them. By integrating these two solutions, Science Exchange users will now have access in real time to more than 25 million banked and prospectively collected specimens, including biofluids, solid tissue, and cells, all available on the iSpecimen Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“iSpecimen shares our commitment to accelerating breakthrough scientific discovery through innovative technology,” said &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Iorns&lt;/span&gt;, PhD, Founder and CEO, Science Exchange. “With the seamless integration of the iSpecimen Marketplace and Science Exchange platform, our users gain direct, on-demand access to millions of human biospecimens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While iSpecimen has been available through Science Exchange since 2014, the new integration minimizes the time and complexity involved with specimen procurement. Additionally, the legal and compliance infrastructure in place for Science Exchange users reduces the risks often associated with biospecimen procurement. In the iSpecimen Marketplace, researchers have instant access to compliance documentation on a per specimen basis, giving researchers assurance before obtaining specimens that their requested samples were ethically sourced with appropriate regulatory oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The drive towards precision medicine is advancing the pace of research and increasing the need for biospecimens and related services,” said &lt;span class=&quot;xn-person&quot;&gt;Christopher Ianelli&lt;/span&gt;, MD, PhD, Founder and CEO, iSpecimen. “The integration of the iSpecimen Marketplace into the Science Exchange environment accelerates research by giving scientists broader access to specimens from within the world’s leading platform for outsourced scientific services. We are honored to be working with Science Exchange in this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers interested in iSpecimen and Science Exchange can learn more and see demonstrations this week at &lt;a class=&quot;linkOnClick&quot; data-include=&quot;300541759&quot; href=&quot;https://procureconpharma.wbresearch.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ProcureCon Pharma&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;span class=&quot;xn-location&quot;&gt;Philadelphia&lt;/span&gt;, where both Ianelli and Iorns will be speaking as part of a plenary panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Robotic docs can boost surgery time and cost</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robotic-docs-can-boost-surgery-time-and-cost"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robotic-docs-can-boost-surgery-time-and-cost</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T15:01:14+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Robots in the OR may not be worth the extra time or money for all procedures.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">The Most Important Thing We Can Do for Our Brain? Exercise!</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/10/24/the-most-important-thing-we-can-do-for-our-brain-exercise/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=23008</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T15:00:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;If I would have guessed ten years ago what the best way to train the brain would be, I would probably have thought about crossword puzzles, sudoku, or cognitive apps. But then I would be wrong. The best way is physical exercise. During the last decade, neuroscience has shown that physical exercise has extraordinary effects on our brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people know by now that exercise will improve their mood—but few know that it will boost &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of their cognitive abilities—memory, attention, creativity, and how we cope with stress. It all gets better in a way unparalleled by any drug, food-supplement, or cognitive training method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what happens in our brain when we move? First. the brain gets more blood. Bloodflow is increased by 20% while walking fast compared to sitting. More blood means more oxygen and nutrients. But increased bloodflow is only the beginning. The rate of neurogenesis—the formation of new brain cells—is increased by exercise. The newly born brain cells are formed in the dentate gyrus, a part of the hippocampus known as the “memory center”, and the effect is substantial. The hippocampus actually grew by 2% when a group of sedentary individuals walked regularly for a year. Typically, the hippocampus shrinks by up to 1% per year from our late twenties onwards, contributing to gradual memory loss as we get older. The exercise-based boost of hippocampal growth not only increases memory but improves mood. Exercise has been shown to be as efficient as antidepressants for mild and moderate depression, useful information in an age where more than one in ten adults are prescribed antidepressants in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How about kids? Exercise does wonders to children’s cognitive abilities and their ability to learn. Just 20 minutes of playing increases math and reading test scores. And this isn’t exclusive to tests in the lab, several studies have shown that kids in good shape actually perform better in school. Physical activity even seems to affect IQ! When data from the Swedish military service was analyzed from 1.2 million 18-year old male Swedes a clear pattern emerged—boys in good cardiovascular fitness had higher IQs, a result that was also apparent for identical twins. In a number of identical twins, one brother was in good shape while the other brother was not. The brother in good shape had a higher IQ than his identical twin—even though they, more or less, have identical genes (there can be small differences in identical twins) and have grown up together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list goes even further. Exercise can make us more creative. A recent study showed that creativity test results for divergent thinking (“brainstorming”) increased by more than 50% if participants had walked for 45 minutes before the test. The creativity-boost is temporary, we get more creative during 1-2 hours after exercise—probably due to increased blood flow, than we are back to our normal creativity-level. The takeaway message is: if you are stuck with a problem, then go for a walk or jog, and rethink of the problem an hour afterward and increase your chances of coming up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; is exercise so important for the brain? It is not at all obvious from our modern perspective but makes more sense if we look at our history. Our brains are basically the same today as they were 10 000 years ago. It was when our ancestors moved: during hunting, running from predators, and discovering new lands, that they really needed their cognitive abilities. That was when they needed to be attentive and have a memory to remember new experiences. That is why evolution has slowly tailored the brain in such a way that it benefits from exercise and that is why we still benefit from it today as our brains have not grossly changed since our ancestors days on the savanna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the human brain is fundamentally unchanged in the past 10 000 or even 20 000 years or so, our lifestyle has changed enormously. Modern sedentary lifestyle deprives many of us from getting enough physical activity, leading to vast consequences not only in terms of obesity and type-2 diabetes but also when it comes to wellbeing and how we function mentally. Exercise is not about sports. It is not about participating in a lifestyle. It is something we need to do for our brain and cognitive abilities since we have evolved for it. Now neuroscience is helping us to rediscover the brain-medicine that we forgot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/feed/#_ftnref1&quot; name=&quot;_ftn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Eriksson P et al (1998) Neurogenetis in the adult human hippocampous. Nature medicine. 4;1313–1317. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/3305&quot;&gt;10.1038/3305&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/feed/#_ftnref2&quot; name=&quot;_ftn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Alvarexz- Bueno C (2017) The Effect of Physical Activity Interventions on Children’s Cognition and Metacognition: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 56(9):729–738. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaac.2017.06.012&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jaac.2017.06.012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/feed/#_ftnref3&quot; name=&quot;_ftn3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; Åberg, M et al (2009) Cardiovascular fitness is associated with cognition in young adulthood. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 106(49):20906–11. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0905307106&quot;&gt;10.1073/pnas.0905307106&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/feed/#_ftnref4&quot; name=&quot;_ftn4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Oppezzo et al (2014) Give Your Ideas Some Legs: The Positive Effect of Walking on Creative Thinking Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition. 40(4):1142–1152. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1037/a0036577&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0036577&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Tumisu-148124/&quot;&gt;Tumisu&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Anders Hansen, MD, MSc</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Florida researcher “cherry picked” data, university investigation finds</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/24/florida-researcher-cherry-picked-data-university-investigation-finds/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52290</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T15:00:26+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A journal has retracted a 2014 paper after a university investigation found that the first author only reported certain data points that supported the paper’s conclusion. Based on a whistleblower’s tip, the University of Florida investigated work by Huabei Jiang, a professor of biomedical engineering, and Lei Yao, a former postdoc and scientist in Jiang’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/24/florida-researcher-cherry-picked-data-university-investigation-finds/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Florida researcher “cherry picked” data, university investigation finds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Unnamed institution makes baffling retraction requests, journals comply</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/24/unnamed-institution-makes-baffling-retraction-requests-journals-comply/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52251</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T12:00:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Two journals are retracting papers published by researchers affiliated with Children’s Hospital Los Angeles (CHLA). To be frank, we’re baffled by most of this story. The retraction notices say “the institution” requested the retractions, but don’t name it; the first and last authors are also affiliated with the University of Southern California, as well as […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/24/unnamed-institution-makes-baffling-retraction-requests-journals-comply/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unnamed institution makes baffling retraction requests, journals comply&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The psychology behind why we value physical objects over digital</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/24/the-psychology-behind-why-we-value-physical-objects-over-digital/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31333</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T07:30:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-467559030.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31421&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31421&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;African woman working at her own bookstore&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1427117781&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;M_a_y_a&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A woman with glasses working in a bookstore&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A woman with glasses working in a bookstore&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-467559030.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-467559030.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-467559030.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/24/the-psychology-behind-why-we-value-physical-objects-over-digital/a-woman-with-glasses-working-in-a-bookstore/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-467559030.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When technological advances paved the way for digital books, films and music, many commentators predicted the demise of their physical equivalents. It hasn’t happened, so far at least. For instance, while there is a huge market in e-books, print books remain dominant. A large part of the reason comes down to psychology – we value things that we own, or anticipate owning, in large part because &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-26/edition-8/psychology-stuff-and-things&quot;&gt;we see them as an extension of ourselves&lt;/a&gt;. And, stated simply, it’s easier to develop meaningful feelings of ownership over a physical entity than a digital one. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jcr/article-abstract/doi/10.1093/jcr/ucx102/4430295/Digital-Goods-Are-Valued-Less-Than-Physical-Goods?redirectedFrom=fulltext&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Consumer Research&lt;/em&gt; presents a series of studies that demonstrate this difference. “Our findings illustrate how psychological ownership engenders a difference in the perceived value of physical and digital goods, yielding new insights into the relationship between consumers and their possessions,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31333&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an initial study at a tourist destination, Ozgun Atasoy and Carey Morewedge arranged for 86 visitors to have their photograph taken with an actor dressed as a historical character. Half the visitors were given a digital photo (emailed to them straight away), the others were handed a physical copy. Then they were asked how much they were willing to pay, if anything, for their photo, with the proceeds going to charity. The recipients of a physical photo were willing to pay more, on average, and not because they thought the production costs were higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a similar story when Atasoy and Morewedge asked hundreds of American volunteers on the Amazon Mechanical Turk survey website to say what they would be willing to pay for either physical or digital versions of the book &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer’s Stone&lt;/em&gt; and physical or digital versions of the movie &lt;em&gt;Dark Knight&lt;/em&gt;. The participants placed higher monetary value on the physical versions, and this seemed to be because they expected to have a stronger sense of ownership for them (for the physical versions, they agreed more strongly with statements like “I will feel like I own it” and “feel like it is mine”). In contrast, participants’ anticipated enjoyment was the same for the different versions and so can’t explain the higher value placed on physical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In further studies, the researchers showed that the greater value that participants no longer placed higher value on physical objects over digital when they would be renting rather than buying – presumably because the greater appeal of owning something physical is irrelevant in this case. Likewise, the researchers found that participants who identified strongly with a particular movie (&lt;em&gt;The Empire Strikes Back&lt;/em&gt;) placed higher value on owning a physical copy versus digital, but participants who had no personal connection with the film did not. This fits the researchers’ theorising because the greater sense of ownership afforded by a physical product is only an enticing prospect when there’s a motivation to experience a strong sense of connection with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is a greater psychological sense of ownership that makes physical objects so appealing, then the researchers reasoned that people disposed with more “need for control” will be particularly attracted to them – after all, to own something is to control it. Atasoy and Morewedge found some support for this in their final study. The higher that participants scored on a “need for control scale” (they agreed with items like “I prefer doing my own planning”), the more than they tended to say that physical books would engender a greater sense of ownership, and, in turn, this was associated with their being willing to pay a higher amount for them, compared with digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings have some intriguing interesting implications for companies seeking to boost the appeal of digital products, the researchers said. Any interventions that might engender a greater psychological sense of ownership over digital entities will likely boost their value – such as allowing for personalisation or being able to interact with them in some way. Similarly, the results may help explain the ubiquity of digital piracy – because people generally place a lower value on digital products (even when they see the production costs as the same physical) it follows that many of us consider the theft of digital products as less serious than physical theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jcr/article-abstract/doi/10.1093/jcr/ucx102/4430295/Digital-Goods-Are-Valued-Less-Than-Physical-Goods?redirectedFrom=fulltext&quot;&gt;Digital Goods are Valued Less than Physical Goods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and author of the TED-ED Lesson &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ed.ted.com/lessons/why-are-we-so-attached-to-our-things-christian-jarrett&quot;&gt;Why are we so attached to our things?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31333/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31333/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31333&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T23:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">India gears up for second Moon mission</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3nsqeb14LH0/nature.2017.22870"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22870</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The Chandrayaan-2 orbiter, lander and rover will track how lunar dust might scupper settlement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22870&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22870&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3nsqeb14LH0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>T. V. Padma</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">To stay young, kill zombie cells</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/dImYrehIsOA/550448a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550448a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Killing off cells that refuse to die on their own has proved a powerful anti-ageing strategy in mice. Now it's about to be tested in humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 448 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550448a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550448a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/dImYrehIsOA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Megan Scudellari</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cancer biology still needs physicists</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3XGCUPm3YFo/550431a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550431a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Considering game theory and the role of physical forces could lead to better treatments for cancer, says Robert Austin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 431 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550431a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550431a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3XGCUPm3YFo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Robert Austin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Reclassify waste to shift the nuclear landscape</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/APLxbMGl1Qc/550429b"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550429b</id>
		<updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The US Department of Energy should classify and dispose of nuclear rubbish according to risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 429 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550429b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550429b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/APLxbMGl1Qc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Nature News &amp; Comment</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inbreeding hurts the next generation’s reproductive success</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/inbreeding-hurts-next-generations-reproductive-success"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/inbreeding-hurts-next-generations-reproductive-success</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T21:46:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Inbreeding has evolutionary consequences for humans.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mating with Neandertals reintroduced ‘lost’ DNA into modern humans</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mating-neandertals-reintroduced-lost-dna-modern-humans"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mating-neandertals-reintroduced-lost-dna-modern-humans</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T18:43:59+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Neandertal DNA brought back some old genetic heirlooms to modern humans.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">BS 138 John Medina: Brain Rules for Aging Well</title>
		<link href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/bs-138-john-medina-brain-rules-for-aging-well"/>
		<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/94a68dff718f8ec28f28443e860c2aa1</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T16:50:45+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;In BS 138 Dr. John Medina returns to discuss his latest book &lt;em&gt;Brain Rules for Aging Well: 10 Principles for Staying Vital, Happy, and Sharp&lt;/em&gt;. This is a lively discussion full of useful information for listeners of all ages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you listen via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com/iphone-apps/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;free &lt;em&gt;Brain Science&lt;/em&gt; mobile app&lt;/a&gt; you also listen to Dr. Medina's original interview (&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com/bsp/brain-rules-with-john-medina-bsp-37.html?rq=john%20medina&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BSP 37&lt;/a&gt;), which is included as Bonus content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Full show notes and episode transcripts are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&quot;&gt;http://brainsciencepodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note to Premium Subscribers: Premium content including episode transcripts is accessed via the free mobile app or by logging in at &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.libsyn.com/auth/login/show_id/18369&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://my.libsyn.com/auth/login/show_id/18369&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ginger Campbell, MD</name>
			<uri>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Science with Ginger Campbell, MD: Neuroscience for Everyone</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Show for Everyone with a Brain</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainsciencepodcast.libsyn.com/rss"/>
			<id>http://brainsciencepodcast.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T16:50:45+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Virginia Campbell, MD</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Veronica Alvarez PhD</title>
		<link href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Entries/2017/10/23_Veronica_Alvarez_PhD.html"/>
		<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/6b0ab5b8-8495-4baf-b36c-43f9591e8ae6</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T15:41:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 Veronica Alvarez (NIAAA) discusses her work using drugs of abuse to probe D2 mechanisms in striatal circuitry and their effect on behavior.  

Duration: 46 minutes

Discussants:(in alphabetical order)
Alfonso Apicella (Asst Prof, UTSA)
Carlos Paladini (Professor, UTSA)
Salma Quraishi (Res Asst Prof, UTSA)
Todd Troyer (Assoc Prof, UTSA) 
Matthew Wanat (Asst Prof, UTSA)
Charles Wilson (Ewing Halsell Chair, UTSA)

acknowledgement: JM Tepper for original music.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica Alvarez PhD</name>
			<uri>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">NEUROSCIENTISTS TALK SHOP</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Neuroscientists Talk Shop is the University of Texas at San Antonio's (UTSA) Neurobiology Podcast, showcasing the current research of internationally renowned guest Neuroscientists. Each episode features a moderated discussion with a cross section of UTSA</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://snrp.utsa.edu/Podcast/rss.xml"/>
			<id>http://snrp.utsa.edu/POD_html/Podcast/Podcast.html</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">Salma Quraishi</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Obsessed with getting cited? You may have “Publiphilia Impactfactorius”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/23/obsessed-getting-cited-may-publiphilia-impactfactorius/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52261</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T15:00:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;As a scientist, are you always focused on improving your metrics by such means as getting papers into prestigious journals? Do your funders and institutions add to that pressure to get ahead? If so, you may be at risk of a new psychiatric condition known as “Publiphilia Impactfactorius” — or, simply, PI, described in a PeerJ […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/23/obsessed-getting-cited-may-publiphilia-impactfactorius/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Obsessed with getting cited? You may have “Publiphilia Impactfactorius”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">One Ring to Rule Them All: Cure-all Drug for Neurodegenerative Conditions Possible</title>
		<link href="http://brainblogger.com/2017/10/23/one-ring-to-rule-them-all-single-drug-for-several-neurodegenerative-conditions-looks-possible/"/>
		<id>http://brainblogger.com/?p=22946</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T15:00:36+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;The secret to finding a single drug treatment for neurodegenerative conditions may lie in unfolding the mystery of misfolded proteins. Most of the non-infectious neurodegenerative diseases (like Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s) are characterized by progressive death of neurons due to the accumulation of misfolded proteins in brain cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the pathogenesis of these diseases we have to first understand proteins.  They are essential for building our body structures and functional regulation. Thus, there are thousands of different proteins with various functions. These proteins are made up of only 20 amino acids. These 20 amino acids are like the alphabet in a language, they can create thousands or millions of proteins when used in different combinations. A single misplaced letter in a word results in a spelling error. Similarly, a misplaced amino acid can create the wrong kind of protein. Misplaced words can create a grammatically wrong and incomprehensible sentence. In a similar fashion, misfolded proteins have no structural or functional value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important concept that has to be understood is how &lt;em&gt;prions&lt;/em&gt; are involved. From school books, we know that infections are caused by microorganisms like bacteria, fungi, and viruses. All of them have genetic material in the form of nucleic acids (as DNA or RNA, or both), that is essential for the reproduction or multiplication of these microorganisms. But prions, unlike microorganisms, are just protein chains that are infectious. These proteins, after entering the living organism, cause misfolding of proteinaceous infectious particles (PrPs). PrPs are found in all of us, our brain and neurons are especially rich in them. Their role, however, is still poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misfolded PrPs cause encephalopathies. These misfolded proteins are also thought to cause a chain reaction resulting in the misfolding of other proteins. These misfolded proteins propagate further like an infectious microorganism. What causes this chain reaction and propagation is still unclear. These chains of proteins are called prions. They cause Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease (CJD) in humans and bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE) in cattle. Prions have a long incubation period, it takes a long time for the disease to appear and progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many neurodegenerative diseases like Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s, misfolded proteins get progressively accumulated in brain cells, leading to the death of neurons. There is growing evidence that the prion-like process of &lt;em&gt;seeding&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;templated protein corruption&lt;/em&gt; are behind the progression of these diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PrP (healthy prion) is commonly found in our brain cells. However, when a defective prion protein is somehow introduced into the cells, it causes misfolding of newly forming PrP. This process is progressive and propagated like an infectious disease to the other cells. Thus, one of the potential treatment approaches is to block the propagation of this prion-like protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accumulation of these prion-like misfolded, mutant proteins is toxic for cells. The prolonged toxic stress produced in brain cells induces specific death pathways. Understanding how these toxic proteins cause stress for neurons and why the cells die could also help to find new treatment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With increasing evidence that prion-like mechanisms are behind the progression and propagation of most neurodegenerative disorders, scientists have started looking for methods to stop this propagation. One such method is the use of specific immunotherapy, where researchers are trying to develop vaccines that can cure these disorders, or at least stop disease progression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larger proteins in our body contain hundreds or thousands of amino acids in various combinations. These large proteins are folded into specific structures. If a protein is misfolded, it loses its specific structure too. It also loses its properties and becomes toxic for cells. One therapeutic approach aims to develop a vaccine that can activate our immune system (B and T cells) against these defective misfolded proteins so that they are destroyed in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this aim, scientist have tried two methods. One of them is to create a vaccine that works against very short chains of misfolded proteins called monomers. They exist while these proteins are being assembled. Another approach is to target the fully formed misfolded protein fibrils. However, both of these methods have so far failed to produce the intended results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, researchers are exploring a new strategy for the development of immunotherapy against these diseases. This strategy targets so-called “oligomers”. The oligomers are molecular intermediates that exist in the process of assembling the prion fibrils. They are not very small like monomers (initial building blocks of prions) and are also not fully formed prion fibrils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller monomers lack the antigenic properties (associated with protein structures called beta-sheets) of misfolded proteins that are needed for an immune response. Meanwhile, fully formed fibrils are too big to propagate through cell walls. Thus, it is quite possible that these oligomers play a critical role in the disease propagation processes. A vaccine or immunotherapy targeting these oligomers could be more effective in initiating an immune response against the misfolded pathological prions than their smaller or larger counterparts. Moreover, these intermediate oligomers are common to most neurodegenerative disorders, unlike fully formed fibrils that are specific to each disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this new approach has shown some success in animal models, there are several challenges to using such immunotherapy in humans. In humans, it is not easy to initiate the immune response because of “self-tolerance.” The misfolded proteins are very similar to normal proteins (normal PrPs). Even if this immune tolerance can be overcome, there is a risk of initiating the wrong kind of immune response against normal proteins. This may lead to sterile encephalopathy or another kind of damage. Further, the blood-brain barrier also poses a challenge: it is important that antibodies created by a vaccine are able to reach a good concentration in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, the idea of having just a single approach to treat all (or at least most) types of neurodegeneration is clearly exciting. These diseases have lots in common in terms of the molecular mechanisms involved, and it is quite likely that immunotherapy targeting all of them can be developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frost, B., Diamond, M.I., 2010. Prion-like Mechanisms in Neurodegenerative Diseases. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 11, 155–159. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2786&quot;&gt;10.1038/nrn2786&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goedert, M., Clavaguera, F., Tolnay, M., 2010. The propagation of prion-like protein inclusions in neurodegenerative diseases. Trends Neurosci. 33, 317–325. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2010.04.003&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.tins.2010.04.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marciniuk, K., Taschuk, R., Napper, S., 2013. Evidence for Prion-Like Mechanisms in Several Neurodegenerative Diseases: Potential Implications for Immunotherapy. J. Immunol. Res. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1155/2013/473706&quot;&gt;10.1155/2013/473706&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rao, R.V., Bredesen, D.E., 2004. Misfolded proteins, endoplasmic reticulum stress and neurodegeneration. Curr. Opin. Cell Biol. 16, 653–662. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceb.2004.09.012&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.ceb.2004.09.012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker, L.C., Diamond, M.I., Duff, K.E., Hyman, B.T., 2013. Mechanisms of Protein Seeding in Neurodegenerative Diseases. JAMA Neurol. 70, 304–310. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.1453&quot;&gt;10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.1453&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/frolicsomepl-54573/&quot;&gt;frolicsomepl&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Viatcheslav Wlassoff, PhD</name>
			<uri>http://brainblogger.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Brain Blogger</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Health and Science Blog Covering Brain Topics</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://brainblogger.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://brainblogger.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:26+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">QB3 Signs Partnership with Science Exchange</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/10/qb3-signs-partnership-with-science-exchange/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1155</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T13:51:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/qb3-science-exchange.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Qb3 Partners With Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1157&quot; height=&quot;107&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/qb3-science-exchange-300x107.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Bay Area Life Science Hub Enables its Startups to Stay Lean with Science Exchange’s R&amp;amp;D Platform&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, October 23, 2017&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, a platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services, today announced a partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;http://qb3.org/&quot;&gt;QB3&lt;/a&gt;, the University of California hub for innovation and entrepreneurship for life sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through an exclusive Science Exchange-QB3 marketplace, QB3-affiliated companies will now have access to a customized and secure marketplace where they can instantly order R&amp;amp;D services from a network of more than 2,500 qualified scientific service providers. Science Exchange’s scientific concierge staff also will offer support to QB3’s start-up companies in identifying innovative providers and ordering complex R&amp;amp;D services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Science Exchange will help accelerate our companies by giving them access to providers that are experienced with entrepreneurial research and that have already been reviewed and qualified,” said Ioana Aanei, Ph.D., Entrepreneurship Program Manager at QB3. “Many of our startups don’t have the resources to purchase their own capital equipment or do the necessary specialized scientific research in-house.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Science Exchange is committed to helping life science companies bring innovative, potentially life-saving products to market,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Science Exchange. “While QB3’s companies focus on discovery, we can help eliminate the barriers, including the time and expertise needed to research and qualify contract research organizations (CROs) and scientific service providers. We also help save time and money in contract negotiation, all while ensuring the protection of intellectual property.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QB3 joins more than 30 enterprise clients and entrepreneurial incubators that are efficiently managing their outsourced R&amp;amp;D with Science Exchange-powered marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About QB3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QB3 is the University of California’s hub for innovation and entrepreneurship in the life sciences. The institute supports UC researchers and empowers Bay Area entrepreneurs to launch startup companies and partner with industry. QB3 helps bio-entrepreneurs create hundreds of high-value jobs and bring more than $750 million into the Bay Area each year. With campus divisions at Berkeley, San Francisco, and Santa Cruz, QB3 is also affiliated with the San Francisco incubator QB3@953 — home to more than 45 companies — and the seed-stage venture capital firm Mission Bay Capital. Visit us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://qb3.org/&quot;&gt;http://qb3.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice: An “absolutely perfect retraction”</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/23/caught-notice-absolutely-perfect-retraction/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52219</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T12:00:08+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When Retraction Watch began in 2010, our co-founders Ivan Oransky and Adam Marcus quickly realized they couldn’t keep up with the hundreds of retractions that appeared each year.  And the problem has only gotten worse — although we’ve added staff, the number of retractions issued each year has increased dramatically. According to our growing database, more than 1300 […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/23/caught-notice-absolutely-perfect-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: An “absolutely perfect retraction”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How bird feeders may be changing great tits’ beaks</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-bird-feeders-may-be-changing-great-tits-beaks"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-bird-feeders-may-be-changing-great-tits-beaks</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Longer beaks may be evolving in U.K. great tits because of the widespread use of bird feeders in the country.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">We know intuitively how many lay opinions outweigh an expert</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/23/we-know-intuitively-how-many-lay-opinions-outweigh-an-expert/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31252</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T08:30:52+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_31265&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-538745770.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31265&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31265&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LONDON, ENGLAND - JUNE 09: Justice Secretary Michael Gove gives a speech at the 'Vote Leave' campaign headquarters in Westminster on June 8, 2016 in London, England. Mr Gove was today joined by Justice Minister Dominic Raab as they made a case for Britain leaving the European Union on the basis of increased border control and security. Britain will go to the polls in a referendum on the 23rd of June on whether or not to leave the European Union. (Photo by Jack Taylor\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1465385551&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2016 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;185&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Michael Gove Discusses How EU Membership Weakens British Border Control And Threatens Our Security&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Michael Gove Discusses How EU Membership Weakens British Border Control And Threatens Our Security&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-538745770.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-538745770.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-538745770.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,639&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/23/we-know-intuitively-how-many-lay-opinions-outweigh-an-expert/michael-gove-discusses-how-eu-membership-weakens-british-border-control-and-threatens-our-security/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-538745770.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;“People in this country have had enough of experts” claimed Michael Gove last year. New findings suggest we weigh popular and expert opinion intuitively&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine contemplating which treatment to undertake for a health problem. Your specialist explains there are two possibilities, and strongly endorses one as right for you. But when you discuss it with a friend, she suggests that based on what she’s heard, the other would be better. Another friend, the same. And another. Does there come a point where the friends outweigh the expert? Given enough information – the accuracy of the expert in the past, the degree to which the public have any insight on the issue – you can in theory mathematically “solve” this issue with a probabilistic model. In fact, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13546783.2017.1378721&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;i&gt;Thinking and Reasoning&lt;/i&gt;, that’s exactly what we do intuitively and with a high degree of accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31252&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a collaboration between Radboud University Nijmegen and University College London, Jos Hornikx’s team asked 146 Dutch adults, most commonly educated to graduate level with an average age of 31, to evaluate five scenarios each involving a public policy decision such as whether to create car-free zones in a city and whether it would impact the number of shop customers. In each scenario, an expert (in this case, a professor of retail marketing) had given a recommendation for or against the proposal, and participants were told their track record – e.g. they had been correct in 80 per cent of previous zoning decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each participant was also told that a subset of the public – for example, local road workers (with no formal training in the topic) – had disagreed with the expert view. Participants were told how much these non-experts had insight into the relevant issues – this varied from participant to participant, with some told the non-experts had been correct only 51 per cent of the time, others as high as 60 per cent. Participants were then asked how many non-experts would need to hold a dissenting view to outweigh the single expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team made a probability model using Bayes’ theorem of belief revision: this shows how much you should shift your initial opinion in the face of new contradictory information. In the current context, the model showed exactly what volume of laypeople should be seen as a counterpoint to an expert, at each of the degrees of accuracy. The researchers evaluated whether human intuition came close to this. It turns out it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, in the zoning situation, participants judged that when lay people had only the barest insight – they’d been right just 51 per cent of the time in the past – you would need a group of 40 expressing the same shared opinion to counter a single expert (with an 80 per cent accuracy record) – a judgment that’s in the ballpark of what the statistical model recommended. When the lay group were said to be more accurate, at 55 per cent or 60 per cent, participants judged that just ten in agreement would outweigh the expert – again, in line with the ideal model. The only place where participants really deviated from the ideal was in a scenario where the expert was suggested to have extremely high accuracy (99.99 per cent), which theoretically outmatches even a few hundred low-insight laypeople. The participants imagined that 50 non-experts would be enough to outweigh an expert in this case, suggesting it’s hard for us to process these high-number levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings suggest we should stop talking about the public and experts as if we have to put our faith in one or the other. Given reasonable context and space to think, we can weigh both in our judgments. It may be rhetorically convenient for advocates to trash experts, or poor scorn on the public, but we can sidestep those claims, to draw on both everyday and specialised wisdom to inform our decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13546783.2017.1378721&quot;&gt;How many laypeople holding a popular opinion are needed to counter an expert opinion?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: The then Justice Secretary Michael Gove gives a speech at the “Vote Leave” campaign headquarters in Westminster on June 8, 2016 in London, England (Photo by Jack Taylor/Getty Images).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31252/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31252/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31252&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Iranian scholar sentenced to death</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rm4sXQaIWqg/nature.2017.22875"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22875</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ahmadreza Djalali, a researcher in disaster medicine, has 20 days to appeal against his death sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22875&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22875&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rm4sXQaIWqg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Michele Catanzaro</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Shrew skulls shrink for winter survival</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/mpvXCt3bvI8/nature.2017.22874"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22874</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Getting smaller by absorbing bone tissue may help animals to save energy when food is scarce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22874&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22874&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/mpvXCt3bvI8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emma Young</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Association analysis identifies 65 new breast cancer risk loci</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/6zPSK286mQU/nature24284"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24284</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Breast cancer risk is influenced by rare coding variants in susceptibility genes, such as BRCA1, and many common, mostly non-coding variants. However, much of the genetic contribution to breast cancer risk remains unknown. Here we report the results of a genome-wide association study of breast cancer in 122,977 cases and 105,974 controls of European ancestry and 14,068 cases and 13,104 controls of East Asian ancestry. We identified 65 new loci that are associated with overall breast cancer risk at P &amp;lt; 5 × 10−8. The majority of credible risk single-nucleotide polymorphisms in these loci fall in distal regulatory elements, and by integrating in silico data to predict target genes in breast cells at each locus, we demonstrate a strong overlap between candidate target genes and somatic driver genes in breast tumours. We also find that heritability of breast cancer due to all single-nucleotide polymorphisms in regulatory features was 2–5-fold enriched relative to the genome-wide average, with strong enrichment for particular transcription factor binding sites. These results provide further insight into genetic susceptibility to breast cancer and will improve the use of genetic risk scores for individualized screening and prevention. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24284&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24284&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/6zPSK286mQU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kyriaki Michailidou</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Locomotor speed control circuits in the caudal brainstem</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tAafvw2ZXP8/nature24064"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24064</id>
		<updated>2017-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Locomotion is a universal behaviour that provides animals with the ability to move between places. Classical experiments have used electrical microstimulation to identify brain regions that promote locomotion, but the identity of neurons that act as key intermediaries between higher motor planning centres and executive circuits in the spinal cord has remained controversial. Here we show that the mouse caudal brainstem encompasses functionally heterogeneous neuronal subpopulations that have differential effects on locomotion. These subpopulations are distinguishable by location, neurotransmitter identity and connectivity. Notably, glutamatergic neurons within the lateral paragigantocellular nucleus (LPGi), a small subregion in the caudal brainstem, are essential to support high-speed locomotion, and can positively tune locomotor speed through inputs from glutamatergic neurons of the upstream midbrain locomotor region. By contrast, glycinergic inhibitory neurons can induce different forms of behavioural arrest mapping onto distinct caudal brainstem regions. Anatomically, descending pathways of glutamatergic and glycinergic LPGi subpopulations communicate with distinct effector circuits in the spinal cord. Our results reveal that behaviourally opposing locomotor functions in the caudal brainstem were historically masked by the unexposed diversity of intermingled neuronal subpopulations. We demonstrate how specific brainstem neuron populations represent essential substrates to implement key parameters in the execution of motor programs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24064&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24064&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tAafvw2ZXP8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Paolo Capelli</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">‘Killer Hurricanes’ reconstructs the past to predict storms of the future</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/killer-hurricanes-reconstructs-past-predict-storms-future"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/killer-hurricanes-reconstructs-past-predict-storms-future</id>
		<updated>2017-10-22T12:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Geologists find clues to the future of deadly hurricanes, written in stone and sand, in the new NOVA documentary “Killer Hurricanes.”</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">&quot;Hyper Brains&quot;? High Intelligence and Health</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9194"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9194</id>
		<updated>2017-10-22T10:33:24+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A few weeks ago I blogged about the idea that high-IQ people suffer from an inability to communicate with less gifted folk. Now, a new paper claims that very intelligent people are more prone to mental illnesses and allergies.



However, I don't think the paper is very smart.

Researchers Ruth I. Karpinski and colleagues surveyed the members of American Mensa, a society for people in the top 2% of IQ (IQ 130+). 3,715 Mensans responded to the survey, which asked them whether they were curr</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Weekend reads: A proposal to end NSF watchdog; Power pose criticism redux; A limit to lifetime word count?</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/21/weekend-reads-proposal-end-nsf-watchdog-power-pose-criticism-redux-limit-lifetime-word-count/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52270</id>
		<updated>2017-10-21T13:33:31+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a journal that will pay authors royalties, a new estimate of how many papers are affected by contaminated cell lines, and threats by more than 20 researchers at Johns Hopkins to resign from a journal’s editorial board if a paper isn’t retracted. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Sen. Rand […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/21/weekend-reads-proposal-end-nsf-watchdog-power-pose-criticism-redux-limit-lifetime-word-count/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A proposal to end NSF watchdog; Power pose criticism redux; A limit to lifetime word count?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ivan Oransky</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Pollution killed 9 million people in 2015</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollution-killed-9-million-people-2015"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollution-killed-9-million-people-2015</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T21:50:57+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 First global look estimates the massive human and financial toll caused by pollution-related health problems.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Beil</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Dawn spacecraft will keep orbiting the dwarf planet Ceres indefinitely</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/dawn-spacecraft-ceres-mission-extension"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/dawn-spacecraft-ceres-mission-extension</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T19:15:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 NASA just gave the Dawn spacecraft a second mission extension to orbit Ceres indefinitely.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html">Problematic Neuropeptides And Statistics (PNAS)</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9180"/>
		<id>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9180</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T16:17:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Back in May I discussed a paper published in PNAS which, I claimed, was using scientific terminology in a sloppy way. The authors, Pearce et al., used the word &quot;neuropeptides&quot; to refer to six molecules, but three of them weren't neuropeptides at all. The authors acknowledged this minor error and issued a correction.



Now, it emerges that there may be more serious problems with the PNAS paper. In a letter published last week, researchers Patrick Jern and colleagues say that the statistics u</content>
		<author>
			<name>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic</name>
			<uri>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Neuroskeptic</title>
			<subtitle type="html">No brain. No gain.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic"/>
			<id>http://discovermagazine.com/rss/blog-feeds/neuroskeptic</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Retract, replace, retract: Beleaguered food researcher pulls article from JAMA journal (again)</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/20/retract-replace-retract-beleaguered-food-researcher-pulls-article-jama-journal/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52253</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T15:54:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A high-profile food researcher who’s faced heavy criticism about his work has retracted the revised version of an article he’d already retracted last month. Yes, you read that right: Brian Wansink at Cornell University retracted the original article from JAMA Pediatrics in September, replacing it with a revised version. Now he’s retracting the revised version, citing […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/20/retract-replace-retract-beleaguered-food-researcher-pulls-article-jama-journal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retract, replace, retract: Beleaguered food researcher pulls article from JAMA journal (again)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Scientists battle over whether violence has declined over time</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-battle-over-whether-violence-has-declined-over-time"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-battle-over-whether-violence-has-declined-over-time</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T13:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 People are no more violent in small-scale societies than in states, researchers contend.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bruce Bower</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Estimate: Nearly 33,000 papers include misidentified cell lines. Experts talk ways to combat growing problem</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/20/estimate-nearly-33000-papers-include-misidentified-cell-lines-experts-talk-ways-combat-growing-problem/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52226</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T12:00:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Although most researchers realize too many are using misidentified cell lines in their work, they may be shocked to see the scope of the problem: Approximately 32,755 articles report on research that relied on misidentified cells, according to a new report in PLoS ONE. And even though more people may be aware of the problem, it […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/20/estimate-nearly-33000-papers-include-misidentified-cell-lines-experts-talk-ways-combat-growing-problem/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Estimate: Nearly 33,000 papers include misidentified cell lines. Experts talk ways to combat growing problem&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Resurrecting extinct species raises ethical questions</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/resurrecting-extinct-species-raises-ethical-questions"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/resurrecting-extinct-species-raises-ethical-questions</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T11:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 'Rise of the Necrofauna' examines the technical and ethical challenges of bringing woolly mammoths and other long-gone creatures back from the dead.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The effect of emotions on your behaviour depends partly on your expectations</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/20/the-effect-of-emotions-on-your-behaviour-depends-partly-on-your-expectations/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31283</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T09:47:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-598165432.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31304&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31304&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;18&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A multi-exposure of an emotional woman.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1472637975&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sdominick&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;65&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman's Emotional Struggle&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woman’s Emotional Struggle&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-598165432.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-598165432.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-598165432.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/20/the-effect-of-emotions-on-your-behaviour-depends-partly-on-your-expectations/womans-emotional-struggle/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-598165432.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you get a better result from a business negotiation if you get angry or remain calm? What about a creative task – will you come up with more solutions to a problem if you’re excited, or relaxed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer, according a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-29279-001&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Emotion&lt;/i&gt;, is that it depends at least in part on what you &lt;i&gt;expect &lt;/i&gt;the impacts of emotions to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some theories linking emotion and behaviour hold that emotions activate fixed behavioural “programmes” (anger activates aggressive actions, for example). Others hold that while emotions do influence behaviour, how they do so depends upon the individual’s past experiences, and the current context. (Faced with a bullying boss, the anger you feel may lead you respond aggressively, if this has worked for you in the past; alternatively, it may prompt you to go off and strengthen bonds with colleagues.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maya Tamir and Yochanan Bigman at the Hebrew University in Jerusalem, Israel, reasoned that if this second class of theory is correct, a given emotion will lead to a particular behaviour if a person expects it to do so – but if that expectation is not there, it won’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31283&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first experiment, the researchers told volunteers that, as part of a study on peer influence, they would be completing a real negotiation task, with financial consequences. The negotiation was over the sharing of coloured chips. Each participant was given a table showing the monetary value of the chips, but they were also told that the other person’s table may not show the same values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going into the negotiation, half were assigned to an “angry” condition. They read testimonials purporting to be from people who had previously been successful at the negotiation task that included comments like, “Throughout the negotiation, I was persistent. Eventually I got angry and my partner felt compelled to give me what I wanted.” They also listened to “angry” music (music rated in a pilot study as inducing feelings of anger), such as &lt;i&gt;Inquisition&lt;/i&gt; by the cello metal – yes, cello metal – band &lt;i&gt;Apocalyptica&lt;/i&gt;. The control group read testimonials that did not mention emotions, but recommended being “reasonable”. They listened to music deemed to be emotionally neutral. Finally, the volunteers described their current emotional state, then went into the negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that the volunteers who said they felt angry made more money, but only &lt;i&gt;if &lt;/i&gt;they’d read the testimonials advocating the benefits of anger, not if they hadn’t. Those who’d read the emotionally neutral testimonials did equally well, whether they felt angry or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another experiment, Tamir and Bigman recruited 159 more students, to look at how expectations about anger might affect performance on a first-person shooter video game.  Half the group was led to believe, via accounts from previous players, that feeling angry would help them kill more baddies, while the other half was led to believe that feeling calm would be beneficial. Those who expected anger to boost their performance played better if they actually felt angry, rather than relatively calm; in contrast, angry participants in the “calm is good” condition didn’t show this advantage. However, against the researchers’ expectations, feeling calm didn’t help the ‘calm is good’ group perhaps because in this context, the lower physiological arousal associated with calmness is a disadvantage, regardless of beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the final study, the researchers switched to creativity. Among people who were encouraged to believe that excitement benefits creativity, those who reported feeling excited did better (as measured by how many uses they could come up with for a brick) than those who reported feeling calm. In contrast, among the “calm is good” group, those who felt calm performed better than those who felt more excited – showing that there are contexts where a low arousal state can be advantageous if you believe it to be so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, more work is needed to explore just what types of performance can be influenced by expectations about the impacts of emotions, and actual emotional states. But this work does show that, as the researchers conclude, “At least in some cases, what we expect emotions to do may determine what they actually do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-29279-001&quot;&gt;Expectations Influence How Emotions Shape Behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31283/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31283/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31283&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T23:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Photons pair up like superconducting electrons</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xm-bVg4Z7rI/nature.2017.22868"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22868</id>
		<updated>2017-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Discovery raises questions about how a light 'supercurrent' might behave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22868&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22868&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xm-bVg4Z7rI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Doubling up on ‘junk DNA’ helps make us human</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/doubling-junk-dna-helps-make-us-human"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/doubling-junk-dna-helps-make-us-human</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T22:18:32+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 DNA duplicated only in humans may contribute to human traits and disease.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Tina Hesman Saey</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Laws to protect athletes’ brains do reduce concussions — eventually</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/laws-protect-athletes-brains-do-reduce-concussions-eventually"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/laws-protect-athletes-brains-do-reduce-concussions-eventually</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T21:11:43+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Recurrent concussions among high school athletes went down about 2½ years after traumatic brain injury laws were on the books, a new study finds.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Open Access Week 2017 – Open in Order to…</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/UT4KiqoBc2Y/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7783</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T18:45:58+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2016/10/OA-sunrise_690x320-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a proud co-founder of Open Access Week, we hope you will join us in celebrating progress and promoting awareness to help make Open Access – the founding principle of PLOS – the new norm in scholarship and research globally.&lt;/strong&gt; This year’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/2017-open-access-week-theme&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt; is “Open in Order to…” and invites the community to focus on what openness enables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since PLOS’ beginning, we’ve been open in order to accelerate progress in science and medicine through publishing, advocacy and innovation to benefit the research community and beyond. PLOS is open in order to ensure that: research outcomes are discoverable, accessible and available for discussion; science communication is constructive, transparent and verifiable; and publishing advances reproducibility, transparency and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Join PLOS in an Open Access Week Event (and find &lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccessweek.org/events&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;other events&lt;/a&gt; near you):&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wed 10/25 5:30–8:00 pm PDT &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://evite.me/zm1rE4XmwC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open House &amp;amp; Poetry Slam at PLOS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Please join us at the PLOS office for refreshments, office tours to see how we work and an Open Mic Poetry Slam with guests invited to share poems, songs, or free verse on the OA Week theme: “Open in order to….” We’ll have fun prizes for all who choose to share!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wed 10/25–Fri 10/27 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.force2017.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FORCE 2017 | Changing the Culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/people#loc-alison-mudditt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alison Mudditt&lt;/a&gt;, PLOS Chief Executive Officer and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/s/staff-editors#loc-emma-ganley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emma Ganley&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology &lt;/em&gt;Chief Editor will be in Berlin at this conference that brings together a diverse group of people interested in changing the way in which scholarly and scientific information is communicated and shared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wed 10/25–Fri 10/27 &lt;a href=&quot;http://biobankingcongress.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Leaders in Biobanking Congress 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/author/sdenker/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sheryl Denker&lt;/a&gt;, PLOS Communications Editor, will be in Nashville presenting on Open Access, Data and Methods Considerations for Publishing in Precision Medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thu 10/26 1:00–2:30 pm PDT &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://events.berkeley.edu/index.php/calendar/sn/library?event_ID=109902&amp;amp;date=2017-10-26&amp;amp;filter=Secondary%20Event%20Type&amp;amp;filtersel=1936&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Understanding the (Changing) Realm of Peer Review&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/s/staff-editors#loc-lauren-richardson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lauren Richardson&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;PLOS Biology &lt;/i&gt;Associate Editor) is participating in this panel discussion at UC Berkeley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fri 10/27 9:00 am–1:15 pm BST &lt;a href=&quot;https://library.medschl.cam.ac.uk/blog/2017/10/helping-researchers-publish-stem/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Helping Researchers Publish in STEM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/s/staff-editors#loc-nicola-stead&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nicola Stead&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/i&gt; Senior Editor) is speaking at this University of Cambridge session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Explore PLOS Journals – which have now published more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/07/publishing-milestone-plos-research-articles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;200,000 research articles&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Celebrate the journal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/plosone10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tenth Anniversary&lt;/a&gt;: browse &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/s/plos-one-10-year-anniversary-collections&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collections&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/category/meet-the-editors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;meet the editors&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2017/10/05/the-winner-of-the-plos-one-tenth-anniversary-t-shirt-design-contest-is/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;winning T-shirt design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/mj-Hs8yD5ek&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;watch a video&lt;/a&gt; about why authors choose to publish with us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Learn about &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/open-highlights-antibiotic-resistance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;antibiotic resistance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/open-highlights-appetite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;appetite&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/open-highlights-roots-of-autism&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;autism&lt;/a&gt; and more in &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/s/open-highlights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Highlights&lt;/a&gt; and hear from scientists why &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/research-matters-biology&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Research Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Browse Special Issues that bring together original research and commentary: &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/trauma-special-issue&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Traumatic Injury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/dementia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dementia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/diabetes-prevention&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Diabetes Prevention&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/cancer-genome&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Translating the Cancer Genome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Explore the latest Focus Feature: &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/network-approaches&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Network Approaches and Applications in Biology&lt;/a&gt;, the popular &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ten-simple-rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ten Simple Rules&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/compbiol-methods&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Methods&lt;/a&gt; Collections and &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/topic-pages&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Topic Pages&lt;/a&gt;–where PLOS Comp Bio meets Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Find out who won this year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/genetics-research-prize/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/i&gt; Research Prize&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/biologue/2017/09/21/genetics-and-microbiome-of-cattle-methane-production-2017-plos-genetics-research-prize-winning-research/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;learn more&lt;/a&gt; about the winning research, submit a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/biologue/2017/04/12/continuing-to-bridge-the-journal-wikipedia-gap-introducing-topic-pages-for-plos-genetics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Topic Page&lt;/a&gt;, browse &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/up-for-a-challenge&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Up For a Challenge – Stimulating Innovation in Breast Cancer Genetic Epidemiology&lt;/a&gt; featuring winning articles from this National Cancer Institute competition and read &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1006448&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bringing &lt;i&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/i&gt; Editors to Preprint Servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Join us in celebrating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/plosntds10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ten years of serving the global community&lt;/a&gt;, browse the the &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ntds-10th-anniversary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;10th Anniversary Collection&lt;/a&gt;, meet journal staff and editors at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/astmh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ASTMH&lt;/a&gt; (Nov 5–9, Booth 313) and respond to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2017/07/23/plos-neglected-tropical-diseases-vectors-collection-a-call-for-papers/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Call for Papers&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/vectors&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vector-borne diseases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Dive into “lessons-that-last” with &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/s/pearls&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pearls&lt;/a&gt;, a living collection of 400+ short, educational articles with practical insights for trainees and scientists at all career stages, share &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/research-matters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Research Matters&lt;/a&gt; – a collection that aims to enhance the public’s understanding of the benefits of basic research – and respond to the call for papers on &lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/bridging-communities&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bridging Communities: Co- and Polymicrobial Infections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Channels&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/cholera&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cholera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/tuberculosis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tuberculosis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Source Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Veterans Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research&lt;/a&gt;: PLOS Channels present content curated by experts from PLOS journals as well as the broader literature with commentary, blogs, news and discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Be Open in Order to:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Distinguish yourself &lt;/b&gt;– create a record of your scholarly contributions by registering for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/orcid&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ORCiD ID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Get early credit and feedback with preprints&lt;/b&gt; – listen to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/10/24/episode26/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOScast&lt;/a&gt; with Jessica Polka (ASAPbio Director), learn the &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005473&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ten Simple Rules&lt;/a&gt; to consider regarding preprint submission and explore the best of both worlds with &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/10/the-best-of-both-worlds-preprints-and-journals/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprints and journals &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Promote reproducibility of research&lt;/b&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/04/protocols-io-tools-for-reproducibility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;receive credit for methods&lt;/a&gt; while saving time and resources and explore &lt;i&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/i&gt;’s approach to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2017/06/14/promoting-reproducibility/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;promoting reproducibility&lt;/a&gt; by emphasizing reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Share your data &lt;/b&gt;– see how &lt;i&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/i&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2017/05/08/making-progress-toward-open-data/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;making progress toward open data&lt;/a&gt; and learn why this is particularly critical to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/02/optimism-on-rare-disease-day-with-research-possibilities-are-limitless/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advance discovery&lt;/a&gt; of treatments and cures for rare diseases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Succeed&lt;/b&gt; – play an active role in accelerating the dissemination of your work with PLOS’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/10/manuscripts-take-flight/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;latest journal transfer option&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get involved:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Learn about &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sparcopen.org/our-work/fastr/act/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;FASTR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – As Open Access takes center stage with the Fair Access to Science and Technology Research Act in Congress, PLOS reaffirms its commitment to and support of Open Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vote for your favorite &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveygizmo.com/s3/3018953/Top-Ten-Taxa-2017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;PLOS Paleo Open Access Taxa of 2017&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; by Nov 15&lt;/b&gt; – authors of the winning paper will receive a commissioned sketch of their new taxa (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/paleocomm/2017/10/02/vote-for-the-top-10-taxa-of-2017/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;learn more&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join the conversation with &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/ama-schedule&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;PLOS Science Wednesdays&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; 1:00 pm EDT &lt;/b&gt;– the Ask Me Anything (AMA) series with PLOS authors on redditscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Listen to the So Crazy It Might Work podcast &lt;/b&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/so-crazy-podcast/idea-2-end-the-stranglehold-of&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;End the stranglehold of scientific journals&lt;/a&gt; with Mark Johnson, PLOS Director of Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publish with PLOS and share your work with the world&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/which-journal-is-right-for-me&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; which journal&lt;/a&gt; is the right fit for your work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/search&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Search PLOS articles&lt;/a&gt; to see where your colleagues are publishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore &lt;a href=&quot;http://researchnews.plos.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Research News&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://researchnews.plos.org/category/author-interview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;author interviews&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://researchnews.plos.org/category/video-highlights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video highlights&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://researchnews.plos.org/category/new-research&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://researchnews.plos.org/category/news-summaries&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;summaries&lt;/a&gt; of newly published PLOS articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Stay in touch with PLOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.plos.org/registration/new&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;updates and eTOCs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow PLOS on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/plos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/PLOS.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/groups/7061842&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/conference-calendar&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;upcoming conferences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Have a great Open Access Week!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/UT4KiqoBc2Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Allison Hawxhurst</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The next wave of bird flu could be worse than ever</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/next-wave-bird-flu-could-be-worse-ever"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/next-wave-bird-flu-could-be-worse-ever</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T18:33:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Deadly bird flu can pass between ferrets through the air.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laurel Hamers</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Gene editing in the brain gets a major upgrade</title>
		<link href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/gene-editing-in-the-brain-gets-a-major-upgrade/"/>
		<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10191</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T16:00:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;h4&gt;Scientists develop a new tool for precise genome editing in neurons&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genome editing technologies have revolutionized biomedical science, providing a fast and easy way to modify genes. However, the technique allowing scientists to carryout the most precise edits, doesn’t work in cells that are no longer dividing – which includes most neurons in the brain. This technology had limited use in brain research, until now. Research Fellow Jun Nishiyama, M.D., Ph.D., Research Scientist, Takayasu Mikuni, M.D., Ph.D., and Scientific Director, Ryohei Yasuda, Ph.D. at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI) have developed a new tool that, for the first time, allows precise genome editing in mature neurons, opening up vast new possibilities in neuroscience research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel and powerful tool utilizes the newly discovered gene editing technology of CRISPR-Cas9, a viral defense mechanism originally found in bacteria. When placed inside a cell such as a neuron, the CRISPR-Cas9 system acts to damage DNA in a specifically targeted place. The cell then subsequently repairs this damage using predominantly two opposing methods; one being non-homologous end joining (NHEJ), which tends to be error prone, and homology directed repair (HDR), which is very precise and capable of undergoing specified gene insertions. HDR is the more desired method, allowing researchers flexibility to add, modify, or delete genes depending on the intended purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coaxing cells in the brain to preferentially make use of the HDR DNA repair mechanism has been rather challenging. HDR was originally thought to only be available as a repair route for actively proliferating cells in the body. When precursor brain cells mature into neurons, they are referred to as post-mitotic or nondividing cells, making the mature brain largely inaccessible to HDR – or so researchers previously thought. The team has now shown that it is possible for post-mitotic neurons of the brain to actively undergo HDR, terming the strategy “vSLENDR (viral mediated single-cell labeling of endogenous proteins by CRISPR-Cas9-mediated homology-directed repair).” The critical key to the success of this process is the combined use of CRISPR-Cas9 and a virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adeno-associated virus (AAV) is a low immunogenic, nontoxic virus utilized by scientists as an efficient delivery mechanism for all kinds of genes. This virus can effectively provide the donor template necessary for HDR, increasing its efficiency. The team first packaged the necessary machinery for genome editing into the AAV and delivered it to neurons of transgenic Cas9 expressing mice, achieving spectacularly efficient HDR in post-mitotic neurons of the brain.&lt;br /&gt;
They next created a dual-viral system allowing them to use the technology in animals that had not been engineered to express Cas9. They tested this dual-viral system in an aged Alzheimer’s disease mouse model showing that the vSLENDR technique can be applicable in pathological models even at advanced ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vSLENDR is a powerful new tool for both basic and translational sciences alike, capable of the precise editing of genetic information regardless of cell type, cell maturity, brain region, or age. The new vSLENDR is more efficient, flexible, and concise, allowing researchers the potential to study a myriad of brain processes and functionalities with unprecedented ease. Equally important is its potential use in neuropathological disease models, accelerating research and the development of novel therapeutics; establishing today’s basic science as the foundation for tomorrow’s cures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was supported National Institute of Health, the Human Frontier Science Program and JST/PRESTO, Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience and Max Planck Society. The content of this article is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the funding agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(17)30933-9&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Virus-Mediated Genome Editing via Homology-Directed Repair in Mitotic and Postmitotic Cells in Mammalian Brain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jun Nishiyama*, Takayasu Mikuni*, and Ryohei Yasuda&lt;br /&gt;
*Co-firt authors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuron, October 19 2017, Advance online publication.&lt;br /&gt;
DOI: 10.1016/j.neuron.2017.10.004&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Helena Decker</name>
			<uri>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/"/>
			<id>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T23:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">After journal retracts their paper, authors post rebuttal on arXiv</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/19/journal-retracts-paper-authors-post-rebuttal-arxiv/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52214</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T15:00:53+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;In July 2017, just days after accepting and publishing a paper, a physics journal discovered “several scientific errors” and decided to retract it. But the authors—Alexander Kholmetskii and Tolga Yarman—strongly objected to the journal’s decision, so much so they published a detailed rebuttal to the retraction on the preprint server arXiv. The paper explores a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/19/journal-retracts-paper-authors-post-rebuttal-arxiv/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;After journal retracts their paper, authors post rebuttal on arXiv&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Science Exchange Honored by Goldman Sachs for Entrepreneurship</title>
		<link href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/10/science-exchange-honored-by-goldman-sachs-for-entrepreneurship/"/>
		<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1153</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T13:35:46+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Co-Founder and CEO Elizabeth Iorns Among 100 Most Intriguing Entrepreneurs at 2017 Builders + Innovators Summit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Palo Alto, CA – October 19, 2017&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; – Goldman Sachs (NYSE:GS) is recognizing Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; as one of the 100 Most Intriguing Entrepreneurs of 2017 at its Builders + Innovators Summit in Santa Barbara, California.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Goldman Sachs selected Elizabeth as one of 100 entrepreneurs from multiple industries to be honored at the two-day event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The life sciences research community has been transformed by Elizabeth’s ability to execute upon her vision to transform the procurement and delivery of outsourced R&amp;amp;D services. Thanks to her tenacity and drive, and her deep understanding of the need for improved R&amp;amp;D efficiency, Science Exchange is enabling breakthrough scientific discoveries by providing researchers with an online platform for efficient access to the world’s best outsourced R&amp;amp;D service providers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“This is a tremendous honor and I’m excited to be recognized by Goldman Sachs along with these other inspiring entrepreneurs,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange.  “The work our team at Science Exchange has been doing in outsourced R&amp;amp;D is critical for driving scientific breakthroughs and innovation and I’m proud to lead the team in this charge.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We are pleased to recognize Elizabeth Iorns as one of the most intriguing entrepreneurs of 2017,” said David M. Solomon, President and Co-Chief Operating Officer at Goldman Sachs. “This is the sixth year that we’ve hosted the Builders + Innovators Summit where emerging business leaders gather to discuss their common interests in building prosperous organizations.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For more than 145 years, Goldman Sachs has been advising and financing entrepreneurs as they launch and grow their businesses. In addition to honoring 100 entrepreneurs, the Summit consists of general sessions and clinics led by Goldman Sachs experts, seasoned entrepreneurs, academics and business leaders as well as resident scholars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Elizabeth Iorns&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., is the CEO and Founder of Science Exchange. Elizabeth Iorns has transformed scientific research by radically improving the procurement and delivery of outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services. Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D. (Institute of Cancer Research, London) was an Assistant Professor at University of Miami’s Miller School of Medicine, where she investigated breast cancer development and progression, before launching Science Exchange in 2011. Elizabeth’s work has been featured in multiple media outlets, and she regularly speaks at thought leadership events, such as the 2017 TechCrunch Disrupt event in San Francisco, 2017 Society for Laboratory Automation and Screening annual meeting and the 2016 MassBio CRO/CMO Symposium. Her recent honors include Nature’s “Ten People that Mattered,” WIRED’s “50 Women Who Are Changing The World,” and the “Kauffman Foundation Emerging Entrepreneur Award.” She is a finalist for 2017 Scrip Executive of the Year Award.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Science Exchange&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange is the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research, providing an efficient procure-to-pay platform for ordering 6,000+ services from a network of more than 2,500 qualified scientific service providers, all with pre-established contracts in place that protect client intellectual property and confidentiality. The platform increases access to innovation and improves productivity, freeing scientists from administrative tasks and delays associated with sourcing, establishing and managing service provider contracts. Additionally, the Science Exchange enterprise program enables large R&amp;amp;D organizations to consolidate research outsourcing spend into a single strategic relationship, driving efficiency, improving transparency and oversight, and delivering cost savings. Since being founded in 2011, Science Exchange has raised more than $58 million from Norwest Venture Partners, Maverick Capital Ventures, Union Square Ventures, Collaborative Fund, Index Ventures, OATV, the YC Continuity Fund, and others. For more information, visit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.ScienceExchange.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Follow the company on Twitter @ScienceExchange.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Team</name>
			<uri>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">The Science Exchange Blog</title>
			<subtitle type="html">The Science Exchange Blog - Enabling Breakthrough Research: Order Experiments From The World's Top Labs</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/"/>
			<id>https://blog.scienceexchange.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Ethical concerns arise for head of controversial stem cell clinic</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/19/ethical-concerns-arise-head-controversial-stem-cell-clinic/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52206</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T12:00:39+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;Journals are raising ethical concerns about the research of a doctor who offers controversial embryonic stem cell treatments. Two journals have issued expressions of concern for three papers by Geeta Shroff, who was the subject of a 2012 CNN investigative documentary. All cite ethical concerns; one mentions the potential link between the procedure the authors […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/19/ethical-concerns-arise-head-controversial-stem-cell-clinic/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ethical concerns arise for head of controversial stem cell clinic&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Han</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">50 years ago, engineers tried catching commercial planes in nets</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-engineers-tried-catching-commercial-planes-nets"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-engineers-tried-catching-commercial-planes-nets</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T11:00:04+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Fifty years ago, aviation experts tried helping commercial aircraft come to a stop during landing by catching them in massive nets. The idea crash-landed for commercial flights, but it’s still used in the military.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Bethany Brookshire</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Reverse “stereotype threat” – women chess players perform better against men</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/19/reverse-stereotype-threat-women-play-chess-better-than-expected-against-men/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31232</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T07:09:56+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-103660991.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31242&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31242&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PerfectionV700&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Actor Humphrey Bogart (1899-1957) and his wife, actress Lauren Bacall, pictured playing chess, USA, circa 1955. (Photo by Archive Photos\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2010 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Bogart And Bacall&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Bogart And Bacall&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-103660991.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-103660991.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-103660991.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;5801,4527&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/19/reverse-stereotype-threat-women-play-chess-better-than-expected-against-men/bogart-and-bacall/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/gettyimages-103660991.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stereotype threat is one of those social psychology concepts that has managed to break out of the academic world and into everyday conversation: the idea that a fear of conforming to stereotypes – for example, that girls struggle at maths – can make those stereotypes self-fulfilling, thanks to the adverse effect of anxiety and excessive self-consciousness on performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annualreviews.org/doi/full/10.1146/annurev-psych-073115-103235&quot;&gt;recent review&lt;/a&gt; suggested that stereotype threat has a robust but small-to-medium sized effect on performance, but a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022440514000831&quot;&gt;meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; suggests that publication bias may be a problem in this literature, inflating the apparent size of the effect. Also, the majority of the work has been done under laboratory conditions, which may not reflect what happens in the wider world. So when a field study comes along, it’s worth paying attention to, and a paper published &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/bpy3t/&quot;&gt;as a pre-print at PsyArXiv&lt;/a&gt; from Tom Stafford at the University of Sheffield looks at a domain involving high pressure, clear success criteria, and a presupposition that’s it’s more a guy thing: chess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31232&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The handy thing about chess is that we have so much solid data: vast databases of matches, and effective ranking systems that allow accurate predictions of who is likely to win upcoming matches. To date, lab-based studies have suggested that women playing chess do suffer from stereotype threat, so Stafford’s question is: what does that look like in real play?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out, he explored a dataset of youngish (average age 32) players ranked officially by FIDE, the World Chess Federation, including 150,000 men and 16,000 women, and the outcomes of over five million games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average man had a higher ranking – 2070 versus 1978 – meaning plenty of the games would put the women players in a challenging situation, which is where stereotype threat is most likely to manifest. And yet the data showed that whether playing a stronger, matched or equal player, women performed better when playing a man than they did a woman. In other words, the data revealed exactly the opposite pattern of performance as predicted by the concept of stereotype threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stafford looked closer at the data, to see whether the expected threat effect emerged under certain conditions, such as among younger and less experienced players; for older players who conceivably grew up around more sexist assumptions; or for players from national leagues where women are even more in the minority. Nothing changed the pattern: women perform better when playing men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor was there evidence that stereotype threat triggered women to drop the ball on matches they were well placed to win. Looking at matches where one player had a rating 500 or more points above the other, Stafford found that female favourites were upset by men in 3.5 per cent of cases, but female underdogs beat the male favourite even more often, in 3.7 per cent of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stafford notes that another factor that increases the likelihood of stereotype effect is when the task attempted is unfamiliar, and this isn’t the case here: the women players had years of experience. Still, the data didn’t merely show no effect, but a reversed one, so there seems to be some sort of gender-related psychological process exerting an effect. Perhaps in domains where women are skilled and self-confident, anticipating a stereotype-related challenge actually sharpens their focus to buckle down. Or, says Stafford, maybe it’s an issue of male &lt;i&gt;under&lt;/i&gt;-performance, whether “male underestimation of female opponents, misplaced chivalry, or ‘choking’ due the ego-threat of being beaten by a women.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first field investigation of stereotype threat to show different effects from laboratory studies. For example, Thomas Wei’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//www.jstor.org/stable/23357023?seq=1%2523page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;investigation of children’s maths performance&lt;/a&gt; found that gender primes before the task actually led girls to do better than normal. Findings like these don’t prove that stereotype threat is non-existent in every situation, but they do suggest it is not as ubiquitous or straightforward as some have claimed. Just as with many phenomena in our rich, complex real world, gendered assumptions about performance may not have the same influence in every situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/bpy3t/&quot;&gt;Female chess players outperform expectations when playing men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Actress Lauren Bacall and her husband actor Humphrey Bogart pictured playing chess, USA, circa 1955. (Photo by Archive Photos/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31232/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31232/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31232&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T23:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The science of puppy dog eyes</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ev-vNotMdKA/nature.2017.22867"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22867</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Dogs' facial expressions depend on human attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22867&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22867&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ev-vNotMdKA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emma Young</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Jupiter's stormy winds churn deep into the planet</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BbawW9LTo5A/nature.2017.22866"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22866</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Juno probe discovers surprising activity in the giant planet’s interior.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22866&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22866&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BbawW9LTo5A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sabre-toothed cats prowled Europe 200,000 years after supposedly going extinct</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bp6AMpFeRBg/nature.2017.22861"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22861</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ancient-DNA analysis also suggests a surprising connection with sabretooths in North America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22861&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22861&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bp6AMpFeRBg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Rachael  Lallensack</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Quantum machine goes in search of the Higgs boson</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ipPgC0Q9LQc/nature.2017.22860"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22860</id>
		<updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;D-Wave system shows quantum computers can learn to detect particle signatures in mountains of data, but doesn’t outpace conventional methods — yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22860&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22860&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ipPgC0Q9LQc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Davide Castelvecchi</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The physics of mosquito takeoffs shows why you don’t feel a thing</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-mosquito-takeoffs"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-mosquito-takeoffs</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T22:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Even when full of blood, mosquitoes use more wing force than leg force to escape a host undetected — clue to why they’re so good at spreading disease.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Caught Our Notice:  Another retraction for researcher paid $100k to leave uni</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/caught-notice-another-retraction-researcher-paid-100k-leave-uni/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52176</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T18:00:27+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;When Retraction Watch began in 2010, our co-founders Ivan Oransky and Adam Marcus quickly realized they couldn’t keep up with the hundreds of retractions that appeared each year.  And the problem has only gotten worse — although we’ve added staff, the number of retractions issued each year has increased dramatically. According to our growing database, just shy of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/caught-notice-another-retraction-researcher-paid-100k-leave-uni/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice:  Another retraction for researcher paid $100k to leave uni&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abritis</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Animal study reveals how a fever early in pregnancy can cause birth defects</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/animal-study-reveals-how-fever-early-pregnancy-can-cause-birth-defects"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/animal-study-reveals-how-fever-early-pregnancy-can-cause-birth-defects</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T18:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Using chicken embryos, study shows that heat itself, not an infectious agent, is the driving factor behind certain heart and facial birth defects.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Aimee Cunningham</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The newest AlphaGo mastered the game with no human input</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newest-alphago-mastered-game-no-human-input"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newest-alphago-mastered-game-no-human-input</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T17:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 AlphaGo Zero is the first AI system of its kind to learn the game just by playing against itself.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Conspiring with engineers helps make science great</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conspiring-engineers-helps-make-science-great"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conspiring-engineers-helps-make-science-great</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T16:30:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill says the passion to acquire knowledge and apply it lives in both engineers and scientists.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Quill</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Readers question photons colliding, black sea snakes and more</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-photons-colliding-black-sea-snakes-and-more"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-photons-colliding-black-sea-snakes-and-more</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T16:15:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Readers had questions about brain flexibility, black sea snakes and photon collisions.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Science News Staff</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_2415446908008574=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Being a vampire can be brutal. Here’s how bloodsuckers get by.</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/blood-real-vampires-animals"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/blood-real-vampires-animals</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T16:00:02+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Blood-sucking animals have specialized physiology and other tools to live on a diet rich in protein and lacking in some nutrients.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Susan Milius</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Journal: Publish here, and we’ll pay you $500</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/journal-publish-well-pay-500/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52201</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T15:00:47+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;A new journal is offering something we’ve never seen before: A cash reward to corresponding authors of papers it publishes. Normally, in the case of open-access journals, researchers have to pay article processing charges (APCs). But Minimally Invasive Surgical Oncology, an open-access journal launched at the end of last year, flips the typical narrative — […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/journal-publish-well-pay-500/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal: Publish here, and we’ll pay you $500&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">Predicting a soldier’s potential for developing depression and PTSD</title>
		<link href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/10/18/predicting-a-soldiers-potential-for-developing-depression-and-ptsd/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9568</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T14:20:06+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-GB">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/Fotolia_54644938_Subscription_Yearly_XL-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Statistics concerning the occurrence of post-traumatic stress disorder, or PTSD, in soldiers returning from combat vary widely depending on when a veteran gets tested for the mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one fact remains constant: anyone who works in a combat environment or other high-stress environment like those created by military service are at risk of developing PTSD during their deployment or after they return home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a new occurrence. Four out of five &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.veteransandptsd.com/PTSD-statistics.html&quot;&gt;Vietnam veterans reported recent symptoms&lt;/a&gt; of PTSD when interviewed decades after the end of that conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0201-4&quot;&gt;A new study has suggested&lt;/a&gt; a potential solution to this problem: a series of validated, self-reported questions administered early in the solder’s career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions could help to predict a soldier’s potential for developing PTSD, depression or other mental illnesses as a direct result of their military service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extended combat scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the operations being conducted in Iraq and Afghanistan, the U.S. military has been participating in combat operations for almost 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These extended combat scenarios have led to an increasing need for psychological health services for military personnel and service members. Depending on when a soldier’s mental state is assessed, the rate of service members returning from combat with symptoms of PTSD ranges from 5 to 45 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many symptoms don’t present until after the solider has returned home, which &lt;a href=&quot;http://military.vista.edu/military-veterans/10-organizations-that-help-veterans-transition-to-civilian-life/&quot;&gt;can make transitioning back to civilian life hard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hypothesis that service members who are assessed before or during the beginning of their career will enable mental health professionals in the military to be better prepared is not a new one, but it hasn’t yet been explored sufficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proactive mental health screenings could have two potential benefits, though: they could help reduce overall mental health care costs over time, and could cut down on the number of people who are at risk for mental illness or PTSD from being exposed to stressful scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Army received the data for this study in three sources: soldier-provided information in the form of the pre- and post-deployment health assessments, the soldiers’ responses to the military Global Assessment Tools and Army demographic information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this was to examine this information for one of two outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soldiers who return home without any mental health concerns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soldiers who have returned home at risk for PTSD, depression, or other mental health diagnoses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based solely on the post-deployment health assessment, roughly 7 percent of the sampled soldiers screened positive for depression, and 11 percent screened positive for PTSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having the soldier’s pre-combat mental state proved essential in determining the potential for the development of these mental health issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, these pre-deployment mental health screenings could cost the organization more, but those costs would likely be offset by the money saved on post-deployment mental health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one major limitation of this study is the lack of actual clinical diagnosis — while the data trended toward depression and PTSD, there were no official diagnoses made. This is also due in part to the negative stigma that surrounds mental illness and prevents people from reporting their concerns.  PTSD in the military is a problem with no quick or easy solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hypothesis could potentially help move military mental health care in the right direction, both by providing more tools for people suffering from PTSD and depression, and helping recruiters to determine who is at risk for developing mental health concerns due to the stresses of military service and combat scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These early screenings could also potentially save the military hundreds of thousands of dollars in mental health care in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/10/18/predicting-a-soldiers-potential-for-developing-depression-and-ptsd/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Predicting a soldier’s potential for developing depression and PTSD&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Kayla Matthews</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">BMC Series blog</title>
			<link rel="self" href="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/"/>
			<id>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog</id>
			<updated>2017-10-18T17:00:27+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Researcher apologizes for ignoring early warnings about earthquake data</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/researcher-apologizes-ignoring-early-warnings-earthquake-data/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52189</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T12:52:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;In 2016, three researchers published data they had collected on a series of devastating earthquakes that hit Japan earlier that year. But, in late September 2017, one of the authors—Hiroyuki Goto—revealed that the Kumamoto Earthquake data contained “wide reaching errors”—and an outside expert had warned him the data might be problematic nine months earlier.   Goto, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/18/researcher-apologizes-ignoring-early-warnings-earthquake-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher apologizes for ignoring early warnings about earthquake data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Stern</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">A brief critique of predictive coding</title>
		<link href="http://romainbrette.fr/a-brief-critique-of-predictive-coding/"/>
		<id>http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1456</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T11:11:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="fr-FR">
 &lt;p&gt;Predictive coding is becoming a popular theory in neuroscience (see for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23663408&quot;&gt;Clark 2013&lt;/a&gt;). In a nutshell, the general idea is that brains encode predictions of their sensory inputs. This is an appealing idea because superficially, it makes a lot of sense: functionally, the only reason why you would want to process sensory information is if it might impact your future, so it makes sense to try to predict your sensory inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are substantial problems in the details of predictive coding theories, for example with the arbitrariness of the metric by which you judge that your prediction matches sensory inputs (what is important?), or the fact that predictive coding schemes encode both noise and signal. But I want to focus on the more fundamental problems. One has to with “coding”, the other with “predictive”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense that brains anticipate. But does it make sense that brains code? Coding is a metaphor of a communication channel, and this is generally not a great metaphor for what the brain might do, unless you fully embrace dualism. I discuss this at length in a recent paper (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/07/31/168237&quot;&gt;Is coding a relevant metaphor for the brain?&lt;/a&gt;) so I won’t repeat the entire argument here. Predictive coding is a branch of efficient coding, so the same fallacy underlies its logic: 1) neurons encode sensory inputs; 2) living organisms are efficient; =&amp;gt; brains must encode efficiently. (1) is trivially true in the sense that one can define a mapping from sensory inputs to neural activity. (2) is probably true to some extent (evolutionary arguments). So the conclusion follows. Critiques of efficient coding have focused on the “efficient” part: maybe the brain is not that efficient after all. But the error is elsewhere: living organisms are certainly efficient, but it doesn’t follow that they are efficient &lt;i&gt;at coding&lt;/i&gt;. They might be efficient at surviving and reproducing, and it is not obvious that it entails coding efficiency (see the last part of the abovementioned paper for a counter-example). So the real strong assumption is there: the main function of the brain is to represent sensory inputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second problem has to with “predictive”. It makes sense that an important function of brains, or in fact of any living organism, is to anticipate (see the great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anticipatory_Systems;_Philosophical,_Mathematical,_and_Methodological_Foundations&quot;&gt;Anticipatory Systems&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Rosen). But to what extent do predictive coding schemes actually anticipate? First, in practice, those are generally not prediction schemes but compression schemes, in the sense that they do not tell us what will happen next but what happens now. This is at least the case of the classical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.utexas.edu/users/dana/nn.pdf&quot;&gt;Rao &amp;amp; Ballard&lt;/a&gt; (1999). Neurons encode the difference between expected input and actual input: this is compression, not prediction. It uses a sort of prediction in order to compress: other neurons (in higher layers) produce predictions of the inputs to those neurons, but the term prediction is used in the sense that the inputs are not known to the higher layer neurons, not that the “prediction” occurs before the inputs. Thus the term “predictive” is misleading because it is not used in a temporal sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it is relatively easy to imagine how predictive coding might be about temporal predictions, although the neural implementation is not straightforward (delays etc). So I want to make a deeper criticism. I started by claiming that it is useful to predict sensory inputs. I am taking this back (I can because I said it was superficial reasoning). It is not useful to know what will happen. What is useful is to know what &lt;i&gt;might&lt;/i&gt; happen, depending on what you do. If there is nothing you can do about the future, what is the functional use of predicting it? So what is useful is to predict the future conditionally to a different set of potential actions. This is about manipulating models of the world, not representing the present.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>admin</name>
			<uri>http://romainbrette.fr</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Romain Brette</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Computational Neuroscience</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/"/>
			<id>http://romainbrette.fr</id>
			<updated>2017-10-18T17:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Moms tweak the timbre of their voice when talking to their babies</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/moms-tweak-timbre-their-voice-when-talking-their-babies"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/moms-tweak-timbre-their-voice-when-talking-their-babies</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T11:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Mothers shift the timbre, or quality, of their voice when talking to their babies, a change that happens in many different languages.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Sanders</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The concept of “compensation” makes sense of several autism puzzles</title>
		<link href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/18/the-concept-of-compensation-makes-sense-of-several-autism-puzzles/"/>
		<id>http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=31185</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T08:57:49+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-21&quot; style=&quot;width: 3166px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-10-18 09.47.38.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-31219&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;31219&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-10-18 09.47.38&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screenshot-2017-10-18-09-47-38.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screenshot-2017-10-18-09-47-38.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screenshot-2017-10-18-09-47-38.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3166,2290&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/18/the-concept-of-compensation-makes-sense-of-several-autism-puzzles/screenshot-2017-10-18-09-47-38/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/screenshot-2017-10-18-09-47-38.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;On British television last night, naturalist and TV presenter Chris Packham described how he hid his autistic traits for most of his life&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A process involved in neurodevelopmental disorders that we are only just beginning to understand is “compensation” – the way that a deficit can be partially or wholly masked by automatic mental processes and/or deliberate behavioural strategies. For instance, a person with dyslexia may achieve typical levels of reading ability after an earlier diagnosis, not because the disorder has gone away (subtle tests might show continuing problems in phonological processing, for example) but through the use of behavioural strategies, such as reverse-engineering a tricky word from the meaning of words around it. In a new review in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0149763417301732&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Lucy Anne Livingston and Francesca Happé, at the Institute of Psychiatry in London, take us through what compensation might mean for autism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-31185&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compensation in autism could make sense of several puzzles. One is how high-risk individuals – with an autistic sibling, and showing markers for the disorder at the age of one – sometimes beat the odds and go on to seemingly normal development. Similarly, some individuals are diagnosed with autism, but in adulthood achieve what is termed a “good outcome”: functional social relationships, work life, and general independence. These cases could be explained by compensation mechanisms kicking in at different times. Meanwhile, people who remain undiagnosed until later life could have been relying to that point on compensation mechanisms that have become ineffective, perhaps because their lives have become more complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, scientists are reassessing the prevalence of autism in girls and women, now understood to stand at around one female for every three males according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrumnews.org/news/estimate-autisms-sex-ratio-reaches-new-low/&quot;&gt;one analysis&lt;/a&gt;. The reason for the historical under-estimate – even fairly recently standing at a male to female ratio of four to one – and for why autism may present differently in women (who are often diagnosed later in life), may again be compensation; one source of evidence for this is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/24/theres-such-a-thing-as-autism-camouflaging-and-it-might-explain-why-some-people-are-diagnosed-so-late/&quot;&gt;women with autism report a higher inclination to camouflage their difficulties in order to fit in socially&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A core deficit of autism is an impairment in Theory of Mind: difficulty figuring out what people are thinking in order to make sense of their behaviour. Livingston and Happé asked themselves how this might be compensated. It’s possible that what neurotypical people achieve implicitly can also be achieved explicitly, by reasoning through situations to predict behaviour and motives. If true, it’s likely higher intelligence would assist this compensatory process. Consistent with this account, intelligence is one of the strongest correlates of “good outcome”; it also tends to be higher in the unaffected siblings of those with autistic spectrum disorders (ASD), but lower in women diagnosed with autism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another factor likely to be relevant to autistic compensation is “executive function” – the suite of meta-cognitive functions that includes planning and inhibiting action, flexibility in thinking and switching focus. It’s easy to see how being able to prevent undesirable behaviours and plan appropriate social responses ahead of an interaction might prevent visible faux pas and allow an individual to pass as neurotypical. For a long time, executive dysfunction was seen as core to autism, and Livingston and Happé point out this could be because when that dysfunction was present, compensation was lacking, making autism symptoms more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For autistic people and those around them, understanding the nature of their compensation may be very useful. Compensation may be deep or shallow: Livingston and Happé refer to the development of echolocation by blind people, which genuinely restores some of the functionality of sight (i.e. deep compensation), versus the use of a cane, which serves a much more circumscribed role (shallow compensation). In autism, two individuals might present as equally adjusted to social situations, such as responding to jokes, but the one relying on a shallow strategy (for example, join in whenever other people laugh) is vulnerable to making errors and may struggle in novel situations (e.g. a one-on-one date).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, compensatory strategies are likely to exact a cost, drawing on resources that would normally be invested into other tasks. A common complaint from those on the spectrum is it’s hard work to “act normal” – as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/2017/10/09/chris-packham-living-aspergers-spent-30-years-telly-trying-best/&quot;&gt;recently expressed&lt;/a&gt; by TV presenter Chris Packham (see footnote). Diagnosed with Asperger’s later in life, Packham says he was “forced to develop” a number of coping mechanisms. Individuals who spent more of their life undiagnosed – and hence without a way to make sense of their difference – are likely to have spent extended periods working to pass invisibly in society, and this may go some way to explain the higher levels of suicidal ideation in this group – at 66 per cent, far higher than in those diagnosed in childhood. Understanding different forms of compensation and their consequences may be an important step in helping autistic people manage their mental health more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it’s early days, we’re starting to understand how to identify compensation in autism. Work with “good outcome” individuals shows that with sufficiently sensitive tasks, such as anticipating where people direct their gaze in complex social scenarios, it’s possible to pick up Theory of Mind deficits that were otherwise undetectable. The next step, argue the authors of this new review, is to develop a gold-standard measure that we agree captures the core, deep marker of Theory of Mind deficits in ASD, just as precise phonological measures do in dyslexia. Through this, we can not only understand the disorder at a scientific, medical level, but we can arrive at a personalised account of the ways individuals live with the disorder, the situations that may challenge them the most, and the psychological toll that they pay to pass in neurotypical cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0149763417301732&quot;&gt;Conceptualising compensation in neurodevelopmental disorders: Reflections from autism spectrum disorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b09b1zbb&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chris Packham: Asperger’s and Me&lt;/em&gt; was broadcast last night on British television and is available in some regions on BBC iPlayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31185/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/31185/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=31185&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>BPS Research Digest</name>
			<uri>https://digest.bps.org.uk</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Research Digest</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/"/>
			<id>https://digest.bps.org.uk</id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T23:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-gb">Dream jobs in research: teaching conservationists – and penguins in the office</title>
		<link href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/dream-jobs-in-research-teaching-conservationists-and-penguins-in-the-office"/>
		<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/dream-jobs-in-research-teaching-conservationists-and-penguins-in-the-office</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T07:38:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 This conservation biologist finds ways to make her research count in the wider world; what’s your dream job?</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elsevier Connect</name>
			<uri></uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Elsevier Connect</title>
			<link rel="self" href="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed"/>
			<id>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed</id>
			<updated>2017-10-18T11:00:28+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Self-taught AI is best yet at strategy game Go</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/zCUcPNeM11M/nature.2017.22858"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22858</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Artificial-intelligence program AlphaGo Zero trained in just days, without any human input.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22858&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22858&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/zCUcPNeM11M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Elizabeth Gibney</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Sleeping sickness can now be cured with pills</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PRumQ1K_q0g/nature.2017.22856"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22856</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Researchers seek approval from regulators for this quicker, easier treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22856&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22856&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PRumQ1K_q0g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Amy Maxmen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Efforts to save leading Hungarian university hit hurdle</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hkWPeEHRJWs/nature.2017.22855"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22855</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;US-registered Central European University faces another year of uncertainty over whether it can continue to operate in Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22855&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22855&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hkWPeEHRJWs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison Abbott</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mysterious particles spotted in Saturn’s atmosphere</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BqZfaV8_qFk/nature.2017.22838"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22838</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Source may be dust shed by planet’s iconic rings, according to data from NASA's doomed Cassini probe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22838&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22838&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BqZfaV8_qFk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alexandra Witze</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Top Chinese university to consider social-media posts in researcher evaluations</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oG77lfJYTFI/nature.2017.22822"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22822</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Controversial policy means mainstream media are starting to rival rigorous academic publications in some universities in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22822&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22822&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oG77lfJYTFI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Cyranoski</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The Human Cell Atlas: from vision to reality</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MENi7Rquiww/550451a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550451a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;As an ambitious project to map all the cells in the human body gets officially under way, Aviv Regev, Sarah Teichmann and colleagues outline some key challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550451a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550451a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MENi7Rquiww&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Orit Rozenblatt-Rosen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The second Renaissance</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bIWzrULum2Q/550327a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550327a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ian Goldin calls on scientists to help society to weather the disruptive transformations afoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 327 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550327a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550327a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bIWzrULum2Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ian Goldin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Lessons from history for the future of work</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5dxvso7-8ps/550321a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550321a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Global comparisons of previous social and economic upheavals suggest that what is to come depends on where you are now, argues Robert C. Allen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 321 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550321a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550321a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5dxvso7-8ps&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Robert C. Allen</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The shape of work to come</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6tmJTgxlIWw/550316a"/>
		<id>http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550316a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Three ways that the digital revolution is reshaping workforces around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 316 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/550316a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550316a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6tmJTgxlIWw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Anthes</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/rdf/newsandcomment/newsandcomment</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:25+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecular basis of USP7 inhibition by selective small-molecule inhibitors</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/7J73j89jHt4/nature24451"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24451</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Ubiquitination controls the stability of most cellular proteins, and its deregulation contributes to human diseases including cancer. Deubiquitinases remove ubiquitin from proteins, and their inhibition can induce the degradation of selected proteins, potentially including otherwise ‘undruggable’ targets. For example, the inhibition of ubiquitin-specific protease 7 (USP7) results in the degradation of the oncogenic E3 ligase MDM2, and leads to re-activation of the tumour suppressor p53 in various cancers. Here we report that two compounds, FT671 and FT827, inhibit USP7 with high affinity and specificity in vitro and within human cells. Co-crystal structures reveal that both compounds target a dynamic pocket near the catalytic centre of the auto-inhibited apo form of USP7, which differs from other USP deubiquitinases. Consistent with USP7 target engagement in cells, FT671 destabilizes USP7 substrates including MDM2, increases levels of p53, and results in the transcription of p53 target genes, induction of the tumour suppressor p21, and inhibition of tumour growth in mice. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24451&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24451&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/7J73j89jHt4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Andrew P. Turnbull</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">The dynamics of molecular evolution over 60,000 generations</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/BqPhWIV4QyQ/nature24287"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24287</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The outcomes of evolution are determined by a stochastic dynamical process that governs how mutations arise and spread through a population. However, it is difficult to observe these dynamics directly over long periods and across entire genomes. Here we analyse the dynamics of molecular evolution in twelve experimental populations of Escherichia coli, using whole-genome metagenomic sequencing at five hundred-generation intervals through sixty thousand generations. Although the rate of fitness gain declines over time, molecular evolution is characterized by signatures of rapid adaptation throughout the duration of the experiment, with multiple beneficial variants simultaneously competing for dominance in each population. Interactions between ecological and evolutionary processes play an important role, as long-term quasi-stable coexistence arises spontaneously in most populations, and evolution continues within each clade. We also present evidence that the targets of natural selection change over time, as epistasis and historical contingency alter the strength of selection on different genes. Together, these results show that long-term adaptation to a constant environment can be a more complex and dynamic process than is often assumed. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24287&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24287&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/BqPhWIV4QyQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Benjamin H. Good</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Disorder in convergent floral nanostructures enhances signalling to bees</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/JUHJFRXNgIQ/nature24285"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24285</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Diverse forms of nanoscale architecture generate structural colour and perform signalling functions within and between species. Structural colour is the result of the interference of light from approximately regular periodic structures; some structural disorder is, however, inevitable in biological organisms. Is this disorder functional and subject to evolutionary selection, or is it simply an unavoidable outcome of biological developmental processes? Here we show that disordered nanostructures enable flowers to produce visual signals that are salient to bees. These disordered nanostructures (identified in most major lineages of angiosperms) have distinct anatomies but convergent optical properties; they all produce angle-dependent scattered light, predominantly at short wavelengths (ultraviolet and blue). We manufactured artificial flowers with nanoscale structures that possessed tailored levels of disorder in order to investigate how foraging bumblebees respond to this optical effect. We conclude that floral nanostructures have evolved, on multiple independent occasions, an effective degree of relative spatial disorder that generates a photonic signature that is highly salient to insect pollinators. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24285&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24285&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/JUHJFRXNgIQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Edwige Moyroud</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Structure of phycobilisome from the red alga Griffithsia pacifica</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/s63sMlZSziE/nature24278"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24278</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Life on Earth depends on photosynthesis for its conversion of solar energy to chemical energy. Photosynthetic organisms have developed a variety of light-harvesting systems to capture sunlight. The largest light-harvesting complex is the phycobilisome (PBS), the main light-harvesting antenna in cyanobacteria and red algae. It is composed of phycobiliproteins and linker proteins but the assembly mechanisms and energy transfer pathways of the PBS are not well understood. Here we report the structure of a 16.8-megadalton PBS from a red alga at 3.5 Å resolution obtained by single-particle cryo-electron microscopy. We modelled 862 protein subunits, including 4 linkers in the core, 16 rod–core linkers and 52 rod linkers, and located a total of 2,048 chromophores. This structure reveals the mechanisms underlying specific interactions between linkers and phycobiliproteins, and the formation of linker skeletons. These results provide a firm structural basis for our understanding of complex assembly and the mechanisms of energy transfer within the PBS. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24278&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/s63sMlZSziE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Jun Zhang</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Indirect effects drive coevolution in mutualistic networks</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/166qgXdHnHw/nature24273"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24273</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Ecological interactions have been acknowledged to play a key role in shaping biodiversity. Yet a major challenge for evolutionary biology is to understand the role of ecological interactions in shaping trait evolution when progressing from pairs of interacting species to multispecies interaction networks. Here we introduce an approach that integrates coevolutionary dynamics and network structure. Our results show that non-interacting species can be as important as directly interacting species in shaping coevolution within mutualistic assemblages. The contribution of indirect effects differs among types of mutualism. Indirect effects are more likely to predominate in nested, species-rich networks formed by multiple-partner mutualisms, such as pollination or seed dispersal by animals, than in small and modular networks formed by intimate mutualisms, such as those between host plants and their protective ants. Coevolutionary pathways of indirect effects favour ongoing trait evolution by promoting slow but continuous reorganization of the adaptive landscape of mutualistic partners under changing environments. Our results show that coevolution can be a major process shaping species traits throughout ecological networks. These findings expand our understanding of how evolution driven by interactions occurs through the interplay of selection pressures moving along multiple direct and indirect pathways. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24273&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24273&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/166qgXdHnHw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Paulo R. Guimarães Jr</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inflammatory memory sensitizes skin epithelial stem cells to tissue damage</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/89kXDbJxjPM/nature24271"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24271</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The skin barrier is the body’s first line of defence against environmental assaults, and is maintained by epithelial stem cells (EpSCs). Despite the vulnerability of EpSCs to inflammatory pressures, neither the primary response to inflammation nor its enduring consequences are well understood. Here we report a prolonged memory to acute inflammation that enables mouse EpSCs to hasten barrier restoration after subsequent tissue damage. This functional adaptation does not require skin-resident macrophages or T cells. Instead, EpSCs maintain chromosomal accessibility at key stress response genes that are activated by the primary stimulus. Upon a secondary challenge, genes governed by these domains are transcribed rapidly. Fuelling this memory is Aim2, which encodes an activator of the inflammasome. The absence of AIM2 or its downstream effectors, caspase-1 and interleukin-1β, erases the ability of EpSCs to recollect inflammation. Although EpSCs benefit from inflammatory tuning by heightening their responsiveness to subsequent stressors, this enhanced sensitivity probably increases their susceptibility to autoimmune and hyperproliferative disorders, including cancer. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24271&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/89kXDbJxjPM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Shruti Naik</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mastering the game of Go without human knowledge</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tdiREnshAu4/nature24270"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24270</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 A long-standing goal of artificial intelligence is an algorithm that learns, tabula rasa, superhuman proficiency in challenging domains. Recently, AlphaGo became the first program to defeat a world champion in the game of Go. The tree search in AlphaGo evaluated positions and selected moves using deep neural networks. These neural networks were trained by supervised learning from human expert moves, and by reinforcement learning from self-play. Here we introduce an algorithm based solely on reinforcement learning, without human data, guidance or domain knowledge beyond game rules. AlphaGo becomes its own teacher: a neural network is trained to predict AlphaGo’s own move selections and also the winner of AlphaGo’s games. This neural network improves the strength of the tree search, resulting in higher quality move selection and stronger self-play in the next iteration. Starting tabula rasa, our new program AlphaGo Zero achieved superhuman performance, winning 100–0 against the previously published, champion-defeating AlphaGo. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 354 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24270&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24270&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tdiREnshAu4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>David Silver</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Single-molecule imaging reveals receptor–G protein interactions at cell surface
            hot spots</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Af6mJ5uiSLA/nature24264"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24264</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
             G-protein-coupled receptors mediate the biological effects of many hormones and
                neurotransmitters and are important pharmacological targets. They
                transmit their signals to the cell interior by interacting with G proteins. However,
                it is unclear how receptors and G proteins meet, interact and couple. Here we
                analyse the concerted motion of G-protein-coupled receptors and G proteins on the
                plasma membrane and provide a quantitative model that reveals the key factors that
                underlie the high spatiotemporal complexity of their interactions. Using two-colour,
                single-molecule imaging we visualize interactions between individual receptors and G
                proteins at the surface of living cells. Under basal conditions, receptors and G
                proteins form activity-dependent complexes that last for around one second. Agonists
                specifically regulate the kinetics of receptor–G protein interactions,
                mainly by increasing their association rate. We find hot spots on the plasma
                membrane, at least partially defined by the cytoskeleton and clathrin-coated pits,
                in which receptors and G proteins are confined and preferentially couple. Imaging
                with the nanobody Nb37 suggests that signalling by G-protein-coupled receptors
                occurs preferentially at these hot spots. These findings shed new light on the
                dynamic interactions that control G-protein-coupled receptor signalling. 
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24264&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24264&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Af6mJ5uiSLA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Titiwat Sungkaworn</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Photobiology: How flowers get the blues to lure bees</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/G5XQs2nzF78/nature24155"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24155</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;The petals of a range of flowers harbour repeated patterns of nanostructures that
            show similar levels of disorder across species. This degree of disorder produces a blue
            halo of scattered light that helps bees to find flowers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24155&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24155&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/G5XQs2nzF78&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Dimitri D. Deheyn</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Inflammation: Memory beyond immunity</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zIY5y6KKcCw/nature24154"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24154</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Epithelial stem cells maintain the skin's epidermis and promote wound healing in
            response to injury. Scientists from two fields discuss implications of the discovery
            that these stem cells harbour a memory of previous injuries, which enables skin to
            respond rapidly to subsequent assaults.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24154&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24154&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zIY5y6KKcCw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Xing Dai</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Molecular evolution: No escape from the tangled bank</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/CW45UGveOE4/nature24152"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24152</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Ecological interactions emerge spontaneously in an experimental study of bacterial
            populations cultured for 60,000 generations, and sustain rapid evolution by natural
            selection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24152&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24152&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/CW45UGveOE4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Joshua B. Plotkin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Glucose feeds the TCA cycle via circulating lactate</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/XDo-H0cVHP8/nature24057"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24057</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Mammalian tissues are fuelled by circulating nutrients, including glucose, amino acids, and various intermediary metabolites. Under aerobic conditions, glucose is generally assumed to be burned fully by tissues via the tricarboxylic acid cycle (TCA cycle) to carbon dioxide. Alternatively, glucose can be catabolized anaerobically via glycolysis to lactate, which is itself also a potential nutrient for tissues and tumours. The quantitative relevance of circulating lactate or other metabolic intermediates as fuels remains unclear. Here we systematically examine the fluxes of circulating metabolites in mice, and find that lactate can be a primary source of carbon for the TCA cycle and thus of energy. Intravenous infusions of 13C-labelled nutrients reveal that, on a molar basis, the circulatory turnover flux of lactate is the highest of all metabolites and exceeds that of glucose by 1.1-fold in fed mice and 2.5-fold in fasting mice; lactate is made primarily from glucose but also from other sources. In both fed and fasted mice, 13C-lactate extensively labels TCA cycle intermediates in all tissues. Quantitative analysis reveals that during the fasted state, the contribution of glucose to tissue TCA metabolism is primarily indirect (via circulating lactate) in all tissues except the brain. In genetically engineered lung and pancreatic cancer tumours in fasted mice, the contribution of circulating lactate to TCA cycle intermediates exceeds that of glucose, with glutamine making a larger contribution than lactate in pancreatic cancer. Thus, glycolysis and the TCA cycle are uncoupled at the level of lactate, which is a primary circulating TCA substrate in most tissues and tumours. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24057&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24057&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/XDo-H0cVHP8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheng Hui</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Network control principles predict neuron function in the Caenorhabditis elegans connectome</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/FgaoaMy3jeE/nature24056"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24056</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Recent studies on the controllability of complex systems offer a powerful mathematical framework to systematically explore the structure–function relationship in biological, social, and technological networks. Despite theoretical advances, we lack direct experimental proof of the validity of these widely used control principles. Here we fill this gap by applying a control framework to the connectome of the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans, allowing us to predict the involvement of each C. elegans neuron in locomotor behaviours. We predict that control of the muscles or motor neurons requires 12 neuronal classes, which include neuronal groups previously implicated in locomotion by laser ablation, as well as one previously uncharacterized neuron, PDB. We validate this prediction experimentally, finding that the ablation of PDB leads to a significant loss of dorsoventral polarity in large body bends. Importantly, control principles also allow us to investigate the involvement of individual neurons within each neuronal class. For example, we predict that, within the class of DD motor neurons, only three (DD04, DD05, or DD06) should affect locomotion when ablated individually. This prediction is also confirmed; single cell ablations of DD04 or DD05 specifically affect posterior body movements, whereas ablations of DD02 or DD03 do not. Our predictions are robust to deletions of weak connections, missing connections, and rewired connections in the current connectome, indicating the potential applicability of this analytical framework to larger and less well-characterized connectomes. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24056&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24056&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/FgaoaMy3jeE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Gang Yan</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Mfsd2b is essential for the sphingosine-1-phosphate export in erythrocytes and platelets</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/f8KmceRpBwU/nature24053"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24053</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 Sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P), a potent signalling lipid secreted by red blood cells and platelets, plays numerous biologically significant roles. However, the identity of its long-sought exporter is enigmatic. Here we show that the major facilitator superfamily transporter 2b (Mfsd2b), an orphan transporter, is essential for S1P export from red blood cells and platelets. Comprehensive lipidomic analysis indicates a dramatic and specific accumulation of S1P species in Mfsd2b knockout red blood cells and platelets compared with that of wild-type controls. Consistently, biochemical assays from knockout red blood cells, platelets, and cell lines overexpressing human and mouse Mfsd2b proteins demonstrate that Mfsd2b actively exports S1P. Plasma S1P level in knockout mice is significantly reduced by 42–54% of that of wild-type level, indicating that Mfsd2b pathway contributes approximately half of the plasma S1P pool. The reduction of plasma S1P in knockout mice is insufficient to cause blood vessel leakiness, but it does render the mice more sensitive to anaphylactic shock. Stress-induced erythropoiesis significantly increased plasma S1P levels and knockout mice were sensitive to these treatments. Surprisingly, knockout mice exhibited haemolysis associated with red blood cell stomatocytes, and the haemolytic phenotype was severely increased with signs of membrane fragility under stress erythropoiesis. We show that S1P secretion by Mfsd2b is critical for red blood cell morphology. Our data reveal an unexpected physiological role of red blood cells in sphingolipid metabolism in circulation. These findings open new avenues for investigating the signalling roles of S1P derived from red blood cells and platelets. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24053&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24053&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/f8KmceRpBwU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Thiet M. Vu</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">USP7 small-molecule inhibitors interfere with ubiquitin binding</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/F5XGmoQk_Ao/nature24006"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24006</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 The ubiquitin system regulates essential cellular processes in eukaryotes. Ubiquitin is ligated to substrate proteins as monomers or chains and the topology of ubiquitin modifications regulates substrate interactions with specific proteins. Thus ubiquitination directs a variety of substrate fates including proteasomal degradation. Deubiquitinase enzymes cleave ubiquitin from substrates and are implicated in disease; for example, ubiquitin-specific protease-7 (USP7) regulates stability of the p53 tumour suppressor and other proteins critical for tumour cell survival. However, developing selective deubiquitinase inhibitors has been challenging and no co-crystal structures have been solved with small-molecule inhibitors. Here, using nuclear magnetic resonance-based screening and structure-based design, we describe the development of selective USP7 inhibitors GNE-6640 and GNE-6776. These compounds induce tumour cell death and enhance cytotoxicity with chemotherapeutic agents and targeted compounds, including PIM kinase inhibitors. Structural studies reveal that GNE-6640 and GNE-6776 non-covalently target USP7 12 Å distant from the catalytic cysteine. The compounds attenuate ubiquitin binding and thus inhibit USP7 deubiquitinase activity. GNE-6640 and GNE-6776 interact with acidic residues that mediate hydrogen-bond interactions with the ubiquitin Lys48 side chain, suggesting that USP7 preferentially interacts with and cleaves ubiquitin moieties that have free Lys48 side chains. We investigated this idea by engineering di-ubiquitin chains containing differential proximal and distal isotopic labels and measuring USP7 binding by nuclear magnetic resonance. This preferential binding protracted the depolymerization kinetics of Lys48-linked ubiquitin chains relative to Lys63-linked chains. In summary, engineering compounds that inhibit USP7 activity by attenuating ubiquitin binding suggests opportunities for developing other deubiquitinase inhibitors and may be a strategy more broadly applicable to inhibiting proteins that require ubiquitin binding for full functional activity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24006&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/F5XGmoQk_Ao&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lorna Kategaya</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Social behaviour shapes hypothalamic neural ensemble representations of conspecific sex</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/X8G922ep6gw/nature23885"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23885</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;
 All animals possess a repertoire of innate (or instinctive) behaviours, which can be performed without training. Whether such behaviours are mediated by anatomically distinct and/or genetically specified neural pathways remains unknown. Here we report that neural representations within the mouse hypothalamus, that underlie innate social behaviours, are shaped by social experience. Oestrogen receptor 1-expressing (Esr1+) neurons in the ventrolateral subdivision of the ventromedial hypothalamus (VMHvl) control mating and fighting in rodents. We used microendoscopy to image Esr1+ neuronal activity in the VMHvl of male mice engaged in these social behaviours. In sexually and socially experienced adult males, divergent and characteristic neural ensembles represented male versus female conspecifics. However, in inexperienced adult males, male and female intruders activated overlapping neuronal populations. Sex-specific neuronal ensembles gradually separated as the mice acquired social and sexual experience. In mice permitted to investigate but not to mount or attack conspecifics, ensemble divergence did not occur. However, 30 minutes of sexual experience with a female was sufficient to promote the separation of male and female ensembles and to induce an attack response 24 h later. These observations uncover an unexpected social experience-dependent component to the formation of hypothalamic neural assemblies controlling innate social behaviours. More generally, they reveal plasticity and dynamic coding in an evolutionarily ancient deep subcortical structure that is traditionally viewed as a ‘hard-wired’ system. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 388 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23885&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23885&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/X8G922ep6gw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Ryan Remedios</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Cancer treatment: Bacterial snack attack deactivates a drug</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/HsfclxHIRE8/550337a"/>
		<id>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/550337a</id>
		<updated>2017-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
 &lt;p&gt;Tumour cells can develop intrinsic adaptations that make them less susceptible to chemotherapy. It emerges that extrinsic bacterial action can also enable tumour cells to escape the effects of drug treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 550 337 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/550337a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/550337a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/HsfclxHIRE8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Christian Jobin</name>
			<uri>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Nature Biological Sciences Research</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Nature is a weekly international journal publishing the finest peer-reviewed research in all fields of science and technology on the basis of its originality, importance, interdisciplinary interest, timeliness, accessibility, elegance and surprising conclusions. Nature also provides rapid, authoritative, insightful and arresting news and interpretation of topical and coming trends affecting science, scientists and the wider public.</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch"/>
			<id>http://www.nature.com/nature/research/biological-sciences.rdf</id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
			<rights type="html">© Nature Publishing Group</rights>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s what space toilets can teach us about finding signs of alien life</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-what-space-toilets-can-teach-us-about-finding-signs-alien-life"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-what-space-toilets-can-teach-us-about-finding-signs-alien-life</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T21:38:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Lessons learned from flushing space toilets can help researchers plan life-hunting missions to icy moons.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Lisa Grossman</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-24T11:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">How volcanoes may have ended the dynasty of Ptolemy and Cleopatra</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-volcanoes-may-have-ended-dynasty-ptolemy-and-cleopatra"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-volcanoes-may-have-ended-dynasty-ptolemy-and-cleopatra</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T19:54:21+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Volcanic ash in polar ice reveal a link between eruptions and the timing of revolts in Cleopatra’s Egypt.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Carolyn Gramling</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Cross-Journal Initiative Helps Manuscripts Take Flight</title>
		<link href="http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/r5cqRA6NQKw/"/>
		<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7773</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T19:09:50+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html" xml:lang="en-US">
 &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/10/papers-flying-away_3-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;All properly executed science deserves to be published as quickly as possible. One common frustration of scientists related to publication speed is the review-rejection cycle that in action resembles a cross between cycling on a hamster wheel and jumping through a hoola-hoop. To offer authors a way out of this cycle of delay, PLOS launched a journal transfer initiative earlier this year that provides authors an alternative to starting from scratch for papers not initially accepted by a subset of PLOS journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How It Works&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manuscripts submitted to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; undergo the usual rigorous peer review. The paper’s editors assess the reviews and if they decide the work does not meet the journal’s criteria for perceived novelty or impact but is sound, well-designed and well-executed, they will offer acceptance and publication in the multidisciplinary journal, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/static/publish&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Publication can take place in as little as three weeks after the offer is accepted by the authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papers which merit publication will go through the peer review and revision process only once, saving authors, reviewers and academic editors time, speeding the way to publication for quality research.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Why It Works&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit to authors is that instead of rejecting the paper outright, editors now may use the decision letter to offer either immediate publication or publication after minor revisions. Importantly, to move the paper along faster for authors – rather than moving the goal posts – the same academic editor will consider the revision. This also ensures consistency of the feedback to authors and expedites the work for editors. Provided the authors agree to the offer, the manuscript will be published in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE &lt;/em&gt;with both the original date of submission to &lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt; and the name of that journal’s academic editor listed in the article’s metadata. As for all articles published by PLOS, this metadata appears together with citation, copyright, data availability, funding and competing interest information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Open In Order To Succeed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS has piloted this initiative over the past six months and we’re pleased to report that with substantial support from journal editorial boards and uptake from authors, we will continue this initiative that relieves authors, reviewers and editors of some of the repetition involved in publishing while bringing quality work to the public, faster. There are now notifications of the program on the relevant journal &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/s/editorial-and-peer-review-process#loc-transferring-to-other-journals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Editorial and Peer Review Process&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;pages. Alongside existing manuscript transfer routes between PLOS journals, this newest initiative offers an effective means for scientists to rapidly communicate ideas, results and discoveries to each other and to the broader public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Access has changed the way readers and researchers around the world discover, use and reuse the scientific literature. Open data provides opportunities for new analysis, new discovery and even previously unrecognized new directions in research. Together with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/tech/open-source-ambra/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open source software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open source hardware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005473&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;preprint servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, forward movement along the path toward a more &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/11/23/open-source-science-communities-an-interview-with-abigail-cabunoc-mayes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has the potential to expand the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2015/03/get-paper-noticed-join-current-scientific-conversation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;venues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/paleocomm/2017/05/23/socialmedia_preprints/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;styles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2015/06/update-on-plos-science-wednesday-redditscience-ama-series-upcoming-featured-plos-authors/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;frequency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of sharing work. Let your manuscript take flight! PLOS authors who take this opportunity for rapid publication in &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; can play an active role in accelerating the discovery and dissemination of their work. With International Open Access Week right around the corner, what better motto to adopt than &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/04/placing-authors-at-the-center-of-the-scientific-endeavor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open In Order To Succeed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—for it is success that we seek for reviewers, editors and most importantly, all authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/r5cqRA6NQKw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Sheryl P. Denker</name>
			<uri>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Public Library of Science</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Diverse Perspectives on Science and Medicine</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed"/>
			<id>http://blogs.plos.org/plos</id>
			<updated>2017-10-25T05:00:24+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">This stretchy implant could help kids avoid repeated open-heart surgeries</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/stretchy-implant-could-help-kids-avoid-repeated-open-heart-surgeries"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/stretchy-implant-could-help-kids-avoid-repeated-open-heart-surgeries</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T15:58:42+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 A new type of surgical implant grows along with its recipient.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Maria Temming</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?_=2486</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T17:00:31+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">21 faculty at Johns Hopkins threaten to resign from board if journal doesn’t retract paper</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/17/21-faculty-johns-hopkins-threaten-resign-board-journal-doesnt-retract-paper/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52170</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T15:22:20+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;More than 20 faculty members at Johns Hopkins University have signed a letter to Scientific Reports saying they will resign from the editorial board if the journal doesn’t retract a 2016 paper. The paper is problematic, they argue, because a biologist at Johns Hopkins claims it plagiarized his work. One of that biologist’s colleagues at […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/17/21-faculty-johns-hopkins-threaten-resign-board-journal-doesnt-retract-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;21 faculty at Johns Hopkins threaten to resign from board if journal doesn’t retract paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>Alison McCook</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-22T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">Here’s a breakdown of the animals that crossed the Pacific on 2011 tsunami debris</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-breakdown-animals-crossed-pacific-2011-tsunami-debris"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-breakdown-animals-crossed-pacific-2011-tsunami-debris</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T15:00:03+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Hundreds of marine animals from Japan have washed up on U.S. beaches since the destructive 2011 earthquake and tsunami.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Mariah Quintanilla</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?sc=gb-1447244002</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-23T11:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en">A universal flu shot may be nearing reality</title>
		<link href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/universal-flu-shot-may-be-nearing-reality"/>
		<id>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/universal-flu-shot-may-be-nearing-reality</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:52:22+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 Scientists are developing a universal vaccine against flu, making annual shots a thing of the past.</content>
		<author>
			<name>Laura Beil</name>
			<uri>https://www.sciencenews.org/feeds/headlines.rss?0_8261957591723981=1</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Science News</title>
			<link rel="self" href=""/>
			<id></id>
			<updated>2017-10-22T11:00:30+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

	<entry>
		<title type="html" xml:lang="en-US">Boys will be boys: Data error prompts U-turn on study of sex differences in school</title>
		<link href="http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/17/boys-will-boys-data-error-prompts-u-turn-study-sex-differences-school/"/>
		<id>http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52165</id>
		<updated>2017-10-17T12:00:29+00:00</updated>
		<content type="html">
 &lt;p&gt;The authors of a 2017 paper on emotional and behavioral gaps between boys and girls have retracted the article after discovering a coding error that completely undermined their conclusions. The revelation prompted the researchers to republish their findings in the same journal, this time with a title that flips the narrative. The PsychJournal study, first […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/10/17/boys-will-boys-data-error-prompts-u-turn-study-sex-differences-school/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Boys will be boys: Data error prompts U-turn on study of sex differences in school&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<author>
			<name>amarcus41</name>
			<uri>http://retractionwatch.com</uri>
		</author>
		<source>
			<title type="html">Retraction Watch</title>
			<subtitle type="html">Tracking retractions as a window into the scientific process</subtitle>
			<link rel="self" href="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/"/>
			<id>http://retractionwatch.com</id>
			<updated>2017-10-22T05:00:33+00:00</updated>
		</source>
	</entry>

</feed>
