<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Resist or avoid? Sad study suggests bullying victims are on their own either way</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19584</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/22/resist-or-avoid-sad-study-suggests-bullying-victims-are-on-their-own-either-way/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19597&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19597&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Colleagues gossiping with sad young businessman in foreground at a bright office&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1425427873&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Wavebreakmedia&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;640&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/22/resist-or-avoid-sad-study-suggests-bullying-victims-are-on-their-own-either-way/office-workers-gossiping-behind-a-worker-who-looks-downcast/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workplace bullying can corrode organisations and wreck individual lives. Research has revealed more and more about effects on victims and the motives of the perpetrators. But bullying is often a performance that demands an audience: you can’t ostracise someone from an empty room, or gossip about them to the wind. So it’s worth looking at the third ingredient in the bullying mix: the bystander. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2016.1152213&quot;&gt;New research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; takes on this task, looking at the factors that dispose a bystander against bullying victims, and what might encourage them to step in and help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19584&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the Netherlands-based Open University recruited 161 working adults and presented each with a hypothetical workplace vignette, in which the victim was interrupted, belittled, excluded and gossiped about by a bullying colleague. In one condition, the victim was proactive, daring the bully to criticise them to their face or demanding they cease their behaviour. In another, the victim avoided the situation, by skipping out when the bully entered a room, or by taking sick leave to avoid work entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants were cast as bystanders to these contrasting situations, and Roelie Mulder’s team predicted that they would have a more negative view of the avoidant victims. Stigma research shows that people are less sympathetic to the suffering of others when they perceive they haven’t taken opportunities to improve their situation. Consistent with this, participants said they would feel more anger towards an avoidant victim, and considered them to hold much more responsibility for their predicament. Proactive victims were additionally seen as more self-reliant. So it might appear that proactivity is a good move if you want to get bystanders on-side and willing to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, that’s not the case. Participants were also asked to report how likely they would be to step in and help the victim, and they showed no greater willingness to help proactive ones. There’s a grim logic behind this: the more responsible a victim was seen to be for being bullied, the less participants wanted to help. But bystanders were also less likely to help victims they saw as self-reliant, presumably because they felt less of a pressing need to do so. You either don’t need help, or you don’t deserve it, a classic catch-22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proactivity appears admirable from the outside: in past work, most people said they would prefer to stand up to hypothetical bullies, and victims looking back on events often wish they had done so. But the reality is that when we find ourselves in these situations, it isn’t so easy – avoidance is the more common strategy – and what’s more, proactivity isn’t always the wisest choice. If you lose your cool, you could be at risk of formal consequences. And even if you play it well, a confronted bully might just double down on their behaviour. A proactive victim might be the one most in need of help, but bystanders don’t see it that way. So if you’re coming out fighting, bear in mind that you may also need to explicitly ask for help from those who seem sympathetic, but haven’t realised the need to throw their hat into the ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2016.1152213&quot;&gt;Workplace mobbing: How the victim’s coping behavior influences bystander responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19584/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19584/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19584&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Predicting medical students who will struggle based on their admissions characteristics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8554</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/22/predicting-medical-students-will-struggle-based-admissions-characteristics/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000012644846Medium-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many debates about the best way to select people into medical school, but one of the questions I ponder is how do we judge the success of such selection processes? There are a few problems in doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, there’s the ‘restriction of range’ problem. The people who don’t get into medical school are often lost to follow-up. We cannot easily set up an experiment to see how they might have got on in medical school, had they been admitted. This means the students we follow are only those who were successful in the selection process. So, simple correlations between selection measures and intra-medical school measures can usually only distinguish the successful from the very successful. The simplest correlations are between selection measures and assessment outcomes – many have done that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-016-0779-x&quot;&gt;including us&lt;/a&gt;. It’s helpful but not the whole answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another measure could relate to our social responsibilities – the extent to which our selection processes match the health needs of our societies in which we practise. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nzma.org.nz/journal/read-the-journal/all-issues/2010-2019/2012/vol-125-no-1361/article-crampton&quot;&gt;Otago medical school&lt;/a&gt; has adopted the ‘mirror on society’ principle where we aim for the demographic makeup of the medical school class to match the demographic makeup of our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These areas generally try to predict success, but a third area to research is to predict difficulty. This area was the focus of our article &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-017-0879-2&quot;&gt;published this week in &lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Even here though, there are challenges for researchers as, in general, medical students are motivated and capable – so they mostly achieve well in medical school. This means the outcome of interest in our research (students who have difficulty in the course) are relatively infrequent –this is a desirable educational outcome, but it is a hindrance in research design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of a more &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6920-11-29&quot;&gt;programmatic approach&lt;/a&gt; to assessment at the University of Otago, we keep a fairly close eye on our students and like to have sensitive measures of difficulty – we’d rather find a few who might be struggling but turn out to be doing well, than to miss a few who later get into bother. Our system is more sensitive than specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…we’d rather find a few who might be struggling but turn out to be doing well, than to miss a few who later get into bother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve found that students who are new to the country and have had less time to acculturate are at greater risk of developing problems, as are those with lower academic grades at entry and those with lower scores on the component of an aptitude test that measures understanding people. Men ran into more problems than women but no ethnic group was at greater risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as it pains me to say it, men are at greater risk of running into difficulty during their course but we’re not about to use gender as a selection measure! Although we keep trying to deny it, whichever way we look at it, academic grades still seem to be a good measure of success and difficulty – I guess doctors need to be smart. However, they also need to understand the society in which they will practise and understand people – these are measures on which we should place a greater focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/22/predicting-medical-students-will-struggle-based-admissions-characteristics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Predicting medical students who will struggle based on their admissions characteristics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 09:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000012644846Medium-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Inside the Chinese lab poised to study world's most dangerous pathogens</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21487</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BIb8uta8_ZY/nature.2017.21487</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Maximum-security biolab is part of plan to build network of BSL-4 facilities across China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 399 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21487&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21487&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BIb8uta8_ZY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: No publication without confirmation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542409a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bPuyrOo6KaQ/542409a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey S. Mogil and Malcolm R. Macleod propose a new kind of paper that combines the flexibility of basic research with the rigour of clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 409 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542409a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542409a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bPuyrOo6KaQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Gene editing in legal limbo in Europe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/thMm-U88qFA/542392a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The European Union is dragging its feet on gene-editing rules and scientists should push the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 392 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542392a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/thMm-U88qFA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Howler monkeys may owe their color vision to leaf hue</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/howler-monkeys-may-owe-their-color-vision-leaf-hue</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/howler-monkeys-may-owe-their-color-vision-leaf-hue</link>
	<description>Better color vision gives howler monkeys an edge at finding food.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 22:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022117_lh_howlermonkey_main_free.jpg?itok=cqWt7cE-" length="24651" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Power may have passed via women in ancient Chaco Canyon society</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/power-may-have-passed-women-new-mexicos-ancient-chaco-canyon-society</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/power-may-have-passed-women-new-mexicos-ancient-chaco-canyon-society</link>
	<description>DNA points to a 330-year-long reign of a maternal dynasty centered in New Mexico’s Chaco Canyon.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 22:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022117_BB_chaco-dna_main.jpg?itok=y2l-ek7u" length="53372" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Former postdoc admitted to fraud in cell bio paper, lead author says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48372</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/former-postdoc-admitted-fraud-cell-bio-paper-lead-author-says/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher in Switzerland has retracted her 2015 paper in the Journal of Cell Biology, saying the first author — her former postdoc — admitted to fabricating multiple aspects of the paper. After Sophie Martin of the University of Lausanne couldn’t reproduce the data from another manuscript she was preparing to submit, she contacted her former student, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/former-postdoc-admitted-fraud-cell-bio-paper-lead-author-says/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Former postdoc admitted to fraud in cell bio paper, lead author says&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Low-status chimps revealed as trendsetters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/low-status-chimps-revealed-trendsetters</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/low-status-chimps-revealed-trendsetters</link>
	<description>Outranked chimpanzees trigger spread of useful new behaviors among their comrades.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_BB_chimpanzee_main.jpg?itok=4CBFOwEC" length="37952" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Making the #CancerMoonshot a reality – starting with a conversation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/making-the-cancermoonshot-a-reality-starting-with-a-conversation</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/making-the-cancermoonshot-a-reality-starting-with-a-conversation</link>
	<description>Watch leading researchers talk about how to accelerate cancer care</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 14:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New, greener catalysts are built for speed</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-greener-catalysts-are-built-speed</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-greener-catalysts-are-built-speed</link>
	<description>Researchers are designing catalysts to move chemical reactions without using precious metals, or at least using less of them.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/030417_catalyst_feat_free_rev.jpg?itok=zb4ErLk9" length="28196" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Got “significosis?” Here are the five diseases of academic publishing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48164</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/got-significosis-five-diseases-academic-publishing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;John Antonakis is psychologist by training, but his research has run the gamut from showing kids accurately predict election outcomes just by looking at candidates’ faces to teaching charisma to people in leadership positions. Now, as the newly appointed editor of The Leadership Quarterly, he’s tackling problems in academic publishing. But his approach is somewhat […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/got-significosis-five-diseases-academic-publishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Got “significosis?” Here are the five diseases of academic publishing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Episode 9: How To Get The Best From Your Team</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19433</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/21/episode-9-how-to-get-the-best-from-your-team/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_19569&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19569&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19569&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,768&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/21/episode-9-how-to-get-the-best-from-your-team/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/ulianne/9604099396/in/photolist-fCFw9C-9Kh5wK-5EWMqc-9DXH3f-hTTcbf-a3kaC1-8URYWK-84UXz4-9Rouno-ppQ9za-afN6Ze-dH3fTv-fD3srb-9ffNjs-5TTbt5-d79ZWm-8kSUdp-QAxLBZ-9oupmE-RGunuY-eKSrMR-eejV36-MMML3-RnJGEL-nybnGE-bYy4DQ-9fcV52-Gpztu-7R1LZb-8h2QC2-fY2wZR-noxBBT-cTv9Z3-4fwh5k-8v9wjM-cjK8xG-7YGZNc-jTsYyn-8Rt4B2-5XgkmS-ev3b31-bCWhXn-4GcE7q-diyuBG-6wBCat-5XgkzE-j7CbC6-a3GJCZ-a6fyCf-2ZqibA&quot;&gt;Julianne/Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psychcrunch.libsyn.com/episode-9&quot;&gt;This is Episode 9 of &lt;strong&gt;PsychCrunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the podcast from the British Psychological Society’s Research Digest, sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;. Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;audio class=&quot;wp-audio-shortcode&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; id=&quot;audio-19433-1&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3?_=1&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Can psychology help us work together better in teams?&lt;/strong&gt; Our presenter Christian Jarrett hears about the benefits of appointing a “meta-knowledge champion” for the team, making sure everyone has contact with the team’s “extra miler”, and why you should think carefully about the physical space that you do your teamwork in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guests in order of appearance: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essec.edu/en/staff/faculty/julija-mell&quot;&gt;Dr Julija Mell&lt;/a&gt; (Essec Business School), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net&quot;&gt;Dr Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (Research Digest writer), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psy.uq.edu.au/directory/index.html?id=1391&quot;&gt;Dr Katherine Greenaway&lt;/a&gt; (University of Queensland).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Studies discussed in the episode&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/09/08/why-your-team-should-appoint-a-meta-knowledge-champion-one-person-whos-aware-of-everyone-elses-area-of-expertise/&quot;&gt;Why your team should appoint a “meta-knowledge” champion – one person who’s aware of everyone else’s area of expertise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/03/23/team-effectiveness-is-disproportionately-influenced-by-your-groups-best-performer-or-extra-miler/&quot;&gt;Team effectiveness is disproportionately influenced by your group’s best performer or “extra-miler”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/05/25/minimalist-anonymous-rooms-are-probably-not-a-good-place-to-do-teamwork/&quot;&gt;Minimalist, anonymous rooms are probably not a good place to do teamwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/ageing-and-society/article/in-home-or-at-home-how-collective-decision-making-in-a-new-care-facility-enhances-social-interaction-and-wellbeing-amongst-older-adults/FBEDCFA8FB9B95D33919BAE18F579B8A&quot;&gt;In home or at home? How collective decision making in a new care facility enhances social interaction and wellbeing amongst older adults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related resources from &lt;em&gt;The Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-24/edition-9/towards-healthier-meetings&quot;&gt;Towards Healthier Meetings&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-25/edition-11/interview-taking-control-your-space&quot;&gt;An Interview With Dr Craig Knight: Taking Back Control Of Your Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Episode credits&lt;/b&gt;: Presented and produced by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;Dr Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;. Mixing and editing &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffknowler.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Jeff Knowler&lt;/a&gt;. Vox pops Ella Rhodes. PsychCrunch theme music Catherine Loveday and Jeff Knowler. Additional music Zander Sehkri/Zeroday Productions (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pond5.com/stock-music/56374486/reach-impossible-epic-cinematic-orchestral-piano.html&quot;&gt;Pond5&lt;/a&gt;). Art work Tim Grimshaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;Check out this episode!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/psychcrunch/id966578696?mt=2&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=75970&amp;amp;refid=stpr&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/3FGoC927WmEteiFzdepSrR&quot;&gt;Subscribe and listen on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Past episodes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/episode-one.html&quot;&gt;Episode one: Dating and Attraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/episode-two.html&quot;&gt;Episode two: Breaking Bad Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/10/episode-three.html&quot;&gt;Episode three: How to Win an Argument&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/12/episode-4.html&quot;&gt;Episode four: The Psychology of Gift Giving&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/03/episode-5.html&quot;&gt;Episode five: How To Learn a New Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/06/episode-6.html&quot;&gt;Episode six: How To Be Sarcastic &lt;img alt=&quot;😉&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/08/episode-7.html&quot;&gt;Episode seven: Use Psychology To Compete Like an Olympian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Episode eight: Can We Trust Psychological Studies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PsychCrunch is sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-10617&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10617&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;936,120&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/podcast/psychcrunch-banner-april-16/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Routledge &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SAGCtSOZXn&quot;&gt;interviewed PsychCrunch presenter Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt; about the aims of the podcast and engaging with the public about psychology research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19433/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19433/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19433&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 12:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3" length="" type="text/html"/>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Coconut crab pinches like a lion, eats like a dumpster diver</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coconut-crab-pinches-lion-eats-dumpster-diver</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coconut-crab-pinches-lion-eats-dumpster-diver</link>
	<description>Coconut crabs use their surprisingly powerful claw for more than cracking coconuts.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/020217_SM_coconut-crab_main.jpg?itok=ZB7hg_oD" length="62613" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PubPeer blog: Vigilant scientists</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200</guid>
	<link>http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=vigilant-scientists-2</link>
	<description>In an editorial entitled “Vigilante science”, the editor-in-chief of Plant Physiology, Michael Blatt, makes the hyperbolic claim that anonymous post-publication peer review by the PubPeer community represents the most serious threat to the scientific process today. We obviously disagree. We … &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 11:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blog.pubpeer.com/?feed=atom">PubPeer</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Energy scientists must show their workings</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542393a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/B_Bfbo_Znmc/542393a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Public trust demands greater openness from those whose research is used to set policy, argues Stefan Pfenninger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 393 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542393a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542393a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/B_Bfbo_Znmc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Researchers should reach beyond the science bubble</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542391a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rVmNrYXQv_8/542391a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists in the United States and elsewhere ought to address the needs and employment prospects of taxpayers who have seen little benefit from scientific advances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 391 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542391a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542391a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rVmNrYXQv_8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Ankur Sinha: Using Wallabag to manage your online reading list</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:ankursinha.in,2017-02-20:/blog/2017/02/20/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</guid>
	<link>http://ankursinha.in/blog/2017/02/20/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I always have quite a bit on my pending list to read - academic papers, blogs, planets, and the sort. Usually, when I go through the planets, such as the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fedoraplanet.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://planet.gnome.org/&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; or the two neuroscience planets I use - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/&quot;&gt;neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt;, I don't have the time to read all the articles right then. I used to either bookmark links, or note them down somewhere to read later. One day, though, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you save the article to read later and makes it available to you on multiple devices. It's extremely convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the one issue with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is that it isn't &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&quot;&gt;Free software&lt;/a&gt;. So, like I do, I went looking for an alternative. After a few hours, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It's written in PHP, and is licensed under the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://tldrlegal.com/license/mit-license&quot;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite easy to deploy, and there's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; where you can get some help too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You either enter the URL in the Wallabag page manually, or you can use the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/wallabagger/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/wallabagger/gbmgphmejlcoihgedabhgjdkcahacjlj&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/wallabagger/?display=en&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; addon - it let's you right click a page or a link and &quot;Wallabag.it!&quot;. There's also a bookmarklet, which you can use with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/5digits/dactyl&quot;&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt;, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code bash literal-block&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Add to ~/.pentadactylrc
&lt;/span&gt;command! wallabagit -description &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Add to wallabag&quot;&lt;/span&gt; open javascript:&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;var%20url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;location.href&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;var%20wllbg&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;window.open&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'https://app.wallabag.it/bookmarklet?url='&lt;/span&gt;%20+%20encodeURI&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'_blank'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;})()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag fetches the text of the page and stores it for you so that you can read it later. You can even organise your saved pages with tags and the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing the Wallabag main page&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a page that I'm trying to read later, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing an article in Wallabag&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played with a deployment, but decided not to deploy and maintain an instance myself. Instead, I signed up for the instance Wallabag have here - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite cheap - they have an offer going too at the moment - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en/news/wallabagit&quot;&gt;only 9€ for an entire year&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag uses a the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fivefilters.org/content-only/&quot;&gt;FiveFilters Full Text RSS tool&lt;/a&gt; to extract the text and other data from web pages. Some websites require special instructions to tell the tool what information needs to be extracted - this tends to happen with a few academic websites. There's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fivefilters/ftr-site-config&quot;&gt;repository of such config files here&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you do run into a website that isn't rendering properly, you can &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://doc.wallabag.org/en/master/user/errors_during_fetching.html&quot;&gt;troubleshoot the issue and submit a config file too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you decide to deploy an instance yourself, or use &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;, I think it's a really useful tool to have. Of course, don't forget to install the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.gaulupeau.apps.InThePoche&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;app on your phone&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 20:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml">ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “I placed too much faith in underpowered studies:” Nobel Prize winner admits mistakes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48348</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/placed-much-faith-underpowered-studies-nobel-prize-winner-admits-mistakes/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Although it’s the right thing to do, it’s never easy to admit error — particularly when you’re an extremely high-profile scientist whose work is being dissected publicly. So while it’s not a retraction, we thought this was worth noting: A Nobel Prize-winning researcher has admitted on a blog that he relied on weak studies in a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/placed-much-faith-underpowered-studies-nobel-prize-winner-admits-mistakes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“I placed too much faith in underpowered studies:” Nobel Prize winner admits mistakes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 17:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Textbook fail: Rosenhan’s classic “On Being Sane In Insane Places” covered without criticism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19463</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/textbook-fail-rosenhans-classic-on-being-sane-in-insane-places-covered-without-criticism/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19544&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19544&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,681&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/textbook-fail-rosenhans-classic-on-being-sane-in-insane-places-covered-without-criticism/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 1970s, eight mentally well people, including psychologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Rosenhan&quot;&gt;David Rosenhan&lt;/a&gt;, presented themselves at psychiatric hospitals, where they showed signs of mild anxiety and complained of auditory hallucinations, specifically words like “empty” and “hollow”. All were admitted and either diagnosed with schizophrenia or, in one case, manic depression, and, despite acting “normal” after arrival, they were kept in hospital for an average of 19 days. On discharge all were described as having schizophrenia (or depression) “in remission”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Rosenhan’s classic study “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosenhan_experiment&quot;&gt;On Being Sane in Insane Places&lt;/a&gt;” which he claimed showed the stigmatising power of psychiatric labels and the inability of psychiatric staff to distinguish normality from supposed abnormality, as have many others since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But from a methodological perspective, the study was problematic for a number of reasons and Rosenhan’s interpretation has been hotly disputed. In their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/50_Great_Myths_of_Popular_Psychology&quot;&gt;highly regarded book on psychology myths&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Lilienfeld&quot;&gt;Scott Lilienfeld&lt;/a&gt; and his co-authors discuss the problem with Rosenhan’s study at length, such as the fact that in the 70s “in remission” was a very rare discharge diagnosis that actually showed psychiatric staff had realised the “pseudo patients” were mentally well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Lilienfeld et al argue that it is a myth that “psychiatric labels cause harm by stigmatising people” and that the overly gullible interpretation of the Rosenhan study has helped propagate this myth. Others may disagree, but it’s at least fair to say that Rosenhan’s study had serious issues and that not all psychologists agree that psychiatric labels are in themselves harmful (consider too &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/09/02/on-being-labelled-schizophrenic-in-the-words-of-the-diagnosed/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; that’s found that while clients say psychiatric labels can be difficult to deal with, they can also be beneficial in some ways, in terms of helping them understand their experiences and helping them to access appropriate treatments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how is this classic study covered in textbooks relating to clinical psychology and mental health (the sub-discipline usually referred to on university courses as “abnormal psychology”)? In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0098628317692634&quot;&gt;new survey&lt;/a&gt; of 12 contemporary abnormal psych textbooks in the journal &lt;em&gt;Teaching of Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, Jared Bartels and Daniel Peters found that half of them still give space to Rosenhan’s flawed study, but only two include any criticism or alternative interpretation of it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small survey and we’re not told the titles of the books, but the findings suggest that the problem of uncritical textbook coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-21/edition-9/foundations-sand&quot;&gt;social psychology’s classic, myth-like studies&lt;/a&gt;, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/23/what-the-textbooks-dont-tell-you-one-of-psychologys-most-famous-experiments-was-seriously-flawed/&quot;&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/10/13/social-psychology-textbooks-ignore-all-modern-criticisms-of-milgrams-obedience-experiments/&quot;&gt;Milgram’s “obedience research”&lt;/a&gt;, may also extend to the realm of classic mental health-related research. Is it that textbook authors are unaware of the criticisms of the Rosenhan study? Possibly, although Bartels and Peters surmise that perhaps authors know of the issues and alternative interpretations, but that these “shortcomings … are considered less important than the edifying message of the stigmatising effect of labels”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0098628317692634&quot;&gt;Coverage of Rosenhan’s “On Being Sane in Insane Places” in Abnormal Psychology Textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rockandrollfreak/16373344899/in/photolist-qWREZZ-rvnCZs-RG2mfN-e8NXbV-djJ8dQ-chyHGd-RQE5jk-awRCKc-ddhZ8o-bALqJc-e8UznG-bWsF9p-pGsnQV-gF5aT-bAJyhZ-cbHERd-enHVf1-dzMHiz-rNA2yv-oQ7yz5-qkmoHW-dpyYAf-sjqV61-qzJC4g-o8XMcK-dY6898-dKdfEr-eaaUSs-fLWk8J-smj7BE-bpuFRi-fLjFsz-pWwZzz-nvE2D4-QFDjPz-RkYRiw-QFDkVH-RG2kYA-RG2cMf-QFDyoP-saGLma-RJEmpZ-rxSMP2-RJESui-RJEq7t-QFEiMx-QFDgP6-p6c3zj-RRXw7J-RVASf6&quot;&gt;Flickr/Freaktography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19463/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19463/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19463&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 17:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Science of the Rorschach Blots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8562</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8562</link>
	<description>When the psychiatrist Hermann Rorschach blotted ink onto paper to produce a series of abstract patterns, could he have known that nearly 100 years later, the Rorschach test would be a household name?



Although the use of the Rorschach to diagnose mental illness is mostly a thing of the past, research on the test continues. Last week, two new papers were published on the Rorschach blots, including a fractal analysis of the images themselves and a brain scanning study using fMRI.



The</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Paper quickly retracted after author used another group’s work</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48295</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/paper-quickly-retracted-author-used-another-groups-work/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The author of a 2016 paper has agreed to retract it after an investigation revealed that most of the article came from another research group at the same university. According to the notice, the author based the majority of his paper on results generated by other scientists without their permission. Here’s the retraction notice for “Controlled synthesis […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/paper-quickly-retracted-author-used-another-groups-work/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paper quickly retracted after author used another group’s work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Multi-contact synapses for stable networks: a spike-timing dependent model of dendritic spine plasticity and turnover</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-02-20:/2017/02/20/multi-contact-synapses-for-stable-networks-a-spike-timing-dependent-model-of-dendritic-spine-plasticity-and-turnover.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/02/20/multi-contact-synapses-for-stable-networks-a-spike-timing-dependent-model-of-dendritic-spine-plasticity-and-turnover.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ankur Sinha's journal club session where he discusses the pre-print paper, &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1609.05730&quot;&gt;Multi-contact synapses for stable networks: a spike-timing dependent model of dendritic spine plasticity and turnover (Deger, M., Seeholzer, A., Gerstner, W. (2016))&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory synaptic connections in the adult neocortex consist of multiple synaptic contacts, almost exclusively formed on dendritic spines. Changes of dendritic spine shape and volume, a correlate of synaptic strength, can be tracked in vivo for weeks. Here, we present a combined model of spike-timing dependent dendritic spine plasticity and turnover that explains the steady state multi-contact configuration of synapses in adult neocortical networks. In this model, many presynaptic neurons compete to make strong synaptic connections onto postsynaptic neurons, while the synaptic contacts comprising each connection cooperate via postsynaptic firing. We demonstrate that the model is consistent with experimentally observed long-term dendritic spine dynamics under steady-state and lesion induced conditions, and show that cooperation of multiple synaptic contacts is crucial for stable, long-term synaptic memories. In simulations of a simplified network of barrel cortex, our plasticity rule reproduces whisker-trimming induced rewiring of thalamo-cortical and recurrent synaptic connectivity on realistic time scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 25/02/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 14:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Metabolic changes associated with aging skin: genomics reveals anti-aging targets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8589</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/20/metabolic-changes-associated-aging-skin-genomics-reveals-anti-aging-targets/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/skin-222664_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we age, our cells reduce their ability to regenerate as effectively, pigmentation increases, and wrinkles emerge. All of us experience some form of detriment to the skin, which cosmetic companies seek to re-mediate. For less of us, aging on the skin poses more serious issues such as cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our metabolism is key to supporting the function of the skin, such as the regulation of collagen and water. However, very little is currently known about metabolic alterations in aged skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessing metabolic changes at the genomic level can lead to new solutions to prevent age induced skin disorders. In the scientific community, it is well established that gene expression adaptions and metabolic changes accompany skin degradation. It has been observed that DNA repair capacities reduce, and methylation changes lead to decreased cellular plasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3547-3&quot;&gt;Recently published research&lt;/a&gt; from ETH Zurich provides valuable information on the metabolic adaptions of aging skin, and may benefit cosmetic companies to devise new solutions for age induced skin deterioration. These adaptions were observed in young (20-25 year old) and old (55-66 years old) human females by analyzing the RNA and metabolites of their skin’s epidermis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key discovery in the aged skin was the reduction of Q10; a coenzyme present within most animals. Often found within eukaryotic cells, Q10 is protein soluble, and can be seen in the market place as a health supplement for regulating energy in the body. Observed alterations to the processing of glucose (glycolysis), the reduced biosynthesis of protein and the organic compound polyamine are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Q10 decreased, there was a rise in the levels of taurine, the bio-marker cresol, and α-CEHC – the vitamin E metabolite. Metabolites for Vitamin E play an important role by providing anti-oxidative functions and preventing oxidative damage induced by UV energy. Most amino acid metabolites accumulated with age, helping to counteract dry skin by promoting moisturization of the epidermis, as the authors discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying metabolome and transcriptome analyses to human epidermal samples has provided insight into the metabolic adaptions associated with skin aging. Various metabolites are observed to have remedial effects on aging skin, which may help improve anti-aging skin products in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/20/metabolic-changes-associated-aging-skin-genomics-reveals-anti-aging-targets/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Metabolic changes associated with aging skin: genomics reveals anti-aging targets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/skin-222664_1920-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Concerning study says psychotherapy research has a problem with undeclared researcher bias</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19408</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/concerning-study-says-psychotherapy-research-has-a-problem-with-undeclared-researcher-bias/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;sharp rise&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19430&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19430&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/Zoonar RF&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sharp rise&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;sharp rise&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/concerning-study-says-psychotherapy-research-has-a-problem-with-undeclared-researcher-bias/sharp-rise/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a good doctor encounters research comparing the effectiveness of drugs A and B, she knows to beware the fact that B was created by the people paying the researchers’ salaries. Pharmaceutical industry funding can be complex, but the general principle of declaring financial conflicts of interest is now embedded in medical research culture. Unfortunately, research into psychological therapies doesn’t yet seem to have got its house in order in an equivalent way. That’s according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/6/4/e010606.long&quot;&gt;new open access article&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;em&gt;BMJ Open&lt;/em&gt; which suggests that, while there is less risk in this field of financially-based conflicts, researchers may be particularly vulnerable to non-financial biases, a problem that hasn’t been adequately acknowledged until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19408&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team, led by Klaus Lieb of the University of Mainz, examined 95 systematic and meta-analytic reviews that had evaluated the efficacy of psychological therapies by looking at the weight of evidence across multiple randomised controlled trials. Such reviews are generally used to give a balanced picture of what really works, above and beyond a single trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journals that publish this kind of research tend to be on the look out for financial conflicts of interest that could lead to a bias: for example, if the author of a meta-analysis of Therapy X was a license-holder for that therapy but chose not to declare that interest when reviewing it. Indeed, Lieb and his team found that four out of every five journals they investigated had explicitly asked that such conflicts be declared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But only a third of the journals asked the same of non-financial conflicts of interest, such as a review author being trained in one specific therapy, or otherwise being a particular advocate of one over others. Lieb and his colleagues argue that this presents a real problem because unlike a pharmaceutical researcher who becomes disenchanted with their favoured drug, “psychotherapy researchers who realise that the effect of the therapy to which they are allied is less beneficial than another therapy cannot easily switch their research programme to another therapy (since they have often been trained in that therapy for many years)”. This is especially true if they have been on record as a cheerleader for a particular therapy, or as a critic of its alternatives. Incidentally, at the end of their paper, Lieb and his colleagues act by example, providing a thorough outline of their own therapeutic training and related information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these conflicts may be especially pernicious for psychological therapies, and the fact that so few journals ask for declarations of these kind of allegiances is alarming. Even in cases where journals had asked for this information, only four researchers volunteered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this just means these conflicts are thankfully rare? This seems unlikely. Lieb’s team found that 34 of the reviews covered at least one and sometimes many more experimental studies authored by the reviewers themselves: not a crime in of itself, but a sign of at least a potential conflict. What’s more, Lieb’s group investigated these 34 reviews using a standard protocol to check for signs of “research allegiance”, that is whether the article betrayed a belief in the superiority of a treatment. Fifteen of the 34 reviews met these criteria, meaning that one or more of the authors had a vested interest in the conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieb and a co-author, Jan von der Osten-Sacken, also read through anonymised versions of all 95 reviews and labelled a conclusion as “spinned” when they felt it wasn’t consistent with the empirical results reported. Based on this, they claimed that reviews they’d identified earlier as having non-financial conflicts also tended to have biased conclusions. However, this link wasn’t statistically significant, so at best this tentative finding indicates something to be studied in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieb’s team emphasise they are not claiming that there is rampant fraud and deliberate misrepresentation. They suspect that “researchers may simply not be seeing the necessity of declaring non-financial interests, or be clear on what this includes”. So it’s incumbent on journals to outline more explicitly what constitutes a conflict of interest, and request and reveal them with more vigilance. Researchers themselves should take to heart the foundation on which the search for truth is built: to let go of your beliefs and be willing to be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/6/4/e010606.long&quot;&gt;Conflicts of interest and spin in reviews of psychological therapies: a systematic review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19408/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19408/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19408&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 10:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Delay in hiring science advisers intensifies Brexit worries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21511</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/HCTku2d9Yu4/nature.2017.21511</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Policy experts want scientists at the table when government decides on environmental protection and membership of international collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21511&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21511&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/HCTku2d9Yu4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The race to map the human body — one cell at a time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21508</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/A07vGfVyBK0/nature.2017.21508</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A host of detailed cell atlases could revolutionize understanding of cancer and other diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 404 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21508&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21508&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/A07vGfVyBK0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Giant crack in Antarctic ice shelf spotlights advances in glaciology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21507</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/AtiBM-8aqR0/nature.2017.21507</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Rift through Larsen C ice shelf has grown to 175 kilometres, and collapse of nearby ice shelves could offer a glimpse of its future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 402 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21507&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21507&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/AtiBM-8aqR0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Light-induced structural changes and the site of O=O bond formation in PSII caught by XFEL</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21400</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/73_4_HTihfo/nature21400</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Photosystem II (PSII) is a huge membrane-protein complex consisting of 20 different subunits with a total molecular mass of 350 kDa for a monomer. It catalyses light-driven water oxidation at its catalytic centre, the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC). The structure of PSII has been analysed at 1.9 Å resolution by synchrotron radiation X-rays, which revealed that the OEC is a Mn4CaO5 cluster organized in an asymmetric, ‘distorted-chair’ form. This structure was further analysed with femtosecond X-ray free electron lasers (XFEL), providing the ‘radiation damage-free’ structure. The mechanism of O=O bond formation, however, remains obscure owing to the lack of intermediate-state structures. Here we describe the structural changes in PSII induced by two-flash illumination at room temperature at a resolution of 2.35 Å using time-resolved serial femtosecond crystallography with an XFEL provided by the SPring-8 ångström compact free-electron laser. An isomorphous difference Fourier map between the two-flash and dark-adapted states revealed two areas of apparent changes: around the QB/non-haem iron and the Mn4CaO5 cluster. The changes around the QB/non-haem iron region reflected the electron and proton transfers induced by the two-flash illumination. In the region around the OEC, a water molecule located 3.5 Å from the Mn4CaO5 cluster disappeared from the map upon two-flash illumination. This reduced the distance between another water molecule and the oxygen atom O4, suggesting that proton transfer also occurred. Importantly, the two-flash-minus-dark isomorphous difference Fourier map showed an apparent positive peak around O5, a unique μ4-oxo-bridge located in the quasi-centre of Mn1 and Mn4 (refs 4,5). This suggests the insertion of a new oxygen atom (O6) close to O5, providing an O=O distance of 1.5 Å between these two oxygen atoms. This provides a mechanism for the O=O bond formation consistent with that proposed previously. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21400&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21400&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/73_4_HTihfo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Survival of tissue-resident memory T cells requires exogenous lipid uptake and metabolism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21379</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/kIwwIMnAQeg/nature21379</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Tissue-resident memory T (TRM) cells persist indefinitely in epithelial barrier tissues and protect the host against pathogens. However, the biological pathways that enable the long-term survival of TRM cells are obscure. Here we show that mouse CD8+ TRM cells generated by viral infection of the skin differentially express high levels of several molecules that mediate lipid uptake and intracellular transport, including fatty-acid-binding proteins 4 and 5 (FABP4 and FABP5). We further show that T-cell-specific deficiency of Fabp4 and Fabp5 (Fabp4/Fabp5) impairs exogenous free fatty acid (FFA) uptake by CD8+ TRM cells and greatly reduces their long-term survival in vivo, while having no effect on the survival of central memory T (TCM) cells in lymph nodes. In vitro, CD8+ TRM cells, but not CD8+ TCM cells, demonstrated increased mitochondrial oxidative metabolism in the presence of exogenous FFAs; this increase was not seen in Fabp4/Fabp5 double-knockout CD8+ TRM cells. The persistence of CD8+ TRM cells in the skin was strongly diminished by inhibition of mitochondrial FFA β-oxidation in vivo. Moreover, skin CD8+ TRM cells that lacked Fabp4/Fabp5 were less effective at protecting mice from cutaneous viral infection, and lung Fabp4/Fabp5 double-knockout CD8+ TRM cells generated by skin vaccinia virus (VACV) infection were less effective at protecting mice from a lethal pulmonary challenge with VACV. Consistent with the mouse data, increased FABP4 and FABP5 expression and enhanced extracellular FFA uptake were also demonstrated in human CD8+ TRM cells in normal and psoriatic skin. These results suggest that FABP4 and FABP5 have a critical role in the maintenance, longevity and function of CD8+ TRM cells, and suggest that CD8+ TRM cells use exogenous FFAs and their oxidative metabolism to persist in tissue and to mediate protective immunity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21379&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21379&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/kIwwIMnAQeg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Enzymes aid rice plants’ arsenic defenses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enzymes-aid-rice-plants-arsenic-defenses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enzymes-aid-rice-plants-arsenic-defenses</link>
	<description>Rice plant roots have natural defenses against arsenic.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 17:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_LH_arsenic-plants_main.jpeg?itok=atXq05M6" length="69375" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New imaging technique catches DNA ‘blinking’ on</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-imaging-technique-catches-dna-blinking</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-imaging-technique-catches-dna-blinking</link>
	<description>Dye-free imaging technique zooms in below 10-nanometer threshold, allowing new cellular views.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 15:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_RE_DNA-fluorescing_main.jpeg?itok=64sDXaJh" length="20566" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Using Discourse Analysis to Assess Cognitive Decline</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-6283119004927853198</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/tYYDadX2k1g/using-discourse-analysis-to-assess.html</link>
	<description>Figure from Gauthier et al. (2005).


Alzheimer's Disease (AD) and other dementias are progressive neurodegenerative conditions that unfold over time. Subtle symptoms such as forgetfulness and word finding problems may progress to mild cognitive impairment (MCI), and then escalate to full-blown dementia. Recent efforts to classify prodromal states have included automated analysis of spontaneous&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/tYYDadX2k1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 12:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Microbes survived inside giant cave crystals for up to 50,000 years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/microbes-survived-inside-giant-cave-crystals-50000-years</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/microbes-survived-inside-giant-cave-crystals-50000-years</link>
	<description>Microbes trapped in crystals in Mexico's Naica mine may represent some of the most distinct life-forms found in Earth so far.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 17:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_AY_mexico-microbes_main.jpg?itok=Qh4NB2Bt" length="28451" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Europa lander mission takes another step toward reality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/europa-lander-mission-takes-another-step-toward-reality</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/europa-lander-mission-takes-another-step-toward-reality</link>
	<description>NASA is working on a possible lander mission in which the main science goal would be to search for signs of life on Jupiter’s moon Europa.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_AY_contamination_main.jpg?itok=mljvwuIS" length="29748" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: The upside of predatory publishers; why no one replicates; the pain of manuscript submission</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48341</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/18/weekend-reads-upside-predatory-publishers-no-one-replicates-pain-manuscript-submission/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a retraction of a state senator’s paper, and an editor busted for citation boosting. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Predatory journals are not desirable, it goes without saying, but the fact that they come about is a sign of a developing market, and a true market in scientific publishing services […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/18/weekend-reads-upside-predatory-publishers-no-one-replicates-pain-manuscript-submission/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: The upside of predatory publishers; why no one replicates; the pain of manuscript submission&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 14:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Common fungus may raise asthma risk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-fungus-may-raise-asthma-risk</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-fungus-may-raise-asthma-risk</link>
	<description>The presence of a fungus in the infant gut can signal development of asthma by age 5.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 22:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_RE_fungus-asthma_main.jpg?itok=tYWL0MHb" length="15658" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Juno spacecraft won’t go into shorter orbit around Jupiter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-spacecraft-wont-go-shorter-orbit-around-jupiter</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-spacecraft-wont-go-shorter-orbit-around-jupiter</link>
	<description>Juno will remain in its 53-day orbit around Jupiter due to an issue with two helium check valves, NASA reports.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 21:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021717_juno_ticker_free.jpg?itok=Kv3blDLR" length="28667" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Fantasy of Connecting Two Spinal Cords</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8555</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8555</link>
	<description>A peculiar new paper proposes the idea of &quot;connecting two spinal cords as a way of sharing information between two brains&quot;. The author is Portuguese psychiatrist Amílcar Silva-dos-Santos and the paper appears in Frontiers in Psychology.



Frontiers are a publisher with a troubled history of publishing dubious science. But this paper is unusual, even by Frontiers' standards, because it contains virtually no science at all.

In a nutshell, Silva-Dos-Santos suggests that it would be interest</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 20:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Antarctic sea ice shrinks to record low</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctic-sea-ice-shrinks-record-low</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctic-sea-ice-shrinks-record-low</link>
	<description>The Antarctic sea ice extent has reached a new low just two years after hitting a record high.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 18:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021717_ticker_ts_antarctica_ice_free.jpg?itok=imLjdZWH" length="43804" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Unusual: Neurology removes author dinged for misconduct from 2016 paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48311</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/unusual-neurology-removes-author-dinged-misconduct-2016-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Neurology has partially retracted a 2016 paper, replacing a figure and removing the author who contributed it after he was found guilty of misconduct. The journal has replaced the figure with a new one that confirmed the findings of the original, and swapped the name of Andrew Cullinane with the scientist who constructed the new […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/unusual-neurology-removes-author-dinged-misconduct-2016-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unusual: Neurology removes author dinged for misconduct from 2016 paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Editor resigns from two journals after “considerable” citation boosting attempts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48321</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/editor-resigns-two-journals-considerable-citation-boosting-attempts/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An editor at two European Geophysical Union journals has resigned following revelations that he or she engaged in citation manipulation — boosting citations to his or her own papers and associated journals. Here’s a letter announcing the news, signed by EGU publication committee chair Hubert Savenije, that ran in several EGU journals earlier this week: […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/editor-resigns-two-journals-considerable-citation-boosting-attempts/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Editor resigns from two journals after “considerable” citation boosting attempts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: We’re seeking a writer to join our team!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19378</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/were-seeking-a-writer-to-join-our-team/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-19380 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19380&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=223&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1169,868&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/were-seeking-a-writer-to-join-our-team/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40/&quot; height=&quot;223&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=223&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Psychology blogger sought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British Psychological Society’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/about-us/&quot;&gt;Research Digest blog&lt;/a&gt;, which keeps hundreds of thousands of people abreast of the latest exciting findings in psychology, is seeking an additional writer. This is a paid staff position, initially on a six-month contract, for seven hours per week. Salary is £32,612 pro-rata, and benefits include paid holiday and access to the Society’s pension scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although based remotely, you’ll work closely with the Research Digest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt; to produce six engaging reports on new psychology studies each month, in a style that entertains and educates. You will show readers how the findings are relevant to their lives, but without resorting to hype. Where appropriate, you should have the confidence and competence to criticise studies.  As one of our writers, you’ll have the satisfaction of seeing your work reach our large international audience and get picked up by the world’s biggest publications, from &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally you will already have experience writing about psychology or related fields for the public. And we’ll also need to see documentation that demonstrates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/right-to-work-checklist&quot;&gt;your right to work in the UK&lt;/a&gt;; further information can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bps.org.uk/jobs/society-office-staff-vacancies/society-office-staff-vacancies&quot;&gt;Job Vacancies page on the Society website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send a short email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:christianjarrett@gmail.com&quot;&gt;christianjarrett@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line “Psychology Blogger”, explaining why you are the right person for this role. Include links or attachments representing three examples of your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline is noon (GMT) 10 March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19378/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19378/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19378&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Helium’s inertness defied by high-pressure compound</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heliums-inertness-defied-high-pressure-compound</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heliums-inertness-defied-high-pressure-compound</link>
	<description>At pressures over a million atmospheres, helium reacts with sodium.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_EC_helium_main.jpg?itok=RaV1wKpi" length="20152" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Citizen scientists are providing stunning new views of Jupiter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-scientists-are-providing-stunning-new-views-jupiter</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-scientists-are-providing-stunning-new-views-jupiter</link>
	<description>A camera aboard NASA’s Juno spacecraft is giving citizen scientists a crack at discovering never-before-seen features of Jupiter.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021617_ay_junocam_feat_free.jpg?itok=IsOjO6EB" length="19038" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: American women seem to be becoming less stereotypically feminine and more dominant</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19249</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/american-women-seem-to-be-becoming-less-stereotypically-feminine-and-more-dominant/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;we_can_do_it&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19319&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19319&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;we_can_do_it&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845?w=791&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845?w=232&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,1294&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/american-women-seem-to-be-becoming-less-stereotypically-feminine-and-more-dominant/we_can_do_it/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True gender equality may be a work in progress, but since the Women’s Liberation Movement beginning in the 1950s and 60s, there has been a lot of positive change, at least in most industrialised nations: a shift towards women having more control over whether and when to have children, for example, and increased opportunities in education and careers, and less tolerance of sexism (though of course it hasn’t gone away). How might these cultural and social changes have influenced women, in terms of how much they act in stereotypically “feminine” ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10804-016-9243-8/fulltext.html?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; by Constance Jones and her colleagues at California State and San Francisco State Universities in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Adult Development&lt;/em&gt; tried to find out by comparing two cohorts of women, one born in the 1920s and the other featuring “Baby Boomers” born in the 1950s. The findings support past work that’s shown how women tend to change through their lives, and they provide evidence for a generation effect: over time, at least in California, women seem to be becoming less stereotypically feminine – that is, less deferential, and more confident and ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19249&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 180 women born in the 1920s took the same California Psychological Inventory five times over as many decades, beginning when they were in their 30s and through into their 80s. The researchers were particularly interested in how they scored on the 32 items of the Inventory that measure femininity defined “as being gentle and warm, but also being dependent, and needing reassurance from others”, and how they scored on the 36 items measuring dominance, defined as “being confident, ambitious, assertive, and enterprising”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, 190 women born in the 1950s (actually daughters of the older participants) answered the same questions about their own femininity and dominance, first in 1980s when they were in their 30s, then twice more in their 40s and 50s/60s (taking us up to 2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones and her team found evidence of lifespan changes in both cohorts. Women in both groups tended to become less stereotypically feminine as they got older (with some return to more femininity later in life) and both groups showed signs of greater dominance with increasing age. Statistically speaking, the magnitude of change was modest in effect size. “[The] women appeared to drop constraining negative aspects of the feminine gender role and take on positive cross-gendered qualities with age,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing across the two cohorts, the women born in the second half of the twentieth century scored lower on femininity when they first completed the inventory in their 30s as compared with the femininity scores of the women born in the 1920s when they were the same age (a modest group difference in terms of effect size). “Most likely reacting to the Women’s Movement zeitgeist, [the younger cohort] entered young adulthood with less obligation to take on feminine gender constraints in the first place,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the rate of increase in dominance shown by the second generation women through their lives was more rapid than that shown by their mothers. Because of this difference in speed of change, the researchers said “we can expect the younger cohort women to be higher than the older cohort women in dominance when they reach later adulthood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be fascinating to see if and how these trends have continued in Generation X and Millenials. If you reflect on your own family – for example, how you or your sisters compare in femininity and dominance (as defined in this study) with your mother – bear in mind the implications of the parallel changes in these traits through lives and across generations. A young woman today might not seem a lot more dominant and less feminine than her mother is today, but that might be because of the way her mother has changed through her life. The chances are that the young woman is more dominant and less feminine than her mother was at the same age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study has some issues, including a reliance on how participants rated themselves and missing data from some of the survey points, which meant the researchers sometimes had to extrapolate from the scores they did have. Also both cohort samples were fairly small, and perhaps the observed generational changes are unique to the Bay Area of California. That said, Jones and her team pointed out that it was “rare to be able to examine personality change across such as expansive portion of the lifespan (age 20s through the 80s) and to be able to tie two historically important cohorts together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10804-016-9243-8/fulltext.html?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Femininity and Dominance Across the Lifespan: Longitudinal Findings from Two Cohorts of Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feminist_movement#/media/File:We_Can_Do_It!.jpg&quot;&gt;via Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19249/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19249/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19249&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 09:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Picking a lemur out of a line-up: introducing LemurFaceID, a facial recognition system for wild lemurs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8578</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/17/picking-lemur-line-introducing-lemurfaceid-facial-recognition-system-wild-lemurs/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 5&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-5-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking a face out of a crowd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our closest relatives, primates have long been a focus of research into their behavior and evolution. As many primate species become threatened with extinction, research on wild populations has become even more important, being crucial to conservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long-term studies, following primate social groups over many years, can be especially informative. However, a key requirement for such studies is to consistently and accurately identify different individuals: not always an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional way of identifying individuals is to capture them and attach a tag or collar. This has proven to be an effective technique on a number of successful long-term field studies. However it also comes with drawbacks. Capturing animals can be hard enough with birds or small mammals like rodents; for large primates, it usually involves darting them with a blow-gun or air rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is both expensive and time-consuming, limiting the number of individuals that can be tagged. Of even greater concern, the act of capture itself can be harmful to the animals, whether through damage caused during capture (anything from stress to broken bones), or by disrupting group dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to capturing and tagging is to identify individuals via natural variation in their features, such as scars or skin patterns. This does, however, require considerable skill on the part of observers. Even with extensive training, it is still inevitable that errors will occur in identification both within and between observers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8581&quot; style=&quot;width: 2000px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8581 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1990&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Examples of different lemur species, demonstrating the facial features that can allow individuals to be accurately identified.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;David Crouse, Rachel Jacobs, Stacey Tecot&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is really needed is a non-invasive identification method that relies less on human perception. The developing field of animal biometrics offers a potential solution, with automated recognition systems showing promise in a number of mammal species. New research, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmczool.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40850-016-0011-9&quot;&gt;published today &lt;/a&gt;in &lt;em&gt;BMC Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, describes the development of such an automated facial recognition system for lemurs: LemurFaceID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who’s that lemur?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study is the result of collaboration between a number of US-based scientists, led by lemur researchers &lt;a href=&quot;http://rachellynjacobs.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Rachel Jacobs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://stecot.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Stacy Tecot&lt;/a&gt; and biometrics researchers David Crouse and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cse.msu.edu/~jain/&quot;&gt;Anil Jain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their work takes advantage of a well-studied population of red-bellied lemurs. Like all lemurs, the red-bellied lemur is found only on the island of Madagascar. The study population, living in Ranomafana National Park, has been the subject of multiple research projects since the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, a substantial database of known individuals has been built up, based on variation in facial patterns. However, substantial training is required to identify individuals in this way, which led the researchers to develop this new system that can automatically match a photo of a lemur’s face to a database of known individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8582&quot; style=&quot;width: 1700px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 2&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8582 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1129&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-2.png&quot; width=&quot;1690&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Red bellied lemurs. The individual on the right is female, on the left a male, with distinctive white patch of skin around the eyes. Facial patterns are individually variable, allowing researchers to identify individuals&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;J. Falinomenjanahary&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, the researchers had access to 462 images of 80 red-bellied lemur individuals. LemurFaceID requires a researcher to manually locate the eyes in the picture, the critical aspect of this recognition system, as with most human facial recognition systems. Various other alterations are then made to the image (see below for a basic outline of the process) before LemurFaceID automatically compares and matches it to the database of known individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8584&quot; style=&quot;width: 4985px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Flowchart of how LemurFaceID works.&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8584&quot; height=&quot;3430&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-6.png&quot; width=&quot;4975&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Flowchart of how LemurFaceID works.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Crouse et al. 2017&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results show that LemurFaceID has a relatively high level of accuracy (98.7%) in ‘closed set’ mode – i.e. when only tested with pictures of known individuals already included in its database. Accuracy was lower in an ‘open-set’ mode when it was tested with pictures of lemurs not already included in the database. This suggests that, for now, LemurFaceID would be most useful for captive or well-studied wild populations (like this one) where all individuals are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the researchers are confident that the system can be further improved by the addition of larger datasets of photos and individuals, along with further field testing, eventually improving its ability to distinguish between known and novel individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facing the potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of the project is to provide a non-invasive method to recognise lemurs that does not require extensive training. The potential benefits of such a system are considerable. By reducing the difficulty and cost of long-term monitoring of wild lemur populations, the scope of such studies could be increased with more and better quality data generated in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have considerable benefit for our knowledge of the evolution of this unique primate radiation, endemic to just a single island, and help us learn more about their social systems. It would also enable improved monitoring of lemur population numbers and demographic structures, helping conservationists better model extinction risk; an important consideration when many lemur species (including the red-bellied lemur) are threatened by human encroachments into their habitat. It could even help fight the illegal pet-trade in lemurs taken from the wild, by allowing law enforcement and tourists to rapidly report sightings and determine the origin of captive lemurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8585&quot; style=&quot;width: 610px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Example of processing carried out on lemur images.&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8585&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-Fig8.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Example of processing carried out on lemur images.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Crouse et al. 2017&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods could also be adapted to other primates or even other large mammal species with variable facial or skin patterns, such as bears, red pandas, or sloths. Already similar automated facial recognition systems have been developed for &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1186/1687-5281-2013-49&quot;&gt;chimps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/282/1802/20142284&quot;&gt;guenons&lt;/a&gt;. Such systems could even be combined with automated remote camera traps, increasingly used to monitor populations of hard-to-track wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the researchers’ caution there is no “one size fits all” approach to automated animal facial recognition, it is clearly a technique that will play an ever larger part in our understanding of, and attempts to preserve, the large mammals of our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/17/picking-lemur-line-introducing-lemurfaceid-facial-recognition-system-wild-lemurs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Picking a lemur out of a line-up: introducing LemurFaceID, a facial recognition system for wild lemurs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 09:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-5-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Why the CRISPR patent verdict isn’t the end of the story</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21510</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0W5UthFBhyM/nature.2017.21510</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;From legal challenges to ongoing experimentation, the story of who owns the rights to CRISPR–Cas9 gene editing is still being written.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21510&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21510&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0W5UthFBhyM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ceres harbors homegrown organic compounds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ceres-harbors-homegrown-organic-compounds</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ceres-harbors-homegrown-organic-compounds</link>
	<description>NASA’s Dawn spacecraft has detected organic matter — the building blocks of life — on the dwarf planet Ceres, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 19:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_EE_ceres_main.jpg?itok=UKKevWra" length="13935" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seagrasses boost ecosystem health by fighting bad bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seagrasses-boost-ecosystem-health-fighting-bad-bacteria</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seagrasses-boost-ecosystem-health-fighting-bad-bacteria</link>
	<description>Seagrasses might reduce bacteria levels in ocean water.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_lh_seagrass_main.jpg?itok=JYo_eBcf" length="40100" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Speech recognition has come a long way in 50 years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/speech-recognition-has-come-long-way-50-years</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/speech-recognition-has-come-long-way-50-years</link>
	<description>Early versions of computer speech recognition relied on word sounds. Now, they add pattern recognition and a lot of statistics.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 17:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/020817_BO_50YA_speech_main_free.jpg?itok=XA5m2gVU" length="24581" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Cancer biologist stops research as his retraction count rises to 13</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48303</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/16/cancer-biologist-stops-research-retraction-count-rises-13/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A cancer biologist based at the University of Maryland is transitioning out of research, as a journal has retracted three more of his papers. Anil Jaiswal has now lost 13 papers, including, as we reported on February 6, six retractions issued earlier this month. The Baltimore Sun reported this week that Jaiswal would no longer […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/16/cancer-biologist-stops-research-retraction-count-rises-13/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cancer biologist stops research as his retraction count rises to 13&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: South Africa S&amp;T Minister Pandor to receive AAAS Award for Science Diplomacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/south-africa-s-and-t-minister-pandor-to-receive-aaas-award-for-science-diplomacy</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/south-africa-s-and-t-minister-pandor-to-receive-aaas-award-for-science-diplomacy</link>
	<description>Pandor will be recognized for her advocacy for young scientists and women scientists</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 15:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Social science isn’t definitive like chemistry:” Embattled food researcher defends his work</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48301</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/16/social-science-isnt-definitive-like-chemistry-embattled-food-researcher-defends-work/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a busy few months for Brian Wansink, a prominent food researcher at Cornell University. A blog post he wrote in November prompted a huge backlash from readers who accused him of using problematic research methods to produce questionable data, and a group of researchers suggested four of his papers contained 150 inconsistencies. The scientist has […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/16/social-science-isnt-definitive-like-chemistry-embattled-food-researcher-defends-work/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Social science isn’t definitive like chemistry:” Embattled food researcher defends his work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 15:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>xcorr.net: An introduction to meta-analysis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://xcorr.net/?p=6788</guid>
	<link>https://xcorr.net/2017/02/16/an-introduction-to-meta-analysis/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading an excellent book on meta-analysis, Introduction to Meta Analysis by Borenstein et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-amazon&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with the motivating example of streptokinase, a &lt;em&gt;blood clot buster.&lt;/em&gt; Early studies showed conflicting evidence of efficacy of the drug in preventing death following a heart attack. These early studies were small, and the main outcome was often not significantly different from zero; it took very large scale studies in 1986 and 1987 to confirm the protective effect of streptokinase, which could reduce deaths by 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-6788&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book makes the convincing case that the protective role of streptokinase could have been confirmed &lt;em&gt;ten years prior&lt;/em&gt; by aggregating the information from early studies. Early results were not truly contradictory; the studies were simply underpowered for the effect of interest – the ratio of the survival rates in the experiment and control arms. As you can see in this forest plot, the error bars in the early studies were huge, and overlapped 0, but many more studies showed a protective effect than not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.nlm.nih.gov/nichsr/hta101/a_images_hta101/04_image01.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That the effect could have been uncovered earlier is obvious from the plot on the right, which shows a cumulative meta-analysis; what happens when we aggregate all the studies up to a certain study? It’s clear from this result that the evidence was already overwhelming by 1977.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good meta analysis, such as this one, can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aggregate disparate information from different studies in an easily digestable from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get precise estimates of effect sizes, allowing decisions to be centered around whether a treatment shows a &lt;em&gt;clinically&lt;/em&gt; significant effect, as opposed to a simply &lt;em&gt;statistically&lt;/em&gt; significant one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify points of agreement and disagreements between studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify factors that moderate effect size through subgroup analysis and meta-regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guide the design of follow-up studies – for example, by identifying what is currently unclear in the extant data, or by furnishing an effect size estimate for power analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The mechanics of meta-analysis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a meta-analysis is to estimate an aggregate effect size. Now, different studies differ in substantive details – the target population, the randomization process, the practices of the institutions that perform the study – and so one cannot simply integrate data from different studies &lt;em&gt;as though&lt;/em&gt; they’re coming from the same study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, one assumes that the true underlying effect – on survival, blood pressure, choice probability, etc. – differs from study to study. Even if each study had an infinite number of subjects, there would still be measurable discrepancies between the measured effect sizes between studies. These differences in effect sizes would then reflect substantive differences between the studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under this &lt;em&gt;random effects&lt;/em&gt; model, bigger studies count more, but smaller studies are still informative about the range of effects that one would measure in real life. The mean effect size is just as interesting as the range of effect sizes. An heterogeneity statistic, $I^2$, can help one judge whether studies generally agree or disagree, and whether this has substantive implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify the source of heterogeneity, one can use subgroup analysis and meta-regression. In subgroup analysis, you slice the data along dimensions of interest, e.g. smokers vs. non-smokers, or different treatment arms. In meta-regression, you instead regress a continuous variable against the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These approaches can be useful in identifying future directions of research, but they must be carefully interpreted, as they are correlational; even if each study was double-blinded, subgroup analysis and meta-regression will break randomization, and should not be interpreted causally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Philosophical issues&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book goes into considerable detail into the manual computation of random effects models using a spreadsheet program, but in all honesty, you’re better off skipping these chapters, going straight into R and &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&quot;meta&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;. I’m using this package for an ongoing meta-analysis I’m running; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/patrickmineault/phaco-meta&quot;&gt;you can take a peek at what the code looks like here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s in the discussion chapters, on philosophical issues and interpretation and &lt;em&gt;gotchas&lt;/em&gt; that the book really shines. One chapter I really liked is on identifying publication bias. Studies can suffer from the &lt;em&gt;file drawer problem&lt;/em&gt;: studies with negative results never get published because of a lack of incentive to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s some techniques that have been developed to deal with publication bias. The underlying model is that large studies get published no matter their result, because they require so much resources and collaboration and are guaranteed a publication slot.  However, smaller studies are much more prone to publication bias; who wants to publish a tiny study with negative results?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;width: 522px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Figure 5: Funnel plot analysis[4]&quot; class=&quot; aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/www.ijmm.org/articles/2014/32/3/images/IndianJMedMicrobiol_2014_32_3_229_136547_u6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;522&quot; /&gt;A funnel plot showing no sign of publication bias [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ijmm.org/article.asp?issn=0255-0857;year=2014;volume=32;issue=3;spage=229;epage=235;aulast=Pabalan&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/figure&gt;The funnel plot is a graphical tool to diagnose the presence of missing studies, which plots effect size on the x axis and study size on the y axis. Large studies are shown at the top, smaller studies at the bottom. Studies should be organized in an orderly funnel – more consistency for larger studies, and less so for the smaller studies. But if smaller studies are missing because of the file drawer problem, the funnel will be &lt;em&gt;asymmetric; &lt;/em&gt;small studies with null results will be missing from the results.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;width: 524px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Figure 6: Simulated funnel plot analysis indicating publication bias&quot; class=&quot; aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/www.ijmm.org/articles/2014/32/3/images/IndianJMedMicrobiol_2014_32_3_229_136547_u7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;524&quot; /&gt;A funnel plot showing clear asymmetry, a potential sign of publication bias [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ijmm.org/article.asp?issn=0255-0857;year=2014;volume=32;issue=3;spage=229;epage=235;aulast=Pabalan&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/figure&gt;The authors a very nice, pragmatic method to estimate publication bias. The idea is to sort studies by descending size, and perform a cumulative meta-analysis; what happens if I analyze only the largest study? the two largest studies? the top 3? and so on. Mechanically, it’s the same analysis to the one that was applied to study when streptokinase could have been shown to be efficacious, but sorting by decreasing study size rather than date.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the analysis suffers from publication bias, the effect size estimate should drift as one adds smaller and smaller studies to the meta-analysis. Rather than try and correct for the bias, one can simply highlight the &lt;em&gt;sensitivity&lt;/em&gt; of the analysis to publication bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend picking up this book as a first-line reference. I just wish it had a better discussion of dealing with missing data. I’m running a meta-analysis on glaucoma treatments with Dr. Masis these days and it seems like every other cell in my worksheet is &lt;code&gt;NA&lt;/code&gt;. That’s unavoidable in a world where multiple researchers do independent studies without consulting each other; they’re going to measure slightly different things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with missing data in a principled way, we can use multiple imputation, or go full Bayesian. Each of these is its own large area of research, and I’ll follow up this post with my experiences with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like this blog? Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/patrickmineault&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/xcorr-computational-neuroscience-290007894348201/?ref=aymt_homepage_panel&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; to get notified of the next post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/xcorr.wordpress.com/6788/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/xcorr.wordpress.com/6788/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=xcorr.net&amp;amp;blog=3084329&amp;amp;post=6788&amp;amp;subd=xcorr&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://xcorr.net/feed/">xcorr: comp neuro</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Women engineers to receive awards for innovative research in developing countries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/women-engineers-to-receive-awards-for-innovative-research-in-developing-countries</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/women-engineers-to-receive-awards-for-innovative-research-in-developing-countries</link>
	<description>OWSD and Elsevier Foundation will recognize five early-career women scientists at AAAS Meeting</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 12:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: For Ebola patients, a few signs mean treatment’s needed — stat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ebola-patients-few-signs-mean-treatments-needed-stat</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ebola-patients-few-signs-mean-treatments-needed-stat</link>
	<description>A few criteria may help identify Ebola patients who need the most care.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021417_TI_ebola-triage_main.jpg?itok=gVkhVKLZ" length="32569" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Feature weighting as a tool for clustered based imputation model</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-02-16:/2017/02/16/feature-weighting-as-a-tool-for-clustered-based-imputation-model.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/02/16/feature-weighting-as-a-tool-for-clustered-based-imputation-model.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Imputation of missing attribute-values is an important data pre-processing
step. Missing of the attribute values are an inevitable problem in real-world
data collection. However, most of the data processing models don’t have any
mechanism to deal with missing values. One of the solutions to this problem is
to have an imputation step added in data pre-processing. Imputation model
relays on the initial prediction of the missing values and has no mechanism to
distinguish the observed and imputed values. But, the imputed values are only
as good as the assumption used to create them. In this research, we introduce
an unsupervised cluster-dependent feature weighing imputation model. This model
uses the feature weighing factor to rescaled the data to nullify the effect of
initial prediction of the missing attribute-values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/02/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 10:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Psychologists say the way we choose to share our good news is rather revealing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19218</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/16/psychologists-say-the-way-we-choose-to-share-our-good-news-is-rather-revealing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Young woman jumping in air, arms and legs outreached, portrait&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19243&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19243&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Low angle&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young woman jumping in air, arms and legs outreached, portrait&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young woman jumping in air, arms and legs outreached, portrait&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-200134879-002.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-200134879-002.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-200134879-002.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1997,1501&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/16/psychologists-say-the-way-we-choose-to-share-our-good-news-is-rather-revealing/young-woman-jumping-in-air-arms-and-legs-outreached-portrait/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-200134879-002.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get a great piece of news, who do you tell? Do you get on the phone to your best friend? Launch the news onto Facebook to sail the sea of Likes? Do you congratulate yourself in front of someone you know doesn’t enjoy the same fortune or ability? Or do you keep it to yourself? Let me share some good news with you: according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/jid/37/4/250/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; published recently in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;, your answers to these questions may say something about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19218&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cara Palmer and her colleagues had 251 US undergrads take a personality questionnaire, then asked them to imagine they’d experienced a number positive events like getting a good grade or hosting a great party, and to say how likely it is that they would share this news in one of three ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way was to tell a good friend or family member about the news, to &lt;em&gt;capitalise&lt;/em&gt; on the event, squeezing the juice out of the good experience by revisiting it with an encouraging audience. The women in the sample more often than the men said that they would probably do this. The personality trait Agreeableness, and having more empathy, were also associated with capitalising on good news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of sharing that the researchers asked the participants about was whether they would &lt;em&gt;brag &lt;/em&gt;about the event, enhancing their self-image by announcing their achievement to someone liable to be envious, like a classmate who struggled on the exam that they themselves had aced. Bragging is normally considered more prototypically masculine, but overall rates of hypothetical bragging were similar across genders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Palmer’s team drilled into the data to find different clusters of responses, and found that only men showed a propensity to fall into a distinct “bragger” group whose other forms of hypothetical news sharing were unremarkable – 30 per cent of men fitted this description versus just five per cent of women. The women braggers, by contrast, tended to be big sharers all round, being more likely than average to say they would share their news in other ways too. Regardless of gender, braggers tended to be less agreeable and conscientious: this is consistent with the idea that to brag you have to be insensitive to the reactions of others and not careful enough to restrict your decisions to avert conflicts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final type of sharing that the researchers asked about was mass-sharing of events on social media. Palmer’s team expected to find gender effects here, as women spend more time on social sites like Facebook than men, and they often cite a major reason for using such sites is to mass-share information, but in this dataset there were no gender differences. In terms of personality, the researchers found that those who said they would mass-share were more likely to score high on narcissism (conversely, those participants who said they were least likely to share in any way tended to be less narcissistic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraversion played a small role in these findings: it was correlated with capitalising but otherwise unrelated to the sharing types or clusters. This is consistent with the familiar experience of being on the receiving end of good news stories from an extravert friend –  studies show they tend to experience more positive events to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing is generally a good thing, especially one-to-one capitalising that allows you to reflect on and process experiences. The positive psychology movement also suggests that acknowledging and noting good experiences is, at least in moderation, beneficial for our psychological health and wellbeing. Bragging, in contrast, can generate resentment and ostracise acquaintances, and is a behaviour better discouraged. This research suggests that male braggers may stand out more obviously, whereas women may brag as part of their share-heavy style where it blends in more – but may be no less corrosive. Next time you want to share something great that’s happened to you, have a think about what you are trying to get out of this – and whether your audience really need to hear it. Don’t let your good news be another’s bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/jid/37/4/250/&quot;&gt;How do people share their positive events? Individual differences in capitalizing, bragging, and mass-sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19218/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19218/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19218&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 10:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ebola funding surge hides falling investment in other neglected diseases</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21505</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/wtBLDR81aKA/nature.2017.21505</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Global research funds for these illnesses are at their lowest levels for a decade, when cash for West Africa epidemic is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21505&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21505&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/wtBLDR81aKA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ocean meadows scrub seawater of harmful bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21504</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0EnjLZda444/nature.2017.21504</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Seagrasses keep waterborne pathogens in check, potentially benefiting people and coral reefs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21504&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0EnjLZda444&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Geologists spy an eighth continent: Zealandia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21503</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/2Kg86bImo84/nature.2017.21503</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This mostly submerged world should be recognized alongside Africa, Australia and others, argue some researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21503&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21503&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/2Kg86bImo84&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Collapse of Aztec society linked to catastrophic salmonella outbreak</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21485</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ULOvIHoHQZc/nature.2017.21485</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;DNA of 500-year-old bacteria is first direct evidence of an epidemic — one of humanity's deadliest — that occurred after Spanish conquest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 404 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21485&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21485&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ULOvIHoHQZc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Gastric bypass controls diabetes long term better than other methods</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gastric-bypass-controls-diabetes-long-term-better-other-methods</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gastric-bypass-controls-diabetes-long-term-better-other-methods</link>
	<description>Bariatric surgery outperforms other weight-loss measures in the longest-term study yet of diabetes outcomes.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 22:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021517_lb_gastric-bypass_free.png?itok=WRbwliFy" length="117134" type="image/png"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Birth may not be a major microbe delivery event for babies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/birth-may-not-be-major-microbe-delivery-event-babies</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/birth-may-not-be-major-microbe-delivery-event-babies</link>
	<description>A study of mother-baby duos suggests that birth itself may not be the main event for getting microbes in and on babies.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 17:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021417_LS_growthcurve-microbiomes_main_free.jpg?itok=NHfvG_YG" length="21649" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A “plethora of data errors” prompts authors to retract oncology paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48271</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/15/plethora-data-errors-prompts-authors-retract-oncology-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers in China have retracted a 2016 cancer imaging paper because they introduced “a plethora of data errors” while preparing the article for submission. Although the retraction notice provides no details on what these errors are or how exactly they occurred, it does point the finger at the researchers, explaining that the data errors happened as a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/15/plethora-data-errors-prompts-authors-retract-oncology-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A “plethora of data errors” prompts authors to retract oncology paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researcher issues massive changes to papers amidst plagiarism investigation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48121</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/15/plagiarism-investigation-underway-researcher-logged-two-mega-corrections/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher in Greece has issued extensive — what we sometimes call “mega” — corrections to two 2016 papers published in a medical journal in Romania. The first author — Alexandra Kalogeraki, a pathology researcher at the University of Crete in Greece — retracted two reviews from the same journal last year for plagiarism. The newest notices […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/15/plagiarism-investigation-underway-researcher-logged-two-mega-corrections/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher issues massive changes to papers amidst plagiarism investigation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sound waves could take a tsunami down a few notches</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sound-waves-could-take-tsunami-down-few-notches</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sound-waves-could-take-tsunami-down-few-notches</link>
	<description>A tsunami’s ferocious force could be taken down a few notches with a pair of counter waves.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/020717_EC_tsunami_main.jpg?itok=Fb5RPYwD" length="49261" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Healthy living: highlights of 2016</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8511</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/15/healthy-living/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Micolo J, Flickr CC&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/14690349697_126f0808ef_hdd-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcsportsscimedrehabil.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13102-016-0050-0&quot;&gt;Exergaming versus traditional gym-based exercise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8519&quot; style=&quot;width: 171px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;g&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8519 &quot; height=&quot;214&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/g-225x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;161&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The Conmunity – Pop Culture Geek, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Exercising with the use of an interactive environment might be an interesting alternative to traditional methods of training. In this study, Barry and colleagues examined exercise using an interactive computer-generated environment (exergaming) compared with traditional gym-based exercise for postural control, flow and technology acceptance in healthy adult participants. A total of 44 participants were allocated to either the exergaming group or a traditional gym-based exercise group. The results suggested that exergaming had a bigger potential to improve postural control compared with standard exercise. Therefore exergaming might be employed as a great way of achieving rehabilitation goals and improving postural control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcobes.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40608-016-0095-3&quot;&gt;The benefits of menu labeling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is menu labeling a potential solution to the obesity epidemic? To investigate this question, Reale and Flint determined the effect of menu labeling on food choice among obese adults. They examined a sample of 61 obese adults motivated to lose weight in order to find out which menu labeling format was the most effective method of promoting healthy eating choices. The first form of menu labeling provided calorie content, the second form supplied information in grams for all seven categories (fat, saturated-fat, protein, carbohydrate, of which sugars, salt and fiber), and the third provided the energy expenditure. Interestingly, participants underestimated calorie content by an average of 303 kcal per meal. The study demonstrates that menu labeling had a positive impact on healthy food choices, with calorie labeling having the strongest impact of the three tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcnutr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40795-015-0042-6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low carbohydrate diet in primary health care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8513&quot; style=&quot;width: 262px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;b1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8513 &quot; height=&quot;168&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/b1-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;252&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Phil Gradwell, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low carbohydrate diets (LCDs) are commonly recommended approaches for the treatment of obesity and diabetes. This study by Barabas et al. investigated the knowledge of healthcare professionals about LCDs in obesity treatment in a Swedish primary healthcare setting. Although an LCD is suggested to have a positive effect in both diabetes care and weight loss, surprisingly a low number of healthcare professionals recommended an LCD for weight loss. Physicians and diabetes nurses were more eager to recommend the diet, whereas trained lifestyle counselors were the least keen. The study showed that healthcare professionals had differing attitudes towards a diet low in carbohydrates with their main concerns being a lack of scientific knowledge of the side- and long-term effects of such a diet. The authors suggest that additional education and medical training might have a positive impact on the awareness of LCDs in obesity treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnutr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40795-016-0056-8&quot;&gt;Kids’ meals from Canadian chain restaurants &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8520&quot; style=&quot;width: 218px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;kids&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8520 &quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/kids-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;208&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;U.S. Department of Agriculture, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past three decades the prevalence of childhood obesity has increased significantly. The consumption of outside-the-home prepared meals is believed to be one of the obesity contributors. Using data from the University of Toronto Restaurant Database, this article reports the nutritional quality of kids’ meals from seven sit-down restaurants and ten fast food chains in Canada. The results indicated that kids’ meals from both types of restaurant contain high levels of sodium and saturated fat as well as being high in calories. Portions served in sit-down restaurants were bigger compared with fast-food places; however, when standardized per 100 g, sit-down restaurants served meals of a lower calorie and sodium content. These findings suggest that dealing with the poor nutritional quality of restaurant kids’ meals should be regarded as part of an obesity battle and a major public health goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcsportsscimedrehabil.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13102-016-0048-7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pedometer use in a cardiac telerehabilitation program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8521&quot; style=&quot;width: 188px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;w&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8521 &quot; height=&quot;266&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/w-1-201x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;178&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Goran Crnkovic, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People suffering from various cardiac diseases might employ pedometers to set activity goals, measure walking activity and improve their overall physiological and psychological health. In this study, Thorup and colleagues enrolled patients involved in a cardiac telerehabilitation program to investigate pedometer use and self-determined motivation for walking. A total of 11 patients, five nurses and six physiotherapists took part in the study and, thanks to the pedometer, the patients could tailor physical activity to their needs and lifestyle. Visible steps enhanced the awareness of walking activity and enabled them to set realistic goals and thus pedometers helped the patients to change their lifestyle into a healthier one, where walking activity became a daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcobes.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40608-016-0125-1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A crucial time in the life of students&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Freshman 15’ refers to the phenomenon that students gain on average 15lbs (6.8kg) over their first academic year. In this study, Vadeboncoeur and colleagues evaluated weight change among first year university students. They recruited 215 students from 23 universities in England asking them to report their weight at three time points: (i) at the beginning of academic year, (ii) before Christmas, and (iii) at the end of academic year. They observed an increase in weight by 0.98 kg over the period of an academic year and, interestingly, there was no significant difference in mean weight change rate between females and males (+1.04 kg and +0.85 kg respectively). These findings suggest that the first year at university appears to be a crucial time when people tend to gain weight; therefore universities must acknowledge their role in promoting healthy behaviors among students in order to prevent the obesity epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8517&quot; style=&quot;width: 231px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;u&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8517 &quot; height=&quot;147&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/u-1-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;221&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;University of the Fraser Valley, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/15/healthy-living/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Healthy living: highlights of 2016&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 11:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/14690349697_126f0808ef_hdd-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Feeling awe can sometimes be awful</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19164</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/15/feeling-awe-can-sometimes-be-awful/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tornadic supercell in the American plains&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19215&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19215&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A huge storm near Panhandle - Oklahoma&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1372214499&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Minerva Studio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;12&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tornadic supercell in the American plains&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tornadic supercell in the American plains&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-179247383.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-179247383.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-179247383.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/15/feeling-awe-can-sometimes-be-awful/tornadic-supercell-in-the-american-plains/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-179247383.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most research into the emotion of awe – a response to something vast or overwhelming – has focused on its positive upsides, classing it alongside delight or pleasure. But the University of California’s Greater Good research programme recently published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2016-59114-001/&quot;&gt;full investigation&lt;/a&gt; of what they call “threatening awe” defined as a strong feeling of wonder and fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amie Gordon and her team looked at times where people felt awe in response to overwhelming stimuli like huge storms or the vastness of the universe, or were exposed for the first time to accounts of historical horrors such as the Vietnam war. Skin conductance and heart rate measures showed that feeling the threatening version of awe activated the sympathetic autonomic nervous system, which is associated with negative emotional states. The data also suggested that feeling threatening awe rather than the positive kind may be influenced by thoughts which make us actively feel powerless – the prospect of being trapped on the pitiless ocean – rather than simply small, such as reflecting on the vastness of the cosmos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas previous work has shown awe to be associated with wellbeing and life satisfaction, one of the new experiments involving 603 participants found that an ominous video with swirling tornadoes, associated with threat-based awe, produced lower wellbeing compared to a positive awe-filled video and even a neutral one. Gordon’s team pointed out that the word awe produces two offspring with very different connotations: awesome and awful. Gazing into the face of God, or the vastness of the cosmos, isn’t a sunshine and kittens experience: awe exists in the “upper reaches of pleasure and on the boundary of fear”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2016-59114-001/&quot;&gt;The dark side of the sublime: Distinguishing a threat-based variant of awe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19164/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19164/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19164&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 09:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Revisionist history: rewriting the story of Indian birds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8569</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/15/revisionist-history-rewriting-story-indian-birds/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Montecincla fairbanki&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Montecincla-fairbanki-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;India is a biogeographic crossroads — a meeting place of different regions with distinct types of species. Although India is biodiverse, the high species richness of the subcontinent is often attributed to the fact that groups from the surrounding regions have been able to colonize and occupy various ecosystems. Furthermore, the conventional wisdom held that most animals in the Indian subcontinent were representatives of groups that were more diverse in other regions and that there were few, if any, distinctly Indian groups — ones that originated and speciated within the landmass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent studies are beginning to challenge these ideas, particularly in some groups of amphibians and reptiles. In our recent study, we now show that there are in fact two groups of birds, &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt;, that have also diversified within India. This is surprising because birds are thought to be really well-studied and these species have been know to science for a long time. Nevertheless, scientists had underestimated the true diversity of these groups and therefore the uniqueness of the avifauna of this region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;conventional wisdom held…there were few, if any, distinctly Indian groups&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the history of taxonomic confusion surrounding these birds, we devised a strategy to examine their evolutionary relationships. Using a combination of modern analyses and gathering a suite of data – genetic, morphometric, song, and plumage – we examined the distinct differences between populations across their range and determined their phylogenetic position to decipher their closest relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results conclusively showed that these two groups were older and more distinct than previously thought and had diversified into multiple species. These two groups of birds, now referred to as &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt;, represent the first known examples of birds that have speciated within the Indian subcontinent as endemic radiations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results have substantial implications for our knowledge of biodiversity and biogeography. First, it indicates that there is still much to be discovered about birds, even in well-inhabited regions. Second, the divergence patterns of these birds reveal the history of the Indian landscape and the role of climatic events in driving diversification. Finally, the dramatic increase in unique species with narrower ranges pushes the urgency of conservation in this vulnerable ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity hiding in plain sight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt; are endemic to the Western Ghats, a coastal mountainous region in southwestern India. Their specific habitat is restricted to the highest elevation zone in what is called Shola forest — a unique form of evergreen forest interspersed with natural grassland that is found only on this mountain range. Species like &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt;, which are restricted to these high montane areas, have patchy distributions within and across these ‘sky islands’ where montane habitat is similar to oceanic islands separated by deep valleys of unsuitable areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…there are still many mysteries to be uncovered in birds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted detailed field surveys across all the sky islands over a period of eight years and examined an unprecedented number (800) of individual birds for this project. Over this period, we measured body features, recorded song, noted plumage variation, and collected blood for genetic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas previously each group was thought to be one or two species (taxonomists disagreed), we show with ample evidence each group had diversified across the mountain range and had more species than currently recognized. This meant we had to revise and describe new species – an exciting yet daunting challenge given the debate amongst ornithologists on how to recognize distinct species (species concepts). There were multiple opinions, even amongst our co-authors, but we ultimately converged on an approach to delimit species that fulfilled the requirements of multiple species concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8572&quot; style=&quot;width: 1610px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sholicola ashambuensis&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8572&quot; height=&quot;1143&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Sholicola-ashambuensis.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sholicola ashambuensis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Shashank Dalvi.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complicate matters further, our phylogenetic analyses showed that neither of the two groups we studied belonged with the genera in which they were traditionally placed. Although they were originally thought to be shortwings and laughingthrushes respectively, &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt; do not belong with these groups. Their new positions in the bird tree of life, as distinct lineages and highly divergent from their closest relatives (and not near the genera they were previously classified in), make it imperative to place them into new genera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why so much excitement about new genera and species of birds? Some of this is due to expectation. For some other groups, like beetles, the rate of new species discovery is still steep and therefore adding new species to the list is fairly commonplace. For birds, on the other hand, many believe we have already discovered 99% of all the living species. New studies like this one highlight that there are still many mysteries to be uncovered in birds. This study also shows the value of phylogenetics and systematic analyses. We may have described the vast majority of species, but the taxonomy of birds is far from being clear, and this can mislead subsequent studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Past connections and current isolation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the big mysteries of Indian biogeography is how organisms got to the Western Ghats. The closest mountain range, the Himalayas, is several hundred miles to the north and intervening is a large expanse of dry, seasonal, lowland habitat. One theory, known as the Satpura Hypothesis, proposes that montane groups were able to migrate from the Himalayas using the hill ranges in central India as a corridor. Although wetter than other parts of peninsular India, the Satpura hills are much lower and many high elevation species do not currently occur on them. However, we know that suitable habitat for these species might have existed in the past when global temperatures were cooler and India was covered in moist forest. One way to test the Satpura Hypothesis was to examine the origin of the Western Ghats birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, our analyses showed that the pattern and timing of divergence in these two groups of birds were nearly identical and occurred at similar times. This lends support to the idea that landscape level changes, as implied by the Satpura Hypothesis, led to the isolation of these populations on their respective sky islands. Both &lt;em&gt;Sholicola&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Montecincla&lt;/em&gt; diverged from their closest relatives in the Himalayas and Southeast Asia around 11 million years ago. This coincides with a period of heightened tectonic activity in the Himalayas and Tibetan Plateau that led to the aridification of the Indian subcontinent, thereby shifting from moist to dry forest. We hypothesize that due to this drying, these cool-adapted birds were isolated in the Western Ghats, the only suitable habitat at the time. Subsequent climate shifts, which limited dispersal across the sky islands, lead to further isolation events across the deep valleys of this mountain range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8573&quot; style=&quot;width: 985px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Shola forest and grassland mosaic of the Western Ghats. Camel’s Hump Mountains, Kerala.&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8573&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Shola-forest.png&quot; width=&quot;975&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The Shola forest and grassland mosaic of the Western Ghats. Camel’s Hump Mountains, Kerala.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biodiversity hotspot becomes hotter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India, being a developing nation with over a billion people, has to reconcile tremendous pressures on natural ecosystems and its extraordinary biodiversity. Nowhere is this more apparent than in the Western Ghats where the interests of people, agriculture, and wildlife collide. This biodiversity hotspot is home not just to unique species but also a diversity of cultures, all of which are threatened by anthropogenic impacts such as economic development and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were the first research team in decades to obtain permissions to handle birds across this landscape&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crucial need for additional scientific studies to study this distinct region is becoming increasing apparent as modern studies like ours uncover dramatically more biodiversity. The type of study we conducted is rare in India and was only possible with persistence and some luck in acquiring the necessary permissions to handle birds, which is challenging in a country that is apprehensive about interference with wildlife. Nevertheless, the field crew, led by Robin and Vishnudas, were supported by a long-term research permit specifically from the Forest Department in the state of Kerala that was able to grasp the importance of this work. We were thus the first research team in decades to obtain permissions to handle birds across this landscape. We hope the results of our study makes the need to facilitate scientific studies an important and urgent venture across all states in the face of increasing threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we hope our study will help to highlight this exceptional and diverse region in terms of the need for more conservation efforts. In additional to their scientific value, birds can generate enormous interest in non-scientists from avid bird-watchers to casual nature observers. We gave our new taxa names inspired by local words for these birds and their habitat. This has already aroused national pride –our publication was released on Republic Day and enthusiastically picked up by supporters and newspapers with the hashtag #MadeInIndia! We hope these new discoveries will not only elevate the protective status of these birds and their shrinking habitat but also encourage interest in studying and preserving the long-term survival of other Western Ghats fauna and flora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/15/revisionist-history-rewriting-story-indian-birds/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Revisionist history: rewriting the story of Indian birds&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Montecincla-fairbanki-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Broad Institute wins bitter battle over CRISPR patents</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21502</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PEb-M5qmcBc/nature.2017.21502</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The US Patent and Trademark Office issues a verdict in legal tussle over rights to genome-editing technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 401 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21502&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PEb-M5qmcBc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Brain scans spot early signs of autism in high-risk babies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21484</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/XwltvyF3wzI/nature.2017.21484</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Experts say replication is needed and other hurdles must be surmounted to apply findings to the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21484&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/XwltvyF3wzI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Winston Churchill’s essay on alien life found</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542289a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BJ0Tb9AyU9A/542289a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A newly unearthed article by the great politician reveals that he reasoned like a scientist about the likelihood of extraterrestrials, writes Mario Livio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 289 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542289a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542289a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BJ0Tb9AyU9A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The Turkish paradox: Can scientists thrive in a state of emergency?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542286a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/z9P45NkOo_E/542286a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Political upheaval threatens Turkey’s ambitious plans for research and development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 286 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542286a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542286a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/z9P45NkOo_E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Human gene editing, a letter to President Trump and a no to homeopathy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542276a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/iOKDfSxuRdk/542276a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 10–16 February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 276 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542276a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542276a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/iOKDfSxuRdk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The dark side of social media</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542272a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ZYRZZum1OkM/542272a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Psychologists find that Internet trolls seem impervious to any efforts to change their behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 272 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542272a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542272a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ZYRZZum1OkM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Steps to help Turkey build a future on research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542271a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5m7gU_5zQ-c/542271a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Turkish government must stop university dismissals and commit itself to creating a welcoming research environment if its grand plans for science are to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 271 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542271a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542271a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5m7gU_5zQ-c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cancer: A targeted treatment with off-target risks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21504</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/t3kgNvnD1qo/nature21504</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It emerges that blood-cancer-targeting drugs that block a tumour-survival pathway also activate a mutation-causing enzyme in mice and in human cells. This might have implications for the clinical use of these drugs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21504&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/t3kgNvnD1qo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cell biology: Stretched divisions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21502</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/mhhhVO1ohrE/nature21502</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Many organ surfaces are covered by a protective epithelial-cell layer. It emerges that such layers are maintained by cell stretching that triggers cell division mediated by the force-sensitive ion-channel protein Piezo1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21502&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/mhhhVO1ohrE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: KICSTOR recruits GATOR1 to the lysosome and is necessary for nutrients to regulate mTORC1</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21423</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/f211tpbqAD4/nature21423</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) is a central regulator of cell growth that responds to diverse environmental signals and is deregulated in many human diseases, including cancer and epilepsy. Amino acids are a key input to this system, and act through the Rag GTPases to promote the translocation of mTORC1 to the lysosomal surface, its site of activation. Multiple protein complexes regulate the Rag GTPases in response to amino acids, including GATOR1, a GTPase activating protein for RAGA, and GATOR2, a positive regulator of unknown molecular function. Here we identify a protein complex (KICSTOR) that is composed of four proteins, KPTN, ITFG2, C12orf66 and SZT2, and that is required for amino acid or glucose deprivation to inhibit mTORC1 in cultured human cells. In mice that lack SZT2, mTORC1 signalling is increased in several tissues, including in neurons in the brain. KICSTOR localizes to lysosomes; binds and recruits GATOR1, but not GATOR2, to the lysosomal surface; and is necessary for the interaction of GATOR1 with its substrates, the Rag GTPases, and with GATOR2. Notably, several KICSTOR components are mutated in neurological diseases associated with mutations that lead to hyperactive mTORC1 signalling. Thus, KICSTOR is a lysosome-associated negative regulator of mTORC1 signalling, which, like GATOR1, is mutated in human disease. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21423&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21423&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/f211tpbqAD4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Mechanical stretch triggers rapid epithelial cell division through Piezo1</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21407</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jhEBnWDO8tw/nature21407</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Despite acting as a barrier for the organs they encase, epithelial cells turn over at some of the fastest rates in the body. However, epithelial cell division must be tightly linked to cell death to preserve barrier function and prevent tumour formation. How does the number of dying cells match those dividing to maintain constant numbers? When epithelial cells become too crowded, they activate the stretch-activated channel Piezo1 to trigger extrusion of cells that later die. However, it is unclear how epithelial cell division is controlled to balance cell death at the steady state. Here we show that mammalian epithelial cell division occurs in regions of low cell density where cells are stretched. By experimentally stretching epithelia, we find that mechanical stretch itself rapidly stimulates cell division through activation of the Piezo1 channel. To stimulate cell division, stretch triggers cells that are paused in early G2 phase to activate calcium-dependent phosphorylation of ERK1/2, thereby activating the cyclin B transcription that is necessary to drive cells into mitosis. Although both epithelial cell division and cell extrusion require Piezo1 at the steady state, the type of mechanical force controls the outcome: stretch induces cell division, whereas crowding induces extrusion. How Piezo1-dependent calcium transients activate two opposing processes may depend on where and how Piezo1 is activated, as it accumulates in different subcellular sites with increasing cell density. In sparse epithelial regions in which cells divide, Piezo1 localizes to the plasma membrane and cytoplasm, whereas in dense regions in which cells extrude, it forms large cytoplasmic aggregates. Because Piezo1 senses both mechanical crowding and stretch, it may act as a homeostatic sensor to control epithelial cell numbers, triggering extrusion and apoptosis in crowded regions and cell division in sparse regions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21407&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jhEBnWDO8tw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase δ blockade increases genomic instability in B cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21406</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/pHR6qUzRmlg/nature21406</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Activation-induced cytidine deaminase (AID) is a B-cell-specific enzyme that targets immunoglobulin genes to initiate class switch recombination and somatic hypermutation. In addition, through off-target activity, AID has a much broader effect on genomic instability by initiating oncogenic chromosomal translocations and mutations involved in the development and progression of lymphoma. AID expression is tightly regulated in B cells and its overexpression leads to enhanced genomic instability and lymphoma formation. The phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase δ (PI3Kδ) pathway regulates AID by suppressing its expression in B cells. Drugs for leukaemia or lymphoma therapy such as idelalisib, duvelisib and ibrutinib block PI3Kδ activity directly or indirectly, potentially affecting AID expression and, consequently, genomic stability in B cells. Here we show that treatment of primary mouse B cells with idelalisib or duvelisib, and to a lesser extent ibrutinib, enhanced the expression of AID and increased somatic hypermutation and chromosomal translocation frequency to the Igh locus and to several AID off-target sites. Both of these effects were completely abrogated in AID-deficient B cells. PI3Kδ inhibitors or ibrutinib increased the formation of AID-dependent tumours in pristane-treated mice. Consistently, PI3Kδ inhibitors enhanced AID expression and translocation frequency to IGH and AID off-target sites in human chronic lymphocytic leukaemia and mantle cell lymphoma cell lines, and patients treated with idelalisib, but not ibrutinib, showed increased somatic hypermutation in AID off-targets. In summary, we show that PI3Kδ or Bruton’s tyrosine kinase inhibitors increase genomic instability in normal and neoplastic B cells by an AID-dependent mechanism. This effect should be carefully considered, as such inhibitors can be administered to patients for years. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21406&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21406&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/pHR6qUzRmlg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: SZT2 dictates GATOR control of mTORC1 signalling</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21378</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/rayeaT1DL8k/nature21378</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (TORC1) integrates nutrient signals to control cell growth and organismal homeostasis across eukaryotes. The evolutionarily conserved GATOR complex regulates mTORC1 signalling through Rag GTPases, and GATOR1 displays GTPase activating protein (GAP) activity for RAGA and RAGB (RAGA/B) and GATOR2 has been proposed to be an inhibitor of GATOR1. Furthermore, the metazoan-specific SESN proteins function as guanine nucleotide dissociation inhibitors (GDIs) for RAGA/B, and interact with GATOR2 with unknown effects. Here we show that SZT2 (seizure threshold 2), a metazoan-specific protein mutated in epilepsy, recruits a fraction of mammalian GATOR1 and GATOR2 to form a SZT2-orchestrated GATOR (SOG) complex with an essential role in GATOR- and SESN-dependent nutrient sensing and mTORC1 regulation. The interaction of SZT2 with GATOR1 and GATOR2 was synergistic, and an intact SOG complex was required for its localization at the lysosome. SZT2 deficiency resulted in constitutive mTORC1 signalling in cells under nutrient-deprived conditions and neonatal lethality in mice, which was associated with failure to inactivate mTORC1 during fasting. Hyperactivation of mTORC1 in SZT2-deficient cells could be partially corrected by overexpression of the GATOR1 component DEPDC5, and by the lysosome-targeted GATOR2 component WDR59 or lysosome-targeted SESN2. These findings demonstrate that SZT2 has a central role in dictating GATOR-dependent nutrient sensing by promoting lysosomal localization of SOG, and reveal an unexpected function of lysosome-located GATOR2 in suppressing mTORC1 signalling through SESN recruitment. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21378&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21378&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/rayeaT1DL8k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Untimely expression of gametogenic genes in vegetative cells causes uniparental disomy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21372</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/GGKY-mCGCkg/nature21372</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Uniparental disomy (UPD), in which an individual contains a pair of homologous chromosomes originating from only one parent, is a frequent phenomenon that is linked to congenital disorders and various cancers. UPD is thought to result mostly from pre- or post-zygotic chromosome missegregation. However, the factors that drive UPD remain unknown. Here we use the fission yeast Schizosaccharomyces pombe as a model to investigate UPD, and show that defects in the RNA interference (RNAi) machinery or in the YTH domain-containing RNA elimination factor Mmi1 cause high levels of UPD in vegetative diploid cells. This phenomenon is not due to defects in heterochromatin assembly at centromeres. Notably, in cells lacking RNAi components or Mmi1, UPD is associated with the untimely expression of gametogenic genes. Deletion of the upregulated gene encoding the meiotic cohesin Rec8 or the cyclin Crs1 suppresses UPD in both RNAi and mmi1 mutants. Moreover, overexpression of Rec8 is sufficient to trigger UPD in wild-type cells. Rec8 expressed in vegetative cells localizes to chromosomal arms and to the centromere core, where it is required for localization of the cohesin subunit Psc3. The centromeric localization of Rec8 and Psc3 promotes UPD by uniquely affecting chromosome segregation, causing a reductional segregation of one homologue. Together, these findings establish the untimely vegetative expression of gametogenic genes as a causative factor of UPD, and provide a solid foundation for understanding this phenomenon, which is linked to diverse human diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21372&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21372&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/GGKY-mCGCkg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Adipose-derived circulating miRNAs regulate gene expression in other tissues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21365</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/HkwRY_S9o5s/nature21365</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Adipose tissue is a major site of energy storage and has a role in the regulation of metabolism through the release of adipokines. Here we show that mice with an adipose-tissue-specific knockout of the microRNA (miRNA)-processing enzyme Dicer (ADicerKO), as well as humans with lipodystrophy, exhibit a substantial decrease in levels of circulating exosomal miRNAs. Transplantation of both white and brown adipose tissue—brown especially—into ADicerKO mice restores the level of numerous circulating miRNAs that are associated with an improvement in glucose tolerance and a reduction in hepatic Fgf21 mRNA and circulating FGF21. This gene regulation can be mimicked by the administration of normal, but not ADicerKO, serum exosomes. Expression of a human-specific miRNA in the brown adipose tissue of one mouse in vivo can also regulate its 3′ UTR reporter in the liver of another mouse through serum exosomal transfer. Thus, adipose tissue constitutes an important source of circulating exosomal miRNAs, which can regulate gene expression in distant tissues and thereby serve as a previously undescribed form of adipokine. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21365&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21365&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/HkwRY_S9o5s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Whole-genome landscape of pancreatic neuroendocrine tumours</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21063</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/W05Yh9sx76A/nature21063</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The diagnosis of pancreatic neuroendocrine tumours (PanNETs) is increasing owing to more sensitive detection methods, and this increase is creating challenges for clinical management. We performed whole-genome sequencing of 102 primary PanNETs and defined the genomic events that characterize their pathogenesis. Here we describe the mutational signatures they harbour, including a deficiency in G:C &amp;gt; T:A base excision repair due to inactivation of MUTYH, which encodes a DNA glycosylase. Clinically sporadic PanNETs contain a larger-than-expected proportion of germline mutations, including previously unreported mutations in the DNA repair genes MUTYH, CHEK2 and BRCA2. Together with mutations in MEN1 and VHL, these mutations occur in 17% of patients. Somatic mutations, including point mutations and gene fusions, were commonly found in genes involved in four main pathways: chromatin remodelling, DNA damage repair, activation of mTOR signalling (including previously undescribed EWSR1 gene fusions), and telomere maintenance. In addition, our gene expression analyses identified a subgroup of tumours associated with hypoxia and HIF signalling. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21063&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21063&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/W05Yh9sx76A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Sterile protection against human malaria by chemoattenuated PfSPZ vaccine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21060</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/keU46FiwJm4/nature21060</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 A highly protective malaria vaccine would greatly facilitate the prevention and elimination of malaria and containment of drug-resistant parasites. A high level (more than 90%) of protection against malaria in humans has previously been achieved only by immunization with radiation-attenuated Plasmodium falciparum (Pf) sporozoites (PfSPZ) inoculated by mosquitoes; by intravenous injection of aseptic, purified, radiation-attenuated, cryopreserved PfSPZ (‘PfSPZ Vaccine’); or by infectious PfSPZ inoculated by mosquitoes to volunteers taking chloroquine or mefloquine (chemoprophylaxis with sporozoites). We assessed immunization by direct venous inoculation of aseptic, purified, cryopreserved, non-irradiated PfSPZ (‘PfSPZ Challenge’) to malaria-naive, healthy adult volunteers taking chloroquine for antimalarial chemoprophylaxis (vaccine approach denoted as PfSPZ-CVac). Three doses of 5.12 × 104 PfSPZ of PfSPZ Challenge at 28-day intervals were well tolerated and safe, and prevented infection in 9 out of 9 (100%) volunteers who underwent controlled human malaria infection ten weeks after the last dose (group III). Protective efficacy was dependent on dose and regimen. Immunization with 3.2 × 103 (group I) or 1.28 × 104 (group II) PfSPZ protected 3 out of 9 (33%) or 6 out of 9 (67%) volunteers, respectively. Three doses of 5.12 × 104 PfSPZ at five-day intervals protected 5 out of 8 (63%) volunteers. The frequency of Pf-specific polyfunctional CD4 memory T cells was associated with protection. On a 7,455 peptide Pf proteome array, immune sera from at least 5 out of 9 group III vaccinees recognized each of 22 proteins. PfSPZ-CVac is a highly efficacious vaccine candidate; when we are able to optimize the immunization regimen (dose, interval between doses, and drug partner), this vaccine could be used for combination mass drug administration and a mass vaccination program approach to eliminate malaria from geographically defined areas. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21060&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/keU46FiwJm4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: See how long Zika lasts in semen and other bodily fluids</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/see-how-long-zika-lasts-semen-and-other-bodily-fluids</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/see-how-long-zika-lasts-semen-and-other-bodily-fluids</link>
	<description>For most men infected with Zika, traces of the virus disappear from semen 81 days after symptoms begin. In other bodily fluids, Zika RNA is typically cleared even faster.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 22:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021417_MR_zika_main_free.jpg?itok=AnRbq17O" length="23072" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Human gene editing therapies are OK in certain cases, panel advises</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-gene-editing-therapies-are-ok-certain-cases-panel-advises</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-gene-editing-therapies-are-ok-certain-cases-panel-advises</link>
	<description>A panel of experts says clinical gene editing to correct and prevent human disease should move forward, but enhancements should not be allowed.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 21:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021417_ti_gene-editing_feat_free.jpg?itok=VC_OAYiy" length="29956" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researchers disagree over how to explain doubts over physics findings</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48247</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/14/researchers-disagree-explain-doubts-physics-findings/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;After an international group of physicists agreed that the findings of their 2015 paper were in doubt, they simply couldn’t agree on how to explain what went wrong. Apparently tired of waiting, the journal retracted the paper anyway. The resulting notice doesn’t say much, for obvious reasons. Apparently, some additional information came to light which […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/14/researchers-disagree-explain-doubts-physics-findings/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researchers disagree over how to explain doubts over physics findings&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 19:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fossil shows that ancient reptile gave live birth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-shows-ancient-reptile-gave-live-birth</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-shows-ancient-reptile-gave-live-birth</link>
	<description>A new fossil shows that a prehistoric reptile may have given birth to live young, unlike its egg-laying descendants, birds and crocodiles.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021417_ee_pregnant-reptile_main_free.jpg?itok=-GxeE5te" length="18804" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Mapping rainforest chemistry from the air reveals 36 types of forest</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mapping-rainforest-chemistry-air-reveals-36-types-forest</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mapping-rainforest-chemistry-air-reveals-36-types-forest</link>
	<description>Aircraft analysis of tree chemicals reveals new biodiversity in the Peruvian rainforest.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 16:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/020917_scivis_forests_feat_free.jpg?itok=jV7Yv3O2" length="32548" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: The look of love through a SciVal analytics lens</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-look-of-love-through-a-scival-lens</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-look-of-love-through-a-scival-lens</link>
	<description>For Valentine’s Day, we take a look at the research into ‘love hormones’</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 14:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researcher sued to stop retractions; he just earned two more and is now up to 11</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48226</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/14/researcher-sued-stop-retractions-just-earned-two-now-11/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The notices keep coming for diabetes researcher Mario Saad. Diabetes has just retracted two more of his papers, both of which had been flagged by expressions of concern, citing problems with duplications. What’s more, the journal added another expression of concern to a 2009 paper on which Saad — based at the University of Campinas […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/14/researcher-sued-stop-retractions-just-earned-two-now-11/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher sued to stop retractions; he just earned two more and is now up to 11&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Proceedings: New Editor, New Scope.  New Proceedings.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8557</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/14/bmc-proceedings-new-editor-new-scope-new-proceedings/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Coffee break, pixabay&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Coffee-break-pixabay-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greetings from &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about anything else, an introduction is probably in order. My name’s Tom Rowles and, as of October 2016, I’m the Editor of &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve spent the last few months getting to know the journal and coming up with plans for the future, and I’d like to use this post to update you on some exciting changes which are currently happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; is an academic journal whose sole purpose is to publish conference proceedings, including full-length articles, abstracts and meeting reports. Our aim is to widely disseminate the valuable material that is collected and presented at academic meetings, as well as to try and capture and distil the essence of the conference, and to provide exposure to the valuable meetings and conversations that take place during the conference, though meeting reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conferences are where research and medical communities come together, and we want to serve those communities by offering a service whereby conferences can extend their reach beyond the few days upon which the meeting takes place. Proceedings can do this, indefinitely extending the life of a conference, and providing a resource both for attendees, and those unable to make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also feel that, for all of their worth, conferences tend to operate as a closed system. All of the valuable information that is presented at a meeting, however useful and relevant to your own research, is for naught if you are unable to attend. We therefore see our role as making conferences open-access, in the same manner that BioMed Central has done for full research publications, and ensuring that cutting-edge scientific research and debate, as well as the guidelines and consensus reports that are often debated at international meetings, reach the researchers and practitioners that need it, wherever they might be in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New scope&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until this point, &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt; has, similarly to all other journals in the BMC series, published only articles and proceedings dealing with either the biological or medical sciences. However, from February 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; 2017, both&lt;em&gt; BMC Proceedings &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will be considering submissions from all scientific and clinical disciplines. You can find out more about the change of scope in &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;, as well as other exciting ongoing developments in that journal &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/14/bmc-research-notes-goes-back-roots/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will this mean in practice? Well, from now on &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings &lt;/em&gt;will consider publishing articles, abstracts and reports from meetings in the following fields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biology and life sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinical and medical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medical and scientific education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bioethics and international health &amp;amp; human rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research methodology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geo-sciences and environmental/earth sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marine biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemistry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paleontology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such an extensive list of subject areas now suitable for consideration, is there anything that we won’t be considering? Well yes; we will still be unable to consider meetings on law (except for when they are directly related to international health &amp;amp; human rights), humanities and arts. However, if you are unsure as to whether your conference would be suitable for consideration as a proceeding then I would encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:supplements@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;, and either myself or one of our supplements team will be able to advise you further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the coming months and years we hope that &lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings &lt;/em&gt;can become a hub for research communities to present and share their conferences. We therefore hope that you can join us and, if you are organising a conference and looking for a means to broaden its impact, then please do get in touch at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:supplements@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;supplements@biomedcentral.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/14/bmc-proceedings-new-editor-new-scope-new-proceedings/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Proceedings&lt;/em&gt;: New Editor, New Scope.  New Proceedings.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Coffee-break-pixabay-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Research Notes goes back to its roots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8565</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/14/bmc-research-notes-goes-back-roots/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Featured image&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Featured-image-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within scholarly publishing, the phrase dark data has been used to describe research outputs that are not usually considered in traditional research journals such as single observations. As a result, these research outputs often never see the light of day and remain hidden in researchers’ notebooks or buried as some extra data to be considered further one day in the future. However, there are many advantages in helping researchers to publish their dark data such as the reduction in duplicating research and the dissemination of fragmented findings or null results potentially useful to the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our vision for &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; is to build a unique, high profile journal focusing on short research notes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was launched in 2008 as part of the &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series with the aim to help free up dark data and provide a home for material that lacked a suitable publication outlet. In 2011, as the journal had begun to receive full-length research articles, both as direct submissions and transfers from other journals, we broadened its remit to include such articles. Whilst there has clearly been a need for &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; to consider full-length research articles, doing so has masked the original vision of the journal as something different; a place where short observations, which might otherwise be unknown, can be made available to the global research community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still committed to providing a home for all scientifically valid research outputs across the &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series. Full-length research articles which would previously have been considered by &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; can find a home in the relevant &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biomedcentral.com/p/the-bmc-series-journals/&quot;&gt;subject specific journals&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series as outlined in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2016/12/05/vital-importance-inclusive/&quot;&gt;recent blog&lt;/a&gt; discussing the editorial threshold for these journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “new” &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are bringing the journal back to its roots with a focus on shorter research notes that aim to bring dark data out of the shadows. The journal will once again focus on less conventional research outputs such as updates to previous work, additions to established methods, single observations and null results that are often overlooked. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; will publish articles without bias and will take the focus away from story-telling to making all valid research outputs freely and openly accessible.&lt;img alt=&quot;subjects&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8566 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/subjects.jpg&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase clarity and simplicity, we have reduced the number of article types and created &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/submission-guidelines/preparing-your-manuscript/research-note&quot;&gt;‘Research note’&lt;/a&gt;, the journals’ main article format. ‘Research note’ has a word limit making it a true note article, structured in introduction, main text and limitations. We believe our new article type will ensure research is easy to digest for readers while being of maximum benefit by clearly stating the objective of the work presented as well as its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; will publish articles without bias and will take the focus away from story-telling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark data is being generated by researchers of all disciplines across the world. &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; aspires to serve a broad and global research community. As a result, the journal will expand its scope to include all scientific and clinical disciplines, i.e. health sciences and medicine, life sciences, physical sciences including all engineering disciplines, computer science and mathematics as well as related disciplines such as science education, bioethics and research methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our vision for &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; is to build a unique, high profile journal focusing on short research notes that will serve as a dedicated open access forum for research outputs which would otherwise remain unknown. As part of the established &lt;em&gt;BMC&lt;/em&gt; series, the journal’s primary goal is to serve the global scientific and clinical research communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/14/bmc-research-notes-goes-back-roots/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; goes back to its roots&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Featured-image-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The animal guide to finding love</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/animal-guide-finding-love</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/animal-guide-finding-love</link>
	<description>Learn to dance, keep an eye on your competition, bring a gift: Animals have some practical advice for finding a mate.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021317_SZ_valentines_main.jpg?itok=cGDH2zHr" length="39783" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Where do women look when sizing each other up?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19105</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/14/where-do-women-look-when-weighing-each-other-up/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Friends enjoying a party in nightclub&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19204&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19204&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6.3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young couple laughing and whispering while Woman in the backround is looking at them jealously, in night club, focus on couple.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1351278071&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dangubic&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;73&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Friends enjoying a party in nightclub&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Friends enjoying a party in nightclub&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-177548929.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-177548929.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-177548929.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1857,1615&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/14/where-do-women-look-when-weighing-each-other-up/friends-enjoying-a-party-in-nightclub/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-177548929.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies show that when heterosexual women look at other women’s bodies, they, just like men, tend to spend a disproportionate amount of time looking at their waists, hips and breasts, as if estimating how much they will appeal to men. This is consistent with “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/11/03/david-buss-derogation-of-competitors/&quot;&gt;mate selection theory&lt;/a&gt;” which argues, among other things, that women have evolved strategies to monitor potential love rivals. However, psychologists are interested in this topic, not only from an evolutionary perspective, but also because women who feel dissatisfied with their bodies, and who are vulnerable to developing eating disorders, may be especially pre-occupied with comparing their body against others, potentially exacerbating their anxieties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past research is mixed: some studies suggest women with body dissatisfaction and/or eating disorders pay disproportionate attention to the bodies of thin women, other studies suggest the opposite. A new &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00426-015-0726-1?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;exploratory paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Research&lt;/em&gt; says hang on a minute, we don’t actually know much about how healthy, confident women behave when they look at other women, nor whether their attention is influenced by their feelings about their own bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19105&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amelia Cundall and Kun Guo at the University of Lincoln asked 33 female heterosexual psychology undergrads to don eye-tracking equipment while they looked at several realistic female computer avatars of different body shapes (from size 6 to size 18 based on UK high-street dress sizes), wearing either tight-fitting or loose clothing, and while they rated each one in terms of attractiveness and estimated dress size. The participants also rated their satisfaction with their own bodies (separately for face, breast, waist, hips, arms and legs); answered questions about how much they tend to compare their physical appearance to others; and the researchers also recorded their body-mass index (BMI), dress and cup size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat consistent with past research, overall the participants spent more time looking at the waist and hip region of the models’ bodies. After that, they spent an equal amount of time looking at their head, upper-body and legs, and the least amount of time looking at their arms. “As women tend to deposit a larger amount of fat onto the lower body parts … these regions may contain more diagnostic cures for body attractiveness and body size assessment than other body regions such as the arms,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of attractiveness ratings, the participants rated the slimmer models as more attractive and the size 18 women as least attractive. But “thinner is not necessarily more attractive”, the researchers pointed out, because size 6 was rated as less attractive than 8, 10, and 12, and seen on a par with size 14. The participants gave slimmer women the same attractiveness ratings regardless of whether they wore tight-fitting or loose clothing, but they rated women of size 12 and up as being more attractive, and estimated them as having a smaller dress size, when they wore loose clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to past findings, there was no link between participants’ own body satisfaction or their body size and the relative amounts of time they spent looking at the on-screen models that they considered more or less attractive, indicating a lack of either a harmful or self-protective bias, respectively. This may be because the participants were all generally confident in their own bodies and they had healthy below-average BMIs whereas past research that’s revealed these kind of viewing biases has studied women with body satisfaction concerns and eating disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the participants in the current research who reported lower overall satisfaction with their own bodies did tend to say that they were more inclined to compare themselves against others. And in terms of where they looked when looking at the women on-screen, the more satisfied the participants were with a particular body area of their own, the less they tended to look at that area on the models. “Self-satisfaction with a body region means the need for comparing that region is reduced and thus gaze is allocated at the neighbouring body areas that are also informative for body attractiveness and size assessment,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irrespective of their body satisfaction ratings, the researchers also found a general pattern for participants’ with smaller chests to spend less time looking at the chest area of the models. “It seems having a smaller chest size may result in an unconscious avoidance of viewing other women’s chest area, possibly to preserve self esteem,” the researchers said. Meanwhile, there was also a tendency for the participants with a higher BMI to spend more time looking at the legs of the slim on-screen models, the opposite of a protective habit. “BMI … is a more changeable construct [than chest size]” the researchers said, “and therefore [one explanation is that] upward comparisons occur in an attempt for healthy self-improvement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small, exploratory study with young students which obviously limits the broader conclusions that can be drawn. Some readers may also feel that research of this kind risks feeding the tendency for our culture to objectify women’s bodies. In its defence, the study has highlighted several interesting patterns in how women view and appraise other women’s bodies, each of which could be followed up by future research to potentially further our understanding of how and why, for some people, body dissatisfaction can develop into a more serious psychological problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00426-015-0726-1?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Women gaze behaviour in assessing female bodies: the effects of clothing, body size, own body composition and body satisfaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19105/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19105/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19105&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 10:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Long Live Hubble</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0317-80</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/hKCyTsPdr3E/scientificamerican0317-80</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 316, 80 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0317-80&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0317-80&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Katie Peek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from the space telescope will yield discoveries long after the instrument is kaput&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/hKCyTsPdr3E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
