<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: The TESS space telescope has spotted its first exoplanet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tess-space-telescope-has-spotted-its-first-exoplanet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tess-space-telescope-has-spotted-its-first-exoplanet</link>
	<description>TESS’s first exoplanet is twice Earth’s size and may have lots of water.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 21:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091818_LG_TESS-ticker_feat.jpg?itok=GKcUJrxw" length="62480" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange and Clora Announce Partnership to Enable Access to Life Science Expertise</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1757</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/09/science-exchange-and-clora-announce-partnership-to-enable-access-to-life-science-expertise/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Palo Alto, CA and Boston, MA, USA – September 18, 2018 — &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;, today announced a strategic partnership with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clora.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Clora&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a technology platform that precisely matches life science companies with flexible, uniquely-qualified expertise. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange customers will gain access to Clora’s extensive network of prequalified consultants selected through a technology-enabled process coupled with Clora’s significant understanding of R&amp;amp;D needs. Clora empowers companies to efficiently access a highly fragmented pool of expertise within days and at a significant cost reduction compared to industry standards.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Clora’s AI-powered access to highly specialized expertise has great potential to boost R&amp;amp;D productivity,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “We are continuously looking for ways to give our many pharmaceutical, medical device, and biotechnology clients a competitive edge, and being able to give them access to Clora’s network of experts will help fulfill that goal.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Science Exchange offers a unique and powerful platform for connecting with life science researchers globally,” said Rahul Chaturvedi, founder and CEO of Clora. “It is our hope that working with Science Exchange will accelerate the development of new therapies by enabling access to top-tier expertise.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Clora’s global network spans all areas of development, including discovery, translational, engineering, regulatory affairs, clinical trial design and management, CMC (chemistry, manufacturing, and controls), medical writing, bioinformatics, commercialization, and many more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Clora&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Clora’s mission is to accelerate and de-risk development in the pharmaceutical, biotechnology, and medical device industries by providing access to expertise in a hyperspecialized and fragmented industry. Clora’s intelligent platform is more precise, faster, and more cost-efficient compared to non-technology-enabled methods. Clora has access to millions of consultants globally that have worked at organizations like Merck &amp;amp; Co., Pfizer, Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, Novartis, Genentech, United States Food &amp;amp; Drug Administration (FDA),, and many others. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Clora is based in Boston, MA and was built by industry veterans who have experienced the pain and costs associated with delays in development due to long start-up times and poor access to the right expertise at the right time. Clora’s investors include Spark Capital, Felicis Ventures, iSeed Ventures, Ludlow Ventures, Notation Capital, and Social Capital among others. Learn more today at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clora.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.clora.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. Follow the company on Twitter @MeetClora, LinkedIn, and Facebook.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Early tests pave the way for a giant neutrino detector</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/early-tests-pave-way-giant-neutrino-detector</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/early-tests-pave-way-giant-neutrino-detector</link>
	<description>A prototype detector demonstrates the technology needed for the DUNE experiment.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 18:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/blogposts/091818_EC_dune-neutrion_feat.jpg?itok=KZeRcYM0" length="56779" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A sensor inspired by an African thumb piano could root out bogus medicines</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sensor-inspired-african-thumb-piano-could-root-out-bogus-medicines</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sensor-inspired-african-thumb-piano-could-root-out-bogus-medicines</link>
	<description>An inexpensive, user-friendly device that’s based on an mbira could help identify counterfeit and contaminated medications.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091718_MT_mbira_feat.jpg?itok=FUo4iVfX" length="20086" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Smart plants can teach us a thing or two</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/smart-plants-can-teach-us-thing-or-two</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/smart-plants-can-teach-us-thing-or-two</link>
	<description>‘The Revolutionary Genius of Plants’ challenges the brain-centered view of intelligence.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/092918_book_plants_feat_free.jpg?itok=tjpYLSVC" length="28997" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: UK study finds children with maths difficulties (SLDM/dyscalculia) far less likely to receive an official diagnosis than their peers with dyslexia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34762</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/18/uk-study-finds-children-with-maths-difficulties-sldm-dyscalculia-are-100-times-less-likely-to-receive-an-official-diagnosis-than-peers-with-dyslexia/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-637223078.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34770&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34770&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D810&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Schoolgirl trying to understand formula&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1483533755&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;gpointstudio&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;320&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Schoolgirl trying to understand formula&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Schoolgirl trying to understand formula&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-637223078.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-637223078.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-637223078.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/18/uk-study-finds-children-with-maths-difficulties-sldm-dyscalculia-are-100-times-less-likely-to-receive-an-official-diagnosis-than-peers-with-dyslexia/schoolgirl-trying-to-understand-formula/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-637223078.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how important maths skills are in everyday life, it is vital that we develop ways to reliably identify those children with particular learning difficulties related to maths (known as “specific learning disorder in mathematics”/SLDM or dyscalculia) so that they can be provided with appropriate support. Unfortunately, maths-related learning problems are far less understood and recognised compared with similar problems related to reading and language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/bjop.12322&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Psychology&lt;/em&gt; highlights this issue, being the first to estimate the prevalence of SLDM/dyscalculia in primary school age children using contemporary criteria (as outlined by the American Psychiatric Association in the latest version of its diagnostic manual). The results provide much needed data on this topic, reveal some worrying facts and also useful insights for policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34762&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research is based on nearly 2,500 children, aged 7 to 13, from 19 rural and urban schools in Northern Ireland. The data are averages of several years’ standardised test results of the children’s maths, reading and IQ, together with background demographic information and notes on any diagnoses of other developmental problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, diagnosis of SLDM/dyscalculia took a child’s IQ into account a child, such that a specific problem with maths was only diagnosed if their maths ability was low relative to their IQ – the so-called “discrepancy criterion”. The newer diagnostic criteria (in DSM 5) abandon this principle. Now a persistent, significant problem with maths counts as SLDM/dyscalculia even if it occurs alongside comparably low IQ or other learning problems (however SLDM is still discounted in the context of extremely low IQ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the new criteria, Kinga Morsanyi and her colleagues at Queen’s University Belfast, estimated the relevance of SLDM/dyscalculia in primary school children at around 6 per cent. This is substantially higher than previous estimates of 1.1 per cent prevalence based on the earlier diagnostic criteria. Morsanyi’s team said this could have “huge consequences for children’s outcomes” because it means more children ought to be able to access maths-based educational support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat worryingly, however, the data showed that only one child in the sample had actually received a formal diagnosis of SLDM/dyscalculia, in contrast with 108 children who had received a diagnosis of dyslexia. Given that prevalence rates of SLDM/dyscalculia and dyslexia are usually similar, the researchers explained that this means “we can say that a child with dyslexia was more than a hundred times more likely to receive an official diagnosis of that disorder (which is necessary to obtain specialist educational support) than a child with dyscalculia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, the revamped diagnostic criteria ought to lead to the identification of more children with SLDM/dyscalculia, thus opening up the chance for them to receive specialist support, but in practice this does not seem to be happening. At least, not yet. Moreover, from speaking to educational psychologists, Morsanyi and her team said the situation is compounded by the fact the educational psychologists said there are “no generally accepted intervention methods that could be recommended” for SLDM (a further complication is that the new diagnostic criteria state that maths problems should be persistent in spite of interventions, which promotes the unhelpful idea that extra support for children with SLDM/dyscalculia is futile – the researchers challenge this view and point to their finding of reduced prevalence of SLDM/dyscalculia with age as evidence that persistent maths problems can be addressed effectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“An important first step,” to addressing these issues, they said, “would be to raise awareness of SLDM/dyscalculia among both teachers and educational psychologists as part of their work training.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of demographic background and other concurrent diagnoses, the new data suggest that children with persistent maths problems also often have problems with English and low IQ; tend to come from relatively deprived backgrounds; usually have other special educational needs; and are more likely to have “newcomer status” (meaning that English wasn’t their first language). The researchers said that additional support for maths should be given to children with SLDM/dyscalculia regardless of the source of their maths problems (be they environmental or cognitive or a mix of the two). They also noted that there were some children with SLDM/dyscalculia who also had a diagnosis of autism, but none with a concurrent diagnosis of ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final finding to note concerns gender differences – overall, there was no evidence that girls or boys were more likely to have dyscalculia/SLDM (or be exceptional in maths), which contrasts with the situation for dyslexia, which is about twice as common among boys. However, when the researchers matched girls and boys for IQ and English scores (which were generally higher in girls overall) and special educational needs status, there was evidence of more maths problems among girls than similar status boys – what the researchers described as “… a hidden gender difference in maths performance even among primary school children. That is, although girls do not underperform in terms of their actual scores, they underperform relative to their cognitive/learning potential”. Considering reports that many girls lose interest in maths and science at around age 11, the researchers said another policy implication of their results was that intervention programmes aimed at encouraging girls into science and maths subjects should start even earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a prepared media statement, Morsanyi wrote that “From these figures, we can estimate that about 10,000 children in Northern Ireland have sustained, serious difficulties with mathematics. Given that virtually no children in our sample received an official diagnosis of mathematics disorder, we can expect that most of these children do not receive educational support with mathematics. This can have very important adverse consequences.” She added that “…these figures in the UK in general would be much higher.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/bjop.12322&quot;&gt;The prevalence of specific learning disorder in mathematics and comorbidity with other developmental disorders in primary school-age children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 08:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: What really happened when two mathematicians tried to publish a paper on gender differences? The tale of the emails</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71498</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/17/what-really-happened-when-two-mathematicians-tried-to-publish-a-paper-on-gender-differences-the-tale-of-the-emails/</link>
	<description>Retraction Watch readers may be familiar with the story of a paper about gender differences by two mathematicians. Last month, in Weekend Reads, we highlighted an account of that story, which appeared in Quillette. The piece, by one of the paper’s authors — titled “Academic Activists Send a Published Paper Down the Memory Hole” — … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/17/what-really-happened-when-two-mathematicians-tried-to-publish-a-paper-on-gender-differences-the-tale-of-the-emails/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;What really happened when two mathematicians tried to publish a paper on gender differences? The tale of the emails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 01:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: A Chink in the Brain Armor: the NFL, Concussion and Omega-3s</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9703</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9703</link>
	<description>On Twitter, I was pointed to the strange story of Brain Armor®, a nutritional supplement which is supposed to promote brain health.

While there are many supplements that are sold for the same purpose, Brain Armor has a unique claim to fame: it is the official brain health supplement of Pro Football Legends (PFL), the &quot;commercial marketing arm of the NFL Alumni.&quot;





Brain Armor's links to the NFL Alumni raised eyebrows on Twitter because the NFL has famously been the target of legal ac</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s how many U.S. kids are vaping marijuana</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-many-us-kids-are-vaping-marijuana</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-many-us-kids-are-vaping-marijuana</link>
	<description>A new study suggests that nearly 1 in 11 middle and high school students in the United States has vaped marijuana, raising concerns about addiction.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/08/main/articles/081718_AC_vaping-pot_feat.jpg?itok=KLGo2MCD" length="27991" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s how clumps of honeybees may survive blowing in the wind</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-how-clumps-honeybees-may-survive-blowing-wind</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heres-how-clumps-honeybees-may-survive-blowing-wind</link>
	<description>Honeybees clumped on trees may adjust their positions to keep the cluster together when it’s jostled by wind, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091418_ec_bee-clump_feat_free.jpg?itok=7qfI2czK" length="44035" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The ghosts of nearly two dozen icy volcanoes haunt dwarf planet Ceres</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ghosts-nearly-two-dozen-icy-volcanoes-haunt-dwarf-planet-ceres</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ghosts-nearly-two-dozen-icy-volcanoes-haunt-dwarf-planet-ceres</link>
	<description>The slumped remains of 21 ice volcanoes suggest that the dwarf planet Ceres has been volcanically active for billions of years.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091418_ec_ceres_feat_free.jpg?itok=2ZL-MAsX" length="34052" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researcher who once tried to sue critics has another dozen papers retracted</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71450</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/17/researcher-who-once-tried-to-sue-critics-has-another-dozen-papers-retracted/</link>
	<description>A cancer researcher who went to court — unsuccessfully — claiming that commenters on PubPeer had cost him a new job has just lost another 12 papers. The twelve now-retracted papers by Fazlul Sarkar and colleagues — as well as another by Sarkar that is now subject to an editor’s note — all appeared in … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/17/researcher-who-once-tried-to-sue-critics-has-another-dozen-papers-retracted/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Researcher who once tried to sue critics has another dozen papers retracted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 11:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A recount of human genes ups the number to at least 46,831</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/recount-human-genes-ups-number-least-46831</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/recount-human-genes-ups-number-least-46831</link>
	<description>A new estimate of the number of human genes adds in some RNA-producing genes.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/0914_ti_gene-count_feat_free.jpg?itok=-oOeIhsL" length="44130" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Who likes to be alone? Not introverts, according to a new paper on personality and the experience of solitude</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34734</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/17/who-likes-to-be-alone-not-introverts-according-to-a-new-paper-on-personality-and-the-experience-of-solitude/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-910786956.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34756&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34756&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PENTAX 645Z&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A young man is standing on the beach&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1504621705&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;55&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young man standing on the beach&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young man standing on the beach&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-910786956.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-910786956.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-910786956.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1999,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/17/who-likes-to-be-alone-not-introverts-according-to-a-new-paper-on-personality-and-the-experience-of-solitude/young-man-standing-on-the-beach/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-910786956.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do some people go to great lengths to have the chance to spend time by themselves, while others find solitude painful and forever crave company? The most obvious answer would seem to be that it relates to differences in social aspects of personality, and specifically that extraverts will find solitude painful while introverts will enjoy their own company more than anyone else’s. However, a new paper, published as &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/sjcwg&quot;&gt;a pre-print&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;PsyArXiv&lt;/em&gt; (not yet peer-reviewed), and involving three diary studies with hundreds of undergrad volunteers, suggests the truth is more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, there was no evidence that introverts enjoyed solitude more than extraverts. Rather, the most important trait related to liking one’s own company was having strong “dispositional autonomy”. This is a concept from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-determination_theory&quot;&gt;self-determination theory&lt;/a&gt; and the researchers, led by Thuy-vy T. Nguyen at the University of Rochester, said that people strong in this trait have alignment between their behaviour, values and interests, are “resistant to pressure from others”, and “are interested in learning more about their personal experiences and emotions”. High scorers in autonomy enjoyed solitude more than others and sought it out for its own sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34734&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the studies involved asking the participants to spend 15 minutes a day in solitude (on seven different days) and then to complete detailed questionnaires afterwards about how they’d found the experience. Introverts enjoyed solitude no more than extraverts (although there was a slight tendency for them to experience fewer negative thoughts), and it didn’t satisfy their basic psychological needs either, such as their feelings of autonomy and competence. In contrast, higher scorers in dispositional autonomy (as measured by agreement with statements like “My decisions represent my most important values and feelings” and “I am deeply curious when I react with fear and anxiety”) enjoyed solitude more than others, experienced fewer negative thoughts and it fulfilled more of their basic psychological needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings for enjoyment of solitude chime with two of the other diary studies that looked into people’s motivations for finding time alone. This showed mixed findings for introverts: one study, but not the other, found that introverts were more likely to engage in “reactive solitude” (that is, being by themselves as a way of escaping being with others). Meanwhile, higher dispositional autonomy was correlated with more “constructive solitude”, which is seeking out solitude for its own sake. Introversion was not correlated with seeking constructive solitude in either study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While taking caution, given that this research has not yet been peer-reviewed, and remembering that further investigations could offer a different perspective, the current results suggest we need to rethink our assumptions about introverts and extraverts and how they experience being alone. If an introverted person doesn’t feel they have chosen to be alone, and they have sought out solitude for relatively negative reasons (as a form of escape), then it would be wrong to assume that just because they are introverted that they will enjoy their situation. Savouring solitude seems to be more associated with being the kind of person who feels free and in control of their life and who finds pleasure in reflecting on their inner experiences – and among both introverts and extraverts there will be those who do and do not fit this description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also looked at the relevance of their participants’ “attachment styles” –  ways of relating to others that are thought to be shaped by the treatment received from caregivers early in life. Among the findings here was that people with an avoidant attachment style (who tend to see others as untrustworthy) sought out more constructive solitude – that is, they wanted to be alone and valued that time more than with others  – but when they actually experienced solitude, they didn’t necessarily enjoy it and had more negative thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Thuy-vy Nguyen and her colleagues said they had shed new light on how people experience solitude, and especially that how it feels to be alone “might be a function of how individuals self-regulate experiences and behaviours, more generally, rather than merely based on introversion or avoidance of others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoting Jean-Paul Sartre (“&lt;em&gt;If you’re lonely when you’re alone, you’re in bad company&lt;/em&gt;“), the researchers added that “… to the extent that individuals are compelled by guilt, anxiety, or avoidance rather than approaching experiences with self-reflection and interest, they will find solitude an unpleasant experience, and derive little enjoyment from time spent alone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/sjcwg&quot;&gt;Identifying Personality Characteristics associated with the Capacity to be Alone using Big-Five Theory, Attachment Theory, and Self-Determination Theory&lt;/a&gt; [This paper is a pre-print and the final peer-reviewed version may differ from the version that this report was based on]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 09:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 3 ways to achieve patient-centered care with interdisciplinary collaboration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-to-achieve-patient-centered-care-with-interdisciplinary-collaboration</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-to-achieve-patient-centered-care-with-interdisciplinary-collaboration</link>
	<description>With the right processes and technology, healthcare teams can work more efficiently and improve outcomes</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Abder Kaidi fraud and bullying scandal unravels</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=28450</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/17/abder-kaidi-fraud-and-bullying-scandal-unravelling/</link>
	<description>The fraud case of Bristol cell biologist Abderrahmane Kaidi looked rather straightforward: Bristol University caught a group leader on data faking and bullying, and immediately had him removed. Turns out, it was not really like that. 
Now I publish some very revealing leaked material, spiced with stories of a guerrilla Twitter account and a deleted student newspaper article.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 05:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Confused mayflies wreak havoc on a Pennsylvania bridge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/confused-mayflies-wreak-havoc-pennsylvania-bridge</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/confused-mayflies-wreak-havoc-pennsylvania-bridge</link>
	<description>Cleaning a river in central Pennsylvania brought back mayflies, which now pose a threat to motorists crossing a bridge.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091218_CP_mayfly_feat.jpg?itok=6ae_E_-n" length="41400" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Top researchers resign over publishing issues; organized crime meets publishing; infamous fraudster rides in on a horse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71402</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/15/weekend-reads-top-researchers-resign-over-publishing-issues-organized-crime-meets-publishing-infamous-fraudster-rides-in-on-a-horse/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a look at authors who publish once every five days, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/15/weekend-reads-top-researchers-resign-over-publishing-issues-organized-crime-meets-publishing-infamous-fraudster-rides-in-on-a-horse/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Top researchers resign over publishing issues; organized crime meets publishing; infamous fraudster rides in on a horse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 13:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Evolution of Neuroimaging</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9696</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9696</link>
	<description>A fun new paper looks at the changing landscape of neuroimaging research through an analysis of the journals Neuroimage and PNAS. The article comes from UPenn researchers Jordan D. Dworkin, Russell T. Shinohara and Danielle S. Bassett.



Dworkin et al. created a network analysis of keywords from the 8,547 Neuroimage papers that were published between 2008 and 2017. This analysis produces a graph in which the nodes are keywords (topics) and the edges (connections) reflect the tendency for th</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 13:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: One Nucleus Strikes Collaboration Deal with Science Exchange To Support Members’ Outsourced R&amp;D Strategies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1756</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/09/one-nucleus-chooses-science-exchange-as-their-platform-of-choice-for-outsourced-rd/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Science Exchange, the &lt;i&gt;leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, announced today that it has become a Corporate Partner of One Nucleus, the membership organization for life science and healthcare companies. This exclusive partnership will give One Nucleus members immediate access to thousands of CROs, CMOs, academic institutes, core labs and a global community of scientists from the world’s top R&amp;amp;D organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based in Cambridge, England, One Nucleus supports institutions, companies, and individuals in its region by connecting them to a vast network of UK-wide and global resources. By providing this connectivity, One Nucleus seeks to maximize the productivity of its members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One Nucleus shares our mission of enabling scientific breakthroughs through human connections,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “We look forward to working together with One Nucleus to help its members gain access to external innovations and take their science on the fastest path to breakthroughs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Science Exchange is the primary outsourcing channel for most of the top R&amp;amp;D organizations,” stated Tony Jones, CEO of One Nucleus. “We’re excited about this partnership and how it will enable our members to evaluate their outsourcing and procurement strategies whilst connecting with Science Exchange’s partners and providers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About One Nucleus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established in 1997, One Nucleus is an award-winning, not-for-profit Life Sciences &amp;amp; Healthcare membership organization centered on the Greater London-Cambridge-East of England corridor. Headquartered in Cambridge, at the heart of Europe’s largest Life Sciences &amp;amp; Healthcare cluster, we support those institutions, companies, and individuals undertaking activity in or with the above region.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 17:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Nuclear pasta in neutron stars may be the strongest material in the universe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nuclear-pasta-neutron-stars-may-be-strongest-material-universe</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nuclear-pasta-neutron-stars-may-be-strongest-material-universe</link>
	<description>Simulations suggest that the theoretical substance known as nuclear pasta is 10 billion times as strong as steel.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 14:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091318_EC_nuclear-pasta_feat.jpg?itok=HHPYRGsV" length="42759" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Irony? The Journal of Failure Analysis and Prevention retracts a paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71369</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/14/irony-the-journal-of-failure-analysis-and-prevention-retracts-a-paper/</link>
	<description>Irony machine, start your engine: A pair of engineers have lost a 2017 paper in the Journal of Failure Analysis and Prevention over a failure to determine who owned the data. The article, “Solder selection for reflowing large ceramic substrates during PCB assembly,” was written by Prashant Reddy Gangidi and Noy Souriyasak, both listed as … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/14/irony-the-journal-of-failure-analysis-and-prevention-retracts-a-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Irony? The Journal of Failure Analysis and Prevention retracts a paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 12:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘Poached’ offers a deep, disturbing look into the illegal wildlife trade</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/poached-offers-deep-disturbing-look-illegal-wildlife-trade</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/poached-offers-deep-disturbing-look-illegal-wildlife-trade</link>
	<description>In ‘Poached,’ a journalist reports from the front lines of the illegal wildlife trade and shows how conservationists are fighting back.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/092918_book_poached_feat_free.jpg?itok=ZIh0OEsw" length="26851" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: New study of trash talking in sport highlights that it is more than a physical contest</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34730</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/14/new-study-of-trash-talking-in-sport-highlights-that-it-is-more-than-a-physical-contest/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34739&quot; style=&quot;width: 2314px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-71403413-2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34739&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34739&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;BERLIN - JULY 09:  Zinedine Zidane (L) of France exchanges words with Andrea Pirlo of Italy, after headbutting Marco Materazzi of Italy in the chest  during the FIFA World Cup Germany 2006 Final match between Italy and France at the Olympic Stadium on July 9, 2006 in Berlin, Germany.\r\n  (Photo by Michael Steele\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2006 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Final Italy v France - World Cup 2006&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Final Italy v France – World Cup 2006&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-71403413-2.jpg?w=845?w=790&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-71403413-2.jpg?w=845?w=231&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-71403413-2.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2314,3000&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/14/new-study-of-trash-talking-in-sport-highlights-that-it-is-more-than-a-physical-contest/final-italy-v-france-world-cup-2006/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-71403413-2.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;BERLIN – JULY 06: Zinedine Zidane (L) of France exchanges words with Andrea Pirlo of Italy, after headbutting Marco Materazzi of Italy in the chest during the FIFA World Cup Final in Germany. (Photo by Michael Steele/Getty Images)&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside the physical jostle, thrust and tug of sport there is a parallel contest involving words. Although this trash talking between players before, during and after games is well known, it is surprisingly unstudied by psychologists. Yet these exchanges play a major role, arguably swinging the outcome of games. Consider an infamous example: the 2006 football world cup final in which Italy’s Marco Materazzi insulted the sister or mother (depending on whose account you believe) of France’s star player Zinadine Zidane, who in turn responded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_uk/article/7xmj4y/zinedine-zidane-and-the-most-important-headbutt-in-the-world&quot;&gt;head butting&lt;/a&gt; Materazzi. Zidane was then sent off, with Italy going on to win the game on penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is trash talking more prevalent in some sports than others? What does trash talk tend to be about? A new &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12110-018-9317-3&quot;&gt;exploratory paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Human Nature&lt;/em&gt; is among the first systematic investigations of trash talking in sport, and certainly the first to examine the phenomenon through an evolutionary lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34730&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Kniffin and Dylan Palacio at Cornell University surveyed 291 undergrad student athletes (including 141 men) who represented their university at the top level in various sports including gymnastics, ice hockey, lacrosse, rowing, soccer, squash, swimming, diving, track and field, volleyball, and wrestling, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students’ task was to indicate how frequently they had ever trash talked against opponents on a number of topics, including those directly relevant to the sport, such as  playing ability, and those less directly relevant to the game, but arguably having evolutionary significance around competing for mates, such as physical appearance, sexual behaviour and slighting opponents’ partners. The students also made the same judgments about how much trash talking they had witnessed by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the students’ reports, trash talking was relatively frequent, and mostly focused on sporting issues, such as physical ability and athleticism. However, they said there was also significant trash talking off-topic, especially about opponents’ physical appearance, relationships and sexual behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together with the fact that trash talking was reported to be notably more common among male players than female players, and also among competitors in contact sports, the researchers said their findings are consistent with the idea that trash talking is a form of verbal aggression – perhaps originating as a form of intra-sexual competition between males – that has survived as a competitive convention because it brings advantages to the trash talker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extra detail is that there was no evidence that trash talking was more frequent among combat sport competitors who wear masks, suggesting anonymity makes no difference in this context (unlike, say, online).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kniffin and Palacio stressed that this was an exploratory study on a little studied topic, and they also caveated their main finding of a gender difference, noting that trash talking may vary with masculinity as a trait, or even with physical size or formidability, rather than maleness per se.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pair hope their study will provide a foundation for future research, which could address this question of masculinity, as well as others, such as whether trash talking varies with age and superstar status; how it affects the recipient; and whether some people are more resilient to trash talking than others. On this last point, the researchers speculated that “in light of research suggesting that sports participation, by men at least, is a form of courtship display, it might be that the same people who are most likely to trash talk are also most likely to be responsive to it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12110-018-9317-3&quot;&gt;Trash-Talking and Trolling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 08:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Interview with Human Brain Project director Katrin Amunts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=27450</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/14/interview-with-human-brain-project-director-katrin-amunts/</link>
	<description>I finally succeeded to interview the only woman among Human Brain Project leaders, the scientific director Katrin Amunts. In my previous article, I published a non-interview, using bits from HBP website as stand-in for her answers. Now, in this long read, Professor Amunts provided me with her replies.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s how climate change is fueling Hurricane Florence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-climate-change-fueling-hurricane-florence</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-climate-change-fueling-hurricane-florence</link>
	<description>Scientists take a stab at predicting climate change’s influence on Hurricane Florence.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091318_CG_hurricane_feat.jpg?itok=sn5sMDZN" length="39744" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: High-profile health policy researcher Gilbert Welch out at Dartmouth after plagiarism charge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71345</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/13/high-profile-health-policy-researcher-gilbert-welch-out-at-dartmouth-after-plagiarism-charge/</link>
	<description>H. Gilbert Welch, a leading researcher in the field of health policy, has resigned from his faculty post at Dartmouth College after the institution concluded that he had plagiarized from a colleague in a 2016 paper. As we reported in STAT earlier this summer, a Dartmouth committee found that Welch had misused a figure from … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/13/high-profile-health-policy-researcher-gilbert-welch-out-at-dartmouth-after-plagiarism-charge/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;High-profile health policy researcher Gilbert Welch out at Dartmouth after plagiarism charge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new map reveals the causes of forest loss worldwide</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-map-reveals-causes-forest-loss-worldwide</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-map-reveals-causes-forest-loss-worldwide</link>
	<description>A new study shows where global forest loss is due to permanent deforestation versus short-term shifts in land use.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 20:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091318_LH_forest-loss_main_FREE.jpg?itok=2iRMjWXL" length="64817" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This flying robot could reveal secrets of the aerial world of insects</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flying-robot-could-reveal-secrets-aerial-world-insects</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/flying-robot-could-reveal-secrets-aerial-world-insects</link>
	<description>A new winged robot with the exceptional agility of a fruit fly could lend insight into animal flight.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 18:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091218_MT_fruit-fly-bot_feat.jpg?itok=YwztAefo" length="12726" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Brain features may reveal if placebo pills could treat chronic pain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-features-may-reveal-if-placebo-pills-could-treat-chronic-pain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-features-may-reveal-if-placebo-pills-could-treat-chronic-pain</link>
	<description>Researchers narrow in on how to identify people who find placebos effective for treating persistent pain.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091118_AC_placebo_feat.jpg?itok=fkfgTkdg" length="22788" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: Opening up to new perspectives: an interview with Aileen Fyfe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8307</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/XjD-U4colzY/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/09/Peer-Review-Gender_blog-image-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/09/its-peer-review-week/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Peer Review Week 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is all about diversity. To look at the changing scholarly landscape, we interviewed science publishing historian, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/history/staff/aileenfyfe.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Aileen Fyfe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, who draws on her experience working in the archives of the Royal Society to explain how diversifying the pool of experts involved in the peer review process can further advance the scientific record.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;How diverse is the peer review process at the moment?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Until more people start publishing their data on both their community of authors and reviewers it’s difficult to tell. There’s certainly concerns about the geopolitical balance, whether the global north is doing much more of the refereeing, whereas the global south is doing a lot of authoring, and not so much refereeing. So that’s a large scale problem. There are certainly suspicions about women’s involvements, whether women are underrepresented as reviewers and editorial board members. The stats that we have so far do suggest that that’s true. But we still don’t know very much about other forms of diversity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;One of the points that I’d like to make about diversity in peer review is that there is always going to be some limit on how diverse peer review can be, because peer review by its nature doesn’t let just anyone do it. So we select as peer reviewers people who have got some form of shared expertise, some certain standards of training and education, and some form of research credentials, which nowadays generally means having published a couple of papers. So, there’s already a limit on exactly how diverse the pool can be, there are going to be some people who are not going to be invited to do this. And for peer review to work we wouldn’t want to lose that. But the interesting question becomes, within those limits, within the pool of people who have the appropriate level of education and professional research training are there any other reasons why diversity should be restricted. Nowadays we would probably say no to that, we wouldn’t think that religion or gender, geographical location or socioeconomic status should have anything to do with it. But those things have all often historically been tied up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Over the years we’ve extended our understanding of who can be involved in peer review, but we don’t want to lose the sense of recognising what good science looks like. But, on the other other hand, there is room for a lot within that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;What happens when the peer review process isn’t diverse? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;An immediate worry is that the process wouldn’t be fair if, for instance, decisions about global science were routinely being made by a handful of elite researchers in a handful of elite institutions. And we know that everyone carries implicit biases against people who are not like them—which is a particular worry in those fields of research that currently use single blind review systems. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But, you’ve also got the worry that with any group of similar minded people who share an understanding of what good science looks like, you’ve got a tendency to commit towards intellectual conservatism. Will they recognise the innovation, the speculative approach that turns out to be really fruitful? Because if you’re looking for stuff that is familiar and solid and rigorous and good, maybe you’ll miss something that’s exciting and novel, so there’s also that kind of aspect of diversity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;This intellectual diversity is slightly different from the social economic, gender, class, ethnicity that we talk about today. And nowadays we try to separate those things, and reckon hopefully we can have intellectual diversity and also have diversity of types of people. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We want to try and ensure that the people doing the editorial and reviewing work, aren’t being too prone to groupthink if you will, that they won’t be dismissing new approaches, new ideas, because they don’t look like the ones that they are familiar with, so there’s a worry that the scientific content could suffer if all the people doing the reviewing all comes from the same institution or from the same sub-field of a discipline.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;What can we do to support diversity in the peer review process and scientific discourse in general?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;One of the things that does seem to work is talking about it! When I look at the change in statistics for the Royal Society’s journals over the last 30 years, it’s quite clear that something has happened…, in terms of who is writing for the Royal Society and reviewing for the Royal Society, that has changed a lot since the 1980s early 1990s and I think it’s changed much more recently than that, and you have to ask why. And the only reason that I can see is that that organisation has started talking a lot about diversity, it has started gathering the statistics, and it’s started wondering what it can do better. And it looks as if that works. In terms of the number of editors, this is still rather male only, but the editorial boards, the publicly visible aspect, is getting better; and diversity among reviewers themselves is also getting better, it’s now similar to the number of authors in terms of gender. The proportion of women who are reviewers is similar to the proportion of women who are authors, which seems like a reasonable place to be.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;So, talking about it, asking questions, getting people to publish their stats.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;I think that that raising awareness thing, which is becoming more common, does seem to be focusing people’s minds, even if it’s just focusing editors’ minds… on who are they going to choose. And that’s the first step towards making some sort of progress, so they don’t automatically go to whatever the equivalent of an old boys club is right now…. And this could be your institutional network, the people you know and went to graduate school with, it could be that kind of group, and ideally you want something more diverse than that. And if you got the editors thinking about that, then that’s got to be a good first step.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;About Aileen Fyfe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Aileen is a professor of history at the University of St. Andrews where she researches the history of scholarly communications. She currently leads a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arts.st-andrews.ac.uk/philosophicaltransactions/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;research project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; based at the Royal Society investigating the history of the world’s oldest scientific journal, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Philosophical Transactions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image: Figure 1, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0197280&quot;&gt;PONE 0197280&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/XjD-U4colzY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Persistence pays off for plagiarized author: emails spur retraction, sanctions against researcher</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71316</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/13/persistence-pays-off-for-plagiarized-author-emails-spur-retraction-sanctions-against-researcher/</link>
	<description>Here’s an object lesson for scientists who find out they’ve been ripped off by other researchers: Taking matters into your own hands can produce results.   An aggrieved author’s doggedness led to the retraction of a 2013 paper that plagiarized his work, along with the revocation of a doctoral degree by one of the scientists … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/13/persistence-pays-off-for-plagiarized-author-emails-spur-retraction-sanctions-against-researcher/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Persistence pays off for plagiarized author: emails spur retraction, sanctions against researcher&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 12:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Women who practice submissive BDSM displayed reduced empathy and an atypical neural response to other people’s pain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34727</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/13/women-who-practice-submissive-bdsm-have-reduced-empathy-and-an-atypical-neural-response-to-other-peoples-pain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-844099546.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34729&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34729&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 700D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Bondage sadomasochism sex games erotic handcuffs and leather bdsm dominance whip.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1480859831&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Bondage sadomasochism sex games erotic handcuffs and leather bdsm dominance whip&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Bondage sadomasochism sex games erotic handcuffs and leather bdsm dominance whip&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-844099546.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-844099546.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-844099546.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2104,1425&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/13/women-who-practice-submissive-bdsm-have-reduced-empathy-and-an-atypical-neural-response-to-other-peoples-pain/bondage-sadomasochism-sex-games-erotic-handcuffs-and-leather-bdsm-dominance-whip/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-844099546.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all differ in how much empathic brain activity we experience in response to witnessing somebody else in pain. For instance, hospital physicians, who are regularly exposed to other people’s suffering, tend to show &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960982207019793&quot;&gt;a dampened response&lt;/a&gt; – perhaps a pragmatic necessity to cope in the job, and might along the way explain the blasé gallows humour seen in the profession. If these differences are found within a job, perhaps they also occur within a lifestyle choice, such as one that involves playing with and consenting to painful activities, such as bondage, discipline, dominance, submission, sadism, and masochism, typically abbreviated to BDSM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0028393217300337?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/em&gt;, Siyang Luo at Sun Yat-Sen University and Xiao Zhang at Jinan University explored this issue by first running a preliminary online study on a Chinese BDSM web forum, finding that across genders and BDSM roles, female submissives showed the clearest differences from controls in terms of their having a diminished response to other people’s pain and lower scores on aspects of an empathy questionnaire. (Female doms didn’t show a reliably different response to pain, and male BDSM practitioners barely differed from controls.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34727&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, Luo and Zhang invited 32 of these female submissive practitioners together with 32 female controls, into their lab, where they measured their electrical brain activity with EEG (electroencephalography) while they viewed images of faces with either neutral or painful expressions. The self-identified submissive participants found painful expressions less unpleasant and intense than controls, and when the images were framed in a BDSM context, they also found them more enjoyable and arousing, loosely replicating what was suggested by the online experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EEG data showed that an early negative spike in brain activity in the frontal lobes (called N1) was larger for the controls when they saw painful versus neutral stimuli, and more so when the participant found the images particularly unpleasant. But for the submissives, the N1 was similar in both cases. Past research has implicated N1 in registering threatening information, such as that denoted in a fearful face, so this could suggest that the submissives were seeing less threat, understandable given submissive practices that willingly incorporate pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a positive spike in brain activity, also in the frontal lobes (called P2), which is usually associated both with pain and emotion processing, was flattened in submissive participants when they viewed generic pain – again suggesting less empathic response. However, when seeing BDSM-related images, their P2 was actually larger than controls, and this correlated with their subjective arousal ratings, suggesting that the brain response was capturing their interest in pain rather than distress. A third brainwave signal, also associated with emotion processing (the “LPP” in the parietal lobe), also showed an attenuation in the submissive group, corroborating the case for a weakening of empathic response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luo and Zhang also measured their participants’ day-to-day empathy, in terms of how they related to other people. Again, the submissive group had significantly lower empathy scores than controls, centred on lower reported ability to take different perspectives – e.g. “I find it difficult to see things from the other guy’s point of view.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is limited to one subgroup of people who practice BDSM, and doesn’t implicate the wider field. The fact that the effects were initially discovered for women, not men, may reflect the fact that men tend to be less empathic to begin with. And the online study’s identification of submissive practitioners, rather than dominant ones, as having lower than normal empathy and an atypical response to pain, could reflect that this is the subset of people who willingly expose themselves to pain experience, which could be densensitising, or because this group is made up of individuals started out less sensitised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last issue is a point to emphasise – because we don’t know whether the kind of person drawn to submissive practices is different from the norm, the study doesn’t show that practicing BDSM causes any changes in empathy. But that the differences could be produced by the practice is certainly conceptually possible, both from the general principles of brain plasticity and from more specific insights from pain science. Working in a pain management service over this summer has left me in no doubt that our relationship with pain is shaped by psychological factors, and can change over time. More research will be needed to tell if this is the case here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If submissive practices were causing empathic changes, would this matter? On the one hand, our neural empathic responses don’t dictate our moral capacities – we don’t assume that emergency ward doctors are less caring than stockbrokers, even if they are less sensitised to someone suffering from an injury. Some even argue that being tethered to reactive empathy is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2017/feb/06/against-empathy-paul-bloom-the-empathy-instinct-peter-bazalgette-review&quot;&gt;a moral state we would do well to forego&lt;/a&gt;. On the other hand, as we covered here at the Digest recently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/05/super-altruists-whove-donated-a-kidney-to-a-stranger-show-heightened-empathic-brain-activity-when-witnessing-strangers-in-pain/%2523more-34660&quot;&gt;there is evidence&lt;/a&gt; linking neural empathic responses to even very concrete altruistic decisions like donating a kidney to a stranger. Also, if the lower trait empathy scores among the BDSM practitioners were the product of their sexual practices, this would arguably be worth reflecting on, as it could have potential consequences for the quality of their relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0028393217300337?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Empathy in female submissive BDSM practitioners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 3 ways to boost your tech and data skills</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-to-boost-your-tech-and-data-skills</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-to-boost-your-tech-and-data-skills</link>
	<description>Here’s how you can develop practical skills while advancing your career</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 07:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sea level rise doesn’t necessarily spell doom for coastal wetlands</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-level-rise-doesnt-necessarily-spell-doom-coastal-wetlands</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-level-rise-doesnt-necessarily-spell-doom-coastal-wetlands</link>
	<description>Wetlands can survive and even thrive despite rising sea levels — if humans give them room to grow.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091118_CG_wetlands_feat.jpg?itok=Qmmgd0iA" length="54463" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Butchered bird bones put humans in Madagascar 10,500 years ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/butchered-bird-bones-put-humans-madagascar-10500-years-ago</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/butchered-bird-bones-put-humans-madagascar-10500-years-ago</link>
	<description>Humans reached the island near Africa 6,000 years earlier than thought, raising questions about how its megafauna went extinct.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091218_BB_madagascar_feat.jpg?itok=FF2oD8Is" length="30371" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This South African cave stone may bear the world’s oldest drawing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/south-african-cave-stone-may-bear-worlds-oldest-drawing</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/south-african-cave-stone-may-bear-worlds-oldest-drawing</link>
	<description>The Stone Age line design could have held special meaning for its makers, a new study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091118_bb_ancientdrawing_feat.jpg?itok=IRHw24mC" length="27777" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new antibiotic uses sneaky tactics to kill drug-resistant superbugs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antibiotic-uses-sneaky-tactics-kill-drug-resistant-superbugs</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antibiotic-uses-sneaky-tactics-kill-drug-resistant-superbugs</link>
	<description>Scientists have developed a molecule that kills off bacteria that are resistant to existing antibiotics.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091118_LH_antibiotic_feat.jpg?itok=YTQ8ksRl" length="21478" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When it comes to authorship, how prolific is too prolific?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71241</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/12/when-it-comes-to-authorship-how-prolific-is-too-prolific/</link>
	<description>One of the suggestions we get regularly here at Retraction Watch is something along the lines of “This researcher publishes too much. You should look into that.” But how much is too much? The phenomenon was the subject of a 2015 paper. It’s also the subject of a new article in Nature by John Ioannidis, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/12/when-it-comes-to-authorship-how-prolific-is-too-prolific/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;When it comes to authorship, how prolific is too prolific?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Olivier Voinnet: not guilty in past, present and future</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=28287</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/12/olivier-voinnet-not-guilty-in-past-present-and-future/</link>
	<description>Olivier Voinnet, responsible for probably the biggest fraud scandal in plant sciences, is back in the news. His present employer ETH Zürich has now concluded, in collaboration with CNRS, their second investigation into data manipulations in Voinnet papers. The ETH professor was declared innocent of any data manipulations, in the past, present and even future.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 11:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Are educational neuromyths actually harmful? Award-winning teachers believe in nearly as many of them as trainees</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34717</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/12/are-educational-neuromyths-actually-harmful-award-winning-teachers-believe-in-nearly-as-many-as-trainees/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34722&quot; style=&quot;width: 1626px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-165816584.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34722&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34722&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector File of Left and Right Brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;kimberrywood&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Left and Right Brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Left and Right Brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-165816584.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-165816584.jpg?w=845?w=265&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-165816584.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1626,1843&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/12/are-educational-neuromyths-actually-harmful-award-winning-teachers-believe-in-nearly-as-many-as-trainees/left-and-right-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-165816584.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The researchers said the idea that neuromyths harm teaching may itself be a neuromyth&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educational neuromyths include the idea that we learn more effectively when taught via our preferred “learning style”, such as auditory or visual or kinesthetic (hear more about this in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/08/29/episode-13-how-to-study-and-learn-more-effectively/&quot;&gt;recent podcast&lt;/a&gt;); the claim that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-10-brain-myth-explained-in-60-seconds/&quot;&gt;we use only 10 per cent of our brains&lt;/a&gt;; and the idea &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/brain-myths/201206/why-the-left-brain-right-brain-myth-will-probably-never-die&quot;&gt;we can be categorised into left-brain and right-brain learners&lt;/a&gt;. Belief in such myths is rife among teachers around the world, according to several surveys published over the last ten years. But does this matter? Are the myths actually harmful to teaching? The researchers who conducted the surveys believe so. For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3475349/&quot;&gt;reporting their survey results in 2012&lt;/a&gt;, Sanne Dekker and her colleagues concluded that “This [belief in neuromyths] is troublesome, as these teachers in particular may implement wrong brain-based ideas in educational practice”. (Full disclosure: I’ve made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/12/10-ways-brain-myths-harming-us/&quot;&gt;similar arguments myself&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now this view has been challenged by a team at the University of Melbourne, led by Jared Horvath, who have pointed out that this is merely an assumption: “Put simply,” they write in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01666/full?utm_source=F-NTF&amp;amp;utm_medium=EMLX&amp;amp;utm_campaign=PRD_FEOPS_20170000_ARTICLE&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, “there is no evidence to suggest neuromyths have any impact whatsoever on teacher efficacy or practice”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horvath’s team tested the assumption that belief in neuromyths harms teaching by comparing belief in the neuromyths among 50 award-winning teachers from the UK, USA and Australia with the belief in these same myths shown by hundreds of trainee and non-award-winning teachers (as recorded in the earlier surveys) – the logic being that if belief in neuromyths has an adverse effect on teaching then presumably the award-winning teachers will show significantly lower rates of endorsement of the myths than their less celebrated counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34717&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Melbourne researchers used the same neuromyths questionnaire as used in the earlier surveys, which comprises 32 statements about the brain, 15 of which are myths. Participants must indicate whether each one is correct, incorrect, or say if they don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 13 of the 15 neuromyths, including learning styles, the 10 per cent myth and left-brain/right-brain learners, belief was just as high among the award-winning teachers as among the trainees and non-award-winning teachers. “This suggests there is not a clear or obvious relationship between neuromyth acceptance rates and teacher effectiveness,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two exceptions were the idea that “there are critical periods in childhood after which certain things can no longer be learned” and that “children must acquire their native language before a second language is learned”, which the award-winning teachers showed less endorsement of compared with the other teachers. The researchers said they were apprehensive to read too much into this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horvath’s team also found the neuromyth questionnaire itself to be wanting because it lacked any internal reliability (answers to the different items appeared entirely unrelated suggesting the questionnaire does not tap one or more coherent factors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, they interpreted their findings as suggesting that the idea that neuromyths harm teaching may itself be a neuromyth. “As has been frequently noted, there is a real risk of neuroscience being misapplied in educational contexts,” the researchers said. “However, in combating this occurrence, it is imperative researchers do not simply create a different mythology equally devoid of evidence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings appear to argue against the idea that belief in neuromyths is harmful to teaching, but it’s important to recognise – and Horvath and his colleagues admit this – that the new survey does not represent a direct test of this question, and there could be many explanations for the results. For instance, and as the researchers speculate, it’s quite possible that the judges allocating teaching awards themselves believe in neuromyths, such as learning styles, and perhaps they even deliberately rewarded teachers who had incorporated such myths into their teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If further research supports the idea that neuromyths have a negligible effect on teaching, this would not be the first time that concerns about misunderstanding neuroscience have turned out to be somewhat overhyped. For instance, for several years it was widely believed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2008/03/31/the-power-of-blobs-on-the-brain/&quot;&gt;images of the brain have a seductive allure&lt;/a&gt;, but it later turned out that this effect was &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/03/04/are-we-now-blase-about-brain-scans/&quot;&gt;difficult to replicate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01666/full?utm_source=F-NTF&amp;amp;utm_medium=EMLX&amp;amp;utm_campaign=PRD_FEOPS_20170000_ARTICLE&quot;&gt;On the Irrelevance of Neuromyths to Teacher Effectiveness: Comparing Neuro-Literacy Levels Amongst Award-Winning and Non-award Winning Teachers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Great-Myths-Brain-Psychology/dp/1118312716&quot;&gt;Great Myths of The Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 09:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s how graphene could make future electronics superfast</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-graphene-could-make-future-electronics-superfast</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-graphene-could-make-future-electronics-superfast</link>
	<description>Graphene-based electronics that operate at terahertz frequencies would be much speedier successors to today’s silicon-based devices.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091018_MT_graphene_feat.jpg?itok=6fDZBtc1" length="28649" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sound waves can make bubbles in levitated drops of liquid</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sound-waves-bubbles-levitated-liquid-drops</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sound-waves-bubbles-levitated-liquid-drops</link>
	<description>A new technique reveals how to make bubbles from droplets suspended in the air.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091118_ec_bubbles_feat_free.jpg?itok=3ZhxGAjL" length="14380" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Retraction Watch readers, we need your help to be able to continue our work</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71182</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/11/retraction-watch-readers-we-need-your-help-to-be-able-to-continue-our-work/</link>
	<description>Dear Retraction Watch readers: Have you seen our database of retractions? While we’re still putting finishing touches on it before an official launch, with more than 18,000 retractions, it’s already the most comprehensive collection of retractions anywhere. We have learned a great deal as we’ve gathered those retractions, which we look forward to sharing quite soon, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/11/retraction-watch-readers-we-need-your-help-to-be-able-to-continue-our-work/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch readers, we need your help to be able to continue our work&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 12:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Marijuana use among pregnant women is rising, and so are concerns</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/marijuana-use-pregnant-women</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/marijuana-use-pregnant-women</link>
	<description>Pediatricians are urging caution as data show more pregnant women are using marijuana. More research is urgently needed on the drug’s effects during pregnancy.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/blogposts/090618_LS_weed-pregnant_feat.jpg?itok=5GOfCJli" length="16904" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Virtual reality research finds large sex difference in navigational efficiency</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34713</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/11/virtual-reality-research-finds-large-sex-difference-in-navigational-efficiency/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34714&quot; style=&quot;width: 620px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-09-11 at 11.21.58.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34714&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34714&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-09-11 at 11.21.58&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/screen-shot-2018-09-11-at-11-21-58.png?w=845?w=620&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/screen-shot-2018-09-11-at-11-21-58.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/screen-shot-2018-09-11-at-11-21-58.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;620,445&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/11/virtual-reality-research-finds-large-sex-difference-in-navigational-efficiency/screen-shot-2018-09-11-at-11-21-58/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/screen-shot-2018-09-11-at-11-21-58.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;Men took more shortcuts and reached their target location faster (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13421-018-0811-y?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&amp;amp;utm_source=toc&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=toc_13421_46_6&quot;&gt;Boone et al, 2018&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a day exploring a new city and it’s time to return to your hotel, do you tend to rely on landmarks and routes that you’ve learned, or do you consult a “mental map” that you’ve created of the area, to try to devise a short-cut back? If you’re a man, you’re more likely to try the latter – whereas women tend to use routes they know, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13421-018-0811-y?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&amp;amp;utm_source=toc&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=toc_13421_46_6&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Memory and Cognition&lt;/i&gt; by researchers at the University of California, Santa Barbara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34713&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Alexander Boone, Xinyi Gong and Mary Hegarty are keen not to be seen as promoting the idea that men are better navigators, a mental map approach is generally regarded as being superior, as it permits novel shortcuts (when they are possible, of course). And in this new virtual reality study, men were not only significantly more likely than women to take short cuts, but they were, on average, more efficient at finding their way to target locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers ran two experiments on groups of UC Santa Barbara students. In the first, 68 men and women were guided along a set route through a virtual maze. The maze measured 55 by 55 metres, and appeared to have concrete walls. Twelve objects (including a chair, a duck, a wooden well and a stove) were placed at various points along the route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning this route, the participants were re-positioned at different locations along it and asked to navigate to another point; for example they were placed near the wooden well and asked to navigate to the stove. Each participant completed 24 navigation trials. In half, it was possible to take a novel shortcut. In six, the shortest novel route and the learned path were the same length, and in a further six, the learned route was in fact the shortest path to the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two raters looked at the routes that the participants took in all the trials and coded each as ‘taking a shortcut’, ‘taking the learned route’, ‘reversing the learned route’, or ‘wandering’. To assess navigation efficiency, times and distances travelled to the goals were all computed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second experiment, involving a new batch of 72 students, was largely a replication of the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both experiments, men showed a greater preference for taking shortcuts than women, who were more likely to follow learned routes and to wander. And on average, the men were significantly faster, and covered less ground, in reaching the target objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier studies have either found no gender differences on navigation challenges, or found that the male participants did better. This study goes a little further, in that it investigates the kinds of strategies that men and women tend to choose themselves. (Interestingly, the strategies that the participants actually used didn’t match up well with the kinds of strategies they reported generally taking.) Still, the findings do tally with those suggesting that men tend to be superior navigators in situations in which: a). It’s possible to create a mental map, and b). that map can be useful (in an environment where shortcuts aren’t possible, it’s not likely to help). The researchers do stress, however, that some women in their study were just as efficient as the best male performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If men are more likely to use mental maps, which permit shortcuts, and women are more likely to use known routes and to wander, why might this be? It has been suggested by psychologists that while using landmarks and known routes won’t always be as efficient, this is likely to be a safer option for women (who, it’s argued, are more vulnerable than men), both in terms of avoiding getting lost and in reducing the risk of encountering something dangerous. (If taking a shortcut turns out to require tiptoeing around a bear’s den, the risk to life surely outweighs the potential gain in cutting a few minutes from the journey home…).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, even in the cases when men and women used the same strategy to navigate, the men were faster at getting to the targets. Why might men be faster at following or reversing a known route? All the participants did get some training in navigating around a VR maze. But the men reported spending more time playing video games than the women. Perhaps that extra gaming practise explains it. In a real-world environment, would men still have the advantage? Only future research can tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13421-018-0811-y?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&amp;amp;utm_source=toc&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=toc_13421_46_6&quot;&gt;Sex differences in navigation strategy and efficiency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 10:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Response to Plan S from Academic Researchers: Unethical, Too Risky!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=27995</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/11/response-to-plan-s-from-academic-researchers-unethical-too-risky/</link>
	<description>This is Appeal by several European scientists protesting against Plan S, recently revealed by the EU and a coalition of European research funders. Lynn Kamerlin and her coauthors worry that Plan S will deprive them of quality journal venues and of international collaborative opportunities, while disadvantaging scientists whose research budgets preclude paying and playing in this OA league. They offer instead their own suggestions how to implement Open Science.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How obesity may harm memory and learning</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-obesity-may-harm-memory-and-learning</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-obesity-may-harm-memory-and-learning</link>
	<description>In obese mice, immune cells chomp nerve cell connections and harm brainpower.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 17:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091018_LS_obesity_main_free.jpg?itok=FV6sR9Av" length="61198" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Max Plank Florida Institute for Neuroscience: MPFI Scientist Receives More than $2 Million in NIH Funding to Study Regulation of Instructive Signaling in the Cerebellum</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=11212</guid>
	<link>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/mpfi-scientist-receives-more-than-2-million-in-nih-funding-to-study-regulation-of-instructive-signaling-in-the-cerebellum/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI) announces that Dr. Jason Christie, MPFI Research Group Leader, has been awarded a grant in the amount of $2,082,074 over five-years to support ongoing investigation of neural circuits in the cerebellum that instruct and guide motor learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cerebellum, an anatomically unique region of the brain, plays a central role in fine motor control and motor learning. When functioning normally, the cerebellum is essential in learning and performing skilled movements, but its dysfunction has been linked to movement disorders such as ataxia (progressive loss of fine motor skills) and dystonia (uncontrollable muscle contractions). These types of disorders make daily movements increasingly difficult as neurons in the cerebellum degenerate. The goal of this study is to identify how neurons in the cerebellum interact with one another, providing fundamental insights into the mechanisms underlying motor learning. Specifically, Dr. Christie and his team will examine the role of a prominent class of inhibitory interneurons that may determine how and when learning occurs. This project will provide new discoveries into the computational principles of the cerebellum and aid in the development of new therapies aimed at ameliorating diseases affecting motor control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motor learning occurs when mistakes are made while performing movements. Specialized cells in the cerebellum, called Purkinje cells, receive powerful instructive signals that guide our behavior and improve subsequent movements. What has remained largely unknown, is how these instructive signals are modulated to produce a spectrum of learning outcomes. Through his research, Dr. Christie has identified the importance of a key type of neuron, Molecular Layer Interneurons (MLIs), that may be essential in modulating error signals and driving adaptability of motor learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employing the latest and most advanced imaging and genetic techniques, MPFI scientists in Dr. Christie’s lab will study the role of MLIs in motor learning from the cellular level, to circuit dynamics and ultimately, how their activation affects behavior. With the support of this crucial funding, Dr. Christie’s research will provide a better understanding of how neural circuits in the cerebellum ensure accurate movement, turning the motor errors we make into reliable, adaptable and meaningful learning; laying the foundational science that will lead to tomorrow’s cures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Christie joined the Max Planck Florida Institute in July 2010 as Research Group Leader in Synaptic Signaling and Computation. Prior to this appointment, Dr. Christie conducted research at the Vollum Institute at the Oregon Health and Science University in Portland, Oregon, where he completed his doctoral and post-doctoral work. He has joint faculty appointments with  Florida Atlantic University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 15:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: It’s Peer Review Week!!!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8300</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/SWFAnZXeP9E/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/09/Peer-Review-Gender_blog-image-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peer Review Week is a global event celebrating the essential role that peer review plays in how we evaluate and communicate most scholarly research. Our aim is to spark discussion and collaboration between researchers and publishers who want to improve scholarly communication. For that, there’s no better jumping off point than this year’s topic: diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How diverse is it? The scholarly landscape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the demand for STEM degrees is on the rise around the world, we still see a relatively small percentage of published papers out of countries in Africa and Latin America. Even more troubling, are the increasingly common stories of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/2018/jul/07/why-science-is-breeding-ground-for-sexism?CMP=share_btn_link&quot;&gt;unsafe &lt;/a&gt;working conditions, lack of resources, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/11/math-women/506417/&quot;&gt;perceptual biases&lt;/a&gt; keeping women out of many higher academic fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.elifesciences.org/articles/21718/elife-21718-v1.pdf&quot;&gt;eLife&lt;/a&gt; found the percentage of female authors, reviewers, and editors in STEM publishing falls far below 50% and predicts these percentages, 37%, 28% and 26% respectively, would not achieve parity with male counterparts until 2042 if currents trends of growth continue. In some fields, the difference in representation is even more staggering. For example, a review of 435 Mathematical journals published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0161357&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found the median number of editorships held by women to be only 7.6%. Fifty-one journals had no women on their editorial boards at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the eLife study, both women and men show an inclination to appoint reviewers of the same gender, limiting possibilities for women on a journal with an editorial board comprised of mostly men and perpetuating the imbalance of representation. Another study in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0192481&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; found similar results, as well as evidence of preference for other shared background characteristics such as country or institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a journal’s peer review process is only as diverse as the network of editors who oversee it, we must diversify our editorial boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The role of publishers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishers, as stewards for scientific research, have a responsibility to raise all voices of the community. To do that, we must offer the tools and opportunities for researchers from all backgrounds to participate in the scholarly discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we can do is to actively seek an even mix of expertise, affiliation, nationality, and gender to represent the editorial board and journal staff. We also need to start stepping outside our comfort zones, ask ourselves whether our tried and true models really work for everyone or if they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/13.7/2018/02/02/581849526/leaky-pipelines-plug-the-holes-or-change-the-system&quot;&gt;hidden barriers&lt;/a&gt; for certain groups. Some great advice for publishers and organizations is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2017/11/16/diversity-scholarly-communications/&quot;&gt;here &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2017/12/12/tackling-diversity-scholarly-communications-part-2/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting the conversation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer review and how to make it better is the focus of many organizations that just last month penned an &lt;a href=&quot;http://asapbio.org/letter&quot;&gt;Open Letter&lt;/a&gt; to the community regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/2018/08/transparency-credit-and-peer-review/&quot;&gt;transparent peer review&lt;/a&gt;. Through posted and signed reviews, we’re taking steps to further our understanding of peer review and to open up opportunities for critical conversations about peer review best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later this week, we’ll be posting an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.st-andrews.ac.uk/history/staff/aileenfyfe.html&quot;&gt;Aileen Fyfe&lt;/a&gt;, science publishing historian, who will talk about the importance of unique voices to advance scientific literature.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/everyone/2018/09/10/peer-review-week-2018-diversity/&quot;&gt;EveryONE blog&lt;/a&gt; also has an additional perspective, as well as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://collections.plos.org/gender-imbalance&quot;&gt;collection&lt;/a&gt; of papers on gender inequality in peer review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we invite you to raise your own voice and share your experiences with the hashtags #PeerReviewWeek18 and #PeerRevDiversityInclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/SWFAnZXeP9E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Finding the best long-term home for Aries Systems</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/finding-the-best-long-term-home-for-aries-systems</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/finding-the-best-long-term-home-for-aries-systems</link>
	<description>“With Elsevier, Aries will be even stronger … with enhanced solutions and analytics to help our customers achieve their goals”</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Japanese university revokes PhD following a retraction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71088</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/10/japanese-university-revokes-phd-following-a-retraction/</link>
	<description>Tokyo Women’s Medical University has stripped a researcher of her PhD, following the retraction of a paper — for data duplication — that was based on her thesis. The August 30th announcement notes that a degree was revoked on July 20. The announcement does not name the researcher, but refers to degree number 2881, which … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/10/japanese-university-revokes-phd-following-a-retraction/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Japanese university revokes PhD following a retraction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new hydrogen-rich compound may be a record-breaking superconductor</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-hydrogen-rich-compound-may-be-record-breaking-superconductor</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-hydrogen-rich-compound-may-be-record-breaking-superconductor</link>
	<description>The record for the highest-temperature superconductor may be toast.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090718_EC_superconductor_feat_REV_2.jpg?itok=5Ol1TcM8" length="24555" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC series: August 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10489</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/10/highlights-bmc-series-august-2018/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/BMCWordle-620x342-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Gastroenterology: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12876-018-0831-x&quot;&gt;Preventing antibiotic-associated diarrhea using probiotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antibiotics can have a number of side effects, the most common being gastro-intestinal such as diarrhea. Antibiotic-associated diarrhea (AAD) is caused by antibiotics disrupting the ecology of the intestinal microbiota, altering the diversity and numbers of bacteria in the gut. This can lead to long-lasting effects on the balance of the intestinal microbiota and consequently on the patient’s susceptibility to infection and other diseases. In an article published in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgastroenterol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Gastroenterology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Kort &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;present a practical guide to the use of probiotics for the prevention of antibiotic-associated diarrhea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10492&quot; style=&quot;width: 970px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10492 size-full&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/antibiotics-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that probiotics were associated with lower incidence of AAD overall. In addition, there are a number of factors affecting the efficacy of probiotics, such as strain composition, probiotic product formulation, and specific patient differences (e.g. – genetic factors). The researchers concluded that there is sufficient evidence to make a recommendation for the use of specific probiotic products for the prevention of AAD. In particular, Kort &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; recommend &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus rhamnosus&lt;/em&gt; GG as the most effective probiotic to prevent AAD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-018-1843-3&quot;&gt;Men’s suicidality in Norway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10414 alignright&quot; height=&quot;287&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/Reasons-for-dying-300x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;287&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gender has been emphasized as crucial for understanding suicidal behavior. Previous research has concluded that men who adhere to traditional masculinity seem to have increased health risks compared to those who do not. Further research has shown that some circumstances make men more vulnerable to suicidal behavior, such as single marital status, unemployment and retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a published article in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; Knizek and Hjelmeland sought to investigate what men who have engaged in a suicidal act perceived as crucial for their decision to harm themselves or attempt to take their life&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers conducted interviews with men who were admitted to hospital after a suicidal act. It was concluded that the main reason or trigger for the suicidal act were complex problems in intimate relationships, with some men saying pain and ennui were reasons. The most striking finding was how unique and different each story was, which makes it important to consider that standardized efforts of suicide prevention may not be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-018-0181-0&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life history traits in a capital breeding pine caterpillar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host plants (or the plants an organism relies on) are thought to play important roles in the evolution of various traits for herbivorous insects. Liu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; sought to investigate the influence of host plant species and pine needle age on larval performances, adult mating behavior and fitness consequences in a capital breeding caterpillar, &lt;em&gt;Dendrolimus punctatus&lt;/em&gt; Walker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that the pine species and needle age significantly affected larval performance, such as developmental duration, survivorship, and body weight. Male body weight was significantly influenced by pine species and needle age; however interestingly, female body weight was only significantly influenced by pine species, not by needle age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings highlight the importance of larval host plants on larval performance and adult reproductive fitness in this pine caterpillar. The previous-year needles of one particular pine (masson pine &lt;em&gt;P. massoniana&lt;/em&gt;) were concluded to be the best host for this pine caterpillar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Anesthesiology: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcanesthesiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12871-018-0574-9&quot;&gt;Palliative care in intensive care units&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9183 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/medical-563427_960_720-pixabay-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Distressing symptoms are common for most intensive care unit (ICU) patients and their families. Previous research has suggested that palliative care assessment should start as early as possible in ICU patients at a high risk of dying, to minimize unnecessary suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A review article published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcanesthesiol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Anesthesiology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discusses palliative care in ICUs and provides anesthesiologists and critical care physicians practical advice on the application of palliative care in ICUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;ICU doctors should be familiar with and competent in all aspects of palliative care through dedicated training&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, ICU doctors may not have the knowledge to effectively carry out palliative care. Therefore, Cortegiani &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; conclude that ICU doctors should be familiar with and competent in all aspects of palliative care through dedicated training. Such training would provide critically ill patients and their families access to care that would meet their needs and improve patients quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-018-0255-y&quot;&gt;Emotion regulation and its relation to symptoms of anxiety and depression in children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10493&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10493&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/child_sad-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulation of emotions is considered to be important in children’s adaptive development. Previous studies have found that children who repeatedly fail to regulate their emotions in accordance to context are at greater risk of developing internalizing symptoms associated with anxiety and depression. Loevaas &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;. sought to investigate the associations between anxious and depressive symptoms and difficulties in emotion regulation in Norwegian school children in a published article in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that a lack of positive strategies to regulate emotions were associated with anxious and depressive symptoms. Therefore, emotional regulation is considered to be a potentially important target in the prevention and identification of children at risk of anxiety and/or depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was found that there was no difference between the maternal and paternal reports regarding the association between emotion regulation in children and anxiety symptoms; though there were differences for depressive symptoms. The study highlighted that research involving children should include both parents if possible, to prevent the chance of bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcenergy.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Energy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A new journal in the BMC Series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Energy&lt;/em&gt; covers theory, development and applications in the interdisciplinary field of energy and fuel research from across the physical sciences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new journal in the BMC Series opened for submissions in August. The journal, &lt;em&gt;BMC Energy&lt;/em&gt;, adds to BMC Series’ expansion into the engineering and energy research fields, joining the already launched &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcbiomedeng.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Biomedical Engineering&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcchemeng.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Chemical Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; journals. &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Energy&lt;/em&gt; covers theory, development and applications in the interdisciplinary field of energy and fuel &lt;/span&gt;research from across the physical sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10494&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10494&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/solar-panel-e1536575475684-300x217.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;The journal will cover the following sections: Solar thermal energy; Bioenergy; Low carbon energy sources; Carbon capture, storage and applications; Energy storage; Energy systems, processes, planning and policy. The journal is open access and peer reviewed, and does not make editorial decisions on the basis of the interest of a study or its likely impact.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/10/highlights-bmc-series-august-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC series: August 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 10:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/BMCWordle-620x342-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Brain stimulation during sleep does not enhance memory for learned material</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-3627239345257875783</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/9517eRCR6dE/brain-stimulation-during-sleep-does-not.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.modernmechanix.com/learn-while-you-sleep/&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot; title=&quot;Modern Mechanix&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1075&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6RFZwpTbwtc/W5SghwQUFDI/AAAAAAAAMnE/4W1Q8fZRS0U9kFsw4wh-ZFeo1dvmKlQRQCLcBGAs/s400/learn_while_you_sleep.jpg&quot; width=&quot;267&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“Learn while you sleep” has been the claim of snake oil salesmen since the 1950s. The old pseudoscience methods involved listening to tapes and records. From a 1958 article by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.modernmechanix.com/learn-while-you-sleep/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Learn While You Sleep (Mechanix Illustrated, Nov 1958)&quot;&gt;Lester David&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Max Sherover, president of the Linguaphone Institute of New York ... coined the word “&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1540-4781.1950.tb04902.x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Sherover M (1950). Dormiphonics—A New Language Learning Technique. The Modern Language Journal 34: 444-446.&quot;&gt;dormiphonics&lt;/a&gt;,” defining it as a “new scientific method that makes quick relaxed learning possible, awake or asleep.” Dormiphonics, declares Mr. Sherover, works by “repeated concentrated impact of selected material on the conscious and subconscious mind.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An “experiment” was conducted at the Tulare County Prison, where 100 convicts “&lt;a href=&quot;https://sleeplearning.com/info/learn-while-you-sleep/&quot;&gt;volunteered&lt;/a&gt; to act as guinea pigs” (considered completely unethical by today's standards). During sleep, they were subjected to low-volume recordings that exhorted them to be better human beings: “Love shall rule your life. You shall love God, your family and others.  You shall do unto others as you want others to do unto you. . .” The low voice also warned them away from the evils of alcohol.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LCqcBZYGb7s/W5XUvtCjHJI/AAAAAAAAMnQ/-q1ZOQlbghYrKy13xer504kBgS0nbTIZwCLcBGAs/s1600/Learn%2Bwhile%2Byou%2Bsleep%2Balbum%2B%2528basic%2Bconditioner%2529.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1024&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1011&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-LCqcBZYGb7s/W5XUvtCjHJI/AAAAAAAAMnQ/-q1ZOQlbghYrKy13xer504kBgS0nbTIZwCLcBGAs/s400/Learn%2Bwhile%2Byou%2Bsleep%2Balbum%2B%2528basic%2Bconditioner%2529.jpg&quot; width=&quot;393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ebay.com/itm/LEARN-WHILE-YOU-SLEEP-KNIGHT-EDUCATION-INC-PLP-06-60s-RED-SELF-HELP-VINYL/273437929222&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;comes in groovy red vinyl&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Knight Education Recordings (1960s)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;a commercially available product of the era&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even earlier, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://centerhistorypsychology.wordpress.com/2017/02/23/the-psycho-phone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Psycho-Phone&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://centerhistorypsychology.files.wordpress.com/2017/01/ben2.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Psychology: Health, Happiness, Success&quot;&gt;Salinger, 1927&lt;/a&gt;) played wax cylinders with different self-help messages, e.g., “Prosperity” and “Life Extension” on a phonograph while the unwitting customer slept. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://centerhistorypsychology.wordpress.com/2017/02/23/the-psycho-phone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cummings Center Blog&lt;/a&gt; has a great post on this odd contraption. Salinger sold the machines for the whopping price of $235 (the equivalent of $3,250 in 2017). He didn't need &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=sleep+eeg+site%3Akickstarter.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;sleep eeg&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=sleep+eeg+site%3Aindiegogo.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;sleep eeg&quot;&gt;Indiegogo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyW0ppsLrLs/W5XfaTjnW8I/AAAAAAAAMnc/Tw0IuIM6ZoQD2FzsMa5qrzRDJKtU7EckQCLcBGAs/s1600/The%2BPsycho-Phone.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;300&quot; data-original-width=&quot;435&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyW0ppsLrLs/W5XfaTjnW8I/AAAAAAAAMnc/Tw0IuIM6ZoQD2FzsMa5qrzRDJKtU7EckQCLcBGAs/s400/The%2BPsycho-Phone.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the modern era, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diytdcs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;DIY tDCS blog&quot;&gt;DIY&lt;/a&gt; brain stimulation enthusiasts promote self-experimentation with battery-driven devices. These &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transcranial_direct-current_stimulation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transcranial direct current stimulation&lt;/a&gt; (tDCS) kits are available online, with a primary goal of enhancing cognitive performance. Using state-of-the-art professionally manufactured devices, scientists have published &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=%22transcranial+direct+current+stimulation%22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thousands&lt;/a&gt; of peer-reviewed papers, with mixed results as to the efficacy of different tDCS protocols.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A newer method is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00279/full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transcranial alternating current stimulation&lt;/a&gt; (tACS), which delivers stimulation within precise frequency bands with the aim of synchronizing oscillations within that band (e.g., ~10 Hz for alpha, ~1-4 Hz for delta, etc.). The goal is to modulate ongoing oscillatory brain rhythms to affect behavior.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, the importance of sleep for the consolidation of previously learned material has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dormivigilia.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/05sleep-memory-1.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Sleep-dependent memory consolidation&quot;&gt;well-documented&lt;/a&gt;.   Conceptually, this is quite different from the discredited “subliminal  sleep learning” from days of yore. New research aims to improve retention of information learned during the day by delivering precisely timed and calibrated tACS during slow wave sleep (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/38/33/7314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ketz et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iztyMnlpaAo/W5YJD8otfhI/AAAAAAAAMno/B_njLqHMMWsRlqrHXpEVAzflmGT6jNwYACLcBGAs/s1600/tDCS%2Band%2BtACS%2Bexperimental%2Bprotocol.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;984&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1305&quot; height=&quot;301&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iztyMnlpaAo/W5YJD8otfhI/AAAAAAAAMno/B_njLqHMMWsRlqrHXpEVAzflmGT6jNwYACLcBGAs/s400/tDCS%2Band%2BtACS%2Bexperimental%2Bprotocol.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fig. 1 (modified from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/38/33/7314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ketz et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(A)&lt;/b&gt; Target detection task. &lt;b&gt;(B)&lt;/b&gt; Memory was tested on two image types: &lt;u&gt;Repeated&lt;/u&gt; (identical to Original) and &lt;u&gt;Generalized&lt;/u&gt; (same as Original but from different viewpoint). &lt;b&gt;(C)&lt;/b&gt; tDCS montage used during training (left), and tACS montage used to augment slow waves during sleep (right).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During the day, participants were trained on a difficult military task that required them to detect hidden targets (explosive devices, snipers, suicide bombers) that were concealed or disguised (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3387543/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clark et al, 2012&lt;/a&gt;). As in their earlier study, tDCS or sham stimulation was delivered during the training phase (over right frontal or right parietal cortices). Previous findings indicated that significant improvements in learning and performance were observed after 30 min tDCS (anodal 2.0 mA) vs. “&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/ejn.12307&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Challenges of proper placebo control for non‐invasive brain stimulation in clinical and experimental applications&quot;&gt;sham&lt;/a&gt;” (0.1 mA). However, this tDCS finding did not replicate in the current study (see &lt;b&gt;Fig, 3A&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;i&gt;left &lt;/i&gt;below). Why? The authors speculated that possible differences in current generation between their previous iontophoresis system (2.0 mA) and the present use of StarStim (1.0 mA) could explain the failure to replicate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After training, tACS was delivered during sleep. The authors' cool closed-loop approach recorded the dominant slow wave (SW) frequency, and then delivered stimulation to match the phase and frequency of this dominant oscillation (range of 0.5 to 1.2 Hz). &lt;b&gt;Fig. 3A&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;i&gt;right&lt;/i&gt;) doesn't look terribly impressive, however. tACS did not improve performance for Repeated images, and had highly variable effects for Generalized images. Nonetheless, the two- and three-way interactions were significant, as was the pairwise comparison between active tACS vs. sham for Generalized images (all p's ≈ .015 for n=16).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xLRKowSX1kM/W5YPIsxzP8I/AAAAAAAAMn0/CB7eq9rYR3k8P0UH2xD6yDtT-Q2q2aQuQCLcBGAs/s1600/waking%2BtDCS%2Beffects%252C%2BSW%2BtACS%2Beffects.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;876&quot; data-original-width=&quot;979&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xLRKowSX1kM/W5YPIsxzP8I/AAAAAAAAMn0/CB7eq9rYR3k8P0UH2xD6yDtT-Q2q2aQuQCLcBGAs/s400/waking%2BtDCS%2Beffects%252C%2BSW%2BtACS%2Beffects.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fig. 3 (modified from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/38/33/7314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ketz et al., 2018&lt;/a&gt;). (A)&lt;/b&gt; Waking tDCS effects (&lt;i&gt;left&lt;/i&gt;) and SW tACS effects during sleep (&lt;i&gt;right&lt;/i&gt;). &lt;b&gt;(B) &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SW events broken down  per sleep stage (&lt;i&gt;left&lt;/i&gt;) and total SW events for each stimulation  condition (&lt;i&gt;right&lt;/i&gt;). Note that active stimulation had fewer total SW events compared with sham. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why was there no change in performance for Repeated images but a small improvement for Generalized images? The authors recognize this conundrum and say:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;...it is unclear why there was no improvement in Repeated images induced by SW tACS, as might be expected based on previous studies.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then they speculate that consolidation of essential ‘gist’ — rather than recognition of specific items — was impacted by tACS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Media coverage of this modest finding was predictably overblown, and originated with the Society for Neuroscience press release, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2018-07/sfn-obs071818.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Overnight Brain Stimulation Improves Memor&lt;span id=&quot;goog_660392221&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;goog_660392222&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;i&gt;Non-invasive technique enhances memory storage without disturbing sleep. &lt;/i&gt;If it enhances memory storage, then why were Repeated images unaffected? Anyway, most commenters at &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17790711&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; were pretty skeptical, which was a pleasant surprise. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnote&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;However, there is some question whether tACS delivered at typical stimulation intensities can really entrain endogenous rhythms (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-01045-x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lafon et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clark VP, Coffman BA, Mayer AR, Weisend MP, Lane TD, Calhoun VD, Raybourn EM, Garcia CM, Wassermann EM. (2012). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3387543/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TDCS guided using fMRI significantly accelerates learning to identify concealed objects&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Neuroimage&lt;/i&gt; 59(1):117-28.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ketz N, Jones AP, Bryant NB, Clark VP, Pilly PK (2018). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jneurosci.org/content/38/33/7314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Closed-Loop Slow-Wave tACS Improves Sleep-Dependent Long-Term Memory Generalization by Modulating Endogenous Oscillations&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;J Neurosci.&lt;/i&gt; 38(33):7314-7326.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lafon B, Henin S, Huang Y, Friedman D, Melloni L, Thesen T, Doyle W, Buzsáki G, Devinsky O, Parra LC, A Liu A. (2017). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-01045-x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Low frequency transcranial electrical stimulation does not entrain sleep rhythms measured by human intracranial recordings&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Nat Commun&lt;/i&gt;. 8(1):1199.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-geTZYfcll18/W5SWFqpyl-I/AAAAAAAAMm4/3tiP_IaJfWojg5lRY6TukQoNYJJNDKgEACLcBGAs/s1600/work%2Band%2Blearn%2Bwhile%2Byou%2Bsleep%2B%2528Dec%2B1921%2529.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;578&quot; data-original-width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-geTZYfcll18/W5SWFqpyl-I/AAAAAAAAMm4/3tiP_IaJfWojg5lRY6TukQoNYJJNDKgEACLcBGAs/s400/work%2Band%2Blearn%2Bwhile%2Byou%2Bsleep%2B%2528Dec%2B1921%2529.jpg&quot; width=&quot;290&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hugo Gernsback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tarzan.org/hugo/biblio2.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;SCIENCE AND INVENTION&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;December 1921&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=9517eRCR6dE:DFwrb7a1Ye0:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/9517eRCR6dE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Alcohol as part of ‘care practices’ in White British women’s everyday personal relationships</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10496</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/10/alcohol-part-care-practices-white-british-womens-everyday-personal-relationships/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/alcohol1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Britain, drinking alcohol is a common practice among White British women; in 2016, just over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/drugusealcoholandsmoking/datasets/adultdrinkinghabits&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;half of this population&lt;/a&gt; had consumed alcohol in the last week. While most White British women keep their consumption within the recommended safe limits, patterns of heavy drinking associated with long and short term health and social harms have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/14659890802040880?src=recsys&amp;amp;journalCode=ijsu20&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;increased&lt;/a&gt; in the last 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that women &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/alcalc/article/47/3/355/146168&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;consume more alcohol in private&lt;/a&gt; (e.g. their own and others people’s homes) than in public settings (e.g. pubs and bars) and that heavy drinking can occur in couple relationships &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/add.13397&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;as well as non-family relationships&lt;/a&gt; (including friends, neighbours and work colleagues). Increased understanding of the meanings that alcohol has for women could help with developing appropriate and relevant interventions for heavy alcohol use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0629-6?utm_source=BMC_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Blog&amp;amp;utm_content=DavFal-BMC-BMC_Women's_Health-Behavior-Global&amp;amp;utm_campaign=BMCS_USG_SEPT2018_Alcohol_White_British_Women&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Our work&lt;/a&gt; explored one context for women’s alcohol use: in relation to stress. It was conducted in the North East of England where White British women have some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://files.digital.nhs.uk/pdf/s/q/hse2016-summary.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;highest levels of heavy episodic drinking in the country&lt;/a&gt;. We conducted one-to-one qualitative interviews with twenty-six women aged 24-67 years with a range of relationships statuses and from different socio-economic backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the participants were in treatment for alcohol misuse, but their narratives suggested they drank at a range of levels, from irregular consumption to heavy regular consumption. We gathered data on the women’s experiences of stress, drinking practices generally and drinking practices in relation to stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thematic_analysis&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thematic analysis&lt;/a&gt; and the application of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethics_of_care&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Feminist Ethics of Care Theory&lt;/a&gt; helped to identify ‘care practices’ as one key theme in the data. This illustrated that they lacked opportunities for receiving care amongst their caregiving and paid work responsibilities. Overall, the key finding is that alcohol was incorporated in ‘care practices’ as a way of enabling care for self and care with others in their couple relationships, when alone and in non-family relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The findings – alcohol and care practices in different relationships &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some women spent a lot of time alone at home, either because they lived alone, because they were single mothers or because their partners were frequently out. While often reflecting that they would rather be with others, these women described drinking as one way of caring for themselves when no options for human care were available. Penny, who at the time of interview had grown-up children, described a regular drinking practice alone when her children were younger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘(My husband) was out a lot at work, he was having to, you know, he was a Director of a company, . . . You didn’t have very much time for yourself and you probably, I probably did have a glass of wine when I was cooking the tea, because it might well have been that I was on my own more.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10510&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10510 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;201&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/iStock-922786904-300x201.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Drinking at home alone was not acceptable to all women and some said they did not like to drink alcohol when their children were in the house.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;© zinkevych / Getty Images / iStockq&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although they always considered their responsibilities to others first, drinking regularly in a controlled way was acceptable to Penny and some other women. However, drinking at home alone was not acceptable to all women and some said they did not like to drink alcohol when their children were in the house, as this was perceived to be putting themselves above their children. More commonly, women spoke about drinking in their couple relationships and with non-family members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The couple relationship, which can come with greater expectations of care than other relationships, dominated many of the women’s accounts. For some women in the sample, paid work and unpaid caregiving in families meant they had little time to spend with their partner. Jane, a woman with three children aged under 10 years, explained a regular drinking practice with her husband. This example is representative of other participants’ accounts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘. . . it’s a drink just to drink because it’s Friday, do you na what I mean? Just sit with him and spend some adult time with him. . . . Ya na, after having three kids, I’ve learnt . . .  we have to make time for each other.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of women like Jane had little freedom to leave the house with their partners, due to child care responsibilities and limited finances, so they were restricted in what they could do to demonstrate care for each other. Drinking together and spending time together at home was one way they did this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other participants who had more flexibility or financial resources to drink outside the home described practices of drinking in public settings (sometimes alongside other activities such as a meal) in a similar way. Drinking together played a role in helping to maintain the women’s relationships but could contribute to sometimes regular and sometimes irregular heavy drinking practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data highlighted that non-family relationships can also be an important source of care for women. Drinking in these relationships offered opportunities for care, in particular emotional support, which was sometimes absent or limited in their couple and other family relationships. Nina was a single professional woman who lived alone who said she preferred not to drink alone at home. She described the value of a regular Friday night heavy drinking practice with her friends in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘If I’ve had a really, really bad week, by Thursday I’ll be . . . at the end of my tether, and I’ll know that on Friday . . . I know there’s a group of people who will just listen to me go, how crap my week has been . . . ’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10500&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10500 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/alcohol3-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Other participants described practices of drinking in public settings (sometimes alongside other activities such as a meal)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina gained care in this practice that she did not gain anywhere else. Her account resembled some of the accounts of the mothers of dependent children who described the value of drinking practices with friends for providing care that was limited in their family and sometimes paid work roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data also suggested that the women modified their drinking practices to fit in with their own and each other’s family roles and responsibilities. One participant spoke about drinking regularly and heavily at her friend’s house because her friend was a single mother and could not drink out of the house. Overall the data demonstrated the importance of sometimes heavy drinking with non-family for providing opportunities for care in their everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does this mean for intervention development? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small study which may not be able to be extrapolated to a wide population. However, inferences can be made from the findings about approaches to intervention development. The key implication of the study is that interventions need to consider that both women’s own need for care and their responsibilities to others are important in their drinking practices. Addressing this lack of care by providing alternative ways for women to care for themselves and to gain social support might be valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These approaches are at odds with the current approaches which are often based on individual behaviour change and see alcohol use as separate from women’s wider everyday lives and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/10/alcohol-part-care-practices-white-british-womens-everyday-personal-relationships/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Alcohol as part of ‘care practices’ in White British women’s everyday personal relationships&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 08:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/alcohol1-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Abderrahmane Kaidi leaves Bristol after misconduct findings</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=27567</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/10/abderrahmane-kaidi-leaves-bristol-after-misconduct-findings/</link>
	<description>University of Bristol mysteriously lost its senior lecturer, Abderrahmane Kaidi. His institutional website was wiped out in August 2018. I obtained an internal email which lifts the mystery: Kaidi was namely found guilty of &quot;having fabricated research data&quot;, and resigned with &quot;immediate effect&quot;. Affected by research misconduct are also publications from Kaidi's postdoc period with Stephen Jackson in Cambridge.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 05:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Wildfires make their own weather, and that matters for fire management</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wildfires-make-their-own-weather-and-matters-fire-management</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wildfires-make-their-own-weather-and-matters-fire-management</link>
	<description>Mathematical equations describing interactions between wildfires and the air around them help explain their power and destruction.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/082718_LH_fire-prediction_feat.jpg?itok=OUQHItGB" length="24148" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: An article on a controversial topic just disappears; mass resignations from a nutrition journal; the likely mistaken history of the vibrator</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71067</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/08/weekend-reads-an-article-on-a-controversial-topic-just-disappears-mass-resignations-from-a-nutrition-journal-the-likely-mistaken-history-of-the-vibrator/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. This week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of happiness, an apology from a journal, and … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/08/weekend-reads-an-article-on-a-controversial-topic-just-disappears-mass-resignations-from-a-nutrition-journal-the-likely-mistaken-history-of-the-vibrator/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: An article on a controversial topic just disappears; mass resignations from a nutrition journal; the likely mistaken history of the vibrator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 13:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open and Shut?: Paywall: The Business of Scholarship  —  a review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882.post-646109238818414069</guid>
	<link>https://poynder.blogspot.com/2018/09/paywall-business-of-scholarship-review.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;My review of &lt;i&gt;Paywall: The Business of Scholarship&lt;/i&gt; has been published in &lt;i&gt;Nature&lt;/i&gt;. Below are the first two paragraphs. The full review can be read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06140-7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Billed as a documentary, &lt;i&gt;Paywall&lt;/i&gt; would be more accurately described as an advocacy film. Its intention seems to be to persuade viewers that the paywalls that restrict access to journal content online are an unnecessary hangover from the print era, and now serve only to perpetuate the excessive profits that legacy publishers such as Elsevier, Wiley and Springer Nature make from the public purse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The film makes a convincing case that the paywall system creates problems — and that universal open access (OA) to scholarly articles would be better for society. But it fails to adequately explore the thorny challenges that arise with OA publishing. These include the fact that the publishers castigated by the film would continue to dominate scholarly communication in an OA world; the increasingly expensive ‘pay-to-publish’ model, which substitutes inequities in access for inequities in affording publication; and the rise of predatory publishing. And although &lt;i&gt;Paywall&lt;/i&gt; acknowledges that current reward systems have slowed the progress of OA publishing, it does not address the puzzling question of why academics have proved so reluctant to make copies of their published papers freely available in their institutional repositories ...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;More &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06140-7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 07:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Richard Poynder)</author>
  <source url="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/7961882/posts/default">Open and Shut?</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Before it burned, Brazil’s National Museum gave much to science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brazil-national-museum-collections-scientific-contributions</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brazil-national-museum-collections-scientific-contributions</link>
	<description>When Brazil’s National Museum went up in flames, so did the hard work of the researchers who work there.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 21:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090718_HT_museum_feat.jpg?itok=lhi0Qb5e" length="56165" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A massive net is being deployed to pick up plastic in the Pacific</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/massive-net-being-deployed-pick-plastic-pacific</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/massive-net-being-deployed-pick-plastic-pacific</link>
	<description>As the Ocean Cleanup project embarks, critics remain unconvinced that scooping up debris is the best way to solve the ocean’s plastic problem.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 21:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090618_CG_ocean-cleanup_feat.jpg?itok=NJ1qXAKb" length="23051" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Webinar: RNA Silencing With Self-Delivering FANA Oligonucleotides</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1750</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/09/webinar-rna-silencing-with-self-delivering-fana-oligonucleotides/</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1750&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2991300 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2991300&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26cab16 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26cab16&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-9ff5ae9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;9ff5ae9&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; October 9, 2018&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 9am PDT/12pm EDT/4pm UTC&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Format:&lt;/strong&gt; 30 minutes with 10 minutes live Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;RNA silencing is widely used for elucidating gene function; however, challenges include delivery into cells and knockdown efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this webinar, Veenu Aishwarya from AUM Biotech will present next-generation self-delivering FANA Antisense Oligonucleotide (FANA-ASO) technology, offering alternatives to siRNA, shRNA, and CRISPR approaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-8de8516 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;8de8516&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-f389597 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;f389597&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-731bbc2 elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button&quot; data-element_type=&quot;button.default&quot; data-id=&quot;731bbc2&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-button-wrapper&quot;&gt;
			&lt;a class=&quot;elementor-button-link elementor-button elementor-size-lg&quot; href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/AUMBiotechwebinar&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-content-wrapper&quot;&gt;
						&lt;span class=&quot;elementor-button-text&quot;&gt;REGISTER NOW&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/a&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
				&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2f0bd775 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;2f0bd775&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-26df1849 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;26df1849&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-7dffee7a elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;7dffee7a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;You will learn:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Advantages of self-deliverable RNA silencing agents&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Comparing knockdown using FANA-ASO vs RNAi&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How to apply FANA-ASO technology to both in vivo and in vitro models&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tips on working with difficult-to-transfect cells, including primary cells&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Who should attend:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Researchers involved in drug discovery and target validation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Researchers using RNA silencing and/or gene editing approaches like CRISPR (along with transfection reagents)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Researchers working in functional genomics and high throughput screening&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Researchers conducting basic, translational and preclinical research&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.scienceexchange.com/AUMBiotechwebinar#speakers&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;About the Speaker&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A study of an “abortion reversal” method has been republished — but its mystery deepens</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=71050</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/07/a-study-of-an-abortion-reversal-method-has-been-republished-but-its-mystery-deepens/</link>
	<description>A study that claimed a highly controversial “abortion reversal” method was effective — and which was temporarily removed from a journal’s site — has been republished. While there are some wording changes in the new version, they don’t seem to clarify much about what happened before and during the study. The study, as we noted … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/07/a-study-of-an-abortion-reversal-method-has-been-republished-but-its-mystery-deepens/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A study of an “abortion reversal” method has been republished — but its mystery deepens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These songbirds violently fling and then impale their prey</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/loggerhead-shrikes-songbirds-fling-impale-prey</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/loggerhead-shrikes-songbirds-fling-impale-prey</link>
	<description>A loggerhead shrike that skewers small animals on barbed wire gives mice whiplash shakeups.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090618_SM_sadistic-songbirds_feat.jpg?itok=ly1MNLwF" length="12935" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: The first study to explore what cisgender kids think of their transgender peers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34688</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/07/the-first-study-to-explore-what-cisgender-kids-think-of-their-transgender-peers/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34700&quot; style=&quot;width: 2139px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-831551486.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34700&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34700&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette illustration of elementary school students standing in front of a school playground&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;After School Playground&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;After School Playground&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-831551486.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-831551486.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-831551486.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2139,1402&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/07/the-first-study-to-explore-what-cisgender-kids-think-of-their-transgender-peers/after-school-playground/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-831551486.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Cisgender kids who categorised their transgender peers by natal sex also showed less liking of them, mirroring similar findings with adults&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an increasing number of young children transitioning socially to the gender opposite to their birth sex, and with rates of bullying and discrimination against transgender youth known to be high, researchers say it is important that we begin to understand more about how cisgender children (those whose gender identity matches their biological sex at birth) view their transgender peers. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15248372.2018.1498338&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition and Development&lt;/em&gt; is the first to explore the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34688&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across two studies, a team led by Selin Gülgöz at the University of Washington in Seattle, presented dozens of cisgender five to ten-year-olds with vignettes about hypothetical peers who were either cisgender or transgender. For instance, in the second study, which used more comprehensive vignettes, one description the children heard was of a baby named Jack who was born with a boy’s body, but who liked playing girl games, wearing girl clothes and who told her parents she was actually a girl and wanted to be called Annie and referred to as “she” and “her”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participating children’s task was to rate how much they liked each child they heard about in the vignettes and to categorise them as either a boy or a girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children generally rated their peers positively, whether cisgender or transgender. However, on average, they rated cisgender peers more positively than transgender peers. Note, though, that the well-known preference that children show for other kids of their own gender also applied, to an extent, to transgender identities – so, for cisgender girls, for instance, their liking for transgender girls (natal boys who had transitioned socially to a female identity) was higher than their liking for cisgender boys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of how they categorised the gender of their transgender peers, the participating children were inconsistent. Some categorised transgender peers by their natal sex (i.e. according to their biological sex at birth); others according to their peers’ transgender identity; while others switched between the two approaches. To the researchers’ surprise, they found that the older children – who they expected to be more accepting of transgender identities – were actually more likely to categorise transgender peers by their natal sex. The researchers speculated that this may be because of the older children’s growing sense of gender as a usually stable concept, rather than as malleable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final important finding was the association between how the cisgender children categorised their transgender peers and their patterns of liking towards those peers – specifically, those who tended to categorise transgender children by natal sex also showed less liking of them, mirroring similar findings with adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new research makes a first contribution toward understanding this topic, but inevitably it has some significant limitations. Apart from the reliance on vignettes, this includes that the transgender children were all presented as being entirely gender stereotypical (i.e. behaving and having interests in line with the stereotypes associated with the gender they had transitioned to) – it remains to be seen how cisgender children might feel toward transgender peers who do not conform to the stereotypes of the gender they have transitioned to, especially considering young children’s tendency to hold peers who do not conform to gender stereotypes in low regard. Also, note these new findings are based on children from a liberal American city, whose parents were happy for them to participate in such research. One can imagine the findings being different in other cultures and contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gülgöz and her colleagues said “We look forward to future work that specifically investigates the relation between cisgender children’s attitudes toward their transgender peers and the well-being of those transgender children, as well as work investigating effective ways to reduce bias against transgender children.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15248372.2018.1498338&quot;&gt;Children’s Evaluation and Categorization of Transgender Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 08:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: What do we know about migraine? Mechanisms, treatment and the future</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10501</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/07/know-migraine-mechanisms-treatment-future/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/Migraine-Brain-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Migraine’s primary symptom is sudden and intense headache usually on one side of the head. The brains of migraineurs are different in both their structure and function. Migraineurs who experience more migraines have more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3795609/pdf/WNL205445.pdf&quot;&gt;structural abnormalities including decreases in grey matter and lesions in white matter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functioning of the migraine brain is also atypical. Changes in the external and internal environments can trigger abnormal electrophysiological and vascular changes throughout the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neurophysiological &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrneurol.2013.192&quot;&gt;explanation for migraines is cortical spreading depression&lt;/a&gt;. During cortical spreading depression, the electrical activity of neurons in a certain brain area is silenced. Once a certain threshold of depression occurs, this silencing spreads throughout the brain like a ripple in a pond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cortical spreading depression often begins in sensory associated brain areas such as those involved in vision. The origin in visual areas could explain the migraine aura, afflicting a third of migraineurs, which manifest as flickering lights or scintillating spots in the visual field preceding the onset of the headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10504 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/Migraine-300x200.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Vasodilation, the dilation of blood vessels, in the brain appears to be another cause for migraines. The trigeminal nerve which is found at the bottom of brain is important for sensation in the face and motor functions such as biting and chewing. Upon the onset of headache in migraines, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3274576/&quot;&gt;trigeminal nerve will release a chemical called calcitonin gene-related peptide&lt;/a&gt; (CGRP). CGRP will relax the blood vessel walls causing vasodilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the treatments?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding effective treatments for migraine has been a challenge. Fifteen years ago, &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.2165/11537990-000000000-00000&quot;&gt;triptans&lt;/a&gt; represented an important step toward migraine attack resolution and symptomatic treatment. Triptans are drugs which bind to and activate specific serotonin receptors called 5-HT&lt;sub&gt;1B&lt;/sub&gt; and 5-HT&lt;sub&gt;1D&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;Activating these receptors with triptans can have multiple effects. Triptans can impact trigeminal nerves involved in pain by decreasing the release of CGRP and substance P, a chemical known for its pain producing properties. Triptans can also modulate the activity of certain brain areas and induce vasoconstriction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five years ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://bpspubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/bph.12763&quot;&gt;botulin toxin&lt;/a&gt;, also known as BoTox®, was introduced as the first treatment for chronic migraine. BoTox® is usually thought of as a substance used for cosmetic surgery, but there is also evidence for its clinical potential. Botulin toxin may help headaches through multiple mechanisms. One mechanism describes how upon injection botulin toxin is taken up by cranial nerves in the face and travels up the trigeminal nerve into the central nervous system. Botulin toxin then reduces inflammation and inhibits the release of CGRP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five years ago &lt;a href=&quot;https://bpspubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/bph.12763&quot;&gt;botulin toxin&lt;/a&gt;, also known as BoTox®, was introduced as the first treatment for chronic migraine. BoTox® is usually thought of as a substance used for cosmetic surgery, but there is also evidence for its clinical potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next milestone in migraine treatment arrived with the approval of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5486583/pdf/11940_2017_Article_463.pdf&quot;&gt;CGRP monoclonal antibody therapy&lt;/a&gt;. Monoclonal antibody therapy involves the creation of antibodies that bind to a specific protein, in this case CGRP, or its receptor. When antibodies bind to these proteins or receptors it inactivates them. By inactivating CGRP, vasodilation caused by this molecule can be prevented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promising non-pharmacological therapeutic options are currently being assessed, but need to be validated. Noninvasive neurostimulation techniques, such as noninvasive vagal nerve stimulation, have shown potential in resolving migraine attack. Noninvasive vagal nerve stimulation involves the stimulation of the vagal nerve via a device that is placed on the skin of your neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other non-pharmacological approaches, such as physical exercise or acupuncture, has demonstrated efficacy in small groups of patients and are worthy of further development through controlled trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a continual search for the various structural and functional abnormalities in the brain which generate such incredibly painful and debilitating events. Our knowledge on pathophysiology and therapeutic strategies is increasing over time, but the challenge of present and future studies is the improvement of migraine management to avoid the evolution toward a chronic form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in reading more? Be sure to check out the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcneurol.biomedcentral.com/articles&quot;&gt;articles in &lt;em&gt;BMC Neurology.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/07/know-migraine-mechanisms-treatment-future/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What do we know about migraine? Mechanisms, treatment and the future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 08:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/09/Migraine-Brain-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Jocelyn Bell Burnell wins big physics prize for 1967 pulsar discovery</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jocelyn-bell-burnell-physics-prize-pulsar-discovery-interview</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jocelyn-bell-burnell-physics-prize-pulsar-discovery-interview</link>
	<description>Astrophysicist Jocelyn Bell Burnell speaks about winning the Breakthrough Prize, impostor syndrome and giving back</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090618_LG_jocelyn-bell_feat.jpg?itok=aBFTI6XP" length="13004" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How plant microbes could feed the world and save endangered species</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-microbes-crops-food-endangered-species</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-microbes-crops-food-endangered-species</link>
	<description>Scientists have only scratched the surface of the plant microbiome, but they already believe it might increase crop yield and save species from extinction.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/091518_AD_plant-microbiome_feat.jpg?itok=S0y-x8Ey" length="57660" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Saturn has two hexagons, not one, swirling around its north pole</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-has-two-hexagons-not-one-swirling-around-its-north-pole</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-has-two-hexagons-not-one-swirling-around-its-north-pole</link>
	<description>NASA’s Cassini spacecraft spied a vortex growing high over Saturn’s north pole, whose hexagonal shape mirrors a famous underlying cyclone.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090518_CC_saturn-vortex_feat.jpg?itok=x6RJ58Wg" length="14350" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When it comes to retracting papers by the world’s most prolific scientific fraudsters, journals have room for improvement</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=70954</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/06/when-it-comes-to-retracting-papers-by-the-worlds-most-prolific-scientific-fraudsters-journals-have-room-for-improvement/</link>
	<description>Journals have retracted all but 19 of the 313 tainted papers linked to three of the most notorious fraudsters in science, with only stragglers left in the literature. But editors and publishers have been less diligent when it comes to delivering optimal retraction notices for the affected articles. That’s the verdict of a new analysis … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/06/when-it-comes-to-retracting-papers-by-the-worlds-most-prolific-scientific-fraudsters-journals-have-room-for-improvement/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;When it comes to retracting papers by the world’s most prolific scientific fraudsters, journals have room for improvement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, a pessimistic view for heart transplants</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-pessimistic-view-heart-transplants</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-pessimistic-view-heart-transplants</link>
	<description>Surgeon Christiaan Barnard performed the first successful human-to-human heart transplant in 1967. In 1968, he predicted that patients would survive five years at best. Fortunately, he was wrong.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/08/main/articles/081518_BB_50ya-heart-transplants_feat.jpg?itok=kYAp2acr" length="21108" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers’ interest piqued by Parker Solar Probe, general relativity and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-interest-piqued-parker-solar-probe-general-relativity-and-more</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-interest-piqued-parker-solar-probe-general-relativity-and-more</link>
	<description>Readers had questions about NASA's Parker Solar Probe, Einstein's general relativity theory and underwater cables used as earthquake sensors.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: To boldly go where no robot explorer has gone before</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/boldly-go-where-no-robot-explorer-has-gone</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/boldly-go-where-no-robot-explorer-has-gone</link>
	<description>Editor in Chief Nancy Shute discusses the importance of robotic space missions for scientific research.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Using a biological framework to resolve the early stages of linguistic divergence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10464</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/06/using-biological-framework-resolve-early-stages-linguistic-divergence/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/man-2814937_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first glance, language and evolution seem to have very few things in common. Closer inspection shows, however, that the three parts that form the core of evolution–variation, heritability and change-causing forces (e.g. selection)–are also found in language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarities between linguistic and biological evolution, already noticed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/cache/epub/2300/pg2300-images.html&quot;&gt;Darwin&lt;/a&gt; and elaborated on by a number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrg2560&quot;&gt;scholars&lt;/a&gt; since then, have enabled the plausible usage of modern methods of evolutionary biology to analyze language data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarities between linguistic and biological evolution, have enabled the plausible usage of modern methods of evolutionary biology to analyze language data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of this work has focused on constructing phylogenies of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://muse.jhu.edu/article/576998&quot;&gt;Indo-European&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/323/5913/479&quot;&gt;Austronesian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://benjamins.com/catalog/dia.30.3.02syr&quot;&gt;Uralic&lt;/a&gt; language families. These phylogenies in turn are used to study the taxonomy or the dispersal histories of these groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these studies, languages are paralleled with species. Due to the hierarchical nature of both entities, it is also possible to parallel the substructures–i.e dialects and populations–with each other and apply population genetic methods to dialect data. The applicability of these methods on dialect data has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://booksandjournals.brillonline.com/content/journals/10.1163/22105832-00602002&quot;&gt;shown in the earlier work&lt;/a&gt; of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bedlan.net&quot;&gt;research group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our current work, we have combined biology and linguistics one step further. Instead of only adopting methods from population genetics, we have also utilized certain elements of the biological microevolutionary framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aimed to advance the present understanding of linguistic divergence, a process which has had an important role in the emergence of the over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethnologue.com/&quot;&gt;7000 languages&lt;/a&gt; that exist in the world today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In biology, species divergence can be investigated at the early phases of the divergence process, which involves the separation of populations within a species. In our current study we examined linguistic divergence by focusing on the initial phase of the process: the divergence of dialects within a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In biology, species divergence can be investigated at the early phases of the divergence process, which involves the separation of populations within a species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took hypotheses from both biological and linguistic literature. Firstly, we studied the role of geographical distance, as it contributes to the divergence of both populations and dialects. In general, the further away the groups are from each other, the less balancing dispersal there is between them, and the more different they turn out to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we adopted the biological hypothesis of &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/evo.12258&quot;&gt;isolation by environment&lt;/a&gt; to investigated whether mere differences in environmental conditions can isolate groups of speakers and have a role in the divergence of dialects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we considered whether linguistic differences can be explained by cultural differences. Culture and specifically its cumulativeness is a special feature of the human species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100 years of linguistic variations in Finland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We studied the divergence of dialects of the Finnish language. We used a dataset describing the linguistic variation of Finnish approximately one hundred years ago (Fig 1). The data is from a time when the differences between dialects were still very clear, as urbanization took place in Finland relatively late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10465&quot; style=&quot;width: 213px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10465&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/Kettunen_mapsheet-203x300.png&quot; width=&quot;203&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;An example page of the Dialect Atlas of Finnish &lt;a href=&quot;http://kettunen.fnhost.org/?i=1&quot;&gt;(Kettunen 1940)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we were interested in differences between dialect groups, we used a population genetic clustering method to infer those groups. To achieve this, we organised the linguistic data in a similar way to genetic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In biology, the individual is the unit of study, and within them, alleles of certain loci are the topic of interest. In the dialect data, we were interested in the local variants of certain linguistic features within a local administrative unit (i.e. municipality). Thus, we paralleled individuals with municipalities, loci with linguistic features, and alleles with local variants of these linguistic features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Finland, there also exists old records of the spatial distribution of various cultural and environmental features. Comparatively, Finland is an environmentally and culturally homogenous country, and hence we were able to study whether small differences in the environmental and cultural conditions may already be connected with linguistic divergence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To our surprise, we found that geographical distance explained the least of the linguistic differences between the dialect groups. In other words, dialects spoken geographically close to each other may remain linguistically very different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While cultural differences explained the majority of the linguistic differences, environmental differences also explained more than just geographical distance. The extent of the roles played by both environment and culture is a remarkable finding, as it suggests that human cultural adaptation may have had a role in the divergence of the Finnish dialects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We formulated a hypothesis that  human’s capability for cultural adaptation in response to different environmental conditions may contribute to the divergence of dialects. While more research on this subject is needed, our study introduces interesting new perspectives on how global linguistic diversity could have taken shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/09/06/using-biological-framework-resolve-early-stages-linguistic-divergence/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Using a biological framework to resolve the early stages of linguistic divergence&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 09:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/08/man-2814937_1920-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Can hallucinations lead to post-traumatic growth?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34694</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/06/can-hallucinations-lead-to-post-traumatic-growth/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-586368522.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34695&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34695&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Blank white speech bubble with copy space for your text inside a human head silhouette in a conceptual illustration on a green background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sirup&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Speech bubble inside a human head inner speech&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Speech bubble inside a human head inner speech&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-586368522.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-586368522.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-586368522.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/06/can-hallucinations-lead-to-post-traumatic-growth/speech-bubble-inside-a-human-head-inner-speech/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-586368522.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you contemplate how a person’s life would be changed by starting to hear or see things others can’t, can you imagine it could offer anything good? A research team from Hull university and the surrounding NHS trusts suggest that among the tumult, hallucinations can also offer opportunities for growth. Writing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omicsonline.org/open-access/a-weird-but-interesting-journey-personal-traumatic-growth-for-individuals-with-hallucinations-2161-0487-1000343-102910.html&quot;&gt;in the Journal of Psychology and Psychotherapy&lt;/a&gt;, lead author Lily Dixon and her team detail the experiences of seven people who have lived with verbal or auditory hallucinations and how, amid the struggles, their journeys have taken them to some positive places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34694&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five men and two women, aged 28 to 53, were recruited from mental health services. Some had begun experiencing hallucinations in childhood, others later in life. The researchers interviewed them about how the experience had affected them and their relationships, the challenges they had faced, and what they expected from the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interviewees were united in seeing the arrival of their hallucinations as an unwelcome shock. They were something to be hidden so as to avoid stigma. “I don’t want to accept it’s schizophrenia because it will always be branded, I’ll always be branded with that name, and if you tell anyone you’ve got schizophrenia they automatically think that you’re a mental case and that you’re going to kill them,” said one interviewee. Some felt that to remain themselves, the experience needed rejecting – “I’m trying to separate the person, I like the person that I am when I’m not hearing voices.” A commonly held early belief was that getting better meant reducing or eliminating the hallucinations. Blur out the visions, silence the voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, over time, the interviewees found their focus had shifted. “Steve” (real names are not used in the paper) reported an event that stuck in his head: “I remember being at my best friend’s house and she said ‘well why don’t you just talk to them’ y’know the voices, rather than sitting around or arguing, so I did and I spoke to them so I went ‘hello’ and they go ‘oh hello you finally talking to us’ and I was like what?!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making that step from denial and conflict to engagement had consequences for Steve, who felt that “they’re more helpful now than disturbing… it’s like I’ve got a lot of friends I talk to every day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others echoed this idea that when the hallucinatory experiences were faced, rather than fended off, the possibility of value could emerge. So much so that the prospect of shedding them no longer felt like a cure. “A lot of people say what if I could change things but I’m not sure I would, y’know, if, I’ve just learnt to accept that it’s part of me now,” said one interviewee. Another said that without his hallucinations, he would feel “hollow”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly what good could come from hallucinations? The answers were hard to pin down, as no interviewee felt they were an unalloyed good, and did not want to tempt fate through naive optimism. One note was the self-fortification that comes from continuous battle – “Debbie” said tentatively “I haven’t let it beat me… it’s made me more tougher… the voice has given me more strength, and it’s it’s sort of like, made me into the person I am, stronger.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another positive thread was that the hallucinations brokered a change in perspective towards others, and even toward experience itself. “I show more empathy maybe, more than I used to” said one interviewee, while another described how “it’s changed the way I see others, think about other attitudes and the way I’ve seen myself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Paul’s” particularly self-scrutinising comment gives a more expansive take: “I think I’d have been a lot more destructive rather than constructive if I maybe wasn’t hearing or seeing things… I think it’s changed my outlook on, on certain things, y’know, of just sometimes learning to sit and watch the world go by, rather than, trying to beat the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What facilitated this apparent journey from dismay to bittersweet growth? The reports suggested that belonging and acceptance had been critical, especially emotional support, simply to have had “somebody listening”. But the journey sometimes also required movement against prevailing winds: one interviewee counselled “don’t give up on wanting to become yourself, rather than your society or whatever, forget all of them forget everything else, you’ve got to be comfortable with yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of the services available was also crucial: clinicians offering alarm and stigma were seen as a common obstacle. The support that seemed most useful was based on the introduction of techniques like mindfulness and relaxation, and engagement with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hearing-voices.org/&quot;&gt;Hearing Voices network&lt;/a&gt;, as this showed that “you’re not on your own”. This normalisation and engagement meant that having an atypical experience of reality no longer sundered the interviewees from society, but offered a different role where that experience had a part to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a simple story. Participants continued to see their hallucinations as something that hindered, only now tempered by the possibility to enrich. Dixon’s team recommend that professionals, friends and family who are close to people having such experiences, and particularly clinicians, should avoid stigmatisation and support them wherever they are at, understanding that a complex relationship with reality does not make the person any less whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omicsonline.org/open-access/a-weird-but-interesting-journey-personal-traumatic-growth-for-individuals-with-hallucinations-2161-0487-1000343-102910.html&quot;&gt;A Weird but Interesting Journey: Personal Traumatic Growth for Individuals with Hallucinations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 07:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Fake data, untouchable men and guilty women at ICR London</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=27233</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/06/fake-data-untouchable-men-and-guilty-women-at-icr-london/</link>
	<description>With nobody above him, ICR director Paul Workman was seemingly investigating himself, and found two female colleagues guilty of placing fake data into his papers, primarily the ICR emeritus Ann Jackman. One paper was retracted, another received an outrageous correction. The previous ICR CEO, Alan Ashworth, together with his right-hand man Chris Lord, have their own impressive, but hitherto ignored, record on PubPeer.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: German skeletons hint that medieval warrior groups recruited from afar</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/german-skeletons-hint-medieval-warrior-groups-recruited-afar</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/german-skeletons-hint-medieval-warrior-groups-recruited-afar</link>
	<description>Graveyard finds may come from an ancient European warrior household with political pull.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090318_bb_warrior_feat.jpg?itok=RTk5KpUZ" length="60999" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Jupiter’s magnetic field is surprisingly weird</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-magnetic-field-surprisingly-weird</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-magnetic-field-surprisingly-weird</link>
	<description>New results from NASA’s Juno spacecraft reveal different magnetic behavior in the planet’s northern and southern hemispheres.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090518_CC_jupiter_feat.jpg?itok=Xiv_H_J6" length="17252" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Rubidium atoms mimic the Eiffel Tower, a Möbius strip and other 3-D shapes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rubidium-atoms-mimic-eiffel-tower-mobius-strip-and-other-3-d-shapes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rubidium-atoms-mimic-eiffel-tower-mobius-strip-and-other-3-d-shapes</link>
	<description>Scientists have arranged atoms of the element rubidium into complex three-dimensional structures.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090318_ec_atom-arrangment_feat.jpg?itok=pnuvm19-" length="11673" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: It’s official: They’ve retracted happiness.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=70880</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/05/its-official-theyve-retracted-happiness/</link>
	<description>They is MDPI Proceedings, which has pulled a 2017 paper, “Role of Happiness as a Habitual Process.” The reason: The paper was not ready for final publication and was put online in error. The paper will be marked as retracted. We apologize to the author and readers for any inconvenience. The author, Pujarini Das, is a … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/05/its-official-theyve-retracted-happiness/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;It’s official: They’ve retracted happiness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: What is computational neuroscience? (XXXIII) The interactivist model of cognition</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1530</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxxiii-the-interactivist-model-of-cognition/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The interactivist model of cognition has been developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lehigh.edu/~mhb0/mhb0.html&quot;&gt;Mark Bickhard&lt;/a&gt; over the last 40 years or so. It is related to the viewpoints of Gibson and O’Regan, among others. The model is described in a book (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lehigh.edu/~mhb0/AIFull.pdf&quot;&gt;Bickhard and Tervenn, 1996&lt;/a&gt;) and a more recent review (&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11229-008-9375-x&quot;&gt;Bickhard 2008&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with a criticism of what Bickhard calls “encodingism”, the idea that mental representations are constituted by encodings, correspondences between things in the world and symbols (this is very similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/07/13/168237&quot;&gt;my criticism of the neural coding metaphor&lt;/a&gt;, except Bickhard’s angle is cognitive science while mine was neuroscience). The basic argument is that the encoding “crosses the boundary of the epistemic agent”: the perceptual system stands on only one side of the correspondence, so there is no way it can interpret symbols in terms of things in the world since it never has access to things in the world at any point. The interpretation of the symbols in terms of things in the world would require an interpreter, some entity that makes sense of &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; arbitrary symbols. But this was precisely the epistemic problem to be solved, so the interpreter is a homunculus and this is an incoherent view. This is related to the skeptic argument about knowledge: there cannot be valid knowledge since we acquire knowledge by our senses and we cannot step outside of ourselves to check that it is valid. Encodingism fails the skeptic objection. Note that Bickhard refutes neither the possibility of representations nor even the possibility of encodings, but rather the fact that encodings can be foundational of representations. There can be derivative encodings, based on existing representations (for example Morse is a derivative encoding, which presupposes that we know about both letters and dots and dashes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key feature that a representational system must have is what Bickhard calls “system-detectable errors”. A representational system must be able to test whether its representations are correct or not. This is not possible in encodingism because the system does not have access to what is being represented (knowledge that cannot be checked is what I called “metaphysical knowledge” in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;Subjective physics&lt;/a&gt; paper). No learning is possible if there are no system-detectable errors. This is the problem of normativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactivist model proposes the following solution: representations are anticipations of potential interactions and their expected impact on future states of the systems, or on the future course of processes of the system (this is close to Gibson’s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affordance&quot;&gt;affordances&lt;/a&gt;”). I give an example taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;Subjective physics&lt;/a&gt;. Consider a sound source located somewhere in space. What does it mean to know where the sound came from? In the encoding view, we would say that the system has a mapping between the angle of the source and properties of the sounds, and so it infers the source’s angle from the captured sounds. But what can this mean? Is the inferred angle in radians or degrees? Surely radians and degrees cannot make sense for the perceiver and cannot have been learned (this is what I called “metaphysical knowledge”), so in fact the representation cannot actually be in the form of the physical angle of the source. Rather, what it means that the source is at a given position is that (for example) you would expect that moving your eyes in a particular way would make the source appear in your fovea (see more detail about the Euclidean structure of space and related topics in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;Subjective physics&lt;/a&gt;). Thus, the notion of space is a representation of the expected consequences of certain types of actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactivist model of representations has the desirable property that it has system-detectable errors: a representation can be correct or not, depending on whether the anticipation turns out to be correct or not. Importantly, what is anticipated is internal states, and therefore the representation does not cross the boundary of the epistemic agent. Contrary to standard models of representation, the interactivist model successfully addresses the skeptic argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactivist model is described at a rather abstract level, often referring to abstract machine theory (states of automata). Thus, it leaves aside the problem of its naturalization: how is it instantiated by the brain? Important questions to address are: what is a ‘state’ of the brain? (in particular given that the brain is a continuously active dynamical system where no “end state” can be identified); how do we cope with its distributed nature, that is, that the epistemic agent is itself constituted of a web of interacting elementary epistemic agents? how are representations built and instantiated?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 10:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Teens born from assisted pregnancies may have higher blood pressure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teens-born-assisted-pregnancies-may-have-higher-blood-pressure</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teens-born-assisted-pregnancies-may-have-higher-blood-pressure</link>
	<description>Kids born from reproductive technologies such as in vitro fertilization are susceptible to high blood pressure as adolescents, a small study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/articles/090318_ac_heart-invitro_feat_free.jpg?itok=LsH13f6e" length="37750" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Do you have this crucial skill needed to succeed in engineering?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/do-you-have-this-crucial-skill-needed-to-succeed-in-engineering</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/do-you-have-this-crucial-skill-needed-to-succeed-in-engineering</link>
	<description>Contest challenges students to solve real-world engineering problems while using Knovel and Engineering Village</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 08:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Super altruists (who’ve donated a kidney to a stranger) show heightened empathic brain activity when witnessing strangers in pain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34660</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/05/super-altruists-whove-donated-a-kidney-to-a-stranger-show-heightened-empathic-brain-activity-when-witnessing-strangers-in-pain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-160194832.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34680&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34680&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D3S&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;surgeon with his fresh delivery&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1357982754&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sturti&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Surgeon with organ donation&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Surgeon with organ donation&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-160194832.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-160194832.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-160194832.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2156,1391&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/05/super-altruists-whove-donated-a-kidney-to-a-stranger-show-heightened-empathic-brain-activity-when-witnessing-strangers-in-pain/surgeon-with-organ-donation/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-160194832.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an evolutionary perspective, altruistic behaviour is still a bit of mystery to psychologists, especially when it comes with a hefty cost to the self and is aimed at complete strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One explanation is that altruism is driven by empathy – experiencing other people’s distress the same way as, or similar to, how we experience our own. However, others have criticized this account – most notably psychologist Paul Bloom, author of &lt;em&gt;Against Empathy: The Case for Rational Compassion&lt;/em&gt;. Their reasons are many, but among them is the fact that our empathy tends to be greatest for people who are most similar to us, which would argue against empathy driving the kind of altruism that involves the giver making personal sacrifices for strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hindering research into this topic is the challenge of measuring empathy objectively and devising a reliable laboratory measure of altruism (including one that overcomes most volunteers’ natural inclination to want to present themselves as morally good).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/eprint/zW2hJbfmcxUEc6Isa4iN/full&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt; overcomes these obstacles by using a neural measure of empathy and by testing a rare group of people whose altruistic credentials are second to none: individuals who have donated one of their kidneys to a complete stranger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34660&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings suggest that – at least for this group of “extraordinary altruists” – empathy for others may be a relevant driving force. Compared with demographically matched controls, the altruists showed a greater amount of overlap in the neural activity they exhibited during their first-hand experience of pain and when observing a stranger in pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US research team, led by Kristen Brethel-Haurwitz at the University of Pennsylvania, invited the 25 kidney donors and the 27 controls to their lab and had them complete various sessions in the brain scanner, during which they either experienced painful pressure applied to their own thumb, or they witnessed a live video feed of a previously unfamiliar study partner (actually a research confederate) suffering the same pain. For comparison, some sessions for both the participant and their partner were completely safe and pain-free, allowing the researchers to investigate brain activity during experienced pain, the anticipation of possible pain, and during safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a group level, the altruists exhibited greater neural overlap while experiencing pain and while witnessing a stranger in pain, including in the left anterior insular, putamen, thalamus, prefrontal cortex and cingulate cortex (all known areas of the brain’s “pain matrix”). The altruists also showed greater neural overlap when anticipating pain themselves and when anticipating that their partner would experience it. These group contrasts are despite the altruists and controls showing comparable average patterns of neural activation when experiencing pain, or the threat of it, themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At an individual level, for the altruists but not the controls, the neural activation they showed in the left anterior insular while in pain correlated with the amount of activation they showed in that same region when observing their partner in pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the researchers also looked at neural connectivity patterns, finding that the altruists displayed greater functional connectivity between pain-related neural regions during first-hand pain and when observing another in pain, as compared with the controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The psychological relevance of the neural findings were supported by the fact the altruists expressed a greater sense of inclusion of their partner in their sense of self (than did the controls), and this sense of closeness appeared to mediate at least some of the neural overlap they exhibited between first-hand and empathic pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the neural data, the “inclusion in self” scores, and the super-altruists’ history of organ donation, the controls rated themselves just as empathic as did the super altruistic kidney donors, which surely places a question mark over the validity of much of the existing literature in this field that has relied on such self-rating measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers acknowledged that their findings may not generalise to less exceptionally altruistic people. However, they believe their work demonstrates an important point that will inform the debate about the role of empathy in altruism. “That altruists, relative to controls, exhibit enhanced self-other mapping for strangers’ distress – ordinarily observed only in response to close others – supports the hypothesis that empathic biases against distant or dissimilar others can be overcome,” they said, “and that, ultimately, empathy can support the provision of costly altruism.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/eprint/zW2hJbfmcxUEc6Isa4iN/full&quot;&gt;Extraordinary Altruists Exhibit Enhanced Self–Other Overlap in Neural Responses to Distress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 08:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Cancer journals retract 10 papers, flag 8 more, and apologize for the delay</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=70872</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/04/cancer-journals-retract-10-papers-flag-8-more-and-apologize-for-the-delay/</link>
	<description>Five journals published by a prominent cancer research society have retracted a total of 10 papers — most of them by a former researcher at the MD Anderson Cancer Center in Houston. Nine of the 10 retractions share that researcher, Bharat Aggarwal, as an author. Aggarwal — who more than five years ago threatened to sue … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/04/cancer-journals-retract-10-papers-flag-8-more-and-apologize-for-the-delay/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Cancer journals retract 10 papers, flag 8 more, and apologize for the delay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A gentoo penguin’s dinner knows how to fight back</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/gentoo-penguin-dinner-knows-how-fight-back</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/gentoo-penguin-dinner-knows-how-fight-back</link>
	<description>Cameras attached to gentoo penguins off the Falkland Islands revealed that, despite the birds’ small size, their lobster krill prey can sometimes win in a fight.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/09/main/blogposts/083118_sz_wt-penguins_feat.jpg?itok=95JfFuLs" length="57172" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘Accessory to War’ probes the uneasy alliance between space science and the military</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/accessory-to-war-space-science-military-neil-degrasse-tyson</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/accessory-to-war-space-science-military-neil-degrasse-tyson</link>
	<description>Neil deGrasse Tyson and Avis Lang’s ‘Accessory to War’ grapples with the millennia-old partnership between space science and warfare.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/08/main/articles/082418_MT_reviews_war_feat.jpg?itok=tUfd1g-X" length="31844" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Publisher retracts two papers, will correct five more for lab with high “level of disorganization”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=70537</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/04/publisher-retracts-two-papers-will-correct-five-more-for-lab-with-high-level-of-disorganization/</link>
	<description>A lab at the University of Malaya has lost two papers and will have to correct five more — just from one publisher — over poor lab practices. One of the retracted papers paper tested the effects of a plant on liver damage; its notice says the paper contains overlap with another paper from the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/04/publisher-retracts-two-papers-will-correct-five-more-for-lab-with-high-level-of-disorganization/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Publisher retracts two papers, will correct five more for lab with high “level of disorganization”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Huge ‘word gap’ holding back low-income children may not exist after all</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/word-gap-low-income-children-psychology-reproducibility</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/word-gap-low-income-children-psychology-reproducibility</link>
	<description>The claim that poor children hear fewer words than kids from higher-income families faces a challenge.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/08/main/articles/082918_bb_wordgap_feat_free.jpg?itok=-w7McFhB" length="27595" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 3 strategies universities are using to tackle societal challenges</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-strategies-universities-are-using-to-tackle-societal-challenges</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-strategies-universities-are-using-to-tackle-societal-challenges</link>
	<description>Research leaders across the Asia-Pacific region talk about how their universities are broadening the scope of academic research and higher education</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 big ideas that highlight technology’s impact on research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-big-ideas-that-highlight-technologys-impact-on-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-big-ideas-that-highlight-technologys-impact-on-research</link>
	<description>From research collaboration tools to innovative uses of AI, here are some highlights of the tech talks at ESOF</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 09:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: The “experiential advantage” is not universal – the less well-off get equal or more happiness from buying things</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34656</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/04/the-experiential-advantage-is-not-universal-the-less-well-off-get-equal-or-more-happiness-from-buying-things/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two vector golden cinema, movie, theatre, concert, performance, party, event, festival tickets&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34675&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34675&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector golden party ticket isolated on white background. Cinema, theatre,  concert, play, party, event and festival gold ticket realistic template set. Ticket icon for website.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Two vector golden cinema, movie, theatre, concert, performance, party, event, festival tickets&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Two vector golden cinema, movie, theatre, concert, performance, party, event, festival tickets&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-927883418.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-927883418.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-927883418.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/04/the-experiential-advantage-is-not-universal-the-less-well-off-get-equal-or-more-happiness-from-buying-things/two-vector-golden-cinema-movie-theatre-concert-performance-party-event-festival-tickets/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/gettyimages-927883418.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; guest blogger &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hulietjodges&quot;&gt;Juliet Hodges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being rich(er) may not guarantee happiness, as shown by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B004TRQAS6/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&quot;&gt;ample evidence from the social sciences&lt;/a&gt;, but there are ways of spending money that will make you happier than others. Recent research has uncovered the “&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2003-10055-017&quot;&gt;experiential advantage&lt;/a&gt;”: greater happiness from spending money on experiences (holidays, meals, theatre tickets) instead of material things (gadgets, clothes, jewellery). This could be for a number of reasons, such as experiences being more closely aligned with our values and being less likely to produce rumination and regret. There are exceptions to this rule, of course. Studies have found that personality traits can influence whether experiences or things make a person happiest; for example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797616635200?journalCode=pssa&quot;&gt;introverts are made much happier by spending vouchers in a bookshop than a bar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another likely exception, that hasn’t previously been studied, is how social class, and specifically access to resources, affects this experiential advantage. Indeed, most research in this area has been performed with college students, who are typically more affluent than the general population, and there are reasons to believe that those who are less well-off might prefer material goods. For them, buying things as opposed to experiences could be more practical: they last longer, can be used multiple times and potentially resold in the future. To put this reasoning to the test, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617736386&quot;&gt;recent paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/i&gt; investigated whether the experiential advantage is diminished or absent for people who can afford very little compared with those who can afford a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34656&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jacob Lee and colleagues began by assessing the social status of hundreds of US citizens – most of them recruited via Amazon’s survey website – using the MacArthur Scale of Subjective Social Status, a ladder with 10 rungs representing relative social standing. At the top are people with the most money, most education and most respected jobs, while the bottom rung represents the worst off in society. Participants indicate where on this ladder they sit, which has been shown to be often more accurate than objective indicators of class, like income and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first experiment, participants recalled recent experiential and material purchases, and rated which one made them happier on a scale from -3 (definitely experiential purchase) to 3 (definitely object purchase). As predicted, those on a lower “rung” of the social ladder reported greater happiness from purchasing objects, while their higher-class counterparts were made happier by experiences.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second experiment, participants were randomly assigned to think of either a recent material or experiential purchase they had made and rate how happy it made them. Again, there was a significant interaction between class and purchase type, with an experiential advantage for higher-class participants. Happiness did not vary by purchase type for the lower-class participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their third and final experiment, the researchers manipulated feelings of affluence to demonstrate a causal effect of social class on the pleasure derived from different purchase types. Participants first recalled a recent material and experiential purchase. Then, half of the participants imagined their monthly income had increased by 50 per cent, while the other half imagined theirs had decreased by 50 per cent. To bring this hypothetical situation to life, the researchers also asked the participants to spend time thinking about how they would allocate their budget with this new income, and how financially comfortable or constrained they would feel.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the participants rated their comparative happiness from an experiential or material purchase. Crucially, this was either the two purchases they had recalled at the beginning of the task, or two imagined purchases they would make now (with their new income). In this way, the researchers were able to demonstrate the difference between the purchase types when participants were primed to feel richer or poorer. Sure enough, there was&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;an experiential advantage in the resource-abundant condition, and a trend towards material purchases in the deprivation condition, although this did not reach statistical significance. These findings are important because they imply a causal effect of access to resources: regardless of existing income, increasing or reducing an individual’s perception of their financial stability affected what type of purchase made them happier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One underlying factor that could contribute to this effect is the amount of time available for experiences. It seems likely that more affluent individuals will have more free time or paid leave as well as disposable income, compared to those working several minimum-wage jobs to make ends meet. This could affect how appealing different purchase types are to both groups, an interpretation supported by lower social class participants in the current studies reporting a lower tendency to make experiential purchases than their higher-class peers.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This introduces the possibility that experiential purchases designed to create extra leisure time, like hiring a cleaner or having the groceries delivered, could be especially valued by the less well-off, building on recent research by Ashley Whillans and colleagues&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;that suggested &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/02/04/people-who-prioritise-time-over-money-are-happier/&quot;&gt;people who prioritise time over money are happier&lt;/a&gt; and that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/114/32/8523&quot;&gt;making time-saving purchases has a positive impact on wellbeing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most obvious limitation of the new research is its reliance on recall tasks. Memory is fallible and we are notoriously bad at knowing what makes us happy, so future studies would benefit from measuring happiness before and after participants make actual purchases of either type. It’s telling that in Whillans’ time-saving research, very few respondents chose to allocate money to save time, despite the results showing that doing so had the greatest impact on happiness. This implies we can’t necessarily rely on the purchases people make, or what they think about them, as an indicator for what is best for wellbeing.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, this new research adds further nuance to our understanding of the complex relationship between money, purchases and happiness, suggesting that what makes you happiest could depend on anything from your income to your personality type to your amount of free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617736386&quot;&gt;Experiential or Material Purchases? Social Class Determines Purchase Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hulietjodges&quot;&gt;Juliet Hodges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Juliet has a background in psychology and behavioural economics, and has applied this in advertising and now healthcare. Follow @hulietjodges on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hulietjodges&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/juliet-hodges-85b3406b/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or read her posts for the Bupa Newsroom &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bupa.co.uk/health-information/health-blog/author-profile/juliet-hodges&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 07:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: Open Access Publishing Forges Ahead in Europe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8274</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/rk2z90jg-zw/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2016/10/OA-sunrise_690x320-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A group of national funders, joined by the European Commission and the European Research Council, have announced plans to make Open Access publishing mandatory for recipients of their agencies’ research funding. Marc Schitlz, the President of Science Europe, has authored an article that outlines the path forward for their agencies. PLOS shares in the coalition’s dedication to disseminate scholarly work as rapidly and widely as possible. Because of its potential for impact on our communities, we’ve posted below an advance version of an article that will soon publish simultaneously in &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.3000031&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1002663&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/neuroscience&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_______________________________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science Without Publication Paywalls: cOAlition S for the Realisation of Full and Immediate Open Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marc Schiltz&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; President, Science Europe, Brussels, Belgium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Marc.Schiltz@fnr.lu&quot;&gt;Marc.Schiltz@fnr.lu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Perspective, a group of national funders, joined by the European Commission and the European Research Council, announce plans to make Open Access publishing mandatory for recipients of their agencies’ research funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Access is Foundational to the Scientific Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universality is a fundamental principle of science (the term ‘science’ as used here includes the humanities): only results that can be discussed, challenged, and, where appropriate, tested and reproduced by others qualify as scientific. Science, as an institution of &lt;em&gt;organised criticism&lt;/em&gt;, can therefore only function properly if research results are made openly available to the community so that they can be submitted to the test and scrutiny of other researchers. Furthermore, new research builds on established results from previous research. The chain, whereby new scientific discoveries are built on previously established results, can only work optimally if all research results are made openly available to the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publication paywalls are withholding a substantial amount of research results from a large fraction of the scientific community and from society as a whole. This constitutes an absolute anomaly, which hinders the scientific enterprise in its very foundations and hampers its uptake by society. Monetising the access to new and existing research results is profoundly at odds with the ethos of science [1]. There is no longer any justification for this state of affairs to prevail and the subscription-based model of scientific publishing, including its so-called ‘hybrid’ variants, should therefore be terminated. In the 21st century, science publishers should provide a service to help researchers disseminate their results. They may be paid fair value for the services they are providing, but &lt;strong&gt;no science should be locked behind paywalls!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Decisive Step Towards the Realisation of Full Open Access Needs to be Taken Now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers and research funders have a collective duty of care for the science system as a whole. The 2003 &lt;em&gt;Berlin Declaration&lt;/em&gt; [2] was a strong manifestation of the science community (researchers and research funders united) to regain ownership of the rules governing the dissemination of scientific information. Science Europe established principles for the transition to Open Access in 2013 [3] but wider overall progress has been slow. In 2016, the EU Ministers of science and innovation, assembled in the Competitiveness Council, resolved that all European scientific publications should be immediately accessible by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As major public funders of research in Europe, we have a duty of care for the good functioning of the science system (of which we are part), as well as a fiduciary responsibility for the proper usage of the public funds that we are entrusted with. As university and library negotiation teams in several countries (e.g. Germany, France, Sweden) [4,5] are struggling to reach agreements with large publishing houses, we feel that a decisive move towards the realisation of Open Access and the complete elimination of publication paywalls in science should be taken now. The appointment of the Open Access Envoy by the European Commission has accelerated this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, driven by our duty of care for the proper functioning of the science system, we have developed&lt;strong&gt; Plan S &lt;/strong&gt;whereby &lt;strong&gt;research funders will mandate that access to research publications that are generated through research grants that they allocate, must be fully and immediately open and cannot be monetised in any way &lt;/strong&gt;(Box 1)&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Box 1. Plan S. Accelerating the transition to full and immediate Open Access to scientific publications.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The key principle is as follows:&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“After 1 January 2020 scientific publications on the results from research funded by public grants provided by national and European research councils and funding bodies, must be published in compliant Open Access Journals or on compliant Open Access Platforms.” &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                Authors retain copyright of their publication with no restrictions. All publications must be published under an open license, preferably the Creative Commons Attribution Licence CC BY. In all cases, the license applied should fulfil the requirements defined by the Berlin declaration;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                The Funders will ensure jointly the establishment of robust criteria and requirements for the services that compliant high quality Open Access journals and Open Access platforms must provide;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                In case such high quality Open Access journals or platforms do not yet exist, the Funders will in a coordinated way provide incentives to establish these and support them when appropriate; support will also be provided for Open Access infrastructures where necessary;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                Where applicable, Open Access publication fees are covered by Funders or universities, not by individual researchers; it is acknowledged that all scientists should be able to publish their work Open Access even if their institutions have limited means;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                When Open Access publication fees are applied, their funding is standardised and capped (across Europe);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                Funders will ask universities, research organisations, and libraries to align their policies and strategies, notably to ensure transparency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                The above principles shall apply to all types of scholarly publications, but it is understood that the timeline to achieve Open Access for monographs and books may be longer than 1 January 2020;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                The importance of open archives and repositories for hosting research outputs is acknowledged because of their long-term archiving function and their potential for editorial innovation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                The ‘hybrid’ model of publishing is not compliant with the above principles;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–                The Funders will monitor compliance and will sanction non-compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Considerations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognise that researchers need to be given a maximum of freedom to choose the proper venue for publishing their results and that in some jurisdictions this freedom may be covered by a legal or constitutional protection. However, our collective duty of care is for the science system as a whole, and researchers must realise that they are doing a gross disservice to the institution of science if they continue to report their outcomes in publications that will be locked behind paywalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also understand that researchers may be driven to do so by a misdirected reward system which puts emphasis on the wrong indicators (&lt;em&gt;e.g&lt;/em&gt;. journal impact factor). We therefore commit to fundamentally revise the incentive and reward system of science, using the San Francisco &lt;em&gt;Declaration&lt;/em&gt; on Research Assessment (DORA) [6] as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subscription-based model of scientific publishing emerged at a certain point in the history of science, when research papers needed extensive typesetting, layout design, printing, and when hardcopies of journals needed to be distributed throughout the world. While moving from print to digital, the publishing process still needs services, but the distribution channels have been completely transformed. There is no valid reason to maintain any kind of subscription-based business model for scientific publishing in the digital world, where Open Access dissemination is maximising the impact, visibility, and efficiency of the whole research process. Publishers should provide services that help scientists to review, edit, disseminate, and interlink their work and they may charge fair value for these services in a transparent way. The minimal standards for services expected from publishers are laid down on page 6 of the 2015 ‘Science Europe Principles on Open Access Publisher Services’ [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, our call for &lt;em&gt;immediate&lt;/em&gt; Open Access is not compatible with any type of embargo period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge that ‘transformative’ type of agreements, where subscription fees are offset against publication fees, may contribute to accelerate the transition to full Open Access. Therefore, it is acceptable that, during a transition period that should be as short as possible, individual funders may continue to tolerate publications in ‘hybrid’ journals that are covered by such a ‘transformative’ type of agreement. There should be complete transparency in such agreements and their terms and conditions should be fully and publicly disclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are aware that there may be attempts to misuse the Open Access model of publishing by publishers that provide poor or non-existent editorial services (&lt;em&gt;e.g&lt;/em&gt;. the so-called ‘predatory’ publishers). We will therefore support initiatives that establish robust quality criteria for Open Access publishing, such as the Directory of Open Access Journals (DOAJ) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org&quot;&gt;https://doaj.org&lt;/a&gt;) and the Directory of Open Access Books (DOAB) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doabooks.org&quot;&gt;https://www.doabooks.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We note that for monographs and books the transition to Open Access may be longer than 1 January 2020, but as short as possible and respecting the targets already set by the individual research funders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cOAlition S: Building an Alliance of Funders and Stakeholders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan S states the fundamental principles for future Open Access publishing. Science Europe, funders, the European Research Council and the European Commission will work together to clarify and publish implementation details. The plan does not advocate any particular Open Access business model, although it is clear that some of the current models are not compliant. We therefore invite publishers to switch to publication models that comply with these principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan S was initiated by the Open Access Envoy of the European Commission and further developed by the President of Science Europe and by a group of Heads of national funding organisations. It also drew on substantial input from the Scientific Council of the European Research Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, a group of national funders initiate the alliance cOAlition S (&lt;a href=&quot;http://scieur.org/coalition-s&quot;&gt;http://scieur.org/coalition-s&lt;/a&gt;) to take action towards the implementation of Plan S, and are joined by the European Commission and the European Research Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite other funding agencies and research councils, as well as stakeholders (notably researchers, universities, libraries, and publishers) to join cOAlition S and thereby contribute to the swift realisation of our vision of science without publication paywalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merton RK. The Normative Structure of Science. In: Merton RK. The Sociology of Science: Theoretical and Empirical Investigations. Chicago: University of Chicago Press; 1973.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Planck Society. Berlin Declaration on Open Access to Knowledge in the Sciences and Humanities. 22 Oct 2003. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://openaccess.mpg.de/Berlin-Declaration&quot;&gt;https://openaccess.mpg.de/Berlin-Declaration&lt;/a&gt;. Cited 29 Aug 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science Europe. Science Europe Principles on Open Access to Research Publications. Apr 2013 (updated May 2015). Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scieur.org/opennew&quot;&gt;http://scieur.org/opennew&lt;/a&gt;. Cited 29 Aug 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kwon D. Universities in Germany and Sweden Lose Access to Elsevier Journals. The Scientist. 19 Jul 2018. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.the-scientist.com/news-opinion/universities-in-germany-and-sweden-lose-access-to-elsevier-journals--64522&quot;&gt;https://www.the-scientist.com/news-opinion/universities-in-germany-and-sweden-lose-access-to-elsevier-journals–64522&lt;/a&gt;. Cited 31 Aug 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kwon D. French Universities Cancel Subscriptions to Springer Journals. The Scientist. 31 Mar 2018. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.the-scientist.com/daily-news/french-universities-cancel-subscriptions-to-springer-journals-29882&quot;&gt;https://www.the-scientist.com/daily-news/french-universities-cancel-subscriptions-to-springer-journals-29882&lt;/a&gt;. Cited 31 Aug 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Francisco Declaration on Research Assessment (DORA). DORA Roadmap: A two-year strategic plan for advancing global research assessment reform at the institutional, national, and funder level. 27 Jun 2018. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfdora.org/2018/06/27/dora-roadmap-a-two-year-strategic-plan-for-advancing-global-research-assessment-reform-at-the-institutional-national-and-funder-level/&quot;&gt;https://sfdora.org/2018/06/27/dora-roadmap-a-two-year-strategic-plan-for-advancing-global-research-assessment-reform-at-the-institutional-national-and-funder-level/&lt;/a&gt;. Cited 29 Aug 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/rk2z90jg-zw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 07:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: Poster Perfection</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=614</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2018/09/04/poster-perfection/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is the latest in the blog series co-authored by myself and the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SueReviews&quot;&gt;Sue Fletcher-Watson&lt;/a&gt;. After a brief hiatus we are back with our latest post – how to put together a great poster. Designing an attractive and informative poster is an incredibly useful skill, especially for early-career researchers. For any non-academic readers – most academic conferences and often internal events at Universities will have a poster session.  These allow more people to share their research findings, in addition to scheduled speakers. So posters matter, but in our experience there is surprisingly little guidance given on how to do them well. So here are our dos and don’ts of putting together a killer poster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;postersession02&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-615&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;615&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MFC-J425W&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;postersession02&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/postersession02.jpeg?w=474?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/postersession02.jpeg?w=474?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/postersession02.jpeg?w=474&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;4309,3219&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2018/09/04/poster-perfection/postersession02/&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/postersession02.jpeg?w=474&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan ahead &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting together a great poster takes some time and you will need to factor in a few days to get it printed as well. So plan ahead. In our experience people leave posters to the absolute last minute (you know who you are). The result is usually something that looks haphazard and counterintuitive. There is also that mad panic and rush to the print shop…which is never open when you need it to be… and then you almost miss your flight… which is always best avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you check whether it needs to be landscape or portrait, and what size the presentation boards will be.  You don’t want a poster that’s too big for your board! The conference organisers will be able to tell you this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great poster is something you can come back to many times – it can be easily shared online, re-used at multiple events, and it might end up being displayed on your department walls – so it is worth doing well. When done properly, a poster should be easy to present, easy on the eye and it may even win you a prize or two J. So plan it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can only tell one good story with a poster &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a paper you may have 2 or 3 ongoing stories, or main findings that the manuscript is constructed around. This doesn’t work for a poster. A poster needs a single key message that you want to get across. Make sure that this features in the title. We both prefer titles that convey the story or finding you’re reporting on, rather than emphasising the method or approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People will only be at your poster for a few minutes (at best). You might not be there or available to explain it to them. It will likely be crowded and noisy. All of this means that you need to boil down the message to a single narrative and explain it well in a few points. When Sue does a poster, she always tries to have two or three bullet points that set out the essential background and central research question.  These are matched with two or three bullets to summarise the conclusions.  It should be possible to understand the study by reading just these sections.  The viewer can quickly and easily decide if they want to linger by your poster board, to get more detail on methods or results. The first step in designing a great poster is choosing this central narrative and presenting it neatly and briefly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select the key pieces of information, and make them pop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid large amounts of text. Graphics are a great way of conveying a lot of information in a small space. Don’t just paste in figures from your paper: these will probably need amending or focussing to fit the tight narrative that you have adopted for the poster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about what will be central – literally, right in the middle – in your poster. This is the prime space for key graphics and findings. Construct the rest of the poster around this. You can also use colour to make sure important details are easy for the reader to spot. If you’re using, say, navy blue text on an off-white background, maybe you could reverse these colours for your conclusions so that they stand out from the main text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imagine you are there… what visual aids would help?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trial run your poster. You would never imagine giving a talk that you hadn’t practiced (would you?!), and you need to apply the same logic to your posters. Show lab mates or departmental colleagues who are not familiar with your study. Can you use the poster to explain the study in about 3 minutes? Are there visual aids or diagrams that might help? Going through this process is vital to make sure that your poster actually works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t be constrained by the template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many institutions have set templates which are approved by corporate people somewhere (I guess). Our advice is to not let this constrain how you display your poster. You are the person who will have to stand next to this thing and use it. As long as you have the right logos and basic palette, and it is otherwise a brilliant poster, you should get away with it. And this is far preferable to a poster structure that simply doesn’t work. A common poster template is a landscape organised into three columns.  If you add information to these in a traditional sequence of background – research question – methods – results – discussion, you can often end up with interesting graphs at the bottom or off to one side. Don’t be afraid of going a little off-piste if this helps you get your message across. We won’t tell corporate if you don’t…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t have an eye for colour then ask someone who does &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you have bad taste when it comes to colours (again… you know who you are) then ask someone to help you. Try and avoid clashing colour combos, needlessly vivid and flashy figures. Posters are an inherently visual medium, so get the colours right. Think about what logos you have to have on the poster, and pick a palette which compliments at least one of them.  An easy fix is to go with different shades of the same colour – blues and greens work well – rather than mixing up your colours too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round this off, here is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dart.ed.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/SFW-IMFAR-clickeast-v2-small.pdf&quot;&gt;poster&lt;/a&gt; – this one made by Sue which she is pretty pleased with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. Investing time to make the poster good is worth it. You will enjoy the conference much more, you might win a prize, and it will look great on the lab wall once you’re done. &lt;strong&gt;So plan ahead, focus the message, get some good graphics… and be a great scientist! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 06:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: One retraction notice says plagiarism. The other says it was an error in an algorithm. Which was it?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=70716</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/03/one-retraction-notice-says-plagiarism-the-other-says-it-was-an-error-in-an-algorithm-which-was-it/</link>
	<description>For the second time in a week, we’ve come across a retraction notice that gave the wrong reason for the retraction. Last week, it was an Elsevier journal that called a plagiarized paper a duplicate of work by the same authors who’d written the original. Today, here’s the story of a chapter in a book … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/09/03/one-retraction-notice-says-plagiarism-the-other-says-it-was-an-error-in-an-algorithm-which-was-it/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;One retraction notice says plagiarism. The other says it was an error in an algorithm. Which was it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New images reveal how an ancient monster galaxy fueled furious star formation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alma-images-starburst-galaxy-star-formation</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/alma-images-starburst-galaxy-star-formation</link>
	<description>Scientists were able to see the abundance of star-forming gas and dust in a giant galaxy from when the universe was less than 2 billion years old.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/08/main/articles/083018_MT_monster-galaxy_feat.jpg?itok=0czDG2Lh" length="22636" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Megagrant, the Russian docu-novel of Paolo Macchiarini</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=26825</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/09/03/megagrant-the-russian-docu-novel-of-paolo-macchiarini/</link>
	<description>This is my review of the Russian book &quot;Megagrant&quot;, which tells of Macchiarini's adventures with the plastic trachea, much of it played out in Russia, funded by a state Megagrant of €4.5mn. Some books are namely only good as court evidence.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 05:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Bad Mobs of Good People: The Paradox of Viral Outrage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9685</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9685</link>
	<description>People become less approving of social media outrage the more people join in with it. One person rebuking another is fine, but ten people doing it looks like a mob.

This is the key finding of an interesting new paper called The Paradox of Viral Outrage, from Takuya Sawaoka and Benoît Monin of Stanford.

According to the authors, the titular 'paradox' is that &quot;individual outrage that would be praised in isolation is more likely to be viewed as bullying when echoed online by a multitude of si</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 19:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Study of 8000 workers finds that gender differences in “achievement motivation” may explain part of the gender pay gap</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34654</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/02/study-of-8000-workers-finds-that-gender-differences-in-achievement-motivation-may-explain-part-of-the-gender-pay-gap/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-925713268.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34655&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34655&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Gender gap and inequality in salary,&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Gender gap and inequality in salary, pay vector concept. Businessman and businesswoman on piles of coins. discrimination, difference, injustice. Vector illustration flat cartoon character design&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Gender gap and inequality in salary, pay vector concept. Businessman and businesswoman on piles of coins. discrimination, difference, injustice. Vector illustration flat cartoon character design&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/gettyimages-925713268.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/gettyimages-925713268.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/gettyimages-925713268.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1963,1527&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/09/02/study-of-8000-workers-finds-that-gender-differences-in-achievement-motivation-may-explain-part-of-the-gender-pay-gap/gender-gap-and-inequality-in-salary-pay-vector-concept-businessman-and-businesswoman-on-piles-of-coins-discrimination-difference-injustice-vector-illustration-flat-cartoon-character-design/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/gettyimages-925713268.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the UK, this has been a year of action on the gender pay gap (the, on average, lower pay for women compared with men), with cross-party MPs launching campaigns like &lt;a href=&quot;https://paymetoo.com/&quot;&gt;#PayMeToo&lt;/a&gt; and the government &lt;a href=&quot;https://genderpaygap.campaign.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;taking steps&lt;/a&gt; to investigate and hold organisations to account on the issue. This has also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.personneltoday.com/hr/jordan-peterson-gender-pay-gap-exist/&quot;&gt;attracted&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://iea.org.uk/gender-pay-gap-reporting-isnt-fit-for-purpose/&quot;&gt;pushback&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.news.com.au/finance/work/careers/how-common-sense-shows-gender-pay-gap-is-a-myth/news-story/6f7f2be3ec8c56484f83b798ff6d548f&quot;&gt;from&lt;/a&gt; those that argue that the gender difference in average pay has many causes, including the different interests of, and life choices taken by, men and women. Now a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/oep/advance-article/doi/10.1093/oep/gpy021/5046671&quot;&gt;published in Oxford Economic Papers&lt;/a&gt; has examined another complicating factor, namely whether the gender pay gap is influenced partly by an on-average difference between the genders in a trait not previously taken into account – the motivation to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34654&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leonora Risse and her team from Melbourne’s RMIT University drew on one year’s data from an Australian household survey of about 8,000 people employed full- or part-time. These workers provided information about their jobs, pay and social background, as well as completing a number of personality measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risse’s team first analysed the pay data and found the usual gender gap suggesting women earned AUS $26 dollars an hour, on average, compared with&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;$32.50 an hour for men – a difference of nearly 20 per cent.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the researchers looked into whether gender-linked personality differences could account for any of this difference, while holding other influences constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic connections drawn between personality and income are around two of the “Big Five” traits: people higher in conscientiousness – those who pay attention to quality and deadlines and work at a high pace – generally earn more, on average; as do people lower on agreeableness (suggesting there is an advantage for those more able and willing to make unlikeable decisions or put themselves before others).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typically seen when comparing the genders, women in this dataset were more agreeable, on average, and this appeared to adversely impact their pay. However they were also more conscientious, which offset things and meant that the net effect of gender differences in these Big Five traits was in explaining just nine cents of the gender pay gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Risse’s team had their eye on another culprit: potential gender differences in a trait called “achievement motivation”, which is made up of the two sub-traits “fear of failure” and “hope for success”. People more motivated by a fear of failure act based on negative emotionality and women&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;typically score higher on this than men. Although fear of failure can propel people to get things done, it isn’t very effective at motivating them to take on new risks or seek opportunities, as this introduces further domains for failure. In contrast with this, the sub-trait “hope for success” drives people towards opportunities with the expectation they will turn out well – and men typically score higher on this trait than women.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Risse and her colleagues predicted gender differences in achievement motivation and its sub-traits would prove important for pay, as a jump forward in earnings often involves taking a risk – asking for a raise, taking a difficult assignment or switching roles or businesses. If men do these things more often – and are more confident when they do so – this could be a component of the gender pay gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, in this dataset, women agreed more strongly with “fear of failure” items like “I am afraid of tasks that I cannot work out or solve”, while men agreed more strongly with “hope for success” items such as “I like situations where I can find out how capable I am”. Moreover, average gender differences in these traits contributed to the gender pay gap in the expected manner, together having twice the impact of the Big Five traits, at about 22 cents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharp minds will notice that this means gender differences in the psychological measures accounted for 31 cents, which is only five per cent of the gender pay gap. Gender differences in workplace factors (e.g. the industries that men and women tend to work in, and whether in the private or public sector) made a far larger contribution to the pay gap (around 80 cents). In turn, workplace factors were overshadowed by average gender differences in age and experience – older people with more experience tend to earn more, and in this dataset, more men than women matched this description (accounting for two dollars of the gender pay gap). Average gender differences in skills had a still bigger impact: over $2.50 of the gap.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the purely psychological measures turned out to be a bit player in this particular show. But drawing strong conclusions from this fact is difficult. One claim could be that social forces matter more than psychology: men are older in the workforce because of historical barriers to entry and because women who have children face more obstacles in returning to the workforce; skill differences reflect differential access to opportunities; and well-paying industries are not welcoming to women. But while there is considerable force to these social explanations, to view them as fully explaining the gender differences in occupational outcomes is likely to be ignoring other psychological features which weren’t measured in this study. Notably, the well-established gender differences in occupational interests, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/17/massive-study-finds-that-a-sizeable-minority-of-us-are-in-jobs-that-dont-fit-our-primary-occupational-interests/&quot;&gt;while not deterministic&lt;/a&gt;, remain an important driver of what choices people make around work, and the differences in how men and women construe &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/28/theres-a-psychological-case-for-paying-female-managers-more-than-male-managers-or-giving-them-more-holiday/&quot;&gt;the trade off between pay and free time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study wasn’t trying to provide us with all the answers. What it does show is clear: that, in aggregate, confidence in success and less fear of failure have real effects on wages, and that this may be relevant to the gender pay gap. One might expect that in certain roles and situations, gender differences in confidence could matter even more.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on their findings, Risse and her team suggest it may help reduce the gender pay gap for some women to undertake motivational and confidence training (although, as they note, personality is not infinitely malleable). The researchers also question whether there is a case for changing organisational cultures – is it necessarily a good thing for a &lt;i&gt;Yes I Can&lt;/i&gt; mindset to so often be the one making it to the top? After all, sometimes that attitude can lead an organisation, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?ei=D4-FW4OvG8fawQLTn6vwAQ&amp;amp;q=2007+financial+crisis+risk+taking&amp;amp;oq=2007+financial+crisis+risk+taking&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..33i22i29i30k1.79132.80058.0.80212.11.11.0.0.0.0.165.1219.2j8.10.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..1.10.1217...0i22i30k1.0.d-vjwBufB3A&quot;&gt;a whole industry&lt;/a&gt;, off a cliff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;—&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/oep/advance-article/doi/10.1093/oep/gpy021/5046671&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Personality and pay: do gender gaps in confidence explain gender gaps in wages?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 18:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
