<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Former MD Anderson researcher objects to retraction of his paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51518</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/former-md-anderson-researcher-objects-retraction-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A cell biology journal has retracted a 2016 paper after an investigation revealed that the corresponding author failed to include two co-authors and acknowledge the funding source. According to the retraction notice, the Journal of Cellular Physiology retracted the paper after the University of Texas, MD Anderson Cancer Center found that last author Jin Wang […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/former-md-anderson-researcher-objects-retraction-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Former MD Anderson researcher objects to retraction of his paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This ancient sea worm sported a crowd of ‘claws’ around its mouth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-sea-worm-mouth-claws</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-sea-worm-mouth-claws</link>
	<description>A newly discovered species of arrow worm that lived over half a billion years ago had about twice as many head spines as its modern kin.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/090217_notebook_introducing_main.jpg?itok=gOoZ2eaJ" length="13254" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Data had been manipulated,” again: Swiss probe prompts two more retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51511</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/data-manipulated-swiss-probe-prompts-two-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A biologist at the University of Basel is retracting two papers, citing data manipulation uncovered during an institutional investigation. That investigation has already led to the retraction of a paper in Science Translational Medicine by some of the same authors earlier this year. The two latest retractions, in the Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC), share […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/23/data-manipulated-swiss-probe-prompts-two-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Data had been manipulated,” again: Swiss probe prompts two more retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seeing one picture at a time helps kids learn words from books</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/seeing-one-picture-time-helps-kids-learn-words-books</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/seeing-one-picture-time-helps-kids-learn-words-books</link>
	<description>A small study found that children were better able to pick up vocabulary from books that show only one picture at a time.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/082217_ls_learning-words_free.jpg?itok=LGzb8GCJ" length="41200" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Whether you snack or not is more about the presence of temptation than your willpower</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29177</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/23/whether-you-snack-or-not-is-more-about-the-presence-of-temptation-than-your-willpower/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy1&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-29268&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29268&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=403&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;403,400&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/23/whether-you-snack-or-not-is-more-about-the-presence-of-temptation-than-your-willpower/giphy1/&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy1.gif?w=300&amp;amp;h=298&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re in the coffee shop and you watch your hand pick up the muffin and place it on your tray, how much of this was down to the situation, and how much to do with your (lack of) willpower or your long-term intentions? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12259/full?hootPostID=3f60ab0b40a8aad5d21ca2cae3244883&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Health Psychology&lt;/em&gt; compared these influences and found that momentary cues, such as seeing someone else snacking, were more strongly associated with how much people snacked than their own baseline psychological traits and intentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29177&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the scene for their research, Katherine Elliston at the University of Tasmania and her colleagues said that in Australia, around 30 to 41 per cent of people’s daily energy intake comes from snacking rather than from proper meals. This makes the psychology of snacking an important part of helping people to avoid over-eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers recruited 61 participants (42 women) through social media and flyers and asked them to complete a range of baseline psychological measures, including how much they think about the costs and benefits of healthy eating as occurring sooner rather than later (this comes from “Temporal Self-regulation Theory” – people are less likely to eat healthily when they see the benefits as distant and the costs as imminent); they also rated their intentions to eat more healthily; reported how often they’d eaten five fruit and veg per day recently; and rated their powers of self-regulation and willpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, for the next two weeks, the participants used an app to record any times that they ate food, and whether it was a snack (high or low energy) or a main meal. Sometimes they were also prompted at this point to record any situational cues relevant to snacking, such as: whether snacks were currently available; whether they were in a bad mood; whether they could see anyone else snacking; whether they were near a fast food shop. The app also beeped at random times through the day and asked the participants to record the presence of any of these same situational cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the participants recorded eating a total of 1127 snacks across the two-week study period. They reported the presence of other people snacking more often when they had just logged their own snacking than during times they weren’t snacking (i.e. when they were prompted randomly by the app), indicating a possible causal role for this situational cue, though the current design can’t prove this. The same pattern was also true for being in a bad mood and having snacks available and easily accessible – these were present more often during snacking than during random prompts when not eating, suggesting these cues may have contributed to snacking. Proximity to food outlets didn’t appear to be a relevant factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intentions and past healthy eating behaviour were not associated with the odds of snacking. Seeing the costs of healthy eating as coming early, before eating, was associated with more snacking. Lower self regulation was also associated with more high energy snacking overall, but these baseline measures were less strongly associated with snacking than momentary cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers said their study represented a successful application of Temporal Self-regulation Theory to explain snacking. “The results demonstrate that snacking is largely guided by momentary cues and that motivational-level factors may be less important in guiding snacking than previously thought,” they said, adding that helping people combat stress and low mood, and reducing the availability of snacks, could help people eat fewer unhealthy snacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings add to previous research that has shown that &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/10/18/is-willpower-overrated/&quot;&gt;goal attainment&lt;/a&gt; and healthy behaviour is more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/01/03/already-struggling-to-keep-new-year-resolutions-heres-the-first-detailed-study-of-daily-temptation-and-resistance/&quot;&gt;avoiding temptation&lt;/a&gt; in the first place than exercising iron willpower. Avoid going to the cafe that sells those amazing muffins, especially when you’re in a bad mood, and you’ll probably find you snack on them less. This sounds simple enough, but unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2009/12/10/step-away-from-the-cookie-jar-over-confidence-in-self-control-leads-us-to-temptation/&quot;&gt;we have a tendency to overestimate our willpower&lt;/a&gt; – especially when we’re not hungry, we forget how tempting snacks can be when we are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjhp.12259/full?hootPostID=3f60ab0b40a8aad5d21ca2cae3244883&quot;&gt;Personal and situational predictors of everyday snacking: An application of temporal self-regulation theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/akbZyUgsLW69q/download&quot;&gt;giphy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29177/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29177/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29177&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 10:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: New on Science Exchange: Nobel-worthy Nanosensors, MacroDSF, Fluidigm, and More</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1116</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/08/new-on-science-exchange-nobel-worthy-nanosensors-macrodsf-fluidigm-and-more/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nobel-worthy nanosensors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In 2007, Charles Lieber, the Harvard scientist who many say is in the running for a Nobel prize, co-founded &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/vista-nanobiosciences&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to enable drug discovery researchers to use his team’s nanosensor technologies for label-free, ultrasensitive detection of proteins, nucleic acids, and even single viral particles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_1118&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Functionalized-nanowires-vista-nanobiosciences.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Functionalized Nanowires Vista NanoBioSciences&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1118 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Functionalized-nanowires-vista-nanobiosciences-300x193.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences’ ultrasensitive biomarker detection platform (left) uses functionalized nanowires (“NW”) that respond to interactions with individual biomolecules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Vista NanoBioSensor&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1117&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Vista-NanoBioSensor-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Now available through Science Exchange, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/vista-nanobiosciences&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista NanoBioSciences&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; offers biomarker assays using its portable NanoBioSensor™ and BioTracker™ platforms. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Vista’s NanoBioSensor precisely detects and measures biomarkers in a finger-stick drop of blood, other bodily fluid, or tissue culture – without labeling and in less than 10 minutes. Vista’s BioTracker provides continuous monitoring of dynamic changes in the targeted analytes of any biological material.  Both devices are portable, exhibiting very high sensitivity (10³&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; increase over ELISA), high specificity, across multiple logs of concentration, in real time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taking the pain out of protein purification with MacroDSF&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Empowered by high-throughput protein purification and structure determination technologies, structure-based drug discovery is enjoying a resurgence.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/novalix&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NovAliX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a new provider on the Science Exchange network, gives you access to the ProteoPlex MacroDSF platform, an exciting tool for rapidly optimizing conditions for protein purification and crystallization. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The instrument quickly optimizes  protein concentration, pH value, salt, buffer, stabilizing additive, etc — potentially increasing a purified protein’s stability or even the resolution of its crystal structure!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/novalix&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NovAliX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; also offers a broad range of biophysical characterization services to provide a complete picture of the protein of interest. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fluidigm custom assay development&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Interested in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fluidigm&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fluidigm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;’s powerful mass cytometry and microfluidics platforms, but lack the resources to design the perfect assay? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Now you can take advantage of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/fluidigm&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fluidigm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;’s expertise using the company’s own team of assay development scientists. Through Science Exchange, you can order custom assays for Fluidigm’s CyTOF®, Helios®, and integrated fluidic circuit-based platforms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Oncology, from ABL1 to ZAP70&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Based in Freiburg, Germany, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/proqinase&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ProQinase&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; has been supporting oncology research for 16 years. Now on Science Exchange, ProQinase offers biochemical assay services (such as kinase screens), cellular assay services (such as proliferation, invasion and spheroid assays), and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; assay services (including immuno-oncology and metastasis models). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The scientific staff at ProQinase are thought leaders in oncology research. At the 2017 AACR Annual Meeting, they presented a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.proqinase.com/sites/default/files/public/uploads/Poster/muellerd_aacr_washington_2017_web.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;novel assay platform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to distinguish ATP-competitive from non-ATP-competitive kinase inhibitors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Medicinal chemistry and process optimization&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you’re looking for a full-service laboratory to execute your chemistry projects, you’ll be happy to see the addition of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/kalexsyn-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Kalexsyn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a chemical synthesis powerhouse based in Michigan, U.S.A, to the Science Exchange network.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Whether it’s developing novel scaffolds, SAR, modification of complex natural products or challenging macrocyclic peptides, Kalexsyn’s deep bench of Ph.D. chemists provides IP-enabling expertise. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Kalexsyn team has produced over 1000 publications and patents and has served over 85 pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Connect with a new provider today!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you new to Science Exchange? &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.scienceexchange.com/hc/en-us&quot;&gt;See how it works.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 02:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Kinetic analysis of a complete nitrifier reveals an oligotrophic lifestyle</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23679</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MiDavezW6FM/nature23679</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Nitrification, the oxidation of ammonia (NH3) via nitrite (NO2−) to nitrate (NO3−), is a key process of the biogeochemical nitrogen cycle. For decades, ammonia and nitrite oxidation were thought to be separately catalysed by ammonia-oxidizing bacteria (AOB) and archaea (AOA), and by nitrite-oxidizing bacteria (NOB). The recent discovery of complete ammonia oxidizers (comammox) in the NOB genus Nitrospira, which alone convert ammonia to nitrate, raised questions about the ecological niches in which comammox Nitrospira successfully compete with canonical nitrifiers. Here we isolate a pure culture of a comammox bacterium, Nitrospira inopinata, and show that it is adapted to slow growth in oligotrophic and dynamic habitats on the basis of a high affinity for ammonia, low maximum rate of ammonia oxidation, high growth yield compared to canonical nitrifiers, and genomic potential for alternative metabolisms. The nitrification kinetics of four AOA from soil and hot springs were determined for comparison. Their surprisingly poor substrate affinities and lower growth yields reveal that, in contrast to earlier assumptions, AOA are not necessarily the most competitive ammonia oxidizers present in strongly oligotrophic environments and that N. inopinata has the highest substrate affinity of all analysed ammonia oxidizer isolates except the marine AOA Nitrosopumilus maritimus SCM1 (ref. 3). These results suggest a role for comammox organisms in nitrification under oligotrophic and dynamic conditions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23679&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23679&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MiDavezW6FM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Feedback regulation of steady-state epithelial turnover and organ size</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23678</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1ivPFJXtHQM/nature23678</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Epithelial organs undergo steady-state turnover throughout adult life, with old cells being continually replaced by the progeny of stem cell divisions. To avoid hyperplasia or atrophy, organ turnover demands strict equilibration of cell production and loss. However, the mechanistic basis of this equilibrium is unknown. Here we show that robustly precise turnover of the adult Drosophila intestine arises through a coupling mechanism in which enterocyte apoptosis breaks feedback inhibition of stem cell division. Healthy enterocytes inhibit stem cell division through E-cadherin, which prevents secretion of mitogenic epidermal growth factors (EGFs) by repressing transcription of the EGF maturation factor rhomboid. Individual apoptotic enterocytes promote divisions by loss of E-cadherin, which releases cadherin-associated β-catenin (Armadillo in Drosophila) and p120-catenin to induce rhomboid. Induction of rhomboid in the dying enterocyte triggers activation of the EGF receptor (Egfr) in stem cells within a discrete radius. When we blocked apoptosis, E-cadherin-controlled feedback suppressed divisions, and the organ retained the same number of cells. When we disrupted feedback, apoptosis and divisions were uncoupled, and the organ developed either hyperplasia or atrophy. Together, our results show that robust cellular balance hinges on the obligate coupling of divisions to apoptosis, which limits the proliferative potential of a stem cell to the precise time and place at which a replacement cell is needed. In this way, localized cell–cell communication gives rise to tissue-level homeostatic equilibrium and constant organ size. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23678&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23678&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1ivPFJXtHQM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Public antibodies to malaria antigens generated by two LAIR1 insertion modalities</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23670</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5X5tA0lok3o/nature23670</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 In two previously described donors, the extracellular domain of LAIR1, a collagen-binding inhibitory receptor encoded on chromosome 19 (ref. 1), was inserted between the V and DJ segments of an antibody. This insertion generated, through somatic mutations, broadly reactive antibodies against RIFINs, a type of variant antigen expressed on the surface of Plasmodium falciparum-infected erythrocytes. To investigate how frequently such antibodies are produced in response to malaria infection, we screened plasma from two large cohorts of individuals living in malaria-endemic regions. Here we report that 5–10% of malaria-exposed individuals, but none of the European blood donors tested, have high levels of LAIR1-containing antibodies that dominate the response to infected erythrocytes without conferring enhanced protection against febrile malaria. By analysing the antibody-producing B cell clones at the protein, cDNA and gDNA levels, we characterized additional LAIR1 insertions between the V and DJ segments and discovered a second insertion modality whereby the LAIR1 exon encoding the extracellular domain and flanking intronic sequences are inserted into the switch region. By exon shuffling, this mechanism leads to the production of bispecific antibodies in which the LAIR1 domain is precisely positioned at the elbow between the VH and CH1 domains. Additionally, in one donor the genomic DNA encoding the VH and CH1 domains was deleted, leading to the production of a camel-like LAIR1-containing antibody. Sequencing of the switch regions of memory B cells from European blood donors revealed frequent templated inserts originating from transcribed genes that, in rare cases, comprised exons with orientations and frames compatible with expression. These results reveal different modalities of LAIR1 insertion that lead to public and dominant antibodies against infected erythrocytes and suggest that insertion of templated DNA represents an additional mechanism of antibody diversification that can be selected in the immune response against pathogens and exploited for B cell engineering. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23670&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23670&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5X5tA0lok3o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Homeostatic control of metabolic and functional fitness of Treg cells by LKB1 signalling</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23665</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/podmlYvf7Bw/nature23665</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Regulatory T cells (Treg cells) have a pivotal role in the establishment and maintenance of immunological self-tolerance and homeostasis. Transcriptional programming of regulatory mechanisms facilitates the functional activation of Treg cells in the prevention of diverse types of inflammatory responses. It remains unclear how Treg cells orchestrate their homeostasis and interplay with environmental signals. Here we show that liver kinase B1 (LKB1) programs the metabolic and functional fitness of Treg cells in the control of immune tolerance and homeostasis. Mice with a Treg-specific deletion of LKB1 developed a fatal inflammatory disease characterized by excessive TH2-type-dominant responses. LKB1 deficiency disrupted Treg cell survival and mitochondrial fitness and metabolism, but also induced aberrant expression of immune regulatory molecules including the negative co-receptor PD-1 and the TNF receptor superfamily proteins GITR and OX40. Unexpectedly, LKB1 function in Treg cells was independent of conventional AMPK signalling or the mTORC1–HIF-1α axis, but contributed to the activation of β-catenin signalling for the control of PD-1 and TNF receptor proteins. Blockade of PD-1 activity reinvigorated the ability of LKB1-deficient Treg cells to suppress TH2 responses and the interplay with dendritic cells primed by thymic stromal lymphopoietin. Thus, Treg cells use LKB1 signalling to coordinate their metabolic and immunological homeostasis and to prevent apoptotic and functional exhaustion, thereby orchestrating the balance between immunity and tolerance. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23665&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23665&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/podmlYvf7Bw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Lhx6-positive GABA-releasing neurons of the zona incerta promote sleep</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23663</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1IA_uAjrOm4/nature23663</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Multiple populations of wake-promoting neurons have been characterized in mammals, but few sleep-promoting neurons have been identified. Wake-promoting cell types include hypocretin and GABA (γ-aminobutyric-acid)-releasing neurons of the lateral hypothalamus, which promote the transition to wakefulness from non-rapid eye movement (NREM) and rapid eye movement (REM) sleep. Here we show that a subset of GABAergic neurons in the mouse ventral zona incerta, which express the LIM homeodomain factor Lhx6 and are activated by sleep pressure, both directly inhibit wake-active hypocretin and GABAergic cells in the lateral hypothalamus and receive inputs from multiple sleep–wake-regulating neurons. Conditional deletion of Lhx6 from the developing diencephalon leads to decreases in both NREM and REM sleep. Furthermore, selective activation and inhibition of Lhx6-positive neurons in the ventral zona incerta bidirectionally regulate sleep time in adult mice, in part through hypocretin-dependent mechanisms. These studies identify a GABAergic subpopulation of neurons in the ventral zona incerta that promote sleep. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23663&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1IA_uAjrOm4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Heart disease: Putative medicines that mimic mutations</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23544</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/IgCeFa4azAA/nature23544</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Molecules that block the activity or production of the protein ANGPTL3 have now been found to lower blood levels of lipoproteins and cholesterol in mice and healthy humans, mimicking the protective effects of genetic mutations in ANGPTL3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23544&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23544&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/IgCeFa4azAA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Plant science: Sexual attraction channelled in moss</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23543</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/xBfiK5KzFeE/nature23543</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis reveals that both sexual reproduction and early-embryo development in the moss  Physcomitrella patens  are controlled by cellular calcium influxes through ion-channel proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23543&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23543&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/xBfiK5KzFeE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A heterochromatin-dependent transcription machinery drives piRNA expression</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23482</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1taAGhmla0M/nature23482</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Nuclear small RNA pathways safeguard genome integrity by establishing transcription-repressing heterochromatin at transposable elements. This inevitably also targets the transposon-rich source loci of the small RNAs themselves. How small RNA source loci are efficiently transcribed while transposon promoters are potently silenced is not understood. Here we show that, in Drosophila, transcription of PIWI-interacting RNA (piRNA) clusters—small RNA source loci in animal gonads—is enforced through RNA polymerase II pre-initiation complex formation within repressive heterochromatin. This is accomplished through Moonshiner, a paralogue of a basal transcription factor IIA (TFIIA) subunit, which is recruited to piRNA clusters via the heterochromatin protein-1 variant Rhino. Moonshiner triggers transcription initiation within piRNA clusters by recruiting the TATA-box binding protein (TBP)-related factor TRF2, an animal TFIID core variant. Thus, transcription of heterochromatic small RNA source loci relies on direct recruitment of the core transcriptional machinery to DNA via histone marks rather than sequence motifs, a concept that we argue is a recurring theme in evolution. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23482&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1taAGhmla0M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New antennas are up to a hundredth the size of today’s devices</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antennas-are-hundredth-size-todays-devices</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-antennas-are-hundredth-size-todays-devices</link>
	<description>A new type of antenna could be used in tiny electronics for wearable tech, injectable medical devices and more.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/082217_MT_tiny-antenna_main_FREE.jpg?itok=nNT1dPwE" length="44839" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These chip-sized spacecraft are the smallest space probes yet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-chip-sized-spacecraft-are-smallest-space-probes-yet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-chip-sized-spacecraft-are-smallest-space-probes-yet</link>
	<description>Space initiative dubbed Breakthrough Starshot sent the smallest spacecraft yet into orbit around Earth.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 17:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/073117_MT_tiniest_satellite_main.jpg?itok=bBU5SNx9" length="25129" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Birth control research is moving beyond the pill</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/birth-control-research-moving-beyond-pill</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/birth-control-research-moving-beyond-pill</link>
	<description>After decades of research, reproductive biologists are on the verge of developing new birth control options that stop sperm from maturing or save a woman's eggs for later.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 16:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/090217_contraceptives_main.jpg?itok=RkA3o1pU" length="26806" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Hey, that’s my case study: Another retraction after doctors claim rights to case write-up</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51505</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/hey-thats-case-study-another-retraction-doctors-claim-rights-case-write/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of researchers have retracted their 2016 case report about a rare dermatologic disorder in the wake of disputes about authorship and institutional approval. The paper describes a young boy with Job’s Syndrome, in which patients experience painful, itchy and frequently disfiguring skin lesions, along with a constellation of other possible symptoms. The condition […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/hey-thats-case-study-another-retraction-doctors-claim-rights-case-write/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hey, that’s my case study: Another retraction after doctors claim rights to case write-up&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Some secrets of China’s terra-cotta army are baked in the clay</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-terra-cotta-army-clay</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-terra-cotta-army-clay</link>
	<description>Specialized production system lay behind the famous terra-cotta troops found in ancient Chinese emperor’s tomb.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 13:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081817_BB_terracotta-army_main_FREE.jpg?itok=4DmSy0CW" length="51744" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: There is no such thing as the true self, but it’s still a useful psychological concept</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29100</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/22/there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-true-self-but-its-still-a-useful-psychological-concept/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-492740240.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29170&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29170&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sliced human head shaped onion on chopping board&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;crispy_fish_images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Layers of personality&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Layers of personality&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3317,2197&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/22/there-is-no-such-thing-as-the-true-self-but-its-still-a-useful-psychological-concept/layers-of-personality/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-492740240.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think you are truly mean, you have sad eyes” Tormund Giantsbane ponders the true self of Sandor ‘The Hound’ Clegane in &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones, Beyond The Wall&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are you really? Is there a “true you” beneath the masquerade? According to a trio of psychologists and philosophers &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691616689495&quot;&gt;writing in &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the idea that we each have a hidden true or authentic self is an incredibly common folk belief, and moreover, the way most of us think about these true selves is remarkably consistent, even across different cultures, from Westeros to Tibet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the concept of a true self useful because it helps explain many of the judgments we make about ourselves and others. Yet, from a scientific perspective, there is actually no such thing as the true self. “The notion that there are especially authentic parts of the self, and that these parts can remain cloaked from view indefinitely, borders on the superstitious,” write Nina Strohminger and her colleagues at Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29100&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way that psychologists have investigated people’s views of the true self is to ask them to consider that a person has changed in various ways – either their memories, or their preferences, or their morals, or their personality, for example – and then ask them after which change has the person’s true self most been altered. The results are incredibly consistent: people most consider that the true self has been altered if a person’s moral sense is changed. In other words, most of us believe that the true self is the moral self.  This also manifests in the common reluctance we have to consider taking hypothetical drugs that might alter our moral judgments (more so than our reluctance to take drugs that would alter our personality, for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to this, explain Strohminger and her co-authors, is that most of us seem to be biased to see our own and other people’s true selves as essentially good. When a bad person turns good, we see this as their true self emerging. Conversely, if a good person turns bad, this is because circumstances have conspired to constrain or corrupt their true self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the normal bias most of us have to assume we are better than average disappears when it comes to the true self: that is, we see both our own and other people’s true selves in a similar, very positive light. “It is worth emphasising just how striking this discrepancy is” write Strohminger and co. “One of the most ubiquitous effects in the self literature – actor-observer valence asymmetry – fails to obtain for true self attribution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These widespread assumptions that the true self is moral and good is remarkably consistent across cultures: even Hindu Indians and Buddhist Tibetans see moral aspects of a person as especially central to their identity, even though the latter group deny that there is such a thing as the self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assumptions we hold about the true self also help explain the judgments we make about other people’s behaviour. For instance, if a person’s emotions lead them to behave badly, we judge them less harshly, presumably because we assume their true self was led astray. Conversely, if a person’s emotions lead them to behave admirably, our praise for them is undiminished, presumably because in this case we assume their virtuous true self was at play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the concept of a true self is useful in terms of understanding people’s judgments and behaviour. And we can speculate and investigate why most of us think about the true self in the ways that we do: for example, perhaps we’ve evolved to see the human true self as fundamentally good because assuming the best in others helps foster social ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on the question of whether there really is such a thing as a true self, Strohminger and her colleagues are sceptical. They point out that views on the true self are highly subjective and skewed by our own judgments of what is good (psychopaths, for instance, see morality as less central to identity presumably because morals are less important to them). Our beliefs about the true self also seem “evidence-insensitive” – claims made about the true self “may completely contradict all available data”. The authors conclude: “These two features – radical subjectivity and unverifiability – prevent the true self from being a scientific concept.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1745691616689495&quot;&gt;The True Self: A Psychological Concept Distinct From the Self&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29100/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29100/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29100&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: One way to boost your uni’s ranking: Ask faculty to cite each other</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51500</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/one-way-boost-unis-ranking-ask-faculty-cite/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Readers who follow scientific publishing will know the term “citation stacking” — as a profile-boosting technique, we’ve seen journals ask authors to cite them, and individual scientists work together to cite each other, forming “citation cartels.” And now, we’ve seen a university do it. A university in Malaysia has instructed its engineering faculty to cite […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/22/one-way-boost-unis-ranking-ask-faculty-cite/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;One way to boost your uni’s ranking: Ask faculty to cite each other&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 11:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: In pictures: Elsevierians experience the solar eclipse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-pictures-elsevierians-watch-the-eclipse</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-pictures-elsevierians-watch-the-eclipse</link>
	<description>In New York City, sharing the glory (and the glasses); in St. Louis — totality!</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: A long journey to reproducible results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548387a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/meb3sO-FcT8/548387a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Replicating our work took four years and 100,000 worms but brought surprising discoveries, explain Gordon J. Lithgow, Monica Driscoll and Patrick Phillips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 387 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548387a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548387a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/meb3sO-FcT8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: To reduce gender biases, acknowledge them</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548373a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/9aUxFpkBkH4/548373a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A former Google engineer’s memo on diversity reveals psychological blind spots, not biological differences, says Debbie Chachra.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 373 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548373a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548373a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/9aUxFpkBkH4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Yourbrainhealth: Can you prevent memory loss and brain ageing?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5077</guid>
	<link>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/can-prevent-memory-loss-brain-ageing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-5078&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/book-1659717_1280-1024x587.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here I take a look at some of the evidence linking education and occupation with better cognitive function in older age.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich lifetime experiences like higher education or engaging in mentally challenging occupations have a major influence on how you age cognitively. This is because mentally stimulating activities help build &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/what-is-cognitive-reserve-how-we-can-protect-our-brains-from-memory-loss-and-dementia-76591&quot;&gt;cognitive reserve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cognitive reserve&lt;/em&gt; refers to the brain’s resilience or ability to cope despite damage or degeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor &lt;a href=&quot;http://sharpbrains.com/blog/2007/07/23/build-your-cognitive-reserve-yaakov-stern/&quot;&gt;Yaakov Stern&lt;/a&gt;, one of the earliest proponents of the notion, says individuals who lead mentally and physically stimulating lives have&lt;em&gt; reduced&lt;/em&gt; risk of developing Alzheimer’s disease because of an&lt;em&gt; increased&lt;/em&gt; cognitive reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Studies suggest that they have 35% to 40% less risk of manifesting the disease. The pathology will still occur, but they are able to cope with it better. Some won’t ever be diagnosed with Alzheimer’s because they don’t present any symptoms. Some individuals have a greater number of neurons and synapses, and somehow those extra structures provide a level of protection.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to university or continually learning and educating yourself promotes more efficient cognitive processing and use of brain networks, which effectively &lt;em&gt;slows &lt;/em&gt;the process of age-related cognitive decline. Often (but not always) better-educated Alzheimer’s disease patients are found to be in a more advanced state of neuropathology when they are first diagnosed than their symptoms might suggest—increased cognitive reserve has allowed them to function symptom-free despite their brain degeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2014-03/uom-mcj032414.php&quot;&gt;Research &lt;/a&gt;has also found that another way to maximise cognitive prowess is to work as a doctor, air traffic controller, financial analyst, or in some other mentally-demanding profession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwenith Fisher is an assistant professor of psychology at Colorado State University. Fisher’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14294-001&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; analysed 4,182 participants who worked in a wide variety of jobs and had been doing the same type of work for roughly 25 years before they retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fisher and her colleagues examined the mental requirements of each job, for example, analysing data, developing objectives and strategies, making decisions, solving problems, evaluating information and thinking creatively. Each retiree’s was assessed for mental functioning and memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Based on data spanning 18 years, our study suggests that certain kinds of challenging jobs have the potential to enhance and protect workers’ mental functioning in later life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retirees who had worked in jobs with greater mental demands were more likely to have better memories before they retired, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; more likely to have slower declines in memory after retiring than people who had worked in jobs with fewer mental demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Working in a job that involves a lot of thinking, analysing, problem-solving, creativity, and other complex mental processing is related to higher levels of cognitive functioning not only before retirement but after retirement as well.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings have been supported by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25054282&quot;&gt;study &lt;/a&gt;from US-based Mayo Clinic researchers who found that a lifetime of learning and an intellectually enriching job can delay the onset of cognitive decline and diseases like dementia for up to three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2014-06-24/study-finds-preventing-cognitive-decline-takes-a/5545792&quot;&gt;ABC’s AM program&lt;/a&gt; Dr Prashanthi Vemuri lead researcher on the study explains,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We were focused on seeing if lifetime intellectual enrichment, whether it’s higher education, occupation and doing more cognitive activities later in life might help someone. And we found that, yes, lifetime intellectual enrichment does help in delaying the onset of cognitive impairment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you have a four-year college degree and then you’re in a professional speciality, like being a doctor or you’re a computer scientist, you’re at lower risk of developing dementia later in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where does this leave you if you don’t have a mentally demanding career or university education? Is it too late to build cognitive reserve? Thankfully, the answer is ‘no’. Cognitive decline is not inevitable, because intellectual enrichment goes beyond the work people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is never too late. Absolutely never too late, irrespective of what you did in your prior life,” say Vermi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We found that high mid- to late-life engagement in cognitively stimulating activities, such as reading books and magazines, playing games or music, artistic activities, craft, group activities, social activities and computer activities, all these help. And you have to engage in them at least three times a week during your mid and late life, that really helps in delaying the onset of dementia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published in the new retired ABC Active Memory blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/can-prevent-memory-loss-brain-ageing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can you prevent memory loss and brain ageing?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 23:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/">Your Brain Health</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: On a mountain in Wyoming, the eclipse brings wonder — and, hopefully, answers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wyoming-eclipse-physics-corona</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wyoming-eclipse-physics-corona</link>
	<description>Astronomy writer Lisa Grossman joined scientists on a mountain in Wyoming who were measuring the corona using four different instruments to try to figure out why it’s so hot.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 23:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/082117_LG_eclipse_day-of_main.jpg?itok=sHWLtnrv" length="8763" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: SAGE journal retracts three more papers after discovering faked reviews</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51490</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/sage-journal-retracts-three-papers-discovering-faked-reviews/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;SAGE recently retracted three 2015 papers from one of its journals after the publisher found the articles were accepted with faked peer reviews. The retraction notices call out the authors responsible for submitting the reviews. This trio of retractions is the second batch of papers withdrawn by Technology in Cancer Research &amp;amp; Treatment over faked […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/sage-journal-retracts-three-papers-discovering-faked-reviews/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;SAGE journal retracts three more papers after discovering faked reviews&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: &quot;R-Factor&quot; Unlikely To Fix Science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9052</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9052</link>
	<description>A new tool called the R-factor could help ensure that science is reproducible and valid, according to a preprint posted on biorxiv: Science with no fiction. The authors, led by Peter Grabitz, are so confident in their idea that they've created a company called Verum Analytics to promote it. But how useful is this new metric going to be?



Not very useful, in my view. The R-factor (which stands for &quot;reproducibility, reputation, responsibility, and robustness&quot;) strikes me as a flawed idea.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 15:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Mars has nighttime snow storms</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-has-nighttime-snow-storms</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-has-nighttime-snow-storms</link>
	<description>When clouds of water-ice particles cool at night, snow starts to fall rapidly on Mars, simulations suggest. The squalls could explain observations made by the Phoenix lander in 2008.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081717_AY_mars_main.jpg?itok=shCRFkVT" length="11987" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Trans men show unusual connectivity patterns in brain networks involved in self perception</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29026</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/21/trans-men-show-unusual-connectivity-patterns-in-brain-networks-involved-in-self-perception/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29079&quot; style=&quot;width: 2140px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-08-21 13.55.14.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29079&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29079&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-08-21 13.55.14&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2140,780&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/21/trans-men-show-unusual-connectivity-patterns-in-brain-networks-involved-in-self-perception/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/screenshot-2017-08-21-13-55-14.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;Photographic stimuli from the “body morph” task that was used in the new research&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most brain imaging studies involving transgender people or people with gender dysphoria have focused on whether their brains look more like what’s typical for the gender they identify with, rather than the gender they were assigned at birth based on their biological sex. For example, whether trans men have “masculine” brains, and trans women have more “feminine” brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results have been mixed and if anything point towards trans people having brains with &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/cercor/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/cercor/bhu194&quot;&gt;distinct&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0085914&quot;&gt;features&lt;/a&gt; that are neither stereotypically male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Brain Imaging and Behaviour&lt;/em&gt; adds to this trend, showing that trans men have unusual patterns of connectivity in brain networks involved in processing of the self, as compared with male and female controls. “The present data do not support the hypothesis that sexual differentiation of the brain of individuals with gender dysphoria is in the opposite direction as their sex assigned at birth,” the researchers said, adding that the unusual connectivity patterns they found in trans men “was detected in comparison with both male and female controls, and there were no differences between the control groups”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29026&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team led by Jamie Feusner at University of California, Los Angeles, scanned the brains of 27 trans men (whom they refer to as female-to-male persons with gender dysphoria) recruited via a gender dysphoria clinic at the Karolinska Institute in Sweden where they’d been diagnosed with gender dysphoria, specifically transsexualism (according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icd10data.com/ICD10CM/Codes/F01-F99/F60-F69/F64-/F64.0&quot;&gt;ICD 10 criteria&lt;/a&gt;). The trans men had not yet undertaken the surgery and/or hormone treatment that they were seeking; they had no other current psychiatric or neurological diagnoses. There were also 27 male and 27 female cisgender controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a resting-state brain scan, so the participants simply lay in the scanner doing nothing. The researchers then analysed the participants’ patterns of neural activity at rest to look for signs of connectivity in various brain networks, including the “default mode network” (which is more active when we’re mind-wandering and thinking about the self rather than engaged with the outside world) and the “salience network” which processes internal bodily sensations, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighteen of the trans participants and some of the controls also completed a body morph test (see example photographs above): they looked at images of their own body, shown for either half a second or two seconds, that were morphed to varying degrees with the body of another man or woman, and they had to say to what degree the photo was of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trans men showed weak connectivity in areas of the default mode network as compared with both the male and female controls. As you’d expect, they were also more likely to rate the body morph photos as being themselves when they were morphed with a man’s body, rather than a woman’s or unmorphed. Moreover, at longer viewing times, this identification with a masculinised version of their own body correlated with greater connectivity within pregenual anterior cingulate cortex – part of the default mode network that’s associated with feelings of self. The controls didn’t show this correlation, but at shorter viewing times they (but not the trans participants) showed a correlation between seeing their unmorphed body as their own and connectivity within the right insula – a region involved in the rapid processing of internal bodily signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interpretation of these different brain activity patterns is highly speculative but the researchers said the results are consistent with the idea that in trans men “higher cortical systems” were modulating the activity of more reflex systems involved in self and own body processing. The researchers said: “Gender dysphoria individuals differ from controls with respect to connectivity within networks involved in self-directed thinking and that relate to own-body identification, which could represent a neurobiological correlate of their condition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether these unusual brain activity patterns play a role in causing gender dysphoria or are the consequence of it, or both, is not clear. It also remains to be seen how surgical or hormone treatment might interact with these neural patterns. More research, especially longitudinal that tests participants over time, is needed to tease out cause and effect; and research with trans women is also required to see if the current findings generalise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Intrinsic network connectivity and own body perception in gender dysphoria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9578-6?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Feusner at al, 2017&lt;/a&gt; shows stimuli from the body morph task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29026/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29026/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29026&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 13:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Released FDA docs reveal details of agency’s (failed) attempt to retract paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51487</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/released-fda-docs-reveal-details-agencys-failed-attempt-retract-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a raging controversy regarding a new drug spilled into the pages of a leading medical journal: the head of the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and another official publicly called for the retraction or correction of a peer-reviewed article about the drug. They didn’t get their wish. Now, documents released by the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/21/released-fda-docs-reveal-details-agencys-failed-attempt-retract-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Released FDA docs reveal details of agency’s (failed) attempt to retract paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 12:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Today is the day! A last-minute guide for watching the Great American Eclipse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/last-minute-guide-watching-great-american-eclipse</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/last-minute-guide-watching-great-american-eclipse</link>
	<description>You’ve probably heard this already, but there’s a total solar eclipse traversing the United States today, August 21. Here’s what you need to know.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/082117_kt_eclipse_highway_free.jpg?itok=9tuqNtrN" length="54150" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Theft of South African relics riles researchers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22479</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ncVg9T0Xu9g/nature.2017.22479</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Efforts to relocate artefacts to sites of origin could stall after gold robbery at national park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22479&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ncVg9T0Xu9g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Martian weather kicks into high gear at night</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22476</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/8F5wcBJX3a0/nature.2017.22476</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Sundown sparks blustery snowstorms in the Red Planet’s lower atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22476&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22476&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/8F5wcBJX3a0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Mysteries of turbulence unravelled</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22474</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ZCJ07EuefDg/nature.2017.22474</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Simulations follow how swirls in a fluid transfer and dissipate energy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22474&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ZCJ07EuefDg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Head injuries in sport must be taken more seriously</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548371a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Af8Xe5UqP9w/548371a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Sports organizations are only starting to understand the harm that can be inflicted by high-contact activities. Science must play its part in highlighting the problem and in aiding diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 371 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548371a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548371a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Af8Xe5UqP9w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Ascorbate regulates haematopoietic stem cell function and leukaemogenesis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23876</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zKtVciSqncU/nature23876</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Stem cell fate can be influenced by metabolite levels in culture but it is unknown whether physiological variations in metabolite levels in normal tissues regulate stem cell function in vivo. We developed a metabolomics method for analysis of rare cell populations isolated directly from tissues and used it to compare haematopoietic stem cells (HSCs) to restricted haematopoietic progenitors. Each haematopoietic cell type had a distinct metabolic signature. Human and mouse HSCs had unusually high levels of ascorbate, which declined with differentiation. Systemic ascorbate depletion in mice increased HSC frequency and function, partly by reducing Tet2 function, a dioxygenase tumour suppressor. Ascorbate depletion cooperated with Flt3ITD leukaemic mutations to accelerate leukaemogenesis, though cell-autonomous and possibly non-cell-autonomous mechanisms, in a manner that was reversed by dietary ascorbate. Ascorbate acted cell-autonomously to negatively regulate HSC function and myelopoiesis through Tet2-dependent and Tet2-independent mechanisms. Ascorbate thus accumulates within HSCs to promote Tet function in vivo, limiting HSC frequency and suppressing leukaemogenesis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23876&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23876&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zKtVciSqncU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Eclipse watchers will go after the biggest solar mystery: Why is the corona so hot?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-hot-corona</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-hot-corona</link>
	<description>Usually when you move away from a heat source, it gets cooler. Not so in the sun’s atmosphere.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-10_main.jpg?itok=aYpg9N9L" length="26846" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Smell as a Weapon, and Odor as Entertainment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-3727540613042333745</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/mn1F_R825R0/smell-as-weapon-and-odor-as.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GHOey04oFr8/WZFvcbz-ijI/AAAAAAAAMOw/aWsnB-EMPEMQU0P3Lc9P0CYtrVvIDPBgACLcBGAs/s1600/blue%2Bfish_Spongebob_Deaugh.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;415&quot; data-original-width=&quot;625&quot; height=&quot;265&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GHOey04oFr8/WZFvcbz-ijI/AAAAAAAAMOw/aWsnB-EMPEMQU0P3Lc9P0CYtrVvIDPBgACLcBGAs/s400/blue%2Bfish_Spongebob_Deaugh.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The use of smell as a weapon, or a deterrent, was explored in a fanciful way in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2017/08/olfactory-deterrence.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Olfactory Deterrence&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on nuclear threats. While poking around the literature, I found a fascinating unclassified document from the Army Research Laboratory, &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.com/books/about/Olfaction_Warfare.html?id=Bmy4oQEACAAJ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Olfaction Warfare: Odor as Sword and Shield&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arl.army.mil/arlreports/2013/ARL-SR-0258.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;). The authors provide a sweeping overview of odor, from chemical tactics in the natural world to the use of scents in the beauty and entertainment industries. The primary military application discussed by Schmeisser et al. (2013) is the use of odor in stealth operations. These are designed to deceive the enemy by masking current location or projecting smells to a false location. Although the document does not propose putrid odor as an offensive weapon, the authors discuss the history of such efforts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stink Bombs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stink bombs are “devices designed to create an unpleasant smell forcing people to leave an area or protecting off-limits areas against being entered.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One unsavory application during WWII was used to make German officers smell like rotten meat, but unfortunately, “this substance was so volatile that it could not be confined to specific targets and contaminated everything in the area.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Another unsuccessful project from 1966 tried to develop “culturally specific stink bombs, which would affect Vietnamese guerillas, leaving the U.S. troops unaffected. The project was abandoned due to technical barriers.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But a more contemporary program reached the pinnacle of olfactory deterrence:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;In 2001 the U.S. announced the development of the ultimate stink bomb aimed at driving away hostile forces by a stench so foul that it results not only in disgust or aversion but also fear. The odorant used in the bomb has been developed by a team of researchers led by Dr. Pamela Dalton at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.monell.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Monell Chemical Senses Center&lt;/a&gt; in Philadelphia and is &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;a mixture of two agents: the U.S. Government Standard Bathroom Malodor (a mixture of eight chemicals with a stench similar to human feces but much stronger) and the Who-Me?, a sulphur-based odorant that smells like rotting carcasses&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;...&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scratch-and-Sniff&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schmeisser et al.'s technical report makes for surprisingly entertaining reading. It's highly unlikely that any other military document praises &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyester_(film)&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Polyester&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, John Waters' 1981 multimodal film event that provided viewers with scratch-and-sniff cards. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The cards had 10 numbered spots (1.roses, 2.flatulence, 3.model airplane glue, 4.pizza, 5.gasoline, 6.skunk, 7.natural gas, 8.new car smell, 9.dirty shoes, and 10.air freshener) that the audience scratched and sniffed when the appropriate number flushed at the corner of the screen. This system, called Odorama, solved the problem with hanging odors that was the main problem of the early smell-distributing systems.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Waters' Odorama succeeded where the older scent distributions systems had failed. Smell-O-Vision (1939) and AromaRama (1959) were financial disasters for movie theaters, because “the odors were weak, the smells persisted longer than was desired, and the molecules were distributed by noisy systems.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Olorama&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Present day technology for odor delivery has advanced beyond scratch-and-sniff, of course, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/smells-in-cinema/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olorama&lt;/a&gt; offers an enhanced cinematic experience (“the smells jump off the screen”). The kits feature “very compact, hidden aromatization devices that are &lt;b&gt;installed under seats&lt;/b&gt; (1 device for every 5-7 seats, depending on their size).”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They also sell a product for home use. Olfactory enhancement of virtual reality is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hitl.washington.edu/people/tfurness/courses/inde543/reports/3doc/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not a new development&lt;/a&gt;, but this VR system looks stylish, at the very least.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uP6UdwVL8LM/WZkK2GB7BoI/AAAAAAAAMPY/oEzXI_C4PEMluR8yy-oEdM7DySGjwjrYACLcBGAs/s1600/Olorama.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;898&quot; data-original-width=&quot;878&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uP6UdwVL8LM/WZkK2GB7BoI/AAAAAAAAMPY/oEzXI_C4PEMluR8yy-oEdM7DySGjwjrYACLcBGAs/s320/Olorama.jpg&quot; width=&quot;312&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olorama Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The company stocks over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.olorama.com/en/list-of-scents/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;70 scents&lt;/a&gt; in categories such as Fantasy, Food, Wild, and...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 style=&quot;font-family: Roboto; font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;ACTION&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;color: #887878; font-size: 15px;&quot;&gt;FIRE - RAIN - FOREST   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(AND COMING SOON...): &lt;br /&gt;GUNPOWDER - BLOOD - BURNING RUBBER &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Schmeisser E, Pollard KA, Letowski T. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arl.army.mil/arlreports/2013/ARL-SR-0258.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Olfaction warfare: odor as sword and shield&lt;/a&gt;. ARMY RESEARCH LAB. ABERDEEN PROVING GROUND MD. HUMAN RESEARCH AND ENGINEERING DIRECTORATE; 2013 Mar.&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=mn1F_R825R0:8q_jkrWMgPk:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/mn1F_R825R0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 04:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: In vivo Phenotypic Screening: Melior Discovery</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1119</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/08/in-vivo-phenotypic-screening-melior-discovery/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;By Natalie Foote, Director of Service Provider Operations, Science Exchange | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/USE-THIS-LOGO-MeliorLogoOutlines-pantone-319.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Melior Logo&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-1120 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;176&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/USE-THIS-LOGO-MeliorLogoOutlines-pantone-319-262x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;154&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Phenotypic Screening Pioneer Launches Novel Analgesia Panel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In this Provider Innovation Profile, we’re proud to feature &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/melior-discovery-inc&quot;&gt;Melior Discovery&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneer of &lt;i&gt;in vivo&lt;/i&gt; phenotypic screening and a leader in the area of drug repositioning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Melior’s platform evaluates compounds through up to 40 different animal models representing 14 broad therapeutic areas, potentially uncovering therapeutic efficacy that might be undetected using traditional assessments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Recently, Melior made the news with its novel opioidTRACE® Analgesic Profiling Platform. Given the need to develop low-abuse analgesics to address the opioid crisis, Melior has configured an &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; platform aimed at specifically profiling opioid therapeutics and related analgesics. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The opioidTRACE® platform addresses the multiple features characteristic of opioids, including rodent models that evaluate acute analgesia, chronic analgesia, respiratory depression, GI mobility, and abuse liability. In addition to opioid testing, Melior has a wide array of animal models of analgesia ranging models of acute pain to chronic neuropathy models. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/opioid-trace-wall.jpg&quot;&gt;[click to view larger view of opioidTRACE® animal models]&lt;img alt=&quot;Opioid Trace In Vivo Models&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-1121&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/opioid-trace-wall-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Backed by Expertise in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In Vivo &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Screening&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Melior’s new panel is just the latest demonstration of the team’s unique know-how in applying “production-mode” methods for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; screening across multiple therapeutic areas. Its proprietary theraTRACE® platform enables rapid and cost-effective identification of new therapeutic potential by systematically screening candidates in a diverse array of validated &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; disease models. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fibrosis is another disease area for which Melior’s panels have exemplified the utility of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;in vivo &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; phenotypic screening. Melior has validated models of liver and lung fibrosis; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/melior-discovery-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;download the validation data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; for these models from the Resources section of Melior’s Science Exchange storefront.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Why Requesters are Choosing Melior for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In vivo &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Melior’s capability directly translates to efficiencies combined with high levels of quality for their clients. Positive ratings and testimonials illustrate the benefits that attract repeat business for Melior:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;High reproducibility and predictive power of in vivo methodologies, models, and assays assuring high quality of data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Lower overall costs resulting from the availability of highly cost effective preclinical services from Melior&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Rapid responses to requests for service and quick turnaround times for preclinical studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Ability to rapidly customize, design, and modify models in response to requests for specialized in vivo services or changes in protocols or unexpected results at any stage of the study&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Sridharan Rajamani, Senior Research Scientist at Gilead Sciences, said that his team chose Melior Discovery because they were responsive and cost effective.  “We are staying with them as a chosen scientific partner because of their thoughtful scientific input to experimental design and attention to detail,” said Dr. Rajamani. “Their expertise and flexibility allowed us to quickly adapt the study design and evaluate additional outcome measures to pursue unexpected activity.”  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Interested in working with Melior Discovery? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/melior-discovery-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Request a quote&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to start the discussion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 03:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: US government disbands climate-science advisory committee</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22484</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/A5w-bXgm0Q8/nature.2017.22484</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Panel sought to help businesses and state and local governments prepare for the effects of global warming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22484&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/A5w-bXgm0Q8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: A troubling precedent out of China; journals as corporate tools; postdocs and suicide</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51485</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/19/weekend-reads-troubling-precedent-china-journals-corporate-tools-postdocs-suicide/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of a paper linked to vaccines, and what happens when a journal retracts 107 papers at once. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Cambridge University Press pulls hundreds of papers from one of its journals on topics the Chinese government deemed politically sensitive. (Holly Else, Times Higher Education) […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/19/weekend-reads-troubling-precedent-china-journals-corporate-tools-postdocs-suicide/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A troubling precedent out of China; journals as corporate tools; postdocs and suicide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Does the corona look different when solar activity is high versus when it’s low?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-cycles</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-cycles</link>
	<description>Carbondale, Ill., will get two eclipses in a row, seven years apart — making it the perfect spot to watch the solar cycle in action.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-9_main_A.jpg?itok=BA6q0mtO" length="21732" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Cosmic lens lets astronomers zoom in on a black hole’s burps</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gravitational-lens-black-hole-astronomy</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gravitational-lens-black-hole-astronomy</link>
	<description>The beginnings of a jet from an active black hole in a distant galaxy were spotted thanks to a lucky alignment.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 21:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081817_LG_gravitational-lensing_main.jpg?itok=B9Vz5VN8" length="8783" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here are the paths of the next 15 total solar eclipses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-total-solar-eclipses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-total-solar-eclipses</link>
	<description>From 2017 to 2040, there will be 15 total solar eclipses. Here's a map of where to see them.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 18:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080517_sciviz_screenshot-main-1200.jpg?itok=7I-frFYe" length="32842" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal knew about problems in a high-profile study before it came out — and did nothing for over a month</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51479</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/18/journal-knew-problems-high-profile-study-came-nothing-month/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In June, Gene Emery, a journalist for Reuters Health, was assigned to write a story about an upcoming paper in the Journal of the American College of Cardiology, set to come off embargo and be released to the public in a few days. Pretty quickly, he noticed something seemed off. Emery saw that the data […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/18/journal-knew-problems-high-profile-study-came-nothing-month/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal knew about problems in a high-profile study before it came out — and did nothing for over a month&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 14:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: We share the Milky Way with 100 million black holes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/we-share-milky-way-100-million-black-holes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/we-share-milky-way-100-million-black-holes</link>
	<description>New census calculates black hole populations in galaxies big and small.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081717_ec_Milky-Way_free.jpg?itok=gfVyn7qF" length="27277" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Curious: A paper’s acknowledgments harshly criticized Spanish gov’t funding. Now two authors object.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51466</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/18/curious-papers-acknowledgments-harshly-criticized-spanish-govt-funding-now-two-authors-object/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, researchers condemned the Spanish Government for “destroying the R&amp;amp;D horizon of Spain and the future of a complete generation” in the acknowledgment section of a paper about wireless networks. Three years later, the two last authors of the paper are protesting that protest, issuing a correction to alert readers that they did not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/18/curious-papers-acknowledgments-harshly-criticized-spanish-govt-funding-now-two-authors-object/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Curious: A paper’s acknowledgments harshly criticized Spanish gov’t funding. Now two authors object.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 12:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Where does the solar wind come from? The eclipse may offer answers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-wind</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-wind</link>
	<description>A quick-fire polarization camera should help scientists detect the origins of the solar wind during the Aug. 21 eclipse.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-8_main.jpg?itok=Pv03uiF6" length="21890" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Ecology Image Competition 2017: the winning images!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9420</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/18/bmc-ecology-image-competition-2017-the-winning-images/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Ribbet-collage-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our 5th annual image competition we once again received terrific entries from talented shutterbug-ecologists from across the world. Anyone affiliated with a research institute was able to enter and we were amazed at the quality and variety of submissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guest judge, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.web.uvic.ca/~darimont/&quot;&gt;Chris Darimont &lt;/a&gt;of the University of Victoria, Canada picked out the overall winners, while our &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/about/editorial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Section Editors&lt;/a&gt; picked the best images from their sections of the journal. For more on the reasoning behind their choices, please do read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0138-8&quot;&gt;accompanying editorial&lt;/a&gt;. This also includes our selection of 24 highly commended images – there are some really great photos, so do take a look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are our eight winning images:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall winner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our winning image was this photo of giant South American turtles (&lt;em&gt;Podocnemis expansa&lt;/em&gt;) taken by Ana Carolina Lima of the University of Aveiro, Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9422&quot; style=&quot;width: 4175px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9422&quot; height=&quot;2902&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-1_Overall-winner_Podocnemis-expansa_Ana-Carolina-Lima​.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4165&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Overall winner&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Ana Carolina Lima&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christin Säwström of Edith Cowan University, Western Australia captured the austere landscape of the Antarctic in her photo ‘Two Towers’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9423&quot; style=&quot;width: 2602px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9423&quot; height=&quot;1944&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2592&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;First runner-up&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Christin Säwström&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second runner-up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An image by Roberto García-Roa of the University of Valencia, Spain entitled ‘Connections’, showing a remarkable series of ecological interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9424&quot; style=&quot;width: 5268px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9424&quot; height=&quot;3505&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;5258&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Second runner-up&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Roberto García-Roa &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conservation Ecology and Biodiversity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our winner in this category was by Zhigang Jiang of the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, with his image of a male Tibetan antelope guarding his harem of females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9425&quot; style=&quot;width: 4906px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9425&quot; height=&quot;3264&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Conservation-winner-Tibetan-Antelope-by-Zhigang-Jiang.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4896&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Conservation ecology and biodiversity winner.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Zhigang Jiang &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavioral and Physiological Ecology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maïlis Huguin from the Institut Pasteur de la Guyane, French Guiana won this category with his image, ‘Wakeful’, of a lone ant defending its territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9426&quot; style=&quot;width: 3372px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9426&quot; height=&quot;5042&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3362&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Behavioral ecology and physiology winner.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Maïlis Huguin &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landscape Ecology and Ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winning image in this category was an image from Mount Teide, the huge volcano located on Tenerife, captured by Harry Seijmonsbergen from the University of Amsterdam, Holland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9427&quot; style=&quot;width: 2085px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9427&quot; height=&quot;1497&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2075&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Landscape Ecology and Ecosystems winner.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Harry Seijmonsbergen &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community, Population, and Macroecology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our winner in this category, entitled ‘Catchers on a hot tin roof’, was this photo of a group of oyster catchers assembling in the morning sun, taken by Trevor Sherwin of the University of Auckland, New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9428&quot; style=&quot;width: 8010px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9428&quot; height=&quot;4638&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;8000&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Community, Population and Macroecology winner.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Trevor Sherwin&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor’s pick&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, play ‘spot the octopus’ with this image by Michelle Achlatis of the University of Queensland in Australia entitled ‘A “well-armed” coral reef community’ (&lt;em&gt;if you are having trouble finding it, look for the eye exactly in the middle of the picture&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9429&quot; style=&quot;width: 6676px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9429&quot; height=&quot;5000&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-8_Editors-pick-_A-well-armed-coral-reef_Michelle-Achlatis.jpg&quot; width=&quot;6666&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Winner, Editor’s pick&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Michelle Achlatis &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all of our winners. Their images, along with our highly commended entries, have been released under a Creative Commons Attribution License (&lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY&lt;/a&gt;), so everyone is welcome and encouraged to share them freely, as long as you clearly attribute the image author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/18/bmc-ecology-image-competition-2017-the-winning-images/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Ecology Image Competition 2017: the winning images!&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Ribbet-collage-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Hate sport? Maybe it’s because you have the genes that make exercise feel awful</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28970</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/18/hate-sport-maybe-its-because-you-have-the-genes-that-make-exercise-feel-awful/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-477104912.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28987&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28987&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;6.7&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 60D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Funny sport man try to doing fitness - exercising, feel the pain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1433617824&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Alen-D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;25&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Funny sport man&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Funny sport man&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-477104912.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-477104912.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-477104912.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2035,1473&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/18/hate-sport-maybe-its-because-you-have-the-genes-that-make-exercise-feel-awful/funny-sport-man/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-477104912.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you seen those people who come out of an exercise class with a spring in their step and self-satisfied smile on their face? They really pushed themselves this time and now they’re riding that endorphin high. To them, the ache and burn feels good. But it’s not so for everyone. Others find exercise unpleasant and unrewarding – the aches just, well, ache. Psychologists call this difference the “affective response to exercise” and in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1469029216303119?utm_content=buffer6b41d&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Psychology of Sport and Exercise&lt;/em&gt; researchers in the Netherlands report new evidence that it is to a significant degree genetically inherited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28970&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nienke Schutte at VU University Amsterdam and his colleagues recruited 115 pairs of identical twins who share the same genes, 111 pairs of non-identical siblings who share roughly half their genes, 35 of their non-twin siblings, and another 6 non-twin sibling pairs (aged 12 to 25). The participants completed a 20 minute non-vigorous ride on an exercise bike and a non-vigorous 20 minute treadmill run. Their breathing was monitored to ensure the exercise didn’t become vigorous. There were also warm up and warm down periods and there was a second brief exercise ride to exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While exercising, participants periodically rated how they were feeling on a scale from very bad to very good, how much they felt they were exerting themselves, and how much they were feeling various adjectival states, such as energetic, lively, jittery or tense. From these measures the researchers established the participants’ affective response to exercise. The researchers also interviewed the participants about how much and how often they participated in voluntary sport and exercise in their everyday lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By looking to see if affective response to exercise was more similar between identical twins than non-identical twins, the researchers were able to deduce how much it is genetically inherited (its “heritability” – in other words, how much the differences in the subjective experience of exercise between people is due to genetic influences).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heritability for the affective response to exercise was significant. For instance, using the simple feeling scale, heritability was 15 per cent for the moderate cycle; for perceived exertion during the treadmill it was 35 per cent; and for the adjectival rating scale, heritability varied from 17 to 37 per cent for non-vigorous exercise, and 12 to 37 per cent for the ride to exhaustion, with the figure depending on the adjectives looked at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, and as logic would dictate, affective response to exercise correlated positively with how much exercise the participants did in their everyday lives: those who found exercise more pleasant engaged in more exercise. And the analysis suggested genetic overlap between these measures: in other words, many of the same genes that influence the affective experience of exercise seem to be the same genes that influence how active people are in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One caveat: causal direction hasn’t been established here. It’s possible that doing more exercise can change how we experience exercise. In which case perhaps it is the known heritability of inclination to do exercise that is driving the apparent heritability of the affective response to exercise. Likely the influences are mutual. Another possibility is genetic pleiotropy in which the same genes have separate effects on different outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study has uncovered a point of principle – that whether we experience exercise as pleasant or unpleasant is to a significant degree influenced by our genes. Establishing what those specific genes are, and what their other functions might be, is for the future. One candidate gene that the researchers mention is the gene that codes for brain-derived neurotrophic factor, a peptide that has been shown to moderate the influence of exercise on mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most interesting is the practical implications this line of research could have for interventions to help people take up more exercise. If some of us are genetically inclined to find exercise less fun and rewarding we might especially benefit from personalised exercise programmes that aim to reduce its arduousness and make it as enjoyable as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1469029216303119?utm_content=buffer6b41d&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;Heritability of the affective response to exercise and its correlation to exercise behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28970/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28970/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28970&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 07:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Anglers' online boasts reveal illegal shark hunting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22475</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/7_FVU11lNQY/nature.2017.22475</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers fear sport fishing is a serious threat to endangered species — but study of Internet forum also finds awareness of environmental issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22475&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22475&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/7_FVU11lNQY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Eclipses show wrong physics can give right results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/eclipses-show-wrong-physics-can-give-right-results</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/eclipses-show-wrong-physics-can-give-right-results</link>
	<description>Math for making astronomical predictions doesn’t necessarily reflect physical reality.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 19:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/060717_LG_white-dwarf_main_free.jpg?itok=0DErtT1g" length="17777" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Embryos kill off male tissue to become female</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/embryos-kill-male-tissue-become-female</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/embryos-kill-male-tissue-become-female</link>
	<description>Female embryos actively dismantle male reproductive tissue, a textbook-challenging study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 18:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081617_TI_girl-protein_main_free_ALT.jpg?itok=sJQ5W90S" length="14282" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How an itch hitches a ride to the brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-itch-hitches-ride-brain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-itch-hitches-ride-brain</link>
	<description>Scientists have figured out how your brain registers the sensation of itch.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 18:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081717_LH_itch_main_free.jpg?itok=PtoZmKmi" length="16568" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Recent finding of misconduct by federal U.S. agency sparks debate</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51465</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/17/recent-finding-misconduct-federal-u-s-agency-sparks-debate/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2011, the University of Florida assembled a misconduct report about one of its ob-gyn researchers, identifying falsified data in a 2010 paper. But when an investigator at the U.S. Office of Research Integrity reviewed the report, something didn’t feel right. “I reviewed the data, and I thought [UF] didn’t do their due diligence,” said […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/17/recent-finding-misconduct-federal-u-s-agency-sparks-debate/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Recent finding of misconduct by federal U.S. agency sparks debate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 15:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lost citation snuffs out Aussie fire paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51452</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/17/lost-citation-snuffs-aussie-fire-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal has retracted a 2016 paper on wildfires in Australia because the authors neglected to cite earlier work — an unintentional lapse, they said. The article, “Projected changes in Australian fire regimes during the 21st century and consequences for Ecosystems,” appeared in the International Journal of Wildland Fire. The authors are Sandy Harrison and Douglas […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/17/lost-citation-snuffs-aussie-fire-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lost citation snuffs out Aussie fire paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How technology empowers healthcare providers to achieve accessibility, affordability and availability</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-technology-empowers-healthcare-providers-to-achieve-accessibility-affordability-and-availability</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-technology-empowers-healthcare-providers-to-achieve-accessibility-affordability-and-availability</link>
	<description>Elsevier’s Director of Clinical Solutions and Product Strategy shares the perspective of developing markets</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 11:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Why are the loops in the sun’s atmosphere so neat and tidy?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-loops</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-loops</link>
	<description>Observations during the total solar eclipse may explain why the sun’s atmosphere is so organized despite arising from a tangled magnetic field.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-7_main_C.jpg?itok=Eka_AnO2" length="29009" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: MDMA/Ecstasy may boost psychotherapy by increasing clients’ openness</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28767</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/17/mdmaecstasy-may-boost-psychotherapy-by-increasing-clients-openness/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-488358430.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28882&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28882&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Infinite Flower optical illusion design in magenta, purple and yellow.  Colors are grouped for easy editing. Zip folder includes AI8 .eps and 5100x5100px .jpeg.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LisaAFischer&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Infinite Flower&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Infinite Flower&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-488358430.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-488358430.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-488358430.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/17/mdmaecstasy-may-boost-psychotherapy-by-increasing-clients-openness/infinite-flower/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-488358430.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3122379/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3573678/&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt; that MDMA (3,4-Methylenedioxymethamphetamine; also known as Ecstasy) can act as a catalyst for psychotherapy, apparently improving outcomes for clients with previously intractable PTSD (post-traumatic stress disorder). Now &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0269881117711712&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; from the same group in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychopharmacology&lt;/em&gt; has uncovered what may be the key psychological mechanism: lasting positive personality change, especially increased trait Openness to Experience and reduced trait Neuroticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speculating as to how MDMA might facilitate these trait changes, the research team, led by Mark Wagner at the Medical University of South Carolina, and including Ann Mithoefer and Michael Mithoefer who’ve conducted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maps.org/research/mdma&quot;&gt;a lot of the recent pioneering research on MDMA-assisted psychotherapy&lt;/a&gt;, observed that “Qualitatively, a consistent subjective theme emerged, with our subjects reporting a profound cathartic experience, often described as going to a ‘place’ (in their mind) where they had never been before”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28767&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data come from earlier research that involved twenty participants (17 women) with a diagnosis of PTSD related to crime or war-based traumatic experiences and which had so far been untreatable with either drugs or psychotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants took part in up to 12 sessions of psychotherapy with a pair of therapists working together. Crucially, during two key experimental eight-hour long sessions in the middle of the course of therapy, half the participants received a dose of MDMA (125mg, with the option of a 62.5mg supplement), the others received an inert placebo. Among its effects MDMA can increase feelings of love, empathy, trust and friendliness and reduce fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these key sessions, all participants were encouraged to introspect and were helped to process traumatic memories and experiences using cognitive restructuring and other techniques (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maps.org/news-letters/v23n1/v23n1_p10-14.pdf&quot;&gt;more detail&lt;/a&gt;). In a later phase of the trial, those participants previously in the placebo group were given the option to take part in MDMA-assisted psychotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from earlier published reports that the participants who took MDMA during the experimental psychotherapy sessions showed significantly improved and lasting recovery from PTSD compared with participants who took placebo (and there was no apparent harm from the drug). What’s new is that the researchers have now reanalysed the data, adding personality trait scores taken through questionnaires at baseline and two-month follow-up as covariates – allowing them to see if changes in personality traits appeared to be important for the differences in symptom outcome for the two groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what they found. When adjusting the data to account for group differences in change to Openness to Experience scores, there was no longer a recovery outcome difference between the MDMA and placebo groups. This suggests MDMA is catalysing psychotherapy by facilitating increased Openness in clients. Indeed, across groups, greater increases in Openness correlated with greater symptom improvement. The same patterns were true for reduced Neuroticism but to a lesser extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new results complement past research that has suggested in some cases the symptoms of PTSD, including chronic social withdrawal and mistrust and feelings of estrangement, can manifest as lasting harmful personality change. It seems MDMA-assisted psychotherapy may help reverse the harmful personality changes sometimes associated with trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Individuals scoring higher on Openness tend to seek out new experiences and be open to self-examination, factors that can serve to enhance therapeutic change in both behaviors and cognitions,” the researchers said. “Qualitatively, and consistently with previous work, therapeutic change seemed to be associated with an epiphany-type experience that subjects consistently reported following the MDMA-assisted psychotherapy sessions and reiterated in the long-term follow-up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously this was a small study and the findings are at a very early experimental stage;  larger replication attempts are needed. A methodological shortcoming was that sometimes the participants and clients were able to correctly guess which group (MDMA or placebo) they were in. The researchers also caution that MDMA may not have beneficial epiphany-related effects outside of a psychotherapy context, in fact the opposite could occur (they added that medically managed MDMA is not the same as street Ecstasy which will be of unknown strength and may contain other ingredients which may be harmful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0269881117711712&quot;&gt;Therapeutic effect of increased openness: Investigating mechanism of action in MDMA-assisted psychotherapy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.talktofrank.com/drug/ecstasy&quot;&gt;Information on MDMA/Ecstasy from the drug advice charity Frank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28767/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28767/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28767&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 09:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Supernova’s messy birth casts doubt on reliability of astronomical yardstick</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22066</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rAaPLs-az8w/nature.2017.22066</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Brightness of exploding stars may vary more than researchers realized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22066&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22066&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rAaPLs-az8w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new tool could one day improve Lyme disease diagnosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-tool-could-one-day-improve-lyme-disease-diagnosis</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-tool-could-one-day-improve-lyme-disease-diagnosis</link>
	<description>There soon could be a way to differentiate between Lyme disease and a similar tick-associated illness.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 20:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081517_AC_lyme_main.jpg?itok=lJTAXMUw" length="40126" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Giant larvaceans could be ferrying ocean plastic to the seafloor</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/giant-larvaceans-could-be-ferrying-ocean-plastic-seafloor</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/giant-larvaceans-could-be-ferrying-ocean-plastic-seafloor</link>
	<description>Giant larvaceans could mistakenly capture microplastics, in addition to food, in their mucus houses and transfer them to the seafloor in their feces.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 19:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/081617_ht_larvaceanplastic_mainA.jpg?itok=dO6_4pxK" length="15113" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Robot, heal thyself</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robot-heal-thyself</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robot-heal-thyself</link>
	<description>Self-healing material is helping make more resilient robots.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 18:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081517_MT_soft-bot_main.jpg?itok=ADordryg" length="22362" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When a journal retracts 107 papers for fake reviews, it pays a price</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51443</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/16/journal-retracts-107-papers-fake-reviews-pays-price/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A company that indexes journals — thereby assigning them impact factors — has chosen to delist a cancer journal after it retracted 107 papers earlier this year for faked peer reviews. Starting July 19, anything published by Tumor Biology will not be indexed in Web of Science, part of Clarivate Analytics (formerly part of Thomson […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/16/journal-retracts-107-papers-fake-reviews-pays-price/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When a journal retracts 107 papers for fake reviews, it pays a price&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 15:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: More on &quot;Behavior Priming&quot; and Unconscious Influences</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9044</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9044</link>
	<description>Last year, psychologists B. Keith Payne and colleagues breathed new life into the debate over 'social priming' with a paper called Replicable effects of primes on human behavior.



Behavioral or social priming - the idea that subtle cues can exert large, unconscious influences on our behaviour - was a major topic of research for many years, but it's since been largely discredited. The field’s reputation suffered when Diederik Stapel, a leader in the field, was exposed as a fraud. Many resea</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 15:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Genetic disorder gets name change, but patient’s father still not happy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51438</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/16/genetic-disorder-gets-name-change-patients-father-still-not-happy/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The leading genetic disease database has chosen a new name for a genetic condition, following complaints from a man whose son has the condition. On Aug. 11, 2017, two days after our coverage of the situation, the Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man (OMIM) database changed the primary name of the phenotype associated with mutations in […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/16/genetic-disorder-gets-name-change-patients-father-still-not-happy/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Genetic disorder gets name change, but patient’s father still not happy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Protect little ones’ eyes from the sun during the eclipse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/protect-kids-eyes-sun-during-eclipse</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/protect-kids-eyes-sun-during-eclipse</link>
	<description>Pay attention to eye safety for kids during the solar eclipse.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/081517_ls_kid-safety_free.jpg?itok=_EqGNApQ" length="46741" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Video blog: Eating with your eyes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9436</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/16/video-blog-eating-with-your-eyes/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/16/video-blog-eating-with-your-eyes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video blog: Eating with your eyes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 11:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What can the eclipse tell us about the corona’s magnetic field?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-magnetic-field</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-solar-magnetic-field</link>
	<description>The corona’s plasma jumps and dances thanks to the magnetic field, but scientists have never measured the field directly.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-6_main_A.jpg?itok=qIWeLj8L" length="60469" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: More intelligent people are quicker to learn (and unlearn) social stereotypes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28731</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/16/more-intelligent-people-are-quicker-to-learn-and-unlearn-social-stereotypes/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-489205086.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28760&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28760&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Ethnic equality concept and racial justice symbol as a black and white crumpled paper shaped as a human head on old rustic wood background with contrasting tones as a metaphor for social race issues.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;wildpixel&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Ethnic Equality&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Ethnic Equality&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-489205086.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-489205086.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-489205086.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2093,1433&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/16/more-intelligent-people-are-quicker-to-learn-and-unlearn-social-stereotypes/ethnic-equality/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-489205086.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart people tend to perform better at work, earn more money, be physically healthier, and be less likely to subscribe to authoritarian beliefs. But a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31437-001&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; reveals that a key aspect of intelligence – a strong “pattern-matching” ability, which helps someone readily learn a language, understand how another person is feeling or spot a stock market trend to exploit – has a darker side: it also makes that person more likely to learn and apply social stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies exploring how a person’s cognitive abilities may affect their attitudes to other people have produced mixed results. But this might be because the questions asked in these studies were too broad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new study, published in the&lt;em&gt; Journal of Experimental Biology&lt;/em&gt;, David Lick, Adam Alter and Jonathan Freeman at New York University decided to home in on social stereotyping. “Because pattern detection is a core component of human intelligence, people with superior cognitive abilities may be equipped to efficiently learn and use stereotypes about social groups,” they theorised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28731&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explore this, they conducted a total of six online studies involving 1,257 people recruited via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk survey website. In the first two studies, volunteers saw pictures of aliens that varied on four dimensions (colour, face shape, eye size, ears), with most of the blue aliens  paired with an “unfriendly” behaviour (like “spat in another alien’s face”) and most of the yellow aliens paired with a friendly behaviour (like “gave another alien a bouquet of flowers”). The volunteers also completed items from Raven’s Advanced Progressive Matrices, which assesses pattern-matching ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A subsequent memory test involved the same participants attempting to pair previously seen faces with their earlier behaviours, but there were also some new blue and yellow faces that actually they hadn’t seen before.  Participants who were better at pattern-matching were more likely to attribute unfriendly behaviours to new blue aliens than to new yellow aliens – suggesting that they’d learned colour–behaviour stereotypes more readily, and applied them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In studies three and four, volunteers were instead shown realistic pictures of male human faces. The displays were manipulated, so that most of the faces with a wide nose (for some participants) or a narrow nose (for others) were paired with negative behaviours – like “laughed and jeered at a homeless person”. Most of the faces with the other nose type were paired with friendly behaviours – like “sent flowers to someone who was sick”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After viewing the faces, the volunteers played a trust game involving sharing money. They were led to believe this was an unrelated interlude in the study. Before the game began, they chose an avatar from a large group of faces to represent them online. They then played 12 rounds of what they believed was a real game, each time with a different partner who was represented by their own avatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the volunteers weren’t playing with real partners, and the experimenters manipulated the “partners’'” avatar photos, so that some had wider noses, and some had narrower noses (there were also female “partners” whose nose width did not systematically vary). The team found that volunteers who did better on the test of pattern detection gave less money to partners whose avatars had a nose width related, in the earlier trial, to unfriendly behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when these volunteers were given new information that contradicted the stereotype they had implicitly developed, the better pattern-detectors were also quicker to update their stereotype – to reverse their biases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a final experiment, the team used a real-world set of stereotypes, relating to traits they believe are often associated with men (such as being more authoritative) and with women (such as being more submissive). After counter-stereotype training – effectively being told that being authoritative is more associated with women rather than men, for example – good pattern-detectors showed a stronger decrease in stereotyping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To our knowledge, these findings are the first to systematically demonstrate that cognitive ability is associated with greater stereotyping,” the researchers write, before adding, “people with superior pattern detection abilities appear to act as naive empiricists, both learning and updating their stereotypes based on incoming information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While existing research tends to focus on the benefits of intelligence, these “findings join a small body of work guiding the field toward a more balanced understanding of the consequences of human aptitudes,” they note. For example, it’s also been suggested that superior, misguided, pattern-matching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19969378&quot;&gt;may play a role in obsessive-compulsive disorder&lt;/a&gt; (OCD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31437-001&quot;&gt;Superior Pattern Detectors Efficiently Learn, Activate, Apply, and Update Social Stereotypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28731/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28731/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28731&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 08:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Revitalize the world’s countryside</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548275a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/fshMlzWJ4c4/548275a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A rural revival is needed to counter urbanization across the globe, say Yansui Liu and Yuheng Li.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 275 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548275a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548275a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/fshMlzWJ4c4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: China’s embrace of embryo selection raises thorny questions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548272a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PPxS5IzZAO4/548272a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Fertility centres are making a massive push to increase preimplantation genetic diagnosis in a bid to eradicate certain diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 272 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548272a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548272a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PPxS5IzZAO4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: China launches brain-imaging factory</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548268a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MqNgnE-JoXg/548268a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hub aims to make industrial-scale high-resolution brain mapping a standard tool for neuroscience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 268 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548268a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548268a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MqNgnE-JoXg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: California scientists push to create massive climate-research programme</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548267a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3gCS19Nh9e4/548267a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Effort backed by the state’s flagship universities comes as US President Donald Trump shrugs off global warming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 267 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548267a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548267a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3gCS19Nh9e4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Opioid emergency, climate language and a frozen fruit cake</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548264a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/aBXFVn982NA/548264a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 11–17 August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 264 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548264a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548264a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/aBXFVn982NA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Against discrimination</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548259b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/uGqrNN0rxog/548259b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Science cannot and should not be used to justify prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 259 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548259b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548259b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/uGqrNN0rxog&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Identification of CMTM6 and CMTM4 as PD-L1 protein regulators</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23669</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Ifm7W1OBe-M/nature23669</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The clinical benefit for patients with diverse types of metastatic cancers that has been observed upon blockade of the interaction between PD-1 and PD-L1 has highlighted the importance of this inhibitory axis in the suppression of tumour-specific T-cell responses. Notwithstanding the key role of PD-L1 expression by cells within the tumour micro-environment, our understanding of the regulation of the PD-L1 protein is limited. Here we identify, using a haploid genetic screen, CMTM6, a type-3 transmembrane protein of previously unknown function, as a regulator of the PD-L1 protein. Interference with CMTM6 expression results in impaired PD-L1 protein expression in all human tumour cell types tested and in primary human dendritic cells. Furthermore, through both a haploid genetic modifier screen in CMTM6-deficient cells and genetic complementation experiments, we demonstrate that this function is shared by its closest family member, CMTM4, but not by any of the other CMTM members tested. Notably, CMTM6 increases the PD-L1 protein pool without affecting PD-L1 (also known as CD274) transcription levels. Rather, we demonstrate that CMTM6 is present at the cell surface, associates with the PD-L1 protein, reduces its ubiquitination and increases PD-L1 protein half-life. Consistent with its role in PD-L1 protein regulation, CMTM6 enhances the ability of PD-L1-expressing tumour cells to inhibit T cells. Collectively, our data reveal that PD-L1 relies on CMTM6/4 to efficiently carry out its inhibitory function, and suggest potential new avenues to block this pathway. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23669&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23669&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Ifm7W1OBe-M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Polylox barcoding reveals haematopoietic stem cell fates realized in vivo</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23653</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Dj9_J8C1H0U/nature23653</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Developmental deconvolution of complex organs and tissues at the level of individual cells remains challenging. Non-invasive genetic fate mapping has been widely used, but the low number of distinct fluorescent marker proteins limits its resolution. Much higher numbers of cell markers have been generated using viral integration sites, viral barcodes, and strategies based on transposons and CRISPR–Cas9 genome editing; however, temporal and tissue-specific induction of barcodes in situ has not been achieved. Here we report the development of an artificial DNA recombination locus (termed Polylox) that enables broadly applicable endogenous barcoding based on the Cre–loxP recombination system. Polylox recombination in situ reaches a practical diversity of several hundred thousand barcodes, allowing tagging of single cells. We have used this experimental system, combined with fate mapping, to assess haematopoietic stem cell (HSC) fates in vivo. Classical models of haematopoietic lineage specification assume a tree with few major branches. More recently, driven in part by the development of more efficient single-cell assays and improved transplantation efficiencies, different models have been proposed, in which unilineage priming may occur in mice and humans at the level of HSCs. We have introduced barcodes into HSC progenitors in embryonic mice, and found that the adult HSC compartment is a mosaic of embryo-derived HSC clones, some of which are unexpectedly large. Most HSC clones gave rise to multilineage or oligolineage fates, arguing against unilineage priming, and suggesting coherent usage of the potential of cells in a clone. The spreading of barcodes, both after induction in embryos and in adult mice, revealed a basic split between common myeloid–erythroid development and common lymphocyte development, supporting the long-held but contested view of a tree-like haematopoietic structure. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23653&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23653&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Dj9_J8C1H0U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Mechanism of intracellular allosteric β2AR antagonist revealed by X-ray crystal structure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23652</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/AIpb0mJnXxs/nature23652</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 G-protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) pose challenges for drug discovery efforts because of the high degree of structural homology in the orthosteric pocket, particularly for GPCRs within a single subfamily, such as the nine adrenergic receptors. Allosteric ligands may bind to less-conserved regions of these receptors and therefore are more likely to be selective. Unlike orthosteric ligands, which tonically activate or inhibit signalling, allosteric ligands modulate physiologic responses to hormones and neurotransmitters, and may therefore have fewer adverse effects. The majority of GPCR crystal structures published to date were obtained with receptors bound to orthosteric antagonists, and only a few structures bound to allosteric ligands have been reported. Compound 15 (Cmpd-15) is an allosteric modulator of the β2 adrenergic receptor (β2AR) that was recently isolated from a DNA-encoded small-molecule library. Orthosteric β-adrenergic receptor antagonists, known as beta-blockers, are amongst the most prescribed drugs in the world and Cmpd-15 is the first allosteric beta-blocker. Cmpd-15 exhibits negative cooperativity with agonists and positive cooperativity with inverse agonists. Here we present the structure of the β2AR bound to a polyethylene glycol-carboxylic acid derivative (Cmpd-15PA) of this modulator. Cmpd-15PA binds to a pocket formed primarily by the cytoplasmic ends of transmembrane segments 1, 2, 6 and 7 as well as intracellular loop 1 and helix 8. A comparison of this structure with inactive- and active-state structures of the β2AR reveals the mechanism by which Cmpd-15 modulates agonist binding affinity and signalling. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23652&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23652&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/AIpb0mJnXxs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: CMTM6 maintains the expression of PD-L1 and regulates anti-tumour immunity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23643</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/A_4Jw-DOLws/nature23643</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Cancer cells exploit the expression of the programmed death-1 (PD-1) ligand 1 (PD-L1) to subvert T-cell-mediated immunosurveillance. The success of therapies that disrupt PD-L1-mediated tumour tolerance has highlighted the need to understand the molecular regulation of PD-L1 expression. Here we identify the uncharacterized protein CMTM6 as a critical regulator of PD-L1 in a broad range of cancer cells, by using a genome-wide CRISPR–Cas9 screen. CMTM6 is a ubiquitously expressed protein that binds PD-L1 and maintains its cell surface expression. CMTM6 is not required for PD-L1 maturation but co-localizes with PD-L1 at the plasma membrane and in recycling endosomes, where it prevents PD-L1 from being targeted for lysosome-mediated degradation. Using a quantitative approach to profile the entire plasma membrane proteome, we find that CMTM6 displays specificity for PD-L1. Notably, CMTM6 depletion decreases PD-L1 without compromising cell surface expression of MHC class I. CMTM6 depletion, via the reduction of PD-L1, significantly alleviates the suppression of tumour-specific T cell activity in vitro and in vivo. These findings provide insights into the biology of PD-L1 regulation, identify a previously unrecognized master regulator of this critical immune checkpoint and highlight a potential therapeutic target to overcome immune evasion by tumour cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23643&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23643&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/A_4Jw-DOLws&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Stromal R-spondin orchestrates gastric epithelial stem cells and gland homeostasis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23642</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5vrgDODtADk/nature23642</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The constant regeneration of stomach epithelium is driven by long-lived stem cells, but the mechanism that regulates their turnover is not well understood. We have recently found that the gastric pathogen Helicobacter pylori can activate gastric stem cells and increase epithelial turnover, while Wnt signalling is known to be important for stem cell identity and epithelial regeneration in several tissues. Here we find that antral Wnt signalling, marked by the classic Wnt target gene Axin2, is limited to the base and lower isthmus of gastric glands, where the stem cells reside. Axin2 is expressed by Lgr5+ cells, as well as adjacent, highly proliferative Lgr5− cells that are able to repopulate entire glands, including the base, upon depletion of the Lgr5+ population. Expression of both Axin2 and Lgr5 requires stroma-derived R-spondin 3 produced by gastric myofibroblasts proximal to the stem cell compartment. Exogenous R-spondin administration expands and accelerates proliferation of Axin2+/Lgr5− but not Lgr5+ cells. Consistent with these observations, H. pylori infection increases stromal R-spondin 3 expression and expands the Axin2+ cell pool to cause hyperproliferation and gland hyperplasia. The ability of stromal niche cells to control and adapt epithelial stem cell dynamics constitutes a sophisticated mechanism that orchestrates epithelial regeneration and maintenance of tissue integrity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23642&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23642&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5vrgDODtADk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: The primed SNARE–complexin–synaptotagmin complex for neuronal exocytosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23484</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/IJyIh9lSbd4/nature23484</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Synaptotagmin, complexin, and neuronal SNARE (soluble N-ethylmaleimide sensitive factor attachment protein receptor) proteins mediate evoked synchronous neurotransmitter release, but the molecular mechanisms mediating the cooperation between these molecules remain unclear. Here we determine crystal structures of the primed pre-fusion SNARE–complexin–synaptotagmin-1 complex. These structures reveal an unexpected tripartite interface between synaptotagmin-1 and both the SNARE complex and complexin. Simultaneously, a second synaptotagmin-1 molecule interacts with the other side of the SNARE complex via the previously identified primary interface. Mutations that disrupt either interface in solution also severely impair evoked synchronous release in neurons, suggesting that both interfaces are essential for the primed pre-fusion state. Ca2+ binding to the synaptotagmin-1 molecules unlocks the complex, allows full zippering of the SNARE complex, and triggers membrane fusion. The tripartite SNARE–complexin–synaptotagmin-1 complex at a synaptic vesicle docking site has to be unlocked for triggered fusion to start, explaining the cooperation between complexin and synaptotagmin-1 in synchronizing evoked release on the sub-millisecond timescale. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23484&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/IJyIh9lSbd4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Mammals divert endogenous genotoxic formaldehyde into one-carbon metabolism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23481</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/VHCky0dEpSo/nature23481</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The folate-driven one-carbon (1C) cycle is a fundamental metabolic hub in cells that enables the synthesis of nucleotides and amino acids and epigenetic modifications. This cycle might also release formaldehyde, a potent protein and DNA crosslinking agent that organisms produce in substantial quantities. Here we show that supplementation with tetrahydrofolate, the essential cofactor of this cycle, and other oxidation-prone folate derivatives kills human, mouse and chicken cells that cannot detoxify formaldehyde or that lack DNA crosslink repair. Notably, formaldehyde is generated from oxidative decomposition of the folate backbone. Furthermore, we find that formaldehyde detoxification in human cells generates formate, and thereby promotes nucleotide synthesis. This supply of 1C units is sufficient to sustain the growth of cells that are unable to use serine, which is the predominant source of 1C units. These findings identify an unexpected source of formaldehyde and, more generally, indicate that the detoxification of this ubiquitous endogenous genotoxin creates a benign 1C unit that can sustain essential metabolism. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23481&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23481&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/VHCky0dEpSo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A randomized synbiotic trial to prevent sepsis among infants in rural India</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23480</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/fdqqMXVNIe8/nature23480</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Sepsis in early infancy results in one million annual deaths worldwide, most of them in developing countries. No efficient means of prevention is currently available. Here we report on a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of an oral synbiotic preparation (Lactobacillus plantarum plus fructooligosaccharide) in rural Indian newborns. We enrolled 4,556 infants that were at least 2,000 g at birth, at least 35 weeks of gestation, and with no signs of sepsis or other morbidity, and monitored them for 60 days. We show a significant reduction in the primary outcome (combination of sepsis and death) in the treatment arm (risk ratio 0.60, 95% confidence interval 0.48–0.74), with few deaths (4 placebo, 6 synbiotic). Significant reductions were also observed for culture-positive and culture-negative sepsis and lower respiratory tract infections. These findings suggest that a large proportion of neonatal sepsis in developing countries could be effectively prevented using a synbiotic containing L. plantarum ATCC-202195. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23480&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23480&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/fdqqMXVNIe8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: CDK4/6 inhibition triggers anti-tumour immunity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23465</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/L0wsjOLsXqQ/nature23465</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Cyclin-dependent kinases 4 and 6 (CDK4/6) are fundamental drivers of the cell cycle and are required for the initiation and progression of various malignancies. Pharmacological inhibitors of CDK4/6 have shown significant activity against several solid tumours. Their primary mechanism of action is thought to be the inhibition of phosphorylation of the retinoblastoma tumour suppressor, inducing G1 cell cycle arrest in tumour cells. Here we use mouse models of breast carcinoma and other solid tumours to show that selective CDK4/6 inhibitors not only induce tumour cell cycle arrest, but also promote anti-tumour immunity. We confirm this phenomenon through transcriptomic analysis of serial biopsies from a clinical trial of CDK4/6 inhibitor treatment for breast cancer. The enhanced anti-tumour immune response has two underpinnings. First, CDK4/6 inhibitors activate tumour cell expression of endogenous retroviral elements, thus increasing intracellular levels of double-stranded RNA. This in turn stimulates production of type III interferons and hence enhances tumour antigen presentation. Second, CDK4/6 inhibitors markedly suppress the proliferation of regulatory T cells. Mechanistically, the effects of CDK4/6 inhibitors both on tumour cells and on regulatory T cells are associated with reduced activity of the E2F target, DNA methyltransferase 1. Ultimately, these events promote cytotoxic T-cell-mediated clearance of tumour cells, which is further enhanced by the addition of immune checkpoint blockade. Our findings indicate that CDK4/6 inhibitors increase tumour immunogenicity and provide a rationale for new combination regimens comprising CDK4/6 inhibitors and immunotherapies as anti-cancer treatment. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23465&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23465&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/L0wsjOLsXqQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Vaccine-driven pharmacodynamic dissection and mitigation of fenethylline psychoactivity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23464</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/A4CoiCxXWCE/nature23464</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Fenethylline, also known by the trade name Captagon, is a synthetic psychoactive stimulant that has recently been linked to a substance-use disorder and ‘pharmacoterrorism’ in the Middle East. Although fenethylline shares a common phenethylamine core with other amphetamine-type stimulants, it also incorporates a covalently linked xanthine moiety into its parent structure. These independently active pharmacophores are liberated during metabolism, resulting in the release of a structurally diverse chemical mixture into the central nervous system. Although the psychoactive properties of fenethylline have been reported to differ from those of other synthetic stimulants, the in vivo chemical complexity it manifests upon ingestion has impeded efforts to unambiguously identify the specific species responsible for these effects. Here we develop a ‘dissection through vaccination’ approach, called DISSECTIV, to mitigate the psychoactive effects of fenethylline and show that its rapid-onset and distinct psychoactive properties are facilitated by functional synergy between theophylline and amphetamine. Our results demonstrate that incremental vaccination against a single chemical species within a multi-component mixture can be used to uncover emergent properties arising from polypharmacological activity. We anticipate that DISSECTIV will be used to expose unidentified active chemical species and resolve pharmacodynamic interactions within other chemically complex systems, such as those found in counterfeit or illegal drug preparations, post-metabolic tissue samples and natural product extracts. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23464&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23464&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/A4CoiCxXWCE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: The rise of algae in Cryogenian oceans and the emergence of animals</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23457</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4g75ln7zTkk/nature23457</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The transition from dominant bacterial to eukaryotic marine primary productivity was one of the most profound ecological revolutions in the Earth’s history, reorganizing the distribution of carbon and nutrients in the water column and increasing energy flow to higher trophic levels. But the causes and geological timing of this transition, as well as possible links with rising atmospheric oxygen levels and the evolution of animals, remain obscure. Here we present a molecular fossil record of eukaryotic steroids demonstrating that bacteria were the only notable primary producers in the oceans before the Cryogenian period (720–635 million years ago). Increasing steroid diversity and abundance marks the rapid rise of marine planktonic algae (Archaeplastida) in the narrow time interval between the Sturtian and Marinoan ‘snowball Earth’ glaciations, 659–645 million years ago. We propose that the incumbency of cyanobacteria was broken by a surge of nutrients supplied by the Sturtian deglaciation. The ‘Rise of Algae’ created food webs with more efficient nutrient and energy transfers, driving ecosystems towards larger and increasingly complex organisms. This effect is recorded by the concomitant appearance of biomarkers for sponges and predatory rhizarians, and the subsequent radiation of eumetazoans in the Ediacaran period. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23457&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23457&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4g75ln7zTkk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: First date with the Hive</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548366a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bhdzx-uqvvs/548366a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Mind how you go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 366 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548366a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548366a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bhdzx-uqvvs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: History: Ingenious solutions sparked by a crisis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281e</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PUvEr34-M-o/548281e</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548281e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PUvEr34-M-o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Carbon emissions: More nuclear power can speed CO2 cuts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281d</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/A8RKm_ajE_I/548281d</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548281d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/A8RKm_ajE_I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Climate adaptation: Past US floods give lessons in retreat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281c</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ESteCw6vdOU/548281c</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548281c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ESteCw6vdOU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Data sharing: do scientists know best?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1Ca1Wn0BvlA/548281b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548281b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548281b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1Ca1Wn0BvlA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seismologists get to the bottom of how deep Earth’s continents go</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seismologists-get-bottom-how-deep-earth-continents-go</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seismologists-get-bottom-how-deep-earth-continents-go</link>
	<description>Scientists may have finally pinpointed the bottoms of the continents.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081517_MT_continential-plates_main.jpg?itok=QXUERcYl" length="37587" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “The paper is extremely flawed:” Journal retracts article linked to vaccines</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51431</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/15/paper-extremely-flawed-journal-retracts-paper-heavy-criticism/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal has retracted a 2016 paper after receiving criticism from outside researchers who raised concerns about its methodology and data. The paper shares multiple authors with another paper that linked the vaccine for human papillomavirus (HPV) to behavioral problems in mice. Last year, a journal removed the study; later that year, the authors published […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/15/paper-extremely-flawed-journal-retracts-paper-heavy-criticism/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“The paper is extremely flawed:” Journal retracts article linked to vaccines&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These spiders crossed an ocean to get to Australia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/trapdoor-spiders-australia-africa</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/trapdoor-spiders-australia-africa</link>
	<description>The nearest relatives of an Australian trapdoor spider live in Africa. They crossed the Indian Ocean to get to Australia, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/wt_trapdoorspider_free.jpg?itok=VCmyI8KD" length="56937" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: What should journals do when peer reviewers do not disclose potential conflicts?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51427</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/15/journals-peer-reviewers-not-disclose-potential-conflicts/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Peer reviewers, like authors, are supposed to declare any potential conflicts of interest. But what happens when they don’t? Take this case: In a court transcript from Feb. 23, 2017, Bryan Hardin testified that he was a peer reviewer on a 2016 paper in Critical Reviews in Toxicology, which found that asbestos does not increase […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/15/journals-peer-reviewers-not-disclose-potential-conflicts/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What should journals do when peer reviewers do not disclose potential conflicts?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Can the eclipse tell us if Einstein was right about general relativity?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-einstein-general-relativity</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-solar-eclipse-einstein-general-relativity</link>
	<description>During the eclipse, astronomers will reproduce the 1919 experiment that confirmed Einstein’s general theory of relativity.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/story-5_main.jpg?itok=xU4Y5_fw" length="21315" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Psychologists have developed the first scientific test of everyday charisma</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28606</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/15/psychologists-have-developed-the-first-scientific-definition-and-test-of-everyday-charisma/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-673558204.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28714&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28714&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;WireImage&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LONDON, ENGLAND - APRIL 26:  George Clooney attends the Lost In Space event to celebrate the 60th anniversary of the OMEGA Speedmaster at the Tate Modern on April 26, 2017 in London, United Kingdom. The OMEGA Speedmaster Watch has been worn by every piloted NASA mission since 1965.  (Photo by Karwai Tang\/WireImage)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1493240881&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Karwai Tang&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Lost In Space - Anniversary party&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Lost In Space – Anniversary party&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-673558204.jpg?w=845?w=767&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-673558204.jpg?w=845?w=225&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-673558204.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;767,1024&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/15/psychologists-have-developed-the-first-scientific-definition-and-test-of-everyday-charisma/lost-in-space-anniversary-party/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-673558204.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Figures such as Princess Diana, Oprah Winfrey, Mahatma Gandhi, Ronald Reagan, and Adolf Hitler share this triumphant, mysterious, and fascinating descriptor”, write the authors of a new paper on charisma. And yet, they add, “the empirical study of charisma is relatively young and sparse, and no unifying conceptualization of charisma currently exists”. The research and theorizing that has been done has focused on charismatic leadership, they explain, neglecting the everyday variety. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31803-001&quot;&gt;their paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; the University of Toronto researchers describe how they developed their new six-item measure “The General Charisma Inventory” (GCI), and they show how scores on the GCI are associated with people’s persuasiveness and likability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28606&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team, led by Konstantin Tskhay, began by asking just over a hundred American volunteers on Amazon’s Mechanical Turk online survey website to come up with four characteristics of charismatic individuals. The researchers then whittled these suggestions down in various stages, which involved volunteers rating the suitability of the items and other volunteers rating themselves on the items. Removing any redundancy, the researchers ended up with a six-item self-report measure of charisma loading onto two main factors to do with having influence over others (including being able to guide them) and coming across as affable (being able to make others feel comfortable and at ease).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants taking the new test are asked to rate their agreement on a five-point scale from 1 Strongly Disagree to 5 Strongly Agree, whether “I am someone who…”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has a presence in a room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the ability to influence people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knows how to lead a group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes people feel comfortable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smiles at people often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can get along with anyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The first three items tap the influence factor of charisma and the last three items tap the affability factor.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having devised their test, the researchers put it through its paces in a number of ways. For example, they asked volunteers to complete the new charisma measure plus lots of other established psychological measures, and were able to show that scores on the new test are related to but distinct from established psychological constructs such as the Big Five personality traits, emotional intelligence and political skill. For instance, people’s scores on the the affability factor of the new test correlated with their trait Agreeableness, which makes conceptual sense. On the other hand, charisma scores appeared to be completely separate from intelligence, suggesting that “individual differences in general charisma are not redundant with cognitive ability”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another study the researchers asked small groups of unacquainted students to chat to each other for five minutes and to rate themselves and other group members on the charisma test. This showed that individuals’ charisma self-ratings on the test correlated with the charisma ratings they received from others. In another similar study, students’ self-ratings on the charisma test correlated with ratings they received from friends or family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also asked pairs of unacquainted students to chat to each other for ten minutes and then rate each other’s likability. The students also rated themselves on standard personality measures and on the new charisma measure. The higher the students scored on charisma (specifically the affability factor), the more likable they tended to be rated by their partners, even after taking into account their scores on the Big Five personality traits of Extraversion, Agreeableness etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another demonstration of the tests’ validity, the researchers asked more student volunteers to read out either a weak or strong argument for wind energy and then to complete the charisma test. Next, participants on Amazon’s Mechanical Turk listened back to the recordings and rated how persuasive they found them. When it came to the weak arguments, they found participants who’d scored themselves higher on charisma (specifically the influence factor) to be more persuasive. In relation to the affability factor, women who scored higher on this were rated as more persuasive, whereas for men the affability scores were not relevant (the researchers speculated this has to do with cultural expectations for women to be warm).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We believe that the investigation of charisma in daily life is important for disentangling a construct previously understood primarily in terms of its consequences for leadership,” Tskhay and his colleagues concluded, “and hope that other researchers will share our enthusiasm about the potential new lines of research that this new conceptualization may elucidate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31803-001&quot;&gt;Charisma in Everyday Life: Conceptualization and Validation of the General Charisma Inventory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: April 2017 George Clooney attends the Lost In Space event at the Tate Modern (Photo by Karwai Tang/WireImage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28606/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28606/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28606&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 09:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The End</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0917-96</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/B_O1CT2ecrE/scientificamerican0917-96</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 96 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0917-96&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0917-96&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mark Fischetti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Do Most Women and Men Die Of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/B_O1CT2ecrE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
