<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: Gay, lesbian and bisexual high schoolers report ‘tragically high’ suicide risk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gay-lesbian-and-bisexual-teens-report-tragically-high-suicide-risk</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gay-lesbian-and-bisexual-teens-report-tragically-high-suicide-risk</link>
	<description>Teens who identify as sexual minorities are more likely to report suicidal behaviors than their heterosexual peers, a new study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 20:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121917_AC_lgbtq_feat.jpg?itok=kjlVdFsN" length="23767" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The sun’s outer atmosphere is far more complex than previously thought</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-corona-outer-atmosphere-complex</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-corona-outer-atmosphere-complex</link>
	<description>The outer corona of the sun was thought to be smooth and uniform. New observations show it’s anything but.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121817_LG_corona_feat.jpg?itok=ziDkkgUi" length="18196" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Specialized protein helps these ground squirrels resist the cold</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/specialized-protein-helps-these-ground-squirrels-resist-cold</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/specialized-protein-helps-these-ground-squirrels-resist-cold</link>
	<description>A less active cold-sensing protein explains, in part, why some hibernating ground squirrels are more tolerant of chilly conditions than the animals’ nonhibernating kin</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121817_LH_hibernatingsquirrels_feat.jpg?itok=1O077ZKU" length="72204" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Editors-in-chief of math journal resign over controversial paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53095</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/19/editors-chief-math-journal-resign-controversial-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Both editors of a math journal have resigned over the decision to publish a controversial paper, which was apparently made without consulting the editorial board. Last week, the editorial board of EMS Surveys in Mathematical Sciences issued a statement about the paper, saying its acceptance was “a serious mistake.” According to the statement, the two […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/19/editors-chief-math-journal-resign-controversial-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Editors-in-chief of math journal resign over controversial paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Researchers uncover a brain process that may help explain the curse of uncontrollable thoughts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32947</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/19/researchers-uncover-a-brain-process-that-may-help-explain-the-curse-of-uncontrollable-thoughts/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32948&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-532378001.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32948&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32948&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Negative human emotions, facial expressions. Colorful painting&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sSplajn&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Closeup portrait of really stressed out person&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Closeup portrait of really stressed out person&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-532378001.jpg?w=845?w=762&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-532378001.jpg?w=845?w=223&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-532378001.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2550,3428&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/19/researchers-uncover-a-brain-process-that-may-help-explain-the-curse-of-uncontrollable-thoughts/closeup-portrait-of-really-stressed-out-person/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-532378001.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The study represents a breakthrough in bridging neurophysiology and psychology&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distressing conditions including PTSD, depression and anxiety have something in common: a difficulty in suppressing unwanted thoughts. Negative self-judgments and re-experienced traumas directly impact mental health and make recovery harder by intruding into the new experiences that should provide distance and a mental fresh start. Understanding what’s involved in thought suppression may therefore be one key to helping people with these conditions. Now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-00956-z&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/i&gt; has uncovered an important new brain process that may help explain why some people struggle to control their thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32947&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, led by Taylor Schmitz, comes from the lab of Michael Anderson at Cambridge’s MRC Cognition and Brain Sciences Unit. Anderson first began investigating thought suppression when the dominant position was that it’s not possible to suppress thoughts voluntarily – “just try to &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; think of a white bear for five minutes and see what happens!” was the popular example of the time, derived from Daniel Wegner’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ironic_process_theory&quot;&gt;ironic processing theory&lt;/a&gt;. However, Anderson used new methods, including the so-called “Think/No-Think paradigm” (more on this in a moment), to show that suppressed thoughts only rebound under certain conditions – in other words, it is sometimes possible to suppress thoughts successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new research used Anderson’s Think/No-Think paradigm. Participants first studied pairs of words. Afterwards they were shown one word from each pair and – depending on the instruction for that pair – either had to recall the other word in the pair (a “Think” trial), or instead had to block the other word from coming to mind (a “No Think” trial) . Later, when participants tried to remember which words were partnered with which, they did worse for pairs from No-Think trials than Think trials, on average (in fact, they did even worse recalling the No-Think pairs than other pairs that hadn’t featured at all since the initial study phase). This shows that No Think pairings had mostly been suppressed successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These effects replicate established findings for the Think/No Think paradigm. The main purpose of the new study was to see what was happening in the brain during this process, and for this, Schmitz and his colleagues used two imaging techniques: functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI), to look at patterns of blood flow during the task, and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;H magnetic resonance spectroscopy (MRS), to look at the concentration of neurotransmitters in different parts of the brain. For comparison, the researchers also scanned the participants’ brains during a task that involves suppressing movements, rather than thoughts (the “Stop Signal” task, in which a key must be pressed as fast as possible in response to certain colour cues, but the button press withheld for other colour cues).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the suppression of thoughts (the No-Think trials), blood flow was reduced in the hippocampus, an area of the brain involved in memory. The extent of this change was related to the levels of the inhibitory neurotransmitter GABA. Participants with a higher concentration of GABA, specifically in the hippocampus, also showed a greater decrease in blood flow in that area. Moreover, the degree of thought suppression correlated with the amount of GABA in the hippocampus (not in the brain more widely). These same patterns were not observed in the Stop Signal task. These findings strongly suggests that hippocampal GABA is playing a specific role in the ability to suppress thoughts, by helping the area to dial-down its activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What triggers the involvement of GABA during No-Think trials? Previous work suggests that the thought suppression process involves a signal starting in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, and the more this frontal brain area is active, the more deactivated the hippocampus becomes – akin to the control area of the brain telling the hippocampus to cool its jets. The new findings suggest that this “negative coupling”, as it’s known, depends on GABA. For people low in hippocampal GABA, this process – which appears to be a key component of thought suppression – didn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new findings have implications for our understanding of mental health conditions, suggesting that lower concentrations of GABA could be a risk factor for some. However, the research is correlational, so this conclusion has to be taken tentatively (causality could be the other way around, such that GABA is driven pathologically low by psychological issues). Bear in mind too that the sample were all mentally well participants. Future research could test the causal role of hippocampal GABA in uncontrolled thoughts (including in clinical samples), as well as refine our understanding of which psychological interventions will be of benefit – most likely those that don’t just harness the involvement of frontal brain areas, but also produce downstream change in the soil health of the hippocampal range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study represents a breakthrough in bridging neurophysiology and psychology, and it looks likely that getting a grip on the role of molecular pathways in the hippocampus will be at least part of the solution to help those for whom issues from the past still plague their present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-00956-z&quot;&gt;Hippocampal GABA enables inhibitory control over unwanted thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32947/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32947/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32947&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 14:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: It’s official: When journals behave badly, there could be some punishment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53084</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/19/official-journals-behave-badly-punishment/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here at Retraction Watch, we constantly receive emails from readers who are frustrated with a particular journal — perhaps it has ignored obvious problems in a published paper, performed only a cursory peer review, or takes months (or years) to take action on a problematic article. Many whistleblowers bring their concerns to the Committee on […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/19/official-journals-behave-badly-punishment/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;It’s official: When journals behave badly, there could be some punishment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How science and society crossed paths in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-events-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-events-2017-yir</link>
	<description>In 2017, Science News covered the science events that everyone was talking about.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_YE-events_main.jpg?itok=L-Jf6PUM" length="13254" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 3 ways data science and technology are helping us help the world</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-data-science-and-technology-are-helping-us-help-the-world</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/3-ways-data-science-and-technology-are-helping-us-help-the-world</link>
	<description>How they’re being used to tackle poverty, natural disasters and fallout from the Syrian refugee crisis</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 11:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: With a little help from my friends – Getting people out of social isolation could help prevent type 2 diabetes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9712</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/19/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends-getting-people-out-of-social-isolation-could-help-prevent-type-2-diabetes/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/Fotolia_49249610_Subscription_Yearly_XXL-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social isolation isn’t just loneliness — it may also affect your health. For instance, social relationships may have an impact on the development of chronic diseases, like type 2 diabetes. A clear picture on how social network characteristics may influence type 2 diabetes could contribute to the prevention of type 2 diabetes, as well as to the improvement of interventions for people who already have the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study, we addressed whether social network size, contact frequency, type of relationship (family, friends, acquaintances), living alone and social participation, were associated with several stages of type 2 diabetes: pre-diabetes, newly diagnosed and previously diagnosed type 2 diabetes. In addition, we investigated whether more quality related characteristics of the social network, like emotional or practical support, were associated with pre-diabetes, newly diagnosed, and previously diagnosed type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In diabetes women, network members lived closer and were more often family than friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, we asked nearly 3000 participants of The Maastricht Study to fill out a questionnaire on their social networks. For example, we asked them to indicate whom they turned to with problems or whom they go out with. Participants in The Maastricht Study are men and women, aged 40 to 75 years, and live in the southern part of the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network size in individuals with type 2 diabetes appeared to be smaller, women with type 2 diabetes typically had 8 network members compared to 12 in those without diabetes, in men this was 7 in type 2 diabetes compared to 10 in those without diabetes. These results indicate that socially isolated individuals more often have type 2 diabetes. In diabetes women, network members lived closer and were more often family than friends. Apparently, a more centralized social network is associated with type 2 diabetes in women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Targeting social networks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these results in mind, we believe that targeting the social network may prove a promising prevention strategy for type 2 diabetes. Socially isolated individuals could be encouraged to improve their lifestyle, for instance lose weight and become more physically active, in a setting that increases their social integration. Such interventions should enable extension and broadening of the social network, by supporting them to make new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Men and women who perceived less social support, and were less involved in social activities, more often had type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, men and women who perceived less social support, and were less involved in social activities, more often had type 2 diabetes. In particular, as men living alone seem to be at a higher risk for the development of type 2 diabetes, they should become recognized as high-risk group in health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, new lifestyle interventions should be combined with stimulating participants to become member of a club (e.g. volunteer organization, sports club, discussion group), as we have shown that a lack of participation in social activities was associated with pre-diabetes and previously diagnosed T2DM. Thus, social network size and social participation may be used as a risk indicator in diabetes prevention strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our study, we endeavor that negative health effects of social isolation and poor social networks become widely recognized. Notably, targeting social network characteristics may also have benefits for other public health concepts, as it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/epidemiology-and-infection/article/development-of-prediction-models-for-upper-and-lower-respiratory-and-gastrointestinal-tract-infections-using-social-network-parameters-in-middleaged-and-older-persons-the-maastricht-study/0381B153773C4755B7CF25F969BAA9C1&quot;&gt;has been shown&lt;/a&gt; that social networks were also strong predictors for infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the mechanisms underlying the associations of social network characteristics with the development of type 2 diabetes are not yet elucidated, our findings are of great importance to the field of diabetes prevention. Our results implicate that strengthening of the social network can be used to optimize non-medical prevention strategies for type 2 diabetes. Our findings support the idea that solving social isolation may prevent the development of type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/19/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends-getting-people-out-of-social-isolation-could-help-prevent-type-2-diabetes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;With a little help from my friends – Getting people out of social isolation could help prevent type 2 diabetes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 09:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/Fotolia_49249610_Subscription_Yearly_XXL-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Secrets of a &quot;Zombie&quot; Fungus Revealed</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9276</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9276</link>
	<description>A parasitic fungus that controls the behaviour of fruit flies has, for the first time, been studied in the lab.

In a fascinating preprint posted on Biorxiv, researchers Carolyn Elya et al. report how they discovered the pathogen in the wild near Berkeley, California. The fungus belongs to the species Entomophthora muscae, which is already known to prey on various species of wild flies. But Elya et al. found a way to infect laboratory flies with the disease, thus allowing them to study the fun</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 08:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Killer Seas</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-80</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/E2KRD-DAXqE/scientificamerican0118-80</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 80 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-80&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-80&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mark Fischetti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mass extinction could begin by 2100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/E2KRD-DAXqE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: War on Science Agencies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-8</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/TeGwu_ESXxU/scientificamerican0118-8</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 8 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-8&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-8&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors: Andrew A. Rosenberg &amp;amp; Kathleen Rest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budget cuts and layoffs threaten the nation's health and safety&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/TeGwu_ESXxU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: 50, 100 &amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-79</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/kr1QCGEvSmk/scientificamerican0118-79</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 79 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-79&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-79&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/kr1QCGEvSmk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Is Anybody Anywhere?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-78</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/ly3zkylBiNc/scientificamerican0118-78</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 78 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-78&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-78&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SETI is still scanning the skies for other galactic citizens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/ly3zkylBiNc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Recommended</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-76</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/pEin2XwitJ4/scientificamerican0118-76</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 76 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-76&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-76&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/pEin2XwitJ4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: How Snakes Came to Slither</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-70</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/f2i1_Hu6058/scientificamerican0118-70</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 70 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-70&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-70&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Hongyu Yi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New fossil analyses and insights from evolutionary developmental biology elucidate the long-sought origin of serpents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/f2i1_Hu6058&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: A School Is Not a Military Post</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-7</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/5nffMaXDLEs/scientificamerican0118-7</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 7 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-7&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-7&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educational facilities are used in armed conflicts—with children inside. We need to stop this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/5nffMaXDLEs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Toxic Well of Loneliness</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-64</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/E7WOE4VCWn4/scientificamerican0118-64</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 64 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-64&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-64&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Francine Russo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isolation from others can lead to a range of illnesses and even premature death. New science is probing causes and solutions to the problem of social disconnection&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/E7WOE4VCWn4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: War against Ourselves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-58</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8zjf6FMLJLU/scientificamerican0118-58</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 58 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-58&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-58&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Waldholz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many new drugs trigger an immune reaction that cripples them—and the race is on to thwart the attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8zjf6FMLJLU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Searching for the Dark</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-50</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Ongw-a42Y8I/scientificamerican0118-50</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 50 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-50&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-50&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Leslie Rosenberg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Axion Dark Matter Experiment just entered the most sensitive phase yet in its search for invisible particles to explain the universe's hidden mass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Ongw-a42Y8I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Letters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-5</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/FJO-NIWMfig/scientificamerican0118-5</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 5 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-5&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-5&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/FJO-NIWMfig&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Can We Save the Corals?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-42</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/36ExTM0yoyg/scientificamerican0118-42</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 42 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-42&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-42&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Rebecca Albright&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists are urgently transplanting, fertilizing and enhancing corals to help them adapt to warmer oceans, but rebuilding entire reefs will be daunting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/36ExTM0yoyg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Evolution of Trust</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-38</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/pGFAZPp8_F4/scientificamerican0118-38</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 38 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-38&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-38&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Natalie Smolenski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate social impact of blockchain technology depends on who controls our digital identities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/pGFAZPp8_F4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The World Bitcoin Created</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-32</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/GWkqRNsQG9E/scientificamerican0118-32</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 32 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-32&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-32&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John Pavlus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first big digital currency gave us a glimpse of a new economic order—one that raises more questions than answers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/GWkqRNsQG9E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Breaking the Bank</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-26</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/leCvh54lf80/scientificamerican0118-26</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 26 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-26&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-26&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Alexander Lipton &amp;amp; Alex “Sandy” Pentland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New financial networks could stop the concentration of wealth and increase participation in the economy—but only if used with care&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/leCvh54lf80&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Future of Money</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-24</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/SNvj6VxXEz8/scientificamerican0118-24</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/SNvj6VxXEz8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: How Well Do Films Predict Our Tech Future?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-23</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/ft_Gn6o9KJw/scientificamerican0118-23</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 23 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-23&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-23&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They get lots wrong but a surprising amount right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/ft_Gn6o9KJw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Messy Facts about Diet and Inflammation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-22</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/GdNsEPsUWco/scientificamerican0118-22</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can certain foods really help you fight heart disease, arthritis and dementia?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/GdNsEPsUWco&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Cobalt Blues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-21</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/YDWVCaaujWY/scientificamerican0118-21</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 21 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-21&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-21&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Prachi Patel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shortage of the metal could create a bottleneck for electric vehicles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/YDWVCaaujWY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Quick Hits</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-20</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/4uyBwB_iHTA/scientificamerican0118-20</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 318, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0118-20&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0118-20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Yasemin Saplakoglu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/4uyBwB_iHTA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new kind of spiral wave embraces disorder</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-kind-spiral-wave-embraces-disorder</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-kind-spiral-wave-embraces-disorder</link>
	<description>Newly discovered spiral wave chimera is disordered in its center.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 21:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121417_EC_spiral-wave_main.jpg?itok=rdkQ_Lu3" length="69919" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Top 10 retractions of 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53074</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/top-10-retractions-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time for the “Best of 2017” lists to start appearing — so why not do one for retractions? We think it’s a good idea, so have partnered with The Scientist for the last few years to compile our most notable notices of the year. From new records to mass resignations, you can check out […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/top-10-retractions-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Top 10 retractions of 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 18:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Do Today’s Technological Advances Threaten Our Species?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23145</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/18/do-todays-technological-advances-threaten-our-species/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of public back-and-forth banter has been going on lately between two giant tech personalities: Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg. Their public debate centers on whether or not artificial intelligence (AI) represents an existential threat to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Elon Musk, when speaking at the National Governors Association in July said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI is a fundamental existential risk for human civilization, and I don’t think people fully appreciate that…It’s the greatest risk we face as a civilization [that will cause World War III]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Zuckerberg on the other hand, touts the benefits of AI and says that Elon Musk’s doomsday predictions about AI are “pretty irresponsible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This prompted Elon Musk to fire back that Mark Zuckerberg’s understanding of AI is “pretty limited.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who is right? Only time will tell of course, but by my science-based speculation, I would say the evidence favors Musk. And greater brains than my own are telling us that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/03/06/chappie-just-how-artificial-is-the-intelligence-behind-this-robot/&quot;&gt;artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt; could be the end of &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; or any other &lt;em&gt;Homo&lt;/em&gt; that follows, including Bill Joy, Stephen Hawking, Vernor Vinge, Shane Legg, Stuart Russell, Max Tegmark, Nick Bostrom, James Barrat, Michael Anissimov, and Irving Good. Brilliant minds, Nobel Prize winners, renowned inventors, and IT pioneers are all on record giving us warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course other existential threats to &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; are possible and could come in the form of another bolide impact like the one that doomed the dinosaurs 66 million years ago or a supervolcano leading to extreme global weather events, a phenomena that also affected early species. Unlike the relentless human pursuit of technologies that could alter, if not eliminate, our species, these threats are essentially out of our control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic engineering, especially if aided by AI, could lead to the future &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/12/20/humans-of-the-future/&quot;&gt;speciation&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; and pose yet another existential threat. Lee Silvers, in his book &lt;em&gt;Remaking Eden&lt;/em&gt;, envisions a future society practicing an extreme form of behavioral &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2006/05/15/anti-stigmatization-social-isolation-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;isolation&lt;/a&gt; based on genetic engineering. In this society, only a small portion of the population, which he calls the GenRich, have the financial means to genetically enhance their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over decades, the GenRich use genetic engineering techniques to optimize a variety of human traits—such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/22/is-there-an-association-between-brain-size-and-intelligence/&quot;&gt;intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, athletic skill, physical appearance, and creativity—that give them a controlling position in society. Over time, cultural disparity between this GenRich minority population and the remaining “naturals” becomes so great that there’s little interbreeding between the two groups. Such a scenario could lead to the genetic development of a postzygotic reproductive barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, genetic engineering could eventually lead to a new species of humans. Once this occurs, the long-term results are unpredictable. This new species—I call it &lt;em&gt;Homo nouveau&lt;/em&gt;—like the GenRich, may not be an existential threat, at least in the early centuries or millennia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s uncertain what could happen when two human species try to coexist. We know things didn’t work out very well for the Neanderthals after &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; arrived. In fact, the same is true for &lt;em&gt;Homo heidelbergensis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Homo erectus&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Homo denisova&lt;/em&gt;, and every other &lt;em&gt;Homo&lt;/em&gt; species that may have coexisted with &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In considering all the possible existential threats to us humans, genetic engineering is a possibility in the not too distant future—say in the next two to four centuries. However, if Elon Musk is right AI could supersede that in one or two centuries if we’re unsuccessful in controlling it. Then again, at any time we could be hit by a bolide. None of this bodes well for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L. Grossman, “2045: The Year Man Becomes Immortal”, &lt;em&gt;Time Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, February 10, 2011. Access &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,2048299,00.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hawking, S., Tegmark, T., Russell, S. (2017). Transcending Complacency on Superintelligent Machines. &lt;em&gt;Huffington Post&lt;/em&gt;. Access &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/stephen-hawking/artificial-intelligence_b_5174265.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bostrom, N. &lt;i&gt;Superintelligence: Paths, Danger, Strategies, &lt;/i&gt;Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F. Heylighen, “Return to Eden? Promises and Perils on the Road to Global Superintelligence,” in &lt;i&gt;The End of the Beginning: Life, Society and Economy on the Brink of the Singularity, &lt;/i&gt;Ben and Ted Goerzel, eds., Humanity + Press, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/stux-12364/&quot;&gt;frolicsomepl&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 16:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Work with someone who later commits misconduct? You may pay the price</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53070</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/work-someone-later-commits-misconduct-may-pay-price/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It makes sense that scientists would adopt a sort of “buyer beware” attitude towards fraud — if researchers choose to collaborate with someone who’s been found guilty of some type of misconduct, their reputation among their peers might take a hit. But what about people who work with someone who is later convicted of misconduct […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/work-someone-later-commits-misconduct-may-pay-price/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Work with someone who later commits misconduct? You may pay the price&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 16:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Our first interstellar visitor may be a camouflaged comet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/our-first-interstellar-visitor-may-be-camouflaged-comet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/our-first-interstellar-visitor-may-be-camouflaged-comet</link>
	<description>Originally thought to be a rocky asteroid, an interstellar traveler may have a comet’s icy heart.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121517_EC_oumuamua_main.jpg?itok=BEf6fpJp" length="35763" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Columbia researcher up to five retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53063</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/caught-notice-columbia-researcher-five-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Endotoxaemia during left ventricular assist device insertion: relationship between risk factors and outcome What Caught Our Attention: Robert J. Frumento first caught our notice in 2013, as a coauthor on a paper retracted with a nonspecific reference to author misconduct.  Three years later, Frumento was clearly identified as having fabricated data and a master’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/18/caught-notice-columbia-researcher-five-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Columbia researcher up to five retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 13:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Ethical questions raised by brain-computer interfaces</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9696</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/18/ethical-questions-raised-by-brain-computer-interfaces/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/iStock-180723100-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brain-computer interfaces (BCI) are devices that measure signals from the brain and translate them into executable output with the help of a machine such as a computer or prosthesis. This technology has varied uses, from assistive devices for disabled individuals to advanced video game control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9699&quot; style=&quot;width: 209px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9699 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/15959228542_cb08e59f1e_b-1-199x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;BCI is portrayed positively in films like Robocop&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Flickr: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/44214515@N06/15959228542&quot;&gt;Wacko Photographer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BCI has been discussed by the media, and by science fiction television and films. Sometimes this technology is positively portrayed, such as the prosthetics seen in &lt;em&gt;Robocop&lt;/em&gt;. Other perspectives warn about how far this technology could go, such as the literal plug-in brain interface in &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;, or the game in &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;’s episode “Playtest” that can create a person’s worst nightmare. Though these examples are very futuristic, some companies have research goals that could be straight out of a science fiction movie: for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/27/15077864/elon-musk-neuralink-brain-computer-interface-ai-cyborgs&quot;&gt;Elon Musk’s company Neuralink&lt;/a&gt; plans to create brain implants that improve memory. The current reality of BCI, however, is more limited than suggested by these futuristic portrayals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, the main use of BCI pursued by researchers is as assistive technology for individuals with debilitating loss of motor control, such as that caused by amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and spinal cord injury. Late stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients often enter a “locked-in” state in which they lose nearly all motor function, including the ability to speak. To help these individuals, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intendix.com/&quot;&gt;BCI electroencephalogram-based spelling systems&lt;/a&gt; have been developed. These devices use electrodes to record brain signals from the surface of the scalp, and users can type messages by focusing on certain letters on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9697&quot; style=&quot;width: 853px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9697&quot; height=&quot;286&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/fneng-05-00014-g007.jpg&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The intendix BCI running on the laptop and user wearing the active electrodes.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Image sourced from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fneng.2012.00014/full&quot;&gt;Frontiers in Neuroengineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example of assistive technology is BCI motor prostheses, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/miguel_nicolelis_brain_to_brain_communication_has_arrived_how_we_did_it/up-next&quot;&gt;robot exoskeleton built by Dr. Miguel Nicolelis&lt;/a&gt; and his colleagues that allowed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27812218&quot;&gt;a paralysed man to kick a soccer ball&lt;/a&gt; during the 2014 Brazil World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethical questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unique direct connection BCI creates between our brains and computers raises important ethical questions. We currently interact with computers with our peripheral nervous system: we use our fingers to type an email on our laptop, or our vocal muscles to produce speech and interact with voice recognition systems. In contrast, BCI captures signals directly from your central nervous system – your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a BCI device sees the thought and executes a harmful action, even though the user would have normally not acted in this way alone, can we say that the BCI user is fully responsible?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has interesting ethical implications, ranging from questions of privacy to loss of humanity. One example is ascription of responsibility for the output of a BCI. Perhaps we have less control over our thoughts than over our actions – many of us have experienced thinking something, yet refrained from saying it aloud. If a BCI device sees the thought and executes a harmful action, even though the user would have normally not acted in this way alone, can we say that the BCI user is fully responsible?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another ethical question is the potentially deceptive role played by the media on perception of BCI. Current BCI technology is not very reliable: spelling devices often cannot be controlled by fully locked-in patients for unclear reasons. In general, most motor-based assistive systems are far more effective than BCI for individuals who retain any motor function. An example is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hawking.org.uk/the-computer.html&quot;&gt;Stephen Hawking’s communication device&lt;/a&gt;, which he controls with minute facial muscle movements and prefers over BCI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, media coverage of BCI tends to be overly positive and futuristic, with the phrases “mind reading” and “cure” seen in &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/7094526.stm&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt;. This misrepresentation can create an expectation gap where patients expect a BCI device to be more effective or simpler to use than it actually is. Disappointment stemming from overly high expectations could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs11948-015-9712-7&quot;&gt;associated with patient depression&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many researchers see great potential in BCI devices, with implications for individuals struggling with severe disabilities and for the future of entertainment. However, the ethics literature indicates that these benefits could be accompanied by moral and societal challenges. It is therefore important that neuroscientists, legislators, ethicists, and the general public discuss the impact this technology could have on legal and moral responsibility, informed consent, and various other ethical issues. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedethics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12910-017-0220-y&quot;&gt;In our paper&lt;/a&gt;, we review these issues and call for greater public discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgements: &lt;/strong&gt;Writing of this blog was supported by a joint grant from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research and the Fonds de recherche du Québec – Santé (European Research Projects on Ethical, Legal, and Social Aspects (ELSA) of Neurosciences) as well as a career award from the Fonds de recherche du Québec – Santé.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/18/ethical-questions-raised-by-brain-computer-interfaces/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ethical questions raised by brain-computer interfaces&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 11:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/iStock-180723100-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How social science is driving a sustainable future (with special issue)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-social-science-is-driving-a-sustainable-future-with-special-issue</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-social-science-is-driving-a-sustainable-future-with-special-issue</link>
	<description>Get free access to the most essential social science sustainability research</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 10:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Makerspace creates tech opportunities for young people</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/makerspace-creates-tech-opportunities-for-young-people</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/makerspace-creates-tech-opportunities-for-young-people</link>
	<description>Imperial College London shows the role technologists can play in inspiring students to study STEM whatever their background</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 10:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Our growing tendency to “chunk” our experiences could explain why life speeds up</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32939</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/18/our-growing-tendency-to-chunk-our-experiences-could-explain-why-life-speeds-up/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32940&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-609948680.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32940&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32940&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Passage of the years. Calendar new year. 2017 with background sky and the sun.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;massimo1g&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Calendar year 2017 sky 002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Calendar year 2017 sky 002&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-609948680.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-609948680.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-609948680.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/18/our-growing-tendency-to-chunk-our-experiences-could-explain-why-life-speeds-up/calendar-year-2017-sky-002/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-609948680.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Using mindfulness to appreciate the uniqueness of moments could make it less likely that they’ll be swallowed up into a “chunk”&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Like a ball rolling down a hill, time often seems to pick up momentum, going faster and faster as we get older…,” write the authors of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15298868.2017.1308878?src=recsys&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Self and Identity&lt;/i&gt; that aims to explain the reasons for this phenomenon. Understand it properly, and it might be possible to stop it – because as Mark Landau at the University of Kansas, US, and his colleagues also note: “Perceiving life as rapidly slipping away is psychologically harmful: unpleasant, demotivating, and possibly even hostile to the sense that life is meaningful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32939&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosopher Douglas Hofstadter suggested that the acceleration of time is the result of our increasing tendency through life to package distinct experiences into bigger “chunks”. For example, for a child, a walk in the park can involve so many new experiences – their first sighting of flowers covered in snow, perhaps, or of a scary dog – that each are remembered as distinct individual events. For the adult accompanying that child, if nothing novel happens, all the varied sensations and impressions associated with that walk may be collapsed – or “chunked” – into a single memory of “a walk in the park”. Since, as far as the adult is concerned, only one thing happened, that span of time will be remembered as brief, while for the child, it will feel long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this explanation, the researchers first asked 107 volunteers to either write about how events over the past year of their lives were similar to the events of other years (a task designed to encourage the chunking of past experiences) or to write about how events and activities could have turned out differently (the “no chunking” group). The participants who’d chunked their previous year perceived it as having passed more quickly than an “objective” calendar year, whereas the other group did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the researchers asked a different group of 115 undergraduates to spend two minutes reflecting on how much time they had spent engaged in four different activity categories (school, job, socialising and other), either over the past year, or over the past day. The idea was that this would prompt them to “chunk” experiences together, but over different periods. All these participants then indicated how quickly they felt the previous year had passed, compared with the “average” year. Those who’d “chunked” their past year reported feeling that it had gone faster than those who’d chunked the previous day. “It appears that perceiving a given period as passing faster depends on whether one chunks that period,” the researchers wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also reasoned that if chunking our experiences causes an existential erosion of life’s meaning (by stripping our memories of evocative detail), then we might use nostalgia to help compensate for this. After the two-minute reflection period, the researchers asked all the participants questions about how important nostalgia was to them. Those who’d chunked a whole year said nostalgia was more important than those who’d chunked the previous day, presumably because they’d lost the detail from a greater part of their lives to the chunking process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar results were found with another group of 105 adults asked to draw pie charts, showing how they’d spent their time either over the past year or past day. Again, those who’d chunked a year reported feeling that it had passed more quickly than those who chunked a day. And they also placed more importance on nostalgia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is worth noting,” the researchers add, that “the inductions used here are meant to simulate a chunking process that, we suspect, takes place spontaneously”. We may well chunk all kinds of periods of time – from a day (into “commute”, “work”, “family time”, “eating”, for example) to a year, or even, especially as we reach middle age (when people tend to report that the passage of time really accelerates), even a decade or more. It’s easy to see how looking back over the past ten years of your life and remembering it in terms of just a few “chunks” (“work”, “family time”, “holiday”, for example) could make it feel as though it has passed in a flash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a positive note, if grouping our experiences into broader chunks is a key part of the reason that life seems to speed up as we get older, there are possible ways to counteract this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One antidote might be mindfulness, the researchers suggest. People who try to live “in the moment” may better appreciate the uniqueness of those moments once they have passed, making it less likely that they’ll be swallowed up into a “chunk”. Meditation and engaging with art may perhaps also help, they write, since “these experiences have the potential to re-sensitise us to the satisfaction of simple things and, perhaps, counteract life’s quickening pace”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15298868.2017.1308878?src=recsys&quot;&gt;Why life speeds up: Chunking and the passage of autobiographical time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32939/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32939/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32939&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 08:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Sad World of Uncited Papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9269</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9269</link>
	<description>A Nature News feature examines academic papers that have never been cited.



According to author Richard Van Noorden, by some estimates up to half of all papers have yet to receive their first citation 5 years after publication, and even 10% of Nobel Prizewinners' papers go uncited.

However, Van Noorden reports that these estimates are far too high. For recent papers indexed on Web of Science (WoS), &quot;records suggest that fewer than 10%&quot; remain uncited, and even this is likely an overesti</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 12:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here are our favorite science books of 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/top-favorite-science-books-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/top-favorite-science-books-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Science News writers and editors make their picks for top science books of the year.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_reviews_collage.jpg?itok=O30SHkrG" length="51924" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: The Emerging Neuroscience of Mind-Body Medicine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23045</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/16/the-emerging-neuroscience-of-mind-body-medicine/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;For years as a hard-nosed neuroscientist, I’ve been baffled by the success of clinical techniques that my wife, Chris Gilbert M.D. Ph.D., has pioneered to diagnose and cure illnesses such as back pain, chronic fatigue, stomach ailments, and recurring respiratory infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for my head-scratching is that many of Dr. Chris’s diagnostic tests and therapies involve no technology at all, and are brain-dead simple. The bench scientist and geek in me (sensory physiology/chrono-neurobiology) instinctively rebels against a no-tech approach to anything, let alone medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an age of biotech marvels such as MRI, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/06/14/glioblastoma-can-gene-therapy-really-help/&quot;&gt;gene therapies&lt;/a&gt;, and targeted immunotherapies, my inner scientist is certain that no-tech approaches can’t be nearly as effective as modern medical science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the maddening fact is, my wife’s techniques do often work—so well in fact—that the bulk of her patients come to her because visits to other doctors who employ the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/07/is-placebo-more-powerful-than-antidepressants-and-psychotherapy/&quot;&gt;drugs&lt;/a&gt;, tests, and procedures have failed to yield lasting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cornerstone of Dr. Chris’s approach is a belief that patients’ bodies know more about what is ailing them and how to achieve lasting cures than do the patients’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/03/13/willpower-and-the-unconscious-on-automatic-pilot/&quot;&gt;conscious&lt;/a&gt; minds. So although she will start by asking questions of a patient’s mind, such as “What is going on in your life?” she quickly transitions to a dialogue with a patient’s body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference between talking to the mind and talking to the body?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she addresses a patient’s mind, Dr. Chris simply asks the patient a question, but when she addresses the patient’s body she will first coach the patient to “become” the body part that is suffering, such the lower back, then to respond in the first person as the lower back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once witnessed (with the patient’s permission) a dialogue between Dr. Chris and an ailing back that went like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Chris&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome to my office, Back, tell me how you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back&lt;/strong&gt;: I am stiff all the time, with shooting pains. After the drive home from work, I get horrible spasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Chris&lt;/strong&gt;. Thank you, Back. Do your spasms usually come after sitting for a long time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes!! I hate, hate, hate sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Chris: &lt;/strong&gt;Is there anything else you hate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back&lt;/strong&gt;: I can’t stand my owner’s mother. When we go over for dinner she picks at him endlessly and I get really tense and tight. I want to stay away from that woman!!! I never want to see her again!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Chris&lt;/strong&gt;: Ok, now that I know what you hate, what do you like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back&lt;/strong&gt;: Swimming! I love it when my owner does laps in the pool. I get warm and loose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After observing such sessions and having been Dr. Chris’s patient myself (for stomach troubles), I have been shocked by how much patient’s bodies “know” what their minds don’t know, and how quickly a dialogue with the body can relieve symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the patient in the Back-to-Dr.Chris dialogue professed ignorance about what was triggering his back spasms, only to immediately pinpoint specific triggers for his pain (such as sitting and a nagging mother) when he was queried as his back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that same patient, who walked into the office with a lower back so stiff that he couldn’t bend at the waist, loosened up almost immediately after the Back-to-Dr.Chris dialogue, as if venting of the true source of back pain (sitting too long and being with his mother too long) in and of itself was therapeutic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I overcame my skepticism that such simple, direct techniques could actually work a lot of the time (although not always), I started asking myself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can neuroscience explain the success of Dr. Chris’s brand of mind-body medicine?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confess that I didn’t have a good answer until recently when I stumbled upon two unrelated sets of research findings more or less at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first body of research described &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/09/16/how-to-deal-with-destination-memory-issues-did-i-already-tell-you/&quot;&gt;implicit memory&lt;/a&gt;. It turns out that we are constantly learning things and storing them away in our unconscious without any conscious awareness that we are learning, or indeed, any overt knowledge of what we have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken Paller and Joel Voss of Northwestern University, for example, have shown that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/01/hidden-brain-podcast-review-harnessing-the-power-of-our-unconscious-mind/&quot;&gt;unconscious learning &lt;/a&gt;occurs when test subjects passively observed kaleidoscope images while paying attention to something else. Moreover, those same subjects were able to make correct “intuitive” guesses based upon what they have learned, without having any conscious awareness that they had learned anything in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This finding, along with a host of similar results from other labs, implies that much of what we ascribe to gut feelings, hunches, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2007/04/11/the-source-of-intuition/&quot;&gt;intuition &lt;/a&gt;are actually products of unconscious or implicit learning from past experiences. For example, Dr. Chris’s patient with lower back pain probably learned unconsciously that his back tightened up every time he went over to his mother’s house for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second body of research that offered clues to the success of Dr. Chris’s methods, concerned the storage of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/12/22/uncovering-the-secrets-of-memory-to-reverse-damage-in-alzheimers-patients/&quot;&gt;long-term memories&lt;/a&gt; in the sensory cortex. These studies suggest that sensory experiences leave lasting memory traces in the very parts of the cerebral cortex that initially activate when the experiences originally occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting the implicit learning and sensory memory research together (admittedly something of an intuitive leap) one could conclude that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/25/repressed-memories-fact-or-fiction/&quot;&gt;unconscious memories&lt;/a&gt; relating to sensations in a particular body part, might be stored in the region of the sensory cortex that activates when that body part experiences sensations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a brain map that shows the how areas of the body stimulate different areas of somatosensory cerebral cortex responsible that are responsible for processing touch, vibration, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/27/neurofeedback-therapy-for-the-management-of-pain/&quot;&gt;pain&lt;/a&gt;, and other sensations from different body parts. The somatosensory cortex occupies a gyrus (i.e., ridge) of the brain just behind the central sulcus (i.e, central fold/groove) called the post-central gyrus. Referring to this map, unconscious sensory memories from the back region (as designated by the blue arrow in the diagram below) would be stored near the top of the post-central gyrus, next to the hemispheric fissure that divides the left and right half of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;295&quot; src=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/wp-content/uploads/brain-map-mind-body-medicine-e1513342054240.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what might be happening when Dr. Chris addresses a patient’s back (vs. the patient themselves) is that she is focusing the patient’s attention on somatosensory memories and associations stored in a particular region of the cerebral cortex and that the local activation in the somatosensory cortex occurs that when she does this helps release memories stored in the “back cortex” that would otherwise have remained unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I have no experimental data (such as fMRI brain scans showing somatosensory activation during Dr. Chris’s dialogues) to support this theory, so for the moment, it remains just a theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at least the scientist in me is less baffled knowing that a plausible explanation for Dr. Chris’s successes in mind-body medicine is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on lots of implicit learning accumulated watching Dr. Chris work, my gut intuition is that neuroscience has as much to learn from the success of her methods as she does from neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about Dr. Chris’s methods and my neuro-scientific explanations of them in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Give-Your-Body-Voice-Unconventional/dp/1590794370&quot;&gt;The listening cure: healing secrets of an unconventional doctor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gandhi, S. (2001). Memory retrieval: Reactivating sensory cortex. Current Biology, 11(1), R32-R34. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/s0960-9822(00)00040-3&quot;&gt;10.1016/s0960-9822(00)00040-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gilbert, C. (2017). Listening Cure : Healing Secrets of an Unconventional Doctor. SelectBooks, Incorporated. ISBN:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Give-Your-Body-Voice-Unconventional/dp/1590794370&quot;&gt;1590794370&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasan, M., Hernández-González, S., Dogbevia, G., Treviño, M., Bertocchi, I., Gruart, A., &amp;amp; Delgado-García, J. (2013). Role of motor cortex NMDA receptors in learning-dependent synaptic plasticity of behaving mice. Nature Communications, 4. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/ncomms3258&quot;&gt;10.1038/ncomms3258&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voss, J., &amp;amp; Paller, K. (2009). An electrophysiological signature of unconscious recognition memory. Nature Neuroscience, 12(3), 349-355. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nn.2260&quot;&gt;10.1038/nn.2260&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Activedia-665768/&quot;&gt;Activedia&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 16:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Weaponized plagiarism; bias against low-income country research; the uncited papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53057</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/16/weekend-reads-weaponized-plagiarism-bias-low-income-country-research-uncited-papers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured commentary on yet another paper claiming a link between autism and vaccines, a welcome useful retraction notice, and a rewrite of a paper that influenced car seat guidelines. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Plagiarism has been weaponized by those who want to change the world to their whims.” (Jonathan Bailey, Plagiarism […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/16/weekend-reads-weaponized-plagiarism-bias-low-income-country-research-uncited-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Weaponized plagiarism; bias against low-income country research; the uncited papers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 15:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In marine mammals’ battle of the sexes, vaginal folds can make the difference</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/marine-mammals-battle-sexes-vaginal-folds-can-make-difference</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/marine-mammals-battle-sexes-vaginal-folds-can-make-difference</link>
	<description>Patricia Brennan and colleagues found certain female ocean mammals have vaginal folds that give them an advantage in mating</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_notebook_scilife_main.jpg?itok=OeGpqFNO" length="11692" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Gambling Addiction: Is it as Bad as Cocaine?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23209</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/15/gambling-addiction-is-it-as-bad-as-cocaine/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Is gambling an addictive pathology that causes changes in the brain and requires treatment? Or is it merely a compulsive behaviour? This question has long kept the medical world confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, it was thought that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/01/sex-addiction-defining-the-subtypes-of-hypersexuality-disorder/&quot;&gt;addiction&lt;/a&gt; could happen only when a person is dependent on some physically existing substance. However, now this traditional way of thinking is changing. The brain seems to have a weakness of getting trapped by either a substance or experience that brings a reward, be it drugs, sex, eating, or gambling. Like addiction to substances, addiction to gambling can affect a person of any background, education level, and level of income. Many celebrities are known to be overindulging in gambling. The list includes Tiger Woods, Ben Affleck, and Pamela Anderson, to name just a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once researchers agreed that pathological gambling exists, the question as to whether it is more like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/01/psychedelics-and-drug-addiction/&quot;&gt;drug addiction&lt;/a&gt; or similar to other &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/07/13/multifaceted-causes-of-obsessive-compulsive-disorder/&quot;&gt;obsessive-compulsive disorders&lt;/a&gt; remained unanswered. Modern research seems to support the idea of higher similarity with substance addiction than with obsessive-compulsive disorder. However, it is entirely possible that pathological gambling is a heterogeneous disorder and thus shares the components of both conditions. Hence, in some people it may be more like an obsessive-compulsion, while in others it is similar to substance dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Functional MRI studies seem to support the view that gambling addiction is more like a substance-abuse disorder. Therefore, in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th edition; DSM-5) is has been classified as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/01/07/social-network-addiction-a-scientific-no-mans-land/&quot;&gt;behavioral addiction&lt;/a&gt;. It does not necessarily mean that other types of this disorder do not exist, as this condition is still not fully understood from a medical point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should gambling be considered an addiction&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps due to the absence of any physical substance, addition to experiences like gambling is more challenging to recognize until considerable harm is done. A large number of people addicted to gambling fail to accept this fact. Yet, it is no secret that gambling addiction can ruin life as effectively as substance addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The person involved in gambling gets ‘high’ and finds it difficult to control or limit gambling, which is also characteristic of drugs addiction. Moreover, there are negative emotions similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/13/debunking-the-myths-of-marijuana-withdrawal-syndrome/&quot;&gt;withdrawal syndrome&lt;/a&gt; when a person is deprived of the gambling activity. And finally, even the medications used to treat substance addiction have shown to be efficient in the management of gambling disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neural changes in gambling addiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any addiction is caused by the combination of several factors such as genetic causes, environmental issues, and social influences and problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mesolimbic and mesocortical dopaminergic pathways are central to motivation, desire, and perception of pleasure. Dysregulation in the mesolimbic pathway (often referred to as reward pathway) is known to play a vital role in the development of addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on pathological gambling is still ongoing; this phenomenon is still not fully understood from a neurobiological point of view. It is clear that in pathological gambling multiple neurotransmitter systems (including dopamine, serotonin, norepinephrine, opioid, and glutamate) and various brain regions are implicated (including the amygdala, nucleus accumbens, prefrontal cortex, and insula).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addiction to gambling is the result of a pathological importance being attached to the activity. High level gambling and substance addicts give excessive motivational significance to the addictive activity. Glutamatergic projections from the prefrontal cortex to the accumbens is thought to be the neural pathway involved in provoking gambling seeking behavior. This anatomical path is found to play a role in most forms of behavior dysregulation and addiction. The prefrontal accumbens pathway is vital to providing motivational or reward salience and goal-directed behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, fMRI was used to compare the brain activity of people occasionally involved in gambling against those known to be suffering from pathological gambling. The scans demonstrated a significant difference in blood-oxygen-level dependent (BOLD) signals between the two groups in the superior temporal regions, inferior frontal, and thalamic region. Those pathologically addicted to gambling showed a distinct frontoparietal activation pattern triggered by gambling-related cues, which is known to play a role in the addiction memory network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatment of pathological gambling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the prevalence of pathological gambling is much higher than many psychiatric disorders like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/03/13/schizophrenias-strongest-genetic-link/&quot;&gt;schizophrenia&lt;/a&gt;, there is a lack of studies and trials aimed at finding the appropriate treatment for this problem. Still, there is a small number of studies that seem to favor the effectiveness of pharmacological treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drugs that have shown the ability to modulate dopaminergic transmission in the mesolimbic pathways, like opioid-receptor antagonists (e.g., naltrexone) have demonstrated effectiveness in trials. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/10/25/antidepressants-during-pregnancy-dangerous-for-the-child/&quot;&gt;Antidepressants&lt;/a&gt; and mood stabilizers are the groups of drugs that may prove to be effective in overcoming gambling addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various clinical investigations have also examined the effectiveness of non-pharmacological treatments. It has been demonstrated that cognitive-behavioural therapy (CBT) could be one such option. Some studies have also investigated the usefulness of video conferencing for ongoing supervision, and the use of congruence couple therapy and therapies that have a holistic approach to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up, the latest neurobiology studies confirm that gambling addiction is similar to substance addictions. It may also have serious implications for the person involved, yet little is known regarding how to effectively treat this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blanco, C., Moreyra, P., Nunes, E. V., Sáiz-Ruiz, J., &amp;amp; Ibáñez, A. (2001). Pathological gambling: addiction or compulsion? &lt;em&gt;Seminars in Clinical Neuropsychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(3), 167–176. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1053/scnp.2001.22921&quot;&gt;10.1053/scnp.2001.22921&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant, J. E., &amp;amp; Kim, S. W. (2006). Medication Management of Pathological Gambling. &lt;em&gt;Minnesota Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;89&lt;/em&gt;(9), 44–48.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holden, C. (2001). “Behavioral” Addictions: Do They Exist? &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;294&lt;/em&gt;(5544), 980–982. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.294.5544.980&quot;&gt;10.1126/science.294.5544.980&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalivas, P. W., &amp;amp; Volkow, N. D. (2005). The Neural Basis of Addiction: A Pathology of Motivation and Choice. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;162&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1403–1413. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.162.8.1403&quot;&gt;10.1176/appi.ajp.162.8.1403&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leung, K. S., &amp;amp; Cottler, L. B. (2009). Treatment of pathological gambling. &lt;em&gt;Current Opinion in Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(1).  doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/YCO.0b013e32831575d9&quot;&gt;10.1097/YCO.0b013e32831575d9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miedl, S. F., Fehr, T., Meyer, G., &amp;amp; Herrmann, M. (2010). Neurobiological correlates of problem gambling in a quasi-realistic blackjack scenario as revealed by fMRI. &lt;em&gt;Psychiatry Research: Neuroimaging&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;181&lt;/em&gt;(3), 165–173. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.pscychresns.2009.11.008&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.pscychresns.2009.11.008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potenza, M. N. (2013). Neurobiology of gambling behaviors. &lt;em&gt;Current Opinion in Neurobiology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;23&lt;/em&gt;(4), 660–667. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2013.03.004&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.conb.2013.03.004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potenza, M. N. (2014). The neural bases of cognitive processes in gambling disorder. &lt;em&gt;Trends in Cognitive Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;18&lt;/em&gt;(8), 429–438. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2014.03.007&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.tics.2014.03.007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban, N. B. L., &amp;amp; Martinez, D. (2012). Neurobiology of Addiction:Insight from Neurochemical Imaging. &lt;em&gt;Psychiatric Clinics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;(2), 521–541. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psc.2012.03.011&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.psc.2012.03.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/whekevi-5158749/&quot;&gt;whekevi&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 16:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: University requests 4th retraction for psychologist under fire</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53049</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/15/university-requests-4th-retraction-psychologist-fire/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Amsterdam has requested another retraction for a prominent social psychologist, after reviewing the dissertations he supervised while at the university. The university made the announcement this week after reviewing the theses supervised by Jens Förster, whose own work has been subject to considerable scrutiny. The results of this investigation come more than […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/15/university-requests-4th-retraction-psychologist-fire/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;University requests 4th retraction for psychologist under fire&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: How fruit fly genetics could save your summer smoothies.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9688</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/15/fruit-fly-genetics-summer-smoothies-berries/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/McEvey-2017-Common-licenced-picture-D-suzukii-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winter is here, Christmas is around the corner, but summer will be back before long, and with it fruit salads, smoothies and in the UK, Pimms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a little-known invader is wreaking havoc with fruit stocks worldwide, thanks to pest migration, largely aided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://gd.eppo.int/taxon/DROSSU/distribution&quot;&gt;global trade&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wherever this tiny terror has gone, economically-significant fruit damage has resulted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where invasive species go, environmental and economic damage swiftly follow. Even the seemingly innocuous fruit fly can have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jipm/article/2/1/G1/2193867&quot;&gt;substantial impact&lt;/a&gt;, and it is one particular species, &lt;em&gt;Drosophila suzukii&lt;/em&gt;, which is the focus of recently-published &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenet.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12863-017-0558-7&quot;&gt;article in BMC Genetics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First recorded in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cabi.org/isc/abstract/19410501073&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;, these flies have gone global, invading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cabi.org/isc/datasheet/109283&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gd.eppo.int/taxon/DROSSU/distribution&quot;&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ou.edu/journals/dis/DIS98/Parchami-AraghiEtal(pg59).pdf&quot;&gt;Iran&lt;/a&gt;. Wherever this tiny terror has gone, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5371946/&quot;&gt;economically-significant&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jipm/article/2/1/G1/2193867&quot;&gt;fruit damage&lt;/a&gt; has resulted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;suzukii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt; lives on berries; female flies pierce the fruit and lay eggs, and their larvae eat the fruit from the inside out, leaving it unmarketable and costing millions in lost income and pest management expenses worldwide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This loss is passed on to consumers in the form of higher prices, potentially affecting public health as fruit prices increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each growing season can see 13 generations of &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii &lt;/em&gt;alive at once, giving plenty of opportunity to develop pesticide resistance, requiring increasingly-strong concentrations and combinations of pesticides, which can be environmentally detrimental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9690&quot; style=&quot;width: 259px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-9690&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/Cherry_suzukii-300x270.jpg&quot; width=&quot;249&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Cherry with scarring from D. suzukii damage.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Italy is &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/statistics-explained/index.php/The_fruit_and_vegetable_sector_in_the_EU_-_a_statistical_overview&quot;&gt;one of the major contributors to fruit production in Europe&lt;/a&gt;, and has been materially affected by this invasive species. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.iospress.com/download/journal-of-berry-research/jbr092?id=journal-of-berry-research%2Fjbr092&quot;&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; economic impact in Trento alone could be over 1.5 million euros per annum, even with a pest-management strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, a number of solutions are available. The most well-established of these include the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4780389/pdf/EVA-9-212.pdf&quot;&gt;Sterile Insect Technique (SIT)&lt;/a&gt;  (in which sterile males are introduced into the breeding population to reduce numbers), and genetic elimination methods such as introducing dominant lethal-carrying insects into a population (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4780389/pdf/EVA-9-212.pdf&quot;&gt;RIDL&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are most effective when the genetic structure of the target population is known. Population genetics allow researchers to reconstruct invasion routes, and determine how related populations of a species are. Gabrielle Tait and colleagues used this approach to characterise 9 populations of &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; in Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between October 2015 and April 2016, the authors caught 278 &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; flies in 9 areas of Italy, aiming to determine the genetic differentiation between each population to understand gene flow of the species in a newly-colonised environment. Their study represents the first attempt to investigate the pattern of genetic variability in this species in Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9692&quot; style=&quot;width: 602px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9692 size-full&quot; height=&quot;296&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/Italy.png&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure 1 from Tait et al. 2017. Trapping areas of D. suzukii in Italy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen previously-determined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5004837/&quot;&gt;single sequence repeat&lt;/a&gt; (SSR) markers  (short, repeated sequence of DNA that are useful for measuring relatedness within and between species, populations, and individuals) were used to determine the genetic variability between the populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyses of the molecular variance between the tested populations revealed that there was little total variation between populations of &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; in Italy. A principal coordinate analysis (PCoA) of the 9 populations determined that the Sicilian population was genetically isolated compared to the rest, though they had the same origin as the other populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9693&quot; style=&quot;width: 602px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9693 size-full&quot; height=&quot;322&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/PCOA.png&quot; width=&quot;592&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure 3 from Tait et al. 2017: PCoA of 9 populations generated from genetic distance calculation in GenAIEx program&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F&lt;sub&gt;ST&lt;/sub&gt; values (the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nrg2611.pdf&quot;&gt;summary statistic&lt;/a&gt; of population differentiation) confirmed that the Sicilian population was genetically different compared to the rest. Population structure analysis determined that genetic differentiation between most populations was moderate, indicating admixture between them. This was not true of the Sicilian flies, which were the most differentiated from the other groups, possibly indicating that the Sicilian populations did not migrate significantly to other areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A principal coordinate analysis of the 9 populations determined that the Sicilian population was genetically isolated compared to the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, flies migrated from Apulia to other regions, but not to Apulia from other regions. Besides Sicily and Apulia, migration rates were similar in both directions between all locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the populations, genetic diversity, as analysed by heterozygosity, was high overall, even further away from the likely spreading centre of the species in Livorno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, when there is a ‘source’ or ‘founder’ population, from which other populations derive and migrate, there is a decrease in genetic diversity as the migrating populations move away from the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of decline in heterozygosity when moving geographically away from the Livorno population, and the high migration between locations indicates &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; moves with ease around most of Italy, likely facilitated by human transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors suggest that the lack of gene flow from Sicily to other regions can be explained by human intervention – Sicilian fruit is transported to the rest of Italy during the cold season, when Sicily still sees moderate temperatures ideal for fruit growing. Sicilian &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; taken to Italy in the process do not find ideal conditions on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pest control mechanisms like SIT and RIDL depend upon this information. Heterozygosity is a good measure of how randomly mating happens in a population, so, broadly, if there is higher heterozygosity, there is less inbreeding and population isolation, and these techniques should be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research has also determined the highest and lowest ‘traffic’ areas for population migration of &lt;em&gt;D. suzukii&lt;/em&gt; across Italy, information that can be used to inform management practices, like increased monitoring in high-risk areas, increased control procedures in inspecting and transporting fruit, and the introduction of modified males (SIT or RIDL) early in the season to control the populations in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be great news for fruit growers; not so much for fruit flies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/15/fruit-fly-genetics-summer-smoothies-berries/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How fruit fly genetics could save your summer smoothies.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/McEvey-2017-Common-licenced-picture-D-suzukii-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Max Plank Florida Institute for Neuroscience: Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience Builds Bridges Across the Globe with Annual Neuroscience Retreat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10370</guid>
	<link>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/max-planck-florida-institute-for-neuroscience-builds-bridges-across-the-globe-with-annual-neuroscience-retreat/</link>
	<description>&lt;h4&gt;Leaders from 14 different Max Planck Institutions came together for a meeting of the minds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November of this year, Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI), the only Max Planck Institute in the U.S., hosted the Max Planck Society’s annual Neuroscience Retreat, bringing together directors and group leaders from 14 Max Planck Institutes worldwide who are engaged in neuroscience research. The goal of this three-day event was to share advancements across the institutions and discover new areas of potential collaboration. The panel of expert speakers featured three keynotes: Prof. Dr. Axel Borst, Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology; Prof. Dr. David Poeppel, Max Planck Institute for Empirical Aesthetics; and Prof. Dr. Reinhard Jahn, Max Planck Institute for Biophysical Chemistry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. Dr. Axel Borst from the Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology in Martinsried, Germany discussed how nerve cells compute the direction of motion. His work involves understanding the neural information processing at the level of individual neurons and small neural circuits. Prof. Dr. David Poeppel, from the Max Planck Institute for Empirical Aesthetics in Frankfurt, Germany, spoke on the brain’s basis of speech perception and language comprehension. The Max Planck Institute for Empirical Aesthetics aims to use scientific methods to explain the psychological, neuronal and socio-cultural basis of aesthetic perceptions and judgments. Prof. Dr. Reinhard Jahn, who has served as Director and Scientific Member at the Max Planck Institute for Biophysical Chemistry since 1997, discussed &lt;em&gt;Exocytosis of synaptic vesicles – a closer look at the fusion machine&lt;/em&gt;. His work includes studying how synaptic vesicles are filled within seconds with thousands of neurotransmitter molecules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are honored to have hosted such a diverse and talented group of researchers,” said Dr. David Fitzpatrick, Chief Executive Officer and Scientific Director at MPFI. “The weekend was filled with discussion around opportunities and challenges among the members of this Max Planck neuroscience research community. Collaboration is key to unlocking major scientific discoveries and we are proud to have served as the catalyst for work that has great implications for the public.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By hosting this event, MPFI is building on strategies to continuously improve and grow the thriving neuroscience community in South Florida. For more information about the Max Planck Neuroscience community across the globe, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maxplanckneuroscience.org/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.maxplanckneuroscience.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 13:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “This is about saving kids’ lives:” Authors update pivotal car seat safety results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53040</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/15/saving-kids-lives-authors-update-pivotal-car-seat-safety-results/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A BMJ journal has published an updated analysis of a 2007 paper that shaped current car seat safety recommendations, which reports less conclusive findings about the safest way to install the seat. The updated analysis follows an expression of concern the journal Injury Prevention added to the paper in June 2017, after the authors and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/15/saving-kids-lives-authors-update-pivotal-car-seat-safety-results/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“This is about saving kids’ lives:” Authors update pivotal car seat safety results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Even brain images can be biased</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/even-brain-images-can-be-biased</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/even-brain-images-can-be-biased</link>
	<description>Brain scan studies that are drawn from rich and well-educated groups could lead to biased ideas of how our brains develop.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/blogposts/121317_BB_brain_feat.jpg?itok=FW45m9oL" length="69713" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Positive parenting gets “under the skin”, showing up years later in the cortisol response</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32930</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/15/positive-parenting-gets-under-the-skin-showing-up-years-later-in-the-cortisol-response/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-564565088.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32931&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32931&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cute pretty teen daughter with mature mother hugging in nature at sunset&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1468696430&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Kikovic&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Daughter with mother hugging at sunset&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Daughter with mother hugging at sunset&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-564565088.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-564565088.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-564565088.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/15/positive-parenting-gets-under-the-skin-showing-up-years-later-in-the-cortisol-response/daughter-with-mother-hugging-at-sunset/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-564565088.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adolescence is when values and relationships are formed and things happen that leave their sticky fingerprints on the life that follows. Even, it seems, in the everyday functioning of brain systems. &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12461/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;New research&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;i&gt;Developmental Science&lt;/i&gt; shows that when teenagers have a positive relationship with their parents, then as adults their brains and bodies respond to stress in a way that helps them better engage with the world. However, the study suggests this benefit may be denied to those raised in a rough environment, which seems to override the influence of positive parenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32930&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, led by Elizabeth Shirtcliff of Iowa State University, studied hundreds of people from Seattle, USA, who, when they were teenagers, had described their relations with their parents through questions like “are you close to your mother?” Trained raters also scored how much encouragement and appropriate reward they received from their parents, based on videos taken of the teens and their parents completing various structured tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some five years later, 280 of the then-teens, now aged between 19 and 22 years, provided saliva samples to Shirtcliff’s team to gauge their cortisol levels. Cortisol is a key indicator of HPA (hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis) activity, which governs our sensitivity to new information and stressors. After controlling for variables such as gender, family income, and sleep habits, the researchers wanted to see how cortisol was related to the measures of teen-parent relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in the analysis it became clear that although the White (European American) and Black (African American) participants in the sample had received similar quality parental care, there were different patterns within these ethnic groups, so the researchers separated them before analysing the results further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the European Americans, having a positive relationship when they were teenagers with their parents, together with observer ratings of having received greater praise and reward from their parents, were all associated with showing higher cortisol levels on waking in young adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem surprising that better teen care would be associated with higher cortisol levels in adulthood – and this certainly contrasts with work on infancy, where high quality care leads to a dampened HPA response. But remember that cortisol stimulates greater attention and alertness. Higher cortisol isn’t much use, or much fun, for a helpless infant already drowning in novelty, so knowing a caregiver will deal with your stress helps them avoid pointless panic at every new detail. However, Shirtcliff and her colleagues think that this sensitive, high-waking cortisol profile, apparently promoted by positive parenting, might generally be advantageous in adult life, helping you notice nuances in human behaviour and drink in the details a little more deeply. In the absence of positive parental relations to buffer stress, in contrast, the HPA system dials down the cortisol response as a protective measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there was little evidence of a high-cortisol profile in any of the African American participants. The results were somewhat mixed, but overall this seemed to be regardless of the quality of the family care they’d received as teenagers. The researchers speculated that this might because the African American participants had been exposed to more early life challenges than the White participants – related to housing, crime, access to resources – that were enough to put them into the protective, self-buffering mode, even if they’d had the most supportive and positive relationship with their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research suggests that poorer care during upbringing can cast a long shadow, distancing us as adults from everyday experience, both urgent and enjoyable. On the other hand, positive parenting seems to have benefits that last into adulthood. But the  apparent lack of this benefit among the African American participants challenges the predominantly right-wing suggestion that the long-term problems faced by minorities can be primarily addressed by remedying the greater familial breakdown seen in some ethnic minority groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12461/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;Positive parenting predicts cortisol functioning six years later in young adults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32930/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32930/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32930&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 08:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: Don’t rule the lab with an iron fist: tips for effective lab management</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=599</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/12/15/dont-rule-the-lab-with-an-iron-fist-tips-for-effective-lab-management/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;download&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-600 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;600&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;download&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/download.jpg?w=479&amp;amp;h=217?w=333&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/download.jpg?w=479&amp;amp;h=217?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/download.jpg?w=479&amp;amp;h=217&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;333,151&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/12/15/dont-rule-the-lab-with-an-iron-fist-tips-for-effective-lab-management/download-2/&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/download.jpg?w=479&amp;amp;h=217&quot; width=&quot;479&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the latest in our semi-regular (trying to be regular) blog series, with the indomitable &lt;a href=&quot;http://@SueReviews&quot;&gt;Sue Fletcher-Watson&lt;/a&gt;. The practical skills of being a good scientist are rarely taught but are vital. This is the subject for our series of blogs, and this time we are turning our attention to managing the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have your University position, you have research funding of some kind (whoop!), and the lab – you, your students, researchers and technicians – is starting to take shape. Managing the team effectively will make for happy and productive group members. This can turn into a virtuous cycle – lab members who enjoy what they are doing are a joy to manage, and make your life so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is stuff we have learnt over the past few years. The points are broadly organised into two sections – firstly we discuss issues of organisation and management style, then we move onto the non-science elements of a successful lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balance lab identity with flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem obvious, but a group needs a shared identity that their projects can hang off. This could be a series of over-arching questions, a particular sample of interest, a set of new methods you are advancing, or a core set of principles. A clear group identity helps lab members understand the overall picture, how their science is contributing, and how/where expertise can be shared. When Sue joined the Patrick Wild Centre and was given a branded PhD mug it made her feel one of the team. This kind of thing makes a real difference for new staff and students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be careful that your lab identity doesn’t kill off flexibility. It’s important that individual lab members are able to take intellectual ownership of their work, even if they are junior. In Duncan’s lab he focuses cognitive and brain development in childhood. When a potential student approached him with an interest in socio-economic status he was initially very reluctant. He could see it could easily turn into an intractable mush – that literature can be a real mess. But he went with it, and together they put together a project they were both happy with. Turns out, the student was amazing, the project highly successful, and this line of research now forms a main arm of his current research programme. Giving lab members intellectual ownership and being flexible about projects means that you give your students and staff permission to innovate. In science this is the most valuable thing of all, and an essential component of how we make progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So have a clear identity and make sure this is explicit, and understood by all members – but don’t sacrifice flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balance easy wins and long-term goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting your lab you will have various potential projects. In the early days when the lab is small you need to be strategic. Investing all of your energies (and those of your lab) in a single demanding, high-risk project, which may take several years to come to fruition, is unwise. When Duncan started his lab in Cambridge a very wise mentor told him to balance easy wins and long-term goals – alongside a large project he needed simpler experiments. This advice was invaluable. That big project took Duncan’s embryonic team 18 months to collect the data alone, and another 18 months or so to analyse fully. All the lab members were trying to build their CVs and could not afford an empty patch for 3 years. So along the way they published several standalone experimental papers, which made everyone feel more relaxed and meant they could establish ourselves as a lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(In the end that big project came to fruition and generated multiple big papers, so our patience was rewarded!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, during Sue’s postdoc she designed a novel intervention and then evaluated it in a small randomised controlled trial.  That’s a long time to wait for your big paper. To make matters worse, she took maternity leave twice during the project! It was a tough time, waiting for that research to get out into the world, though writing a few review papers and getting the remainder of her PhD studies into journals helped pass the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t rule your lab with an iron fist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all heard about those labs where the staff are not so much managed as subjugated (maybe there will be a blog on that, if we are feeling brave enough). Lab members are micromanaged, their outgoing emails vetted and they are subjected to surprise inspections. If you are tempted to run your lab in this way, or if this is your natural management style, our advice: &lt;u&gt;just don’t&lt;/u&gt;.  It results in very unhappy lab members, creates needless extra work for you, and is ultimately pointless. If your lab members are not enjoying working within your group then they will not be productive. Running them like a sweatshop will do nothing to improve that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better approach is to have a clear role-setting process when each member joins the lab. Explain your role as the PI and their role as the post-doc (or whatever). This role-setting includes outlining expectations – mandatory meetings, duties within the group, initial goals, the schedule for your individual meetings etc. If you feel this has not been respected, then of course, pull them up and gently tell them that you want to change things. But don’t micro-manage your group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have regular meetings with minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular group meetings (we both have them fortnightly) provide a space for sharing experience, best practice, technical expertise, troubleshooting and peer support. They’re also a quick and easy way to get a snapshot of where everyone is up to on their projects. Good lab meetings will save you time, and build a happy team. Make sure you reserve a timeslot and don’t let them run over. If you fall into the habit of having needlessly long lab meetings they can easily become onerous. Keep them to time. When you meet, get members of the lab to take turns writing minutes. Sue’s lab stores these in a shared folder which is also crammed with resources to help lab members work independently – model ethics documents and cover letters, useful logos and campus maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes subgroups within your lab may need to meet without you – let them. This could be a really valuable way of them tackling various problems without you needing to expend any time. Don’t insist on being there for every discussion or meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we have focussed on elements of lab organisation, strategy and management style. For the next set of points we turn our attention to the more interpersonal elements of running a successful lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage your lab to have a social life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Duncan’s lab there is a designated Social Secretary, with the job of orchestrating lab social events (checking availability, garnering opinion of what people would like to do, making bookings etc). Make sure that any social events are not enforced, and remember that alcohol is not an essential component of social occasions! It is important not to make anyone feel excluded. N.B. some social activities like life drawing classes might be an unwise choice (sorry Joe), so try to stick to simple events that allow everyone an opportunity to chat without feeling uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things to keep in mind: what is your role within these social situations? Remember that you still have to be these people’s boss come Monday morning. Have fun but don’t be unprofessional. No-nos include gossiping about your colleagues or asking intrusive questions about people’s personal lives. While taking to the dancefloor to bust a groove is a big YES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a good mentor and keep an eye on wellbeing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running a successful lab is also about keeping an eye on the wellbeing of those you manage. It’s important to let them know that you care. Both Sue and Duncan make a point of asking, even though everyone seems pretty happy most of the time. This makes lab members mindful of their own wellbeing and flags the fact that you are a person they can speak to if / when they struggle. If you’re doing an annual review, ask them if they’re happy with their work-life balance. Remind your lab group to take time off – especially PhD students who can fall for the myth that they ought to be working 7-day weeks. It can also be a good idea for lab members to have mentors outside the group. With their mentor they can discuss matters like job opportunities, or difficulties they are having with their PI (i.e. you!). It can also provide a valuable alternate perspective on their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always a slight tension about how much of your own personal life you expose lab members to. Both Sue and Duncan think it is important to show your lab members that you too are a human being, with your own stresses, frustrations and problems. In our experience, when you choose to be yourself with your lab members, and be honest about how you are doing, you give lab members permission to do likewise. It creates a safe space in which everyone feels that they can be themselves, and this is important in creating a supportive work environment. Don’t overshare, but do be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there we have it, our tips on running an effective lab. &lt;strong&gt;Be flexible, be a human being, be a good scientist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/599/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/599/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=599&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 08:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Harvard and Elsevier explore collaborations in data science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/harvard-and-elsevier-explore-collaborations-in-data-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/harvard-and-elsevier-explore-collaborations-in-data-science</link>
	<description>For the Harvard Data Science Initiative, colleagues brainstormed about how to support evidence-based policy and advance precision medicine and healthcare</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 06:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Data Protection and Compliance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1204</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/12/data-protection-and-compliance/</link>
	<description>&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Are Your Outsourced R&amp;amp;D Partners Ready for 2018?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Compliance-Article.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Compliance Article&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1205&quot; height=&quot;149&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Compliance-Article-300x209.png&quot; width=&quot;214&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The latest news from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2017/12/13/Science-Exchange-continues-expanding-outsourced-research-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Outsourcing-pharma.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; investigates the compliance challenges being faced by companies, their information technology teams, and their outsourced R&amp;amp;D partners in light of the upcoming &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2017/12/13/Science-Exchange-continues-expanding-outsourced-research-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The GDPR, which will go into effect on May 25, 2018, has been called “the most important change to data privacy regulation in 20 years,” and will impact most companies that handle personal data of EU citizens. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Although the regulation applies to many contract research organizations (CROs) and their clients, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2017/12/13/Science-Exchange-continues-expanding-outsourced-research-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;only &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;8 out of 40 top CROs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; have achieved EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, which demonstrates adherence to GDPR requirements. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Outsourcing Pharma &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outsourcing-pharma.com/Article/2017/12/13/Science-Exchange-continues-expanding-outsourced-research-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;interviewed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO and Co-Founder of Science Exchange, which received Privacy Shield Framework certification earlier this year. Dozens of companies are partnering with Science Exchange to mitigate risk — knowing that, by outsourcing R&amp;amp;D through Science Exchange’s secure platform, they will be protected from fines and noncompliance, even if CROs are not compliant.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Andrew Gutierrez, CFCM, Science Exchange’s Director of Contracts and Compliance, adds his thoughts around the implications of GDPR on pharma, biotech and life sciences:  “With the GDPR compliance deadline imminent next year, companies based in the US and operating in the EU must have a strategy in place to ensure they’re prepared for the impact on data transfer processes, including with their outsourced R&amp;amp;D partners.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“With the right plan in place, organizations can adhere to regulations and remain competitive, without disruptions to R&amp;amp;D programs. At Science Exchange, we reviewed our processes and quickly received EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification. These steps not only protect our customers and the outsourced R&amp;amp;D data transferred through our platform, but also save our customers significant time and resources they might spend ensuring compliance — or paying up to 20 million euros in fines for noncompliance.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Be safe and GDPR-compliant – &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;contact Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to request a demonstration of our platform and a free consultation with our compliance team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: AI has found an 8-planet system like ours in Kepler data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ai-has-found-8-planet-system-ours-kepler-data</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ai-has-found-8-planet-system-ours-kepler-data</link>
	<description>An AI spotted an eighth planet circling a distant star, unseating the solar system as the sole record-holder for most known planets.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 01:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121417_MT_kepler_main_REV.jpg?itok=g_LpYjcP" length="9567" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These weather events turned extreme thanks to human-driven climate change</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-weather-events-turned-extreme-thanks-human-driven-climate-change</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-weather-events-turned-extreme-thanks-human-driven-climate-change</link>
	<description>Ruling out natural variability, scientists say several of 2016’s extreme weather events wouldn’t have happened without human-caused climate change.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 21:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121317_CG_climatechange_feat.jpg?itok=SlidUoSK" length="58974" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Saturn’s rings are surprisingly young and may be from shredded moons</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-rings-age-young-moons</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/saturn-rings-age-young-moons</link>
	<description>Final data from the Cassini spacecraft put a date and a mass on the gas giant’s iconic rings.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121417_LG_saturn_feat.jpg?itok=26Bloe17" length="13963" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: U.S. religion is increasingly polarized</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/us-religion-increasingly-polarized</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/us-religion-increasingly-polarized</link>
	<description>Organized religion in the United States increasingly belongs to fervent believers, a new study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121217_BB_religion_feat.jpg?itok=CVEmhXB9" length="21506" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Mathematician protests retraction, alleging “manhunt”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53032</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/14/mathematician-protests-retraction-alleging-manhunt/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A math journal has retracted a 2015 paper after three outside experts informed the editors that “the paper contains errors which invalidate its main results.” According to the retraction notice, published in the July 2017 issue of Manuscripta Mathematica, the author Ilya Karzhemanov “has not admitted to the alleged errors and disagrees with the retraction.” […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/14/mathematician-protests-retraction-alleging-manhunt/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mathematician protests retraction, alleging “manhunt”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 16:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In a tally of nerve cells in the outer wrinkles of the brain, a dog wins</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/animals-nerve-cells-neurons-brain-comparison</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/animals-nerve-cells-neurons-brain-comparison</link>
	<description>Among some carnivores, golden retrievers rate at the top for numbers of nerve cells, study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/120517_LS_brain-comparison_main.jpg?itok=xbKXEmer" length="24476" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice:  A retraction that is “useful for investigators”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53019</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/14/caught-notice-retraction-useful-investigators/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title:  Yeast CAF-1 assembles histone (H3-H4) 2 tetramers prior to DNA deposition What Caught Our Attention: Informative retraction notices can be infrequent, but rarer still are notices that fulfill an oft-ignored function: To be a source of learning for others in the field. Here, the authors offer a nearly 800-word “detailed description of the issues” […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/14/caught-notice-retraction-useful-investigators/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice:  A retraction that is “useful for investigators”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: An abundance of toys can curb kids’ creativity and focus</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/too-many-toys-creativity</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/too-many-toys-creativity</link>
	<description>Too many toys may lead to more shallow play for toddlers, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/blogposts/121317_LS_toys-creativity_feat.jpg?itok=ELhZEm4p" length="51032" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: These Elsevier collaborations use machine learning to turn data into knowledge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/these-elsevier-collaborations-use-machine-learning-to-turn-data-into-knowledge</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/these-elsevier-collaborations-use-machine-learning-to-turn-data-into-knowledge</link>
	<description>Computer scientists are finding new ways to extract information from the literature, making data more accessible in bioinformatics, chemistry and clinical decision support</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 10:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Healthy diet, happy child</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9662</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/14/healthy-diet-happy-child/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/FFOOD-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the mood for food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growing body of evidence has suggested that diet is just as important to mental health as it is to physical health, with an unhealthy diet presenting risks for depression, anxiety and even schizophrenia. Ingesting adequate amounts of complex carbohydrates, essential fats, amino acids, vitamins, minerals and water can provide feelings of well-being; diet recommendations for promoting a balanced mood include eating fewer high sugar foods and more wholegrain cereals, nuts, beans, lentils, fruits and vegetables. This is discussed further in a 2015 &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2015/10/07/diet-mental-health-food-affect-mood/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; presenting research published in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which suggests that fruit and vegetable consumption may be associated with reduced psychological distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although half of mental illnesses first manifest prior to 14 years of age, evidence of the association between diet and psychosocial well-being in children is limited and inconsistent. Most studies are observational and it is therefore difficult to tease apart cause and effect. Furthermore, it is possible that observed associations are explained by reverse causality – ie: mental ill health promotes an unhealthy diet rather than the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diet and happiness in children &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This calls for a need for more prospective studies on the subject. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4920-5&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published today in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Louise Arvidsson and colleagues have investigated the bidirectional association between adherence to healthy dietary guidelines and children’s psychosocial well-being. They have also examined how the associations might differ between children with different weight status. It is the first study of its kind and the study findings are unique in that they are based on a large longitudinal study of children from different parts of Europe, adding to the largely cross-sectional, current evidence on diet and psychosocial health in children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9666 size-full alignright&quot; height=&quot;158&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/Happykids.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers examined 7,675 children two to nine years of age from eight European countries – Belgium, Cyprus, Estonia, Germany, Hungary, Spain and Sweden. At the beginning of the study, parents were asked to report how often per week their children consumed food from a list of 43 items. Children were then assigned a Healthy Dietary Adherence (HDAS) score depending on the consumption of these foods. The HDAS aims to capture adherence to healthy dietary guidelines, which includes limiting intake of refined sugars, reducing fat intake and eating fruit and vegetables. A higher HDAS indicates better adherence to the guidelines and therefore healthier eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also measured children’s weight and height and assessed well-being based on self-esteem, parent relations, emotional and peer problems as reported by the parents in response to validated questionnaires. All questionnaires and measurements were repeated two years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study found that a higher HDAS at the beginning of the study period was associated with better self-esteem and fewer emotional and peer problems two years later. Fish intake according to guidelines (2-3 times per week) was associated with better self-esteem and no emotional and peer problems. Intake of whole meal products were associated with no peer problems. The researchers also concluded that the associations between HDAS and well-being were similar for children who had normal weight and children who were overweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emotions regulate eating and vice versa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9667 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/food-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;The associations in the study were found to go in both directions; better well-being was associated with consumption of fruit and vegetables in accordance with dietary guidelines, better self-esteem was associated with limited intake of refined sugars, good parent relations were associated with fruit and vegetable consumption according to guidelines, fewer emotional problems were associated with fat intake according to guidelines and fewer peer problems were associated with consumption of fruit and vegetables according to guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food for thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental disorders account for the largest disability across the globe. With the 20th century seeing major shifts in dietary intakes globally, there is a marked increase in the consumption of sugars, snack foods, take-away foods and high-energy foods, suggesting that the threat of an increase in mental health disorders is bigger than ever. The findings of research such as that discussed above are important for bringing to the forefront the urgency of addressing obesogenic environments and providing prevention and treatment strategies that focus on improving our diets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/12/14/healthy-diet-happy-child/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Healthy diet, happy child&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/12/FFOOD-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: “Strongest evidence yet” for ego depletion – the idea that self control is a limited resource</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32909</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/14/strongest-evidence-yet-for-ego-depletion-the-idea-that-self-control-is-a-limited-resource/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-543744061.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32923&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32923&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D810&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1422508390&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tara Moore&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;56&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;504&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young man with laptop at home rubbing his eyes&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young man with laptop at home rubbing his eyes&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-543744061.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-543744061.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-543744061.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2112,1419&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/14/strongest-evidence-yet-for-ego-depletion-the-idea-that-self-control-is-a-limited-resource/young-man-with-laptop-at-home-rubbing-his-eyes/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-543744061.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, “ego depletion” has been a dominant theory in the study of self control. This is the intuitive idea that self control or willpower is a limited resource, such that the more you use up in one situation, the less you have left over to deploy in another. It makes sense of the everyday experience of when you come home after a hard day at the office, abandon all constructive plans, and instead binge on snacks in front of the TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble is, the theory has taken some hard knocks lately, including a failed joint replication attempt by &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1745691616652873&quot;&gt;23 separate labs&lt;/a&gt;. Critics have pointed out that most supportive studies – and there are over 200 of them – are small and underpowered. &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/24/new-research-challenges-the-idea-that-willpower-is-a-limited-resource/&quot;&gt;A meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; that corrected for a positive bias in the existing literature concluded that ego depletion is not real. A study in India – where there’s a cultural belief that exercising self-control is energising – even found evidence for “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/12/reverse-ego-depletion-people-in-india-find-mental-effort-energising/&quot;&gt;reverse ego depletion&lt;/a&gt;“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not easy to weigh the evidence for and against, but perhaps the science is tipping back in favour of ego depletion. Two new studies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/pgny3/&quot;&gt;made publicly available on the PsyArXiv preprint website&lt;/a&gt;, provide what the researchers at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, led by Katie Garrison, describe as “the strongest evidence yet of the ego depletion effect”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32909&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studies involved relatively large samples and were preregistered, meaning the methods and hypotheses were made publicly available prior to data collection, a practice that reduces the risk of false-positive or spurious results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard format in most research into ego depletion is that one group of participants perform a particularly challenging version of a mental task, designed to drain their self control, then they perform a second task. A control group performs an easy version of the same initial task, then performs the exact same second task as the first group. Inferior performance on the second task by the “ego depleted” group compared with the control group is taken as evidence for ego depletion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garrison and her colleagues followed this format. In a first study with 657 student participants, the first task involved either writing for five minutes about a recent trip (easy version) or writing about a recent trip without using the letters “A” or “N” (i.e. a more difficult version requiring more self control). The writing task was followed by one of two versions of the Stroop task: either participants had to name the ink colour of colour-denoting words, such as the word “red” written in blue ink, or the ink colour of emotional or neutral words. It takes a degree of self control to ignore the meaning of colour words, or emotional words, and focus on the ink colour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants who completed the more difficult version of the writing task responded just as fast, but made more mistakes on the Stroop tasks than the control group. “This pattern represents unambiguous evidence for poorer attention control under ego depletion,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second study was similar. Over 350 participants completed either the easy or difficult writing task and then the Attention Network Test, which involves repeatedly indicating the direction of target arrows on a computer screen, while ignoring the direction of adjacent, distracting arrows, which either face in the same or a different direction (the task is trickier when they face in a different direction). Participants who completed the harder writing task made more errors on the Attention Network Test, which is again consistent with ego depletion theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a complication with the second study. When the researchers removed outlier participants, as they said they would in their preregistered plans (for instance because participants were particularly slow or fast to respond, or made a particularly large number of mistakes), then there was no longer a significant difference in performance on the Attention Network Test between participants who’d performed the easy or difficult version of the writing task. However, it’s notable that more participants who’d completed the difficult writing task were excluded for making excessive amounts of errors on the attention test, which is again as would be expected based on ego depletion theory. Moreover, combining results from the two studies, there was an overall small, but statistically significant, ego depletion effect even after removing outlier participants (and this was after only a five-minute self control challenge, so you can imagine the effects being larger after more arduous real life challenges).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it can be established that ego depletion is a real thing, a question remains about how exactly it occurs, such as whether it’s due to running out of self control, or perhaps more to do with motivation or conserving energy. “The answer remains to be seen,” the researchers concluded, “but the current experiments provide new evidence that this is still a question worth asking”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyarxiv.com/pgny3/&quot;&gt;Ego Depletion Reduces Attention Control: Evidence from Two High-Powered Preregistered Experiments&lt;/a&gt; (note, this paper is a pre-print, which means it hasn’t yet been subjected to peer review)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Further reading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-25/edition-2/self-control-%E2%80%93-moral-muscle&quot;&gt;Self-control – the moral muscle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg23531420-400-dont-quit-now-why-you-have-more-willpower-than-you-think/&quot;&gt;Don’t quit now: Why you have more willpower than you think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32909/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32909/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32909&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 09:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fracking linked to low birth weight in Pennsylvania babies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fracking-linked-low-birth-weight-pennsylvania-babies</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fracking-linked-low-birth-weight-pennsylvania-babies</link>
	<description>Babies born to moms living within one kilometer of a hydraulic fracturing site were more likely to be born underweight, researchers say.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 22:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121217_AC_fracking-birth-weight_main_free.jpg?itok=PdIr7dNj" length="19281" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Federal maps underestimate flood risk for tens of millions of people, scientists warn</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/federal-maps-underestimate-flood-risk-tens-millions-people-scientists-warn</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/federal-maps-underestimate-flood-risk-tens-millions-people-scientists-warn</link>
	<description>New flood maps suggest that the U.S. government underestimates how many people live in floodplains.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 20:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121217_CG_flood-risk_main.jpg?itok=u127I8Ph" length="54356" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Electric eels provide a zap of inspiration for a new kind of power source</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/electric-eels-provide-zap-inspiration-new-kind-power-source</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/electric-eels-provide-zap-inspiration-new-kind-power-source</link>
	<description>Battery-like devices inspired by electric eels could someday power wearable and implantable tech or soft robots.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 18:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121317_MT_eelpower_feat.jpg?itok=xLbhKti1" length="48273" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These are the most-read Science News stories of 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-popular-stories-science-news-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-popular-stories-science-news-2017-yir</link>
	<description>From Cassini and eclipses to ladybugs and dolphins, Science News online readers had a wide variety of favorite stories on our website.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_feedback_main.jpg?itok=U2KqTqbs" length="18846" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: How Does Starting School Early Impact Educational Attainment?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23211</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/13/how-does-starting-school-early-impact-educational-attainment/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A singular cutoff point for school entry results in age differences between children of the same grade. In many school systems, September-born children, begin compulsory education in September of the year in which they turn five, making them relatively older than summer born children who begin school aged four.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on these annually age-grouped cohorts reveal relative age effects (RAEs) that convey the greater achievements accrued by the relatively old (RO) students compared to the relatively young (RY) students. RAEs are pervasive. Across OECD countries, in fourth grade, RY students scored 4–12% lower than RO students, while in eight grade the difference was 2–9% lower. RAEs are most evident in early formal education and can diminish as children mature. In 2016 for instance, Thoren, Heinig, and Brunner published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00679&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; on three grades attending public school in Berlin, Germany, and showed that the RAE in disappeared for reading by grade 8 and was reversed for math in favor of RY students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating the mechanisms involved is important because RAEs can remain evident in &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1920/wp.ifs.2010.1006&quot;&gt;high-stakes&lt;/a&gt; exams taken at the end of compulsory education. RAEs may impact educational attainment, which is defined as an individual’s highest educational qualification (i.e., compulsory schooling, apprenticeship, or university education). For example, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cambridgeassessment.org.uk/Images/109784-birthdate-effects-a-review-of-the-literature-from-1990-on.pdf&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; by Sykes, Bell, and Rodeiro found that 5% less August-born GCSE students than September-born GCSE students chose at least one A level. Likewise, August-born students were 20% less likely to progress to university than September-born students. RO students also outperformed RY students on college admission tests to a university in Brazil, which significantly impacted the probability of being accepted to that university. Moreover, in Japan the percentage of graduates (aged 19–22 and 23–25) was two points greater for those born in April than those born in March. Collectively, these findings indicate that RAEs impact educational attainment because of their direct link to students’ acceptance to higher education. Since much of children’s development occurs within compulsory education, a natural question is whether educators act to alleviate or exacerbate RAE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAEs emerge primarily because of within-group maturity differences among RO and RY children (age-at-school-entry effect). RO children, have a one-year developmental advantage over RY children when they sit exams (age-at-test effect). Based on these advantaged test scores and maturation, RO children receive special opportunities from educators to excel in school. Using attainment, program participation, and attendance data from 657 students aged 11–14 from a secondary school in North England, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0013845&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Cobley, McKenna, Baker and Wattie found that RO students were more likely than RY students achieve high scores across various subjects and be admitted to gifted programs. Even if RO students accepted to gifted programs are not actually gifted, the prestige of attending such programs would help them to foster strong positive self-esteem, which can persist over time. In turn, RO students may experience enhanced learning and praise long after small age differences are important in and of themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, teachers lower their expectations of RY students because RY students appear less developed and intelligent than RO students. Interestingly, having RO classmates can prompt a spillover effect that boosts RY students’ grades, but also increases the probability that RY students will to be pathologized. This research suggests that RAEs emerge as a consequence of maturity differences but are maintained by the magnitude and persistence of social factors, such as educator-student interaction. Another &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1503/cmaj.111619&quot;&gt;study &lt;/a&gt; also reported RAEs in the diagnosis and treatment of ADHD in children aged 6–12 in British Columbia. Incorrect diagnosis can unnecessarily limit RY students’ academic performance by diminishing their self-esteem and task involvement, which are school achievement predictors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these inequalities decline over time, the influence of RAE on educational attainment is arguably minimal. However, if relative advantages such as skill accumulation persist in favor of RO students throughout formal education, RAEs translate into academic disadvantages for RY students. For instance, RY students’ negative self-perceptions of academic competence and learning disability can mediate the relationship between depressive symptoms and school dropout in adolescence. In turn, lack of formal education or poor academic performance makes entry to higher education arduous. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1920/wp.ifs.2010.1006&quot;&gt;Research &lt;/a&gt; illustrates with 16-year-old RY students scoring 0.13 standard deviations lower than RO students. This test score predicted that RY students would have a 5.8% higher potential dropout rate from high school and a consequently 1.5% lower college admission rate than RO students. Initial gains for RO students partly explain why they have a 10% greater probability of attending top-ranking universities and why they are more likely to graduate from university than RY students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on the impact of RAE on educational attainment is not as straightforward as discussed thus far. Cascio and Schanzenbach used experimental variation by randomly assigning students to classrooms. Results showed improved test scores for RY students up to eight years after kindergarten and an increased probability of taking a college-entry exam. These positive spillover effects are evident when RY students, in a relatively mature peer environment, strive to catch up with higher-achieving RO students and end up surpassing them. Since RO students may strain under the expectations placed on them to be top of the class, RY students have an opportunity to catch up. Alternatively, RO students may not have the same incentive as RY students to work hard for academic success because RAEs already work in their favor. To overcome RAEs and succeed academically, RY students need greater persistence and attention than RO students in their schoolwork, which helps them gain a motivated mindset that benefits lifelong learning. For example, RY students in high school are more likely than RO students to study and compensate for poor academic achievement in middle school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a university in Italy, RY students obtained better grades than RO students. This reversal effect was also reported at university in the UK. The researchers postulated that due to RAEs, the RY students developed social skills more slowly. Therefore, RY students had less active social lives and more time to concentrate on educational attainment. The impact of RAEs on educational attainment is, subsequently, probabilistic not deterministic. Although &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03055690802034302&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; by Abel, Sokol, Kruger, and Yargeau indicated that RAEs do not affect the success of either RO or RY students’ university applications, they reported that more RO than RY students applied to medical school. In addition, Kniffin and Hank’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/coep.12114&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; did not find RAEs that influence whether a university student obtains a PhD. These two studies suggest that RAEs do not have such an important influence on college acceptance or educational attainment once in college. Instead, RAEs are a salient influence in so far as students in compulsory education obtain the necessary grades to apply to university in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acquisition of higher mental functions and schooling over time helps normalize the student population by minimizing the attainment gap between RO and RY students, which helps explain why RAEs lessen in university. In addition, universities are often learning environments with great diversity in age (i.e., mature and repeat students), culture (i.e., international students), and academic achievement (i.e., doctorate/master’s students). Perceived developmental parities are inherently less important in university because classroom composition becomes heterogeneous, mitigating and masking the remaining relative age differences. Given this knowledge, greater classroom heterogeneity could be applied to compulsory education to minimize RAEs. Students in mixed-grade classrooms in Norwegian junior high schools, for example, outperformed students in single-grade classrooms on high-stakes school finishing exams. With this classroom composition, it is not disproportionately skewed in favor of younger/older students, the losses for RO students following class mixing would not outweigh the gains of the RO students. With more heterogenous classes, educational attainment could subsequently become less influenced by RAEs and a more equalized pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since mitigating the impact of RAE on educational attainment depends partly on the strength of compensating investments such as classroom environments, streaming remains controversial. Academic streaming involves separating students according to innate ability. In reality, streaming is based on students’ prior academic performance, which is an imperfect measure of ability that can lead to misallocations. Streaming in early education can be particularly unfair because RY students do not get the opportunity to more closely approximate older classmates’ mental and physical development when sitting exams. In Germany for instance, being relatively old increased test scores by 0.40 standard deviations, increasing the probability of attending the highest secondary school track (gymnasium) by 12%. RY students are also at risk of being unfairly streamed into lower-ability classes because they are more likely than RO students to be diagnosed with behavioral problems and learning disabilities. Streaming thereby provides students with unequally differentiated educational experiences of teaching, competition, and opportunity that limit their academic exposure. Therefore, postponing streaming can reduce the impact of RAEs on educational attainment by ensuring that any developmental gaps have time to narrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unequal educational experiences can limit RY students’ educational attainment. In 2015, the average number of 25–64-year-olds with tertiary education was greater for countries who exhibit almost no streaming, such as Ireland (42.8%), compared to the OECD average (35%). Is it the case that streaming at multiple stages can rectify initial misallocations while still enhancing academic achievement? In Austria, children are streamed in grade five (aged ten) and in grade nine (aged fourteen). In one &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/sjoe.12046&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;, RY students in grade five were 40% less likely to be streamed into higher classes, but the second streaming, in grade nine, helped mitigate RAEs by giving students the opportunity to upgrade to a higher stream. In a complex interplay, streaming and RAEs can reinforce and be reinforced by existing socioeconomic inequalities. In this vein, the researchers concluded that RAEs only disappeared for students with favorable parental backgrounds in the second streaming. In contrast, RY students with unfavorable parental backgrounds were 21% less likely than RO students to move to a high-ranking school. As previously mentioned, learning at the wrong academic level can strain academic achievement and reduce the chances of continuing to higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socioeconomic status is the extent to which learning opportunities are disadvantaged as a result of low-income. Socioeconomic status can exacerbate the impact of RAEs on educational attainment. Huang and Invernizzi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00220671.2012.658456&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; examined a cohort of 405 students in a high poverty, low performing school from the beginning of kindergarten until the end of grade two. Results concluded that early-age literacy achievement gaps between RO and RY students narrowed over time but did not fully close by the end of grade two. Similarly, a Madagascar-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/wber/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/wber/lhw065/2875342?redirectedFrom=PDF&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Galasso, Weber, and Fernald indicated that differences in home stimulation are dependent on the wealth gradient and accounted for 12–18% of the predicted gap in early outcomes between advantaged and disadvantaged children. At least in early education, these findings suggest that diminished academic performance and exacerbated RAEs are in direct proportion to socioeconomic status. Thus, greater flexibility regarding age at entry in compulsory schooling could help lessen the impact of RAE on academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suziedelyte and Zhu published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2015.02.001&quot;&gt;“Longitudinal Study of Australian Children”&lt;/a&gt; and reported that starting school early benefits children from low-income families who, compared to children from high-income families, have limited access to learning resources at home and formal pre-school services. However, a three-month postponement of the cutoff enrollment date (increasing grade age) can increase both academic success and the likelihood of repeating a grade. Similarly, a one year delay in school enrollment (redshirting) can produce a 0.303 standard deviation decrease in test scores and lead to significantly lower math scores for students identified with a disability when compared to nonredshirted students with disability. These mixed findings suggest that equalizing educational attainment opportunities among RO and RY students, by implementing a flexible entry cutoff point, varies as a function of individual difference. Therefore, managing and mitigating RAEs requires greater sensitivity to confounds such as socioeconomic status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of starting school early on educational attainment is mediated by social factors, school policy, and socioeconomic factors, resulting in individual differences in learning outcomes. RAEs fade throughout formal schooling and can even reverse in higher education. The relative age phenomenon, nevertheless, caveats that ascribing merit to students based on relative age can lead to the provision of unequal learning opportunities and harmful pathologies. Unfortunately, the mechanisms that underpin the impact of RAEs on educational attainment are currently quite speculative and inconclusive. In this sense, existing findings warrant further empirical research and reveal the need for more comprehensive methods for determining an appropriate school entry cutoff point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abel, E., Sokol, R., Kruger, M., &amp;amp; Yargeau, D. (2008). Birthdates of Medical School Applicants. Educational Studies, 34(4), 271-275. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03055690802034302&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrett, P., Davies, F., Zhang, Y., &amp;amp; Barrett, L. (2015). The Impact of Classroom Design on Pupils’ Learning: Final Results of a Holistic, Multi-Level Analysis. Building And Environment, 89, 118-133. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.buildenv.2015.02.013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bedard, K., &amp;amp; Dhuey, E. (2006). The Persistence of Early Childhood Maturity: International Evidence of Long-Run Age Effects. Quarterly Journal Of Economics, 121(4), 1437-1472. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1162/qjec.121.4.1437&quot;&gt;10.1162/qjec.121.4.1437&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billari F., &amp;amp; Pellizzari, M. (2011). The Younger, the Better? Age-Related Differences in Academic Performance at University. Journal Of Population Economics, 25(2), 697-739. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00148-011-0379-3&quot;&gt;10.1007/s00148-011-0379-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascio, E., &amp;amp; Schanzenbach, D. (2016). First in the Class? Age and the Education Production Function. Education Finance And Policy, 11(3), 225-250. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1162/edfp_a_00191&quot;&gt;10.1162/edfp_a_00191&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobley, S., McKenna, J., Baker, J., &amp;amp; Wattie, N. (2009). How Pervasive are Relative Age Effects in Secondary School Education?. Journal Of Educational Psychology, 101(2), 520-528. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0013845&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0013845&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawford, C., Dearden, L., &amp;amp; Greaves, E. (2011). “Does When You are Born Matter? The Impact of Month of Birth on Children’s Cognitive and Non-Cognitive Skills in England.” IFS Briefing Note: BN 122, Institute of Fiscal Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawford, C., Dearden, L., &amp;amp; Meghir, C. (2010). When You Are Born Matters: The Impact of Date of Birth on Educational Outcomes in England. Institute for Fiscal Studies, 2-4, 21-22. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1920/wp.ifs.2010.1006&quot;&gt;10.1920/wp.ifs.2010.1006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elder, T., &amp;amp; Lubotsky, D. (2009). Kindergarten Entrance Age and Children’s Achievement: Impacts of State Policies, Family Background, and Peers. Journal Of Human Resources, 44(3), 641-683. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1353/jhr.2009.0015&quot;&gt;10.1353/jhr.2009.0015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortner, C., &amp;amp; Jenkins, J. (2017). Kindergarten Redshirting: Motivations and Spillovers Using Census-Level Data. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 38, 44-56. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2016.09.002&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.ecresq.2016.09.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galasso, E., Weber, A., &amp;amp; Fernald L. C. H., (2017). Dynamics of Child Development: Analysis of a Longitudinal Cohort in a Very Low Income Country. The World Bank Economic Review, lhw065.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang, F., &amp;amp; Invernizzi, M. (2012). The Association of Kindergarten Entry Age with Early Literacy Outcomes. The Journal Of Educational Research, 105(6), 431-441. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00220671.2012.658456&quot;&gt;10.1080/00220671.2012.658456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kniffin, K., &amp;amp; Hanks, A. (2015). Revisiting Gladwell’s Hockey Players: Influence of Age Effects upon Earning the PhD. Contemporary Economic Policy, 34(1), 21-36. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/coep.12114&quot;&gt;10.1111/coep.12114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leuven, E., &amp;amp; Rønning, M. (2014). Classroom Grade Composition and Pupil Achievement. The Economic Journal, 126(593), 1164-1192. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ecoj.12177&quot;&gt;10.1111/ecoj.12177&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matta, R., Ribas, R., Sampaio, B., &amp;amp; Sampaio, G. (2016). The Effect of Age at School Entry on College Admission and Earnings: A Regression-Discontinuity Approach. IZA Journal Of Labor Economics, 5(1). doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/s40172-016-0049-5&quot;&gt;10.1186/s40172-016-0049-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matsubayashi, T., &amp;amp; Ueda, M. (2015). Relative Age in School and Suicide among Young Individuals in Japan: A Regression Discontinuity Approach. PLOS ONE, 10(8), e0135349. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0135349&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0135349&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morrow, R., Garland, E., Wright, J., Maclure, M., Taylor, S., &amp;amp; Dormuth, C. (2012). Influence of Relative Age on Diagnosis and Treatment of Attention-deficit/hyperactivity Disorder in Children. Canadian Medical Association Journal, 184(7), 755-762. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1503/cmaj.111619&quot;&gt;10.1503/cmaj.111619&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N.A. (2015) Education attainment – Adult education level – OECD Data. Retrieved 10 April 2017, from https://data.oecd.org/eduatt/adult-education-level.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nam, K. (2014). Until When Does the Effect of Age on Academic Achievement Persist? Evidence from Korean Data. Economics Of Education Review, 40, 106-122. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2014.02.002&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.econedurev.2014.02.002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pehkonen, J., Viinikainen, J., Böckerman, P., Pulkki-Råback, L., Keltikangas-Järvinen, L., &amp;amp; Raitakari, O. (2015). Relative Age at School Entry, School Performance and Long-term Labour Market Outcomes. Applied Economics Letters, 22(16), 1345-1348. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13504851.2015.1031864&quot;&gt;10.1080/13504851.2015.1031864&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pekrun, R., Lichtenfeld, S., Marsh, H., Murayama, K., &amp;amp; Goetz, T. (2017). Achievement Emotions and Academic Performance: Longitudinal Models of Reciprocal Effects. Child Development. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/cdev.12704&quot;&gt;10.1111/cdev.12704&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peña, P. A. (2015). Creating Winners and Losers: Date of Birth, Relative Age in School, and Outcomes in Childhood and Adulthood”, unpublished manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puhani, P., &amp;amp; Weber, A. (2006). Does the Early Bird Catch the Worm? Instrumental Variable Estimates of Early Educational Effects of Age of School Entry in Germany. Empirical Economics, 32(2-3), 359-386. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00181-006-0089-y&quot;&gt;10.1007/s00181-006-0089-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiroga, C., Janosz, M., Bisset, S., &amp;amp; Morin, A. (2013). Early Adolescent Depression Symptoms and School Dropout: Mediating Processes Involving Self-Reported Academic Competence and Achievement. Journal Of Educational Psychology, 105(2), 552-560. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0031524&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0031524&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roberts, S., &amp;amp; Stott, T. (2015). A New Factor in UK Students’ University Attainment: The Relative Age Effect Reversal?. Quality Assurance In Education, 23(3), 295-305. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/qae-01-2013-0008&quot;&gt;10.1108/qae-01-2013-0008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robertson, E. (2011). The Effects of Quarter of Birth on Academic Outcomes at the Elementary School Level. Economics Of Education Review, 30(2), 300-311. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1016/j.econedurev.2010.10.005&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.econedurev.2010.10.005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schneeweis, N., &amp;amp; Zweimüller, M. (2014). Early Tracking and the Misfortune of Being Young. The Scandinavian Journal Of Economics, 116(2), 394-428. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/sjoe.12046&quot;&gt;10.1111/sjoe.12046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suziedelyte, A., &amp;amp; Zhu, A. (2015). Does Early Schooling Narrow Outcome Gaps for Advantaged and Disadvantaged Children?. Economics Of Education Review, 45, 76-88. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2015.02.001&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.econedurev.2015.02.001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sykes, E., Bell, J., &amp;amp; Rodeiro, C. (2009). Birthdate Effects: A Review of the Literature from 1990-on (pp. 3-4). Cambridge, England: University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas, J. (2012). Combination Classes and Educational Achievement. Economics Of Education Review, 31(6), 1058-1066. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2012.07.013&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.econedurev.2012.07.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoren, K., Heinig, E., &amp;amp; Brunner, M. (2016). Relative Age Effects in Mathematics and Reading: Investigating the Generalizability across Students, Time and Classes. Frontiers In Psychology, 7 (n/a). http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00679&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhang, S., Zhong, R., &amp;amp; Zhang, J. (2017). School Starting Age and Academic Achievement: Evidence from China’s Junior High Schools. China Economic Review. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chieco.2017.03.004&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.chieco.2017.03.004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/stux-12364/&quot;&gt;frolicsomepl&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Doctor with 9 retractions loses lawsuit over work as expert witness</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53026</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/13/doctor-9-retractions-loses-lawsuit-work-expert-witness/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A Canadian doctor with nine retractions due to misconduct has lost a court case seeking payment for an expert medical exam he performed in August 2014. The exam took place several months after his university found he had allowed a breach of research integrity in his lab and a month before news of the investigation […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/13/doctor-9-retractions-loses-lawsuit-work-expert-witness/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Doctor with 9 retractions loses lawsuit over work as expert witness&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 2017 delivered humility, and proved our potential</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-top-science-stories-editor-letter-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2017-top-science-stories-editor-letter-yir</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill reflects on some of the top scientific stories of 2017.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_YE_all_main.jpg?itok=A5-WlTaH" length="40693" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Colliding neutron stars, gene editing, human origins and more top stories of 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>A gravitational wave discovery is the year's biggest science story — again.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_0_intro_feat.jpg?itok=6phSSp6N" length="29843" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This year’s neutron star collision unlocks cosmic mysteries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-collision-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-collision-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>A rare and long-awaited astronomical event united thousands of astronomers in a frenzy of observations.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_1_ec_neutronstars_feat.jpg?itok=eZCXf8Mw" length="30988" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: CRISPR gene editing moved into new territory in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-gene-editing-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-gene-editing-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Scientists edited viable human embryos with CRISPR/Cas9 this year.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_2_TI_human-embryo_feat.jpg?itok=Kvrl2ffK" length="19143" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Larsen C ice shelf break has sparked groundbreaking research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/larsen-c-ice-shelf-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/larsen-c-ice-shelf-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>The hubbub over the iceberg that broke off Larsen C may have died down, but scientists are just getting warmed up to study the aftermath.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_3_larsen_c_main_REV.jpg?itok=4nDuKriz" length="34003" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The story of humans’ origins got a revision in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-evolution-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-evolution-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Human evolution may have involved the gradual assembly of scattered skeletal traits, fossils of Homo naledi and other species show.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_4_BB_homofossils_feat.jpg?itok=RxO5pqHF" length="30402" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seven Earth-sized planets entered the spotlight this year</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/trappist-1-earth-sized-planets-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/trappist-1-earth-sized-planets-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>The discovery of seven Earth-sized planets orbiting a single cool star fuels a debate over what counts as good news in the search for life outside the solar system.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_5_LG_trappist_main_REV.jpg?itok=6VFtta19" length="11686" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A quantum communications satellite proved its potential in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-quantum-communication-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/global-quantum-communication-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Quantum communication through space is now possible, putting the quantum internet within closer reach.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_6_EC_quantum-communication_main.jpg?itok=6tLYnj7_" length="25918" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Worries grow that climate change will quietly steal nutrients from major food crops</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nutrition-climate-change-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nutrition-climate-change-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Studies show that rice, wheat and other staples could lose proteins and minerals, putting more people at risk of hunger worldwide.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_7_SM_nutrition-climate-change_main.jpg?itok=8iGhCUez" length="60857" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Approval of gene therapies for two blood cancers led to an ‘explosion of interest’ in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/car-t-cell-gene-therapy-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/car-t-cell-gene-therapy-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>The first gene therapies approved in the United States are treating patients with certain types of leukemia and lymphoma.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_8_LH_car-T_main.jpg?itok=HYcsQbUy" length="48814" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Brains of former football players showed how common traumatic brain injuries might be</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cte-brain-damage-football-players-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cte-brain-damage-football-players-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>Examinations of NFL players’ postmortem brains turned up chronic traumatic encephalopathy in 99 percent of samples in large dataset.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_9_LS_CTE_feat_0.jpg?itok=Iyo6ckoW" length="38881" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Zika cases are down, but researchers prepare for the virus’s return</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-virus-top-science-stories-2017-yir</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-virus-top-science-stories-2017-yir</link>
	<description>The number of Zika cases in the Western Hemisphere have dropped this year, but the need for basic scientific and public health research of the virus remains strong.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/122317_10_AC_zika_feat.jpg?itok=SmVd-9lv" length="18916" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Utterly awful:” David Gorski weighs in on yet another paper linking vaccines and autism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=53003</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/13/utterly-awful-david-gorski-weighs-yet-another-paper-linking-vaccines-autism/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Retraction Watch readers may be forgiven for thinking that there has been at least a small uptick in the papers that claim to link autism and vaccines, and yet tend to raise more questions than they answer. Sometimes, they are retracted. See here, here and here, for example. We talk to David Gorski, well known […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/13/utterly-awful-david-gorski-weighs-yet-another-paper-linking-vaccines-autism/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Utterly awful:” David Gorski weighs in on yet another paper linking vaccines and autism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 13:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Imagining bodily states, like feeling full, can affect our future preferences and behaviour</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32907</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/13/imagining-bodily-states-like-feeling-full-can-affect-our-future-preferences-and-behaviour/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-sb10069449r-003.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32908&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32908&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;date created: 2008:03:16 | release references: Laurapa4 | release status: MR&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1211484084&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young woman choosing cake or carrots, indoors&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young woman choosing cake or carrots, indoors&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-sb10069449r-003.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-sb10069449r-003.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-sb10069449r-003.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1973,1520&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/12/13/imagining-bodily-states-like-feeling-full-can-affect-our-future-preferences-and-behaviour/young-woman-choosing-cake-or-carrots-indoors/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/12/gettyimages-sb10069449r-003.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our current bodily states influence our preferences and our behaviour much more than we usually anticipate – as anyone who has gone shopping hungry and come back with bags full of fattening food can attest. “Even when people have previous experience with a powerful visceral state, like pain, they show surprisingly little ability to vividly recall the state or to predict how it affects someone (including themselves) when they are not experiencing it,” write Janina Steinmertz at Utrecht University and her colleagues in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0146167217741315&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is their research suggests we can exploit this phenomenon – we can trick ourselves into thinking we’re feeling differently, thereby influencing our preferences in ways that help us. For instance, one potentially important finding from their paper was that people who thought themselves full went on to choose smaller food portion sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32907&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research builds on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S105774081300079X&quot;&gt;earlier work&lt;/a&gt; that’s found that getting people to consider a particular experience can have a similar effect as actually doing it. For example, people who looked at pictures of salty, savoury foods and rated how much they’d enjoy them, subsequently enjoyed eating peanuts less than others who’d first looked at images of sweet foods. It’s as if merely considering salty food had led to a degree of satiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steinmertz and her colleagues wanted to investigate whether mentally simulating feeling warm or cold, and also hungry or full, affected people’s subsequent preferences, and even their actual behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first study, 119 participants spent 30 seconds imagining themselves in a picture that either depicted a very cold environment (a snowy landscape or a picture of a glacier) or a hot environment (a desert or a lava lake). Afterwards, people in the cold condition reported feeling colder and were more likely to say they preferred “warming” activities, like a hot bath, to cooling activities, like a “cool, refreshing shower”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar effect occurs based purely on our imagination, without the aid of pictures. For the second study, 300 participants were spent 60 seconds imagining, in detail, feeling very hot – or cold, hungry, or full. They then wrote about how they thought they would feel, and how they would act. This kind of purely mental simulation also influenced their reported preferences for related activities – people who’d imagined being hungry were more likely to say they’d prefer to go on a date to a restaurant than a date to see a movie, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out if we can exploit these effects to our advantage, the researchers recruited another 111 people to explore the effects of imagining bodily states on subsequent food choices. Participants spent a minute imagining either being hungry or full. Then they were asked to choose between a variety of rewards, including varying sizes of popcorn, chocolate ice cream and crisps, one of which they were told they would receive. Crucially, the participants who’d imagined being full chose smaller food portion sizes than those who’d imagined being hungry. This showed, the researchers write, that mentally simulating visceral states “can affect real choices with immediate consequences”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0146167217741315&quot;&gt;Mental Simulation of Visceral States Affects Preferences and Behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32907/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32907/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32907&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 09:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: In photos: Celebrating LGBTQ Pride at Elsevier — with new chapter in NYC</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-photos-celebrating-LGBTQ-pride-at-elsevier</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/in-photos-celebrating-LGBTQ-pride-at-elsevier</link>
	<description>Employees have formed Pride groups in the Netherlands, the US, the Philippines and India to raise awareness of LGBTQ issues and promote an inclusive workplace</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 03:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Evolution of a designed protein assembly encapsulating its own RNA genome</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25157</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ZfFdaltRly8/nature25157</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The challenges of evolution in a complex biochemical environment, coupling genotype to phenotype and protecting the genetic material, are solved elegantly in biological systems by the encapsulation of nucleic acids. In the simplest examples, viruses use capsids to surround their genomes. Although these naturally occurring systems have been modified to change their tropism and to display proteins or peptides, billions of years of evolution have favoured efficiency at the expense of modularity, making viral capsids difficult to engineer. Synthetic systems composed of non-viral proteins could provide a ‘blank slate’ to evolve desired properties for drug delivery and other biomedical applications, while avoiding the safety risks and engineering challenges associated with viruses. Here we create synthetic nucleocapsids, which are computationally designed icosahedral protein assemblies with positively charged inner surfaces that can package their own full-length mRNA genomes. We explore the ability of these nucleocapsids to evolve virus-like properties by generating diversified populations using Escherichia coli as an expression host. Several generations of evolution resulted in markedly improved genome packaging (more than 133-fold), stability in blood (from less than 3.7% to 71% of packaged RNA protected after 6 hours of treatment), and in vivo circulation time (from less than 5 minutes to approximately 4.5 hours). The resulting synthetic nucleocapsids package one full-length RNA genome for every 11 icosahedral assemblies, similar to the best recombinant adeno-associated virus vectors. Our results show that there are simple evolutionary paths through which protein assemblies can acquire virus-like genome packaging and protection. Considerable effort has been directed at ‘top-down’ modification of viruses to be safe and effective for drug delivery and vaccine applications; the ability to design synthetic nanomaterials computationally and to optimize them through evolution now enables a complementary ‘bottom-up’ approach with considerable advantages in programmability and control. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25157&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25157&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ZfFdaltRly8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Dynamics of phosphoinositide conversion in clathrin-mediated endocytic traffic</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25146</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/aXJOy-_7Eco/nature25146</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
             Vesicular carriers transport proteins and lipids from one organelle to another,
                recognizing specific identifiers for the donor and acceptor membranes. Two important
                identifiers are phosphoinositides and GTP-bound GTPases, which provide well-defined
                but mutable labels. Phosphatidylinositol and its phosphorylated derivatives are
                present on the cytosolic faces of most cellular membranes.
                Reversible phosphorylation of its headgroup produces seven distinct
                phosphoinositides. In endocytic traffic, phosphatidylinositol-4,5-biphosphate marks
                the plasma membrane, and phosphatidylinositol-3-phosphate and
                phosphatidylinositol-4-phosphate mark distinct endosomal compartments. It is unknown what sequence of changes in lipid content confers
                on the vesicles their distinct identity at each intermediate step. Here we describe
                ‘coincidence-detecting’ sensors that selectively report the
                phosphoinositide composition of clathrin-associated structures, and the use of these
                sensors to follow the dynamics of phosphoinositide conversion during endocytosis.
                The membrane of an assembling coated pit, in equilibrium with the surrounding plasma
                membrane, contains phosphatidylinositol-4,5-biphosphate and a smaller amount of
                phosphatidylinositol-4-phosphate. Closure of the vesicle interrupts free exchange
                with the plasma membrane. A substantial burst of phosphatidylinositol-4-phosphate
                immediately after budding coincides with a burst of
                phosphatidylinositol-3-phosphate, distinct from any later encounter with the
                phosphatidylinositol-3-phosphate pool in early endosomes;
                phosphatidylinositol-3,4-biphosphate and the GTPase Rab5 then appear and remain as
                the uncoating vesicles mature into Rab5-positive endocytic intermediates. Our
                observations show that a cascade of molecular conversions, made possible by the
                separation of a vesicle from its parent membrane, can label membrane-traffic
                intermediates and determine their destinations. 
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25146&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25146&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/aXJOy-_7Eco&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Effector CD8 T cells dedifferentiate into long-lived memory cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25144</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/b1OWHDHiwVU/nature25144</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Memory CD8 T cells that circulate in the blood and are present in lymphoid organs are an essential component of long-lived T cell immunity. These memory CD8 T cells remain poised to rapidly elaborate effector functions upon re-exposure to pathogens, but also have many properties in common with naive cells, including pluripotency and the ability to migrate to the lymph nodes and spleen. Thus, memory cells embody features of both naive and effector cells, fuelling a long-standing debate centred on whether memory T cells develop from effector cells or directly from naive cells. Here we show that long-lived memory CD8 T cells are derived from a subset of effector T cells through a process of dedifferentiation. To assess the developmental origin of memory CD8 T cells, we investigated changes in DNA methylation programming at naive and effector cell-associated genes in virus-specific CD8 T cells during acute lymphocytic choriomeningitis virus infection in mice. Methylation profiling of terminal effector versus memory-precursor CD8 T cell subsets showed that, rather than retaining a naive epigenetic state, the subset of cells that gives rise to memory cells acquired de novo DNA methylation programs at naive-associated genes and became demethylated at the loci of classically defined effector molecules. Conditional deletion of the de novo methyltransferase Dnmt3a at an early stage of effector differentiation resulted in reduced methylation and faster re-expression of naive-associated genes, thereby accelerating the development of memory cells. Longitudinal phenotypic and epigenetic characterization of the memory-precursor effector subset of virus-specific CD8 T cells transferred into antigen-free mice revealed that differentiation to memory cells was coupled to erasure of de novo methylation programs and re-expression of naive-associated genes. Thus, epigenetic repression of naive-associated genes in effector CD8 T cells can be reversed in cells that develop into long-lived memory CD8 T cells while key effector genes remain demethylated, demonstrating that memory T cells arise from a subset of fate-permissive effector T cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25144&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25144&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/b1OWHDHiwVU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Convergent evolution of bilaterian nerve cords</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25030</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/H1V-FXmUbec/nature25030</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 It has been hypothesized that a condensed nervous system with a medial ventral nerve cord is an ancestral character of Bilateria. The presence of similar dorsoventral molecular patterns along the nerve cords of vertebrates, flies, and an annelid has been interpreted as support for this scenario. Whether these similarities are generally found across the diversity of bilaterian neuroanatomies is unclear, and thus the evolutionary history of the nervous system is still contentious. Here we study representatives of Xenacoelomorpha, Rotifera, Nemertea, Brachiopoda, and Annelida to assess the conservation of the dorsoventral nerve cord patterning. None of the studied species show a conserved dorsoventral molecular regionalization of their nerve cords, not even the annelid Owenia fusiformis, whose trunk neuroanatomy parallels that of vertebrates and flies. Our findings restrict the use of molecular patterns to explain nervous system evolution, and suggest that the similarities in dorsoventral patterning and trunk neuroanatomies evolved independently in Bilateria. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25030&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/H1V-FXmUbec&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cryo-EM structures of the TMEM16A calcium-activated chloride channel</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25024</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ijQc3CLibPI/nature25024</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Calcium-activated chloride channels (CaCCs) encoded by TMEM16A control neuronal signalling, smooth muscle contraction, airway and exocrine gland secretion, and rhythmic movements of the gastrointestinal system. To understand how CaCCs mediate and control anion permeation to fulfil these physiological functions, knowledge of the mammalian TMEM16A structure and identification of its pore-lining residues are essential. TMEM16A forms a dimer with two pores. Previous CaCC structural analyses have relied on homology modelling of a homologue (nhTMEM16) from the fungus Nectria haematococca that functions primarily as a lipid scramblase, as well as subnanometre-resolution electron cryo-microscopy. Here we present de novo atomic structures of the transmembrane domains of mouse TMEM16A in nanodiscs and in lauryl maltose neopentyl glycol as determined by single-particle electron cryo-microscopy. These structures reveal the ion permeation pore and represent different functional states. The structure in lauryl maltose neopentyl glycol has one Ca2+ ion resolved within each monomer with a constricted pore; this is likely to correspond to a closed state, because a CaCC with a single Ca2+ occupancy requires membrane depolarization in order to open (C.J.P. et al., manuscript submitted). The structure in nanodiscs has two Ca2+ ions per monomer and its pore is in a closed conformation; this probably reflects channel rundown, which is the gradual loss of channel activity that follows prolonged CaCC activation in 1 mM Ca2+. Our mutagenesis and electrophysiological studies, prompted by analyses of the structures, identified ten residues distributed along the pore that interact with permeant anions and affect anion selectivity, as well as seven pore-lining residues that cluster near pore constrictions and regulate channel gating. Together, these results clarify the basis of CaCC anion conduction. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25024&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ijQc3CLibPI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Mechanisms of mTORC1 activation by RHEB and inhibition by PRAS40</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25023</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zwA3aa2YyY0/nature25023</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
             The mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) controls cell growth and
                metabolism in response to nutrients, energy levels, and growth factors. It contains
                the atypical kinase mTOR and the RAPTOR subunit that binds to the Tor signalling
                sequence (TOS) motif of substrates and regulators. mTORC1 is activated by the small
                GTPase RHEB (Ras homologue enriched in brain) and inhibited by PRAS40. Here we
                present the 3.0 ångström cryo-electron microscopy structure
                of mTORC1 and the 3.4 ångström structure of activated
                RHEB–mTORC1. RHEB binds to mTOR distally from the kinase active site,
                yet causes a global conformational change that allosterically realigns active-site
                residues, accelerating catalysis. Cancer-associated hyperactivating mutations map to
                structural elements that maintain the inactive state, and we provide biochemical
                evidence that they mimic RHEB relieving auto-inhibition. We also present crystal
                structures of RAPTOR–TOS motif complexes that define the determinants of
                TOS recognition, of an mTOR FKBP12–rapamycin-binding (FRB)
                domain–substrate complex that establishes a second substrate-recruitment
                mechanism, and of a truncated mTOR–PRAS40 complex that reveals PRAS40
                inhibits both substrate-recruitment sites. These findings help explain how mTORC1
                selects its substrates, how its kinase activity is controlled, and how it is
                activated by cancer-associated mutations. 
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25023&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zwA3aa2YyY0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: An electric-eel-inspired soft power source from stacked hydrogels</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24670</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/OuTkmuTeWnM/nature24670</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Progress towards the integration of technology into living organisms requires electrical power sources that are biocompatible, mechanically flexible, and able to harness the chemical energy available inside biological systems. Conventional batteries were not designed with these criteria in mind. The electric organ of the knifefish Electrophorus electricus (commonly known as the electric eel) is, however, an example of an electrical power source that operates within biological constraints while featuring power characteristics that include peak potential differences of 600 volts and currents of 1 ampere. Here we introduce an electric-eel-inspired power concept that uses gradients of ions between miniature polyacrylamide hydrogel compartments bounded by a repeating sequence of cation- and anion-selective hydrogel membranes. The system uses a scalable stacking or folding geometry that generates 110 volts at open circuit or 27 milliwatts per square metre per gel cell upon simultaneous, self-registered mechanical contact activation of thousands of gel compartments in series while circumventing power dissipation before contact. Unlike typical batteries, these systems are soft, flexible, transparent, and potentially biocompatible. These characteristics suggest that artificial electric organs could be used to power next-generation implant materials such as pacemakers, implantable sensors, or prosthetic devices in hybrids of living and non-living systems. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 552 214 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24670&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24670&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/OuTkmuTeWnM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Activation mechanism of the calcium-activated chloride channel TMEM16A revealed by cryo-EM</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24652</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ACMaeIruAJ8/nature24652</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The calcium-activated chloride channel TMEM16A is a ligand-gated anion channel that opens in response to an increase in intracellular Ca2+ concentration. The protein is broadly expressed and contributes to diverse physiological processes, including transepithelial chloride transport and the control of electrical signalling in smooth muscles and certain neurons. As a member of the TMEM16 (or anoctamin) family of membrane proteins, TMEM16A is closely related to paralogues that function as scramblases, which facilitate the bidirectional movement of lipids across membranes. The unusual functional diversity of the TMEM16 family and the relationship between two seemingly incompatible transport mechanisms has been the focus of recent investigations. Previous breakthroughs were obtained from the X-ray structure of the lipid scramblase of the fungus Nectria haematococca (nhTMEM16), and from the cryo-electron microscopy structure of mouse TMEM16A at 6.6 Å (ref. 14). Although the latter structure disclosed the architectural differences that distinguish ion channels from lipid scramblases, its low resolution did not permit a detailed molecular description of the protein or provide any insight into its activation by Ca2+. Here we describe the structures of mouse TMEM16A at high resolution in the presence and absence of Ca2+. These structures reveal the differences between ligand-bound and ligand-free states of a calcium-activated chloride channel, and when combined with functional experiments suggest a mechanism for gating. During activation, the binding of Ca2+ to a site located within the transmembrane domain, in the vicinity of the pore, alters the electrostatic properties of the ion conduction path and triggers a conformational rearrangement of an α-helix that comes into physical contact with the bound ligand, and thereby directly couples ligand binding and pore opening. Our study describes a process that is unique among channel proteins, but one that is presumably general for both functional branches of the TMEM16 family. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24652&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24652&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ACMaeIruAJ8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Origin and differentiation of human memory CD8 T cells after vaccination</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24633</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/mX1FEQscUG8/nature24633</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The differentiation of human memory CD8 T cells is not well understood. Here we address this issue using the live yellow fever virus (YFV) vaccine, which induces long-term immunity in humans. We used in vivo deuterium labelling to mark CD8 T cells that proliferated in response to the virus and then assessed cellular turnover and longevity by quantifying deuterium dilution kinetics in YFV-specific CD8 T cells using mass spectrometry. This longitudinal analysis showed that the memory pool originates from CD8 T cells that divided extensively during the first two weeks after infection and is maintained by quiescent cells that divide less than once every year (doubling time of over 450 days). Although these long-lived YFV-specific memory CD8 T cells did not express effector molecules, their epigenetic landscape resembled that of effector CD8 T cells. This open chromatin profile at effector genes was maintained in memory CD8 T cells isolated even a decade after vaccination, indicating that these cells retain an epigenetic fingerprint of their effector history and remain poised to respond rapidly upon re-exposure to the pathogen. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24633&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24633&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/mX1FEQscUG8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New Horizons’ next target might have a moon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-horizons-next-target-might-have-moon</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-horizons-next-target-might-have-moon</link>
	<description>New Horizons’ next target, Kuiper Belt object MU69, may have a small moon.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 23:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121217_LG_newhorizons_feat.jpg?itok=5xI1EmkU" length="32273" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Jupiter’s massive Great Red Spot is at least 350 kilometers deep</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-massive-great-red-spot-least-350-kilometers-deep</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-massive-great-red-spot-least-350-kilometers-deep</link>
	<description>NASA’s Juno spacecraft has measured the depth of Jupiter’s Great Red Spot for the first time.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 21:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121117_LG_red-spot_main.jpg?itok=rSKp3vih" length="28689" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lesson one: How to design a good experiment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52982</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/12/lesson-one-design-good-experiment/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s clear science has a reproducibility problem. What’s less clear is how to address it. Recently, the U.S. National Institutes of Health awarded the Global Biological Standards Institute (GBSI) $2.34 million to train students in good experimental design (also covered by The Scientist). The first week begins June 2018 at Harvard Medical School. We spoke […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/12/12/lesson-one-design-good-experiment/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lesson one: How to design a good experiment&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 16:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ticks had a taste for dinosaur blood</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ticks-had-taste-dinosaur-blood</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ticks-had-taste-dinosaur-blood</link>
	<description>A tick found trapped in amber is evidence the bloodsuckers preyed on feathered dinosaurs, a new study says.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/12/main/articles/121117_LH_ticks-dinos_main.jpg?itok=UbWjKw8e" length="38472" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
