<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Ben Carson and the Power of the Hippocampus</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8603</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8603</link>
	<description>&quot;I could take the oldest person here, make a little hole right here on the side of the head, and put some depth electrodes into their hippocampus and stimulate. And they would be able to recite back to you, verbatim, a book they read 60 years ago.&quot;

So said Ben Carson, the U.S. Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, yesterday. Carson is known for his unorthodox claims, such as his attempt to rewrite the Egyptology textbooks, but this time, as he's a former neurosurgeon himself, he might</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 20:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Hindsight’s a bitch:” Colleagues dissect painful retraction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48607</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/07/hindsights-bitch-colleagues-dissect-painful-retraction/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Two blog posts are shining additional light on a recent retraction that included some unanswered questions — namely, the identity of the researcher who admitted to manipulating the results. To recap: Psychological Science recently announced it was retracting a paper about the relationship between the words you use and your mood after a graduate student tampered […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/07/hindsights-bitch-colleagues-dissect-painful-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Hindsight’s a bitch:” Colleagues dissect painful retraction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fleets of drones could pollinate future crops</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fleets-drones-could-pollinate-future-crops</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fleets-drones-could-pollinate-future-crops</link>
	<description>Chemist Eijiro Miyako turned a lab failure into a way to rethink artificial pollination.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/022117_ee_pollinator-drone_main_free.jpg?itok=DJGPYazY" length="29037" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Pay to play? Three new ways companies are subverting academic publishing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48630</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/07/pay-play-three-new-ways-companies-subverting-academic-publishing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some recent communications from companies involved in academic publishing have some journal representatives worried. In one instance, a manuscript editing company offered to pay an editor to help its papers get published in his journal; in another, a research ethics company threatened to investigate all of an author’s papers if he or she didn’t donate […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/07/pay-play-three-new-ways-companies-subverting-academic-publishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pay to play? Three new ways companies are subverting academic publishing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 14:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Invasive species, climate change threaten Great Lakes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/invasive-species-climate-change-threaten-great-lakes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/invasive-species-climate-change-threaten-great-lakes</link>
	<description>In The Death and Life of the Great Lakes, a journalist chronicles the lakes’ downward spiral and slow revival.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030217_CM_reviews-greatlakes_main.jpg?itok=3vNhWkIv" length="32020" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Virtual reality has a motion sickness problem</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/virtual-reality-has-motion-sickness-problem</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/virtual-reality-has-motion-sickness-problem</link>
	<description>Virtual reality games and experiences can make some people sick, and women are more susceptible.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/031817_vr_main_free.jpg?itok=W74R5wRb" length="29228" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Risk-taking teens’ brains seem to disregard past bad outcomes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=20339</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/07/risk-taking-teens-brains-seem-to-disregard-past-bad-outcomes/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two Male Freerunners Jumping Over a Wall Performing Parkour&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-20351&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;20351&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;11&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;E-500&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Two young male parkour freerunners jumping over a wall.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;innovatedcaptures&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;14&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.004&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Two Male Freerunners Jumping Over a Wall Performing Parkour&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Two Male Freerunners Jumping Over a Wall Performing Parkour&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-124672133.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-124672133.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-124672133.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2560,1920&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/07/risk-taking-teens-brains-seem-to-disregard-past-bad-outcomes/two-male-freerunners-jumping-over-a-wall-performing-parkour/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-124672133.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucyfoulkes.com/home&quot;&gt;Lucy Foulkes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adolescents take more risks than adults: they are more likely to binge drink, have casual sex, commit crimes and have serious car accidents. In fact, adolescence is a paradox because it is a time of peak physical fitness, but also the time when people are most likely to be injured or killed in an accident. For this reason, it’s critical to understand what drives teenagers to take more risks. To date, many explanations of teenage risk taking have focused on the positive side of these behaviours: the rewarding “kick” that comes from taking a risk that ends well. Some studies have shown that teenagers experience more of this rewarding feeling, and this contributes to the increased risk taking seen at this age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fewer studies have considered how teenagers respond when risks turn out badly. This is important because all our previous experiences, both good and bad, affect our subsequent behaviour. If we make a risky decision like gambling money, and it pays off, it’s more likely we’ll decide to gamble again in the near future. Equally, if we take a gamble and it turns out badly, we’ll probably be a bit more reserved next time. But it turns out that some teenagers don’t respond like this: according to a new study in &lt;em&gt;NeuroImage&lt;/em&gt;, some of them do not adjust their behavior so readily when things go wrong, and this may be linked to a distinct pattern of activation in their brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-20339&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethan McCormick and Eva Telzer at North Carolina University asked 58 adolescents (aged 13 to 17) to play a game that involved risks. The researchers scanned the participants’ brains while they played, and also monitored how losing the game in one round (taking a risk that didn’t pay off) affected their behaviour in the subsequent round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game involved blowing up 24 virtual balloons shown on a computer screen. Each balloon started small, and the more that participants pumped it up (by pressing a keyboard key), the more points they earned. However, there was a catch: as the balloon got bigger, there was always a chance that it would pop, causing a loud explosion on the screen and losing the participant all the points they had obtained on that round. So the teenagers had to make a series of risky decisions: should they cash out and save the points they had accumulated so far, or risk the balloon popping for the chance of even more points?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, the outcome from one balloon affected the teens’ behaviour on the next one. After an explosion outcome (a risk that turned out badly), they tended to pump fewer times on the subsequent balloon before cashing out. Conversely, when they successfully cashed out the points before the balloon popped, the teens tended to risk more pumps the next time round. Importantly, though, this wasn’t the same for all of them: some of the teenagers continued to pump a lot even after their last balloon had just exploded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCormick and Telzer found that this behaviour was linked to a distinctive pattern of neural activation. Specifically, teens who were less sensitive to past explosions (i.e. less likely to change their behaviour on subsequent rounds) had reduced activity in the medial prefrontal cortex. This part of the brain is involved in decision making processes, like judging how risky we think a decision is, and how good we consider the result. These same teens also said they engaged in more real-life risk-taking, like drinking alcohol or taking drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current findings suggest that – for some teenagers at least – it’s not just about remembering the good times, it’s about forgetting the bad times, too: some teenagers are not using past outcomes to change their current behavior. It’s not clear from the brain activity differences whether this is a conscious decision, or whether this insensitivity to the past is happening outside of the person’s awareness. It’s also important to note that the study focused on teenagers only, and didn’t include a group of children or adults, so we don’t know whether the findings reported here are unique to this age group, or common to big risk-takers of all ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we use this information to reduce risk taking in teenagers? Might it be beneficial to encourage those who take risks to consider their past behavior, to remember when things turned out badly, and suggest they use this to guide their behaviour? From the present data, it’s not clear whether this is a skill that could be taught. It’s also important to consider just how much we want to reduce risk taking. Adolescence is a time of potential vulnerability, and we need to educate young people to protect them from harming themselves. But risk taking is not inherently bad. Within limits, taking risks allows us to become independent and to learn about the world around us. It’s a fundamental part of growing up. We need to walk the fine line between encouraging our young people to stay safe, whilst also allowing them to navigate the world for themselves – even when this means taking risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1053811916307649?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Failure to retreat: Blunted sensitivity to negative feedback supports risky behavior in adolescents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lucyfoulkes.com/home&quot;&gt;Dr Lucy Foulkes&lt;/a&gt; (@lfoulkesy) for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bps-research-digest.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Lucy is currently working as a postdoctoral research associate in Prof Sarah-Jayne Blakemore’s lab at the Institute of Cognitive Neuroscience on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oxfordmindfulness.org/learn/myriad/&quot;&gt;MYRIAD project&lt;/a&gt; – a Wellcome Trust-funded project assessing the feasibility of teaching mindfulness in schools, and the ways in which mindfulness might promote mental health and resilience in adolescents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20339/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20339/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=20339&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 10:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Prominent British geneticist offers defence in long-running misconduct investigation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21581</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/QkhucKhWZRo/nature.2017.21581</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;David Latchman says he did not have direct involvement in images at the heart of criticized papers from his group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21581&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/QkhucKhWZRo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: How Facebook, fake news and friends are warping your memory</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543168a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Ih4fyLBGfV0/543168a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Research on collective recall takes on new importance in a post-fact world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 168 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543168a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543168a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Ih4fyLBGfV0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The perfect grant and how to get it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543151a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/cxim4Xacw3Q/543151a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;To help scientists build a career, Panayiota Poirazi says funders must earmark cash, reduce emphasis on collaboration and improve the application process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 151 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543151a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543151a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/cxim4Xacw3Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Science journalism can be evidence-based, compelling — and wrong</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543150a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0Get8nj4F_0/543150a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A ranking of the best science-news outlets misjudges the relationship between research and reporting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 150 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543150a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543150a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0Get8nj4F_0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Patent for Stimulation of Brodmann Areas 1-48 and all other structures</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-517600126569403993</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/dY6f5HDzZek/patent-for-stimulation-of-brodmann.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator tr_bq&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NftG9ajVL9k/WL0eUB-ag0I/AAAAAAAAMD0/DFdWBCIOVtM_gcqZHbMBUBlZTozz1sS0QCLcB/s1600/Number%2Bof%2Bpatents%2Bimplicating%2Bbrain%2Bregions.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;232&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NftG9ajVL9k/WL0eUB-ag0I/AAAAAAAAMD0/DFdWBCIOVtM_gcqZHbMBUBlZTozz1sS0QCLcB/s400/Number%2Bof%2Bpatents%2Bimplicating%2Bbrain%2Bregions.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fig&lt;span&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nbt.3782&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roskams-Edriset al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/b&gt;. The number of patents implicating specific brain regions has risen from 1976 to the mid 2010s. Results were obtained by searching The Lens patent database (http://lens.org/).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;“What is the ethical value of awarding patent rights that implicate regions of the brain&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;?”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do the applicants intend to patent the function of specific brain areas? This absurd scenario was the first thing that came to mind. The murky waters of neurotech patent law were explored by a group of neuroethics and intellectual property experts (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nbt.3782&quot;&gt;Roskams-Edriset al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;) who noted several problems:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The first practical challenge to patents that relate to brain regions is  well known to patent law: the danger of overbroad, vague, or obvious claims.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One egregious example is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/patents/US9327069&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;US 9327069 B2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Methods and systems for treating a medical condition by promoting neural remodeling within the brain&lt;/i&gt;. The language is extremely vague (and redundant):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Methods of treating a medical condition include applying at least one stimulus to a stimulation site within the brain of a patient with an implanted stimulator in accordance with one or more stimulation parameters. The [&lt;i&gt;sic&lt;/i&gt;]  at least one stimulus is configured to promote neural remodeling within the brain of the patient. Systems for treating a medical condition include an implantable stimulator configured to apply at least one stimulus to a stimulation site within the brain of a patient in accordance with one or more stimulation parameters...&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What kind of stimulus will “promote neural remodeling?” All of them. As stated in the Detailed Description:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The stimulus may include an electrical stimulation current, one or more drugs, gene infusion, chemical stimulation, thermal stimulation, electromagnetic stimulation, mechanical stimulation, and/or any other suitable stimulus.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What brain conditions can be treated? All of them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Many medical conditions have been linked to faulty neural connections and/or abnormal developmental pruning of axons, dendrites, and synapses within the brain. Such medical conditions include, but are not limited to, autism, psychological disorders (e.g., schizophrenia, compulsive behaviors, and depression), neurodegenerative diseases (e.g., Huntington's disease, Alzheimer's disease, and amyotrophic lateral sclerosis), and chromosomal abnormalities (e.g., Down syndrome and Klinefelter syndrome).&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, what are the implicated brain regions? You guessed it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nearly every brain area has been implicated in the disorders listed above.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; In particular, it is believed that faulty neural connections and/or abnormal developmental pruning of neural structures within the temporal lobe, limbic system, pituitary gland, brainstem, cerebral cortex, and/or any other midbrain structure are at least in part responsible for the deficits of one or more of the disorders listed above.  &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/patents/US9327069&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Claims&lt;/a&gt; that apply in this patent (e.g., stimulation sites and medical conditions) are slightly more specific, but still outlandish:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;4. ... said stimulation site comprises at least one or more of a  temporal lobe, cerebral ventricle, structure within a limbic system,  pituitary gland, brainstem, and cerebral cortex. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5. ...said medical condition comprises at least one or more of  autism, a psychological disorder, a neurodegenerative disease, a  chromosomal abnormality, a bad habit, and an injury to said brain.&lt;/blockquote&gt;A bad habit??&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;100,000,000 Hz&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even better is Patent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/patents/US9050463&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;US 9,050,463&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Systems and methods for stimulating cellular function in tissue&lt;/i&gt;), which touts the application of electrical fields with frequencies of 100,000,000 Hz and above to the entire nervous system...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;....various structures within the brain or nervous system including but not limited to dorsal lateral prefrontal cortex, any component of the basal ganglia, nucleus accumbens, gastric nuclei, brainstem, thalamus, inferior colliculus, superior colliculus, periaqueductal gray, primary motor cortex, supplementary motor cortex, occipital lobe, Brodmann areas 1-48, primary sensory cortex, primary visual cortex, primary auditory cortex, amygdala, hippocampus, cochlea, cranial nerves, cerebellum, frontal lobe, occipital lobe, temporal lobe, parietal lobe, sub-cortical structures, spinal cord, nerve roots, sensory organs, and peripheral nerves.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt; ...to treat all known diseases:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Such pathologies that may be treated include but are not limited to Multiple Sclerosis, Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis, Alzheimer's Disease, Dystonia, Tics, Spinal Cord Injury, Traumatic Brain Injury, Drug Craving, Food Craving, Alcohol Craving, Nicotine Craving, Stuttering, Tinnitus, Spasticity, Parkinson's Disease, Parkinsonianism, Obsessions, Depression, Schizophrenia, Bipolar Disorder, Acute Mania, Catonia, Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder, Autism, Chronic Pain Syndrome, Phantom Limb Pain, Epilepsy, Stroke, Auditory Hallucinations, Movement Disorders, Neurodegenerative Disorders, Pain Disorders, Metabolic Disorders, Addictive Disorders, Psychiatric Disorders, Traumatic Nerve Injury, and Sensory Disorders. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O-mG68AVIFM/WL09k-_RhGI/AAAAAAAAMEE/iHbki5UyfNAtkNIfTkjO_EYwx2t82KJhQCLcB/s1600/US%2B8594783%2BB..png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;216&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-O-mG68AVIFM/WL09k-_RhGI/AAAAAAAAMEE/iHbki5UyfNAtkNIfTkjO_EYwx2t82KJhQCLcB/s320/US%2B8594783%2BB..png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oddly, the specific &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/patents/US9050463&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Claims&lt;/a&gt; in this patent include an indication limited to Parkinson's disease. But the list of targeted brain regions (see above) is irrelevant in this disorder.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nbt.3782&quot;&gt;Roskams-Edriset al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; conclude with a warning drawn from previous efforts to patent human genes: “brain biomaterial and brain processes cannot be invented and, like genes, they similarly ought not to be owned.” There should be no legal rights to brain regions, or else we risk losing autonomy over our own thoughts and actions. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reference&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Nature+Biotechnology&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1038%2Fnbt.3782&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Situating+brain+regions+among+patent+rights+and+moral+risks&amp;amp;rft.issn=1087-0156&amp;amp;rft.date=2017&amp;amp;rft.volume=35&amp;amp;rft.issue=2&amp;amp;rft.spage=119&amp;amp;rft.epage=121&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Fdoifinder%2F10.1038%2Fnbt.3782&amp;amp;rft.au=Roskams-Edris%2C+D.&amp;amp;rft.au=Anderson-Redick%2C+S.&amp;amp;rft.au=Kiss%2C+Z.&amp;amp;rft.au=Illes%2C+J.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Medicine%2CNeuroscience%2CNeuroethics&quot;&gt;Roskams-Edris, D., Anderson-Redick, S., Kiss, Z., &amp;amp; Illes, J. (2017). Situating brain regions among patent rights and moral risks. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nature Biotechnology, 35&lt;/span&gt; (2), 119-121. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nbt.3782&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.1038/nbt.3782&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=dY6f5HDzZek:GlKv6D7UI90:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/dY6f5HDzZek&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 21:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Author says he lied about approval for animal research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48362</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/06/author-says-lied-approval-animal-research/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher in South Korea has retracted a 2015 paper after telling the journal he falsified the institutional approval required to conduct the animal experiments. In the article, the author explicitly says that the Animal Experiment Review Board of a university based in Seoul, South Korea approved the experiments, but according to the journal, “the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/06/author-says-lied-approval-animal-research/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author says he lied about approval for animal research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 16:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Magnetism helps black holes blow off gas</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetism-helps-black-holes-blow-gas</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetism-helps-black-holes-blow-gas</link>
	<description>The turbulent winds that swirl around black holes are probably driven by magnetic fields, scientists say.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030317_AY_black-hole_main.jpg?itok=A-9BQcd7" length="17535" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Video blog: How Atlantic salmon prepare for life in saltwater</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8535</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/06/video-blog-atlantic-salmon-prepare-life-saltwater/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/06/video-blog-atlantic-salmon-prepare-life-saltwater/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video blog: How Atlantic salmon prepare for life in saltwater&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 14:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Two retracted papers were published behind bosses’ backs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48290</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/06/two-retracted-papers-published-behind-bosses-backs/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers have retracted two 2016 papers from the same journal which were published without the permission of the supervising scientists. According to the retraction notices, the two Applied Materials &amp;amp; Interfaces articles were “published without the full knowledge or consent of the principal investigators” who guided the research, but are not named in the notices. The papers share […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/06/two-retracted-papers-published-behind-bosses-backs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Two retracted papers were published behind bosses’ backs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 14:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Smarter people are happier, says new analysis involving 80,000 participants, but only a bit</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=20262</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/06/smarter-people-are-happier-says-new-analysis-involving-80000-participants-but-only-a-bit/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;albert_einstein_head&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-20328&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;20328&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;albert_einstein_head&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/albert_einstein_head.jpg?w=845?w=768&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/albert_einstein_head.jpg?w=845?w=225&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/albert_einstein_head.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3250,4333&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/06/smarter-people-are-happier-says-new-analysis-involving-80000-participants-but-only-a-bit/albert_einstein_head/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/albert_einstein_head.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“happiness in intelligent people is the rarest thing I know” Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us would like to be smarter and happier, but does one lead to the other? Folk wisdom suggests not: old sayings tell us that “ignorance is bliss” and that “only a fool can be happy”. What does the psychology literature say? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300039&quot;&gt;new meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vocational Behaviour&lt;/em&gt; has combined the results from dozens of previous studies involving many tens of thousands of participants and, contrary to the received wisdom, it concludes that higher intelligence actually does correlate with greater happiness (or “life satisfaction”) and job satisfaction, but only weakly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-20262&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Gonzalez-Mulé at Indiana University and his colleagues sifted the literature, identifying relevant papers, published and unpublished, going back to 1980. Combining the results from 33 papers involving nearly 50,000 participants, they found that intelligence (or what they called “general mental ability”) had a weak but statistically non-significant positive correlation with life satisfaction, and a modest, statistically significant positive correlation with job satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found further evidence for the apparent benefits of higher intelligence for life satisfaction by factoring in the influence of “job complexity” (greater complexity meaning a job with more variety, skill demands and autonomy) and job income, two factors that are themselves correlated with greater happiness. This showed that higher intelligence has indirect links with greater happiness because more intelligent people tend to earn more, but especially because they tend to have more complex jobs, which presumably are more rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to 38 studies involving nearly 30,000 participants, higher intelligence also had indirect links with job satisfaction by virtue of the fact that it correlated with job complexity and income. But this is psychology, so of course there’s a twist that somewhat supports the folk wisdom about intelligent people rarely being happy. When the researchers held job complexity and income constant in their analysis, they found that higher intelligence actually correlated with less job satisfaction. Put differently, if you imagine a range of people at a given level of job complexity and income, those with higher intelligence will tend to be less happy with their jobs. This makes intuitive sense if you consider that smarter people will be more likely than others to experience boredom and frustration at jobs that are not challenging enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great strength of meta-analyses like this one is in the huge amounts of data that they can draw on. But the new study also has some obvious limitations: some of the data is decades-old and may not be relevant to today’s world. Also, this is cross-sectional data which can’t convincingly address whether intelligence is causing changes in life and job satisfaction, nor how such processes may unfold over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300039&quot;&gt;Are smarter people happier? Meta-analyses of the relationships between general mental ability and job and life satisfaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image by Orren Jack Turner, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein#/media/File:Albert_Einstein_Head.jpg&quot;&gt;via Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20262/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20262/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=20262&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 14:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Anesthesia for youngsters is a tricky calculation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/anesthesia-youngsters-tricky-calculation</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/anesthesia-youngsters-tricky-calculation</link>
	<description>Scientists, doctors and parents face uncertainty when it comes to anesthesia for babies.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/blogposts/030317_ls_anesthesia_free.jpg?itok=4qb2uctD" length="29896" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Identity of ‘Tully monster’ still a mystery</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/identity-%E2%80%98tully-monster%E2%80%99-still-mystery</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/identity-%E2%80%98tully-monster%E2%80%99-still-mystery</link>
	<description>Paleontologists challenge whether the Tully monster actually was a vertebrate because it lacks key vertebrate structures.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030317_EE_tully-monster_main.jpg?itok=Eiiu9u7s" length="22970" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: What Trump's new travel ban means for science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21588</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/T3t7WygVyuM/nature.2017.21588</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Policy reinstates restrictions on immigration from six countries but exempts current visa-holders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21588&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21588&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/T3t7WygVyuM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Taxi-sharing in cities follows universal maths law</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21586</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/c6p9yD0Ldrs/nature.2017.21586</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ride-sharing algorithm finds untapped potential to cut costs and reduce emissions in cities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21586&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21586&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/c6p9yD0Ldrs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: IBM's quantum cloud computer goes commercial</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21585</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/YSXi9RSJX44/nature.2017.21585</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Company plans a bigger, better system aimed at creating a market for the still-immature technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 159 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21585&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21585&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/YSXi9RSJX44&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Quantum microscope offers MRI for molecules</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21573</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/WD2CdapwF1E/nature.2017.21573</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Diamond-based imaging system uses magnetic resonance of electrons to detect charged atoms and peer at chemical reactions in real time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21573&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21573&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/WD2CdapwF1E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Paleoproterozoic sterol biosynthesis and the rise of oxygen</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21412</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/q-goyaWUDe0/nature21412</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Natural products preserved in the geological record can function as ‘molecular fossils’, providing insight into organisms and physiologies that existed in the deep past. One important group of molecular fossils is the steroidal hydrocarbons (steranes), which are the diagenetic remains of sterol lipids. Complex sterols with modified side chains are unique to eukaryotes, although simpler sterols can also be synthesized by a few bacteria. Sterol biosynthesis is an oxygen-intensive process; thus, the presence of complex steranes in ancient rocks not only signals the presence of eukaryotes, but also aerobic metabolic processes. In 1999, steranes were reported in 2.7 billion year (Gyr)-old rocks from the Pilbara Craton in Australia, suggesting a long delay between photosynthetic oxygen production and its accumulation in the atmosphere (also known as the Great Oxidation Event) 2.45–2.32 Gyr ago. However, the recent reappraisal and rejection of these steranes as contaminants pushes the oldest reported steranes forward to around 1.64 Gyr ago (ref. 6). Here we use a molecular clock approach to improve constraints on the evolution of sterol biosynthesis. We infer that stem eukaryotes shared functionally modern sterol biosynthesis genes with bacteria via horizontal gene transfer. Comparing multiple molecular clock analyses, we find that the maximum marginal probability for the divergence time of bacterial and eukaryal sterol biosynthesis genes is around 2.31 Gyr ago, concurrent with the most recent geochemical evidence for the Great Oxidation Event. Our results therefore indicate that simple sterol biosynthesis existed well before the diversification of living eukaryotes, substantially predating the oldest detected sterane biomarkers (approximately 1.64 Gyr ago), and furthermore, that the evolutionary history of sterol biosynthesis is tied to the first widespread availability of molecular oxygen in the ocean–atmosphere system. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21412&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/q-goyaWUDe0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Molecular basis of ancestral vertebrate electroreception</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21401</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/CJYd51cyJko/nature21401</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Elasmobranch fishes, including sharks, rays, and skates, use specialized electrosensory organs called ampullae of Lorenzini to detect extremely small changes in environmental electric fields. Electrosensory cells within these ampullae can discriminate and respond to minute changes in environmental voltage gradients through an unknown mechanism. Here we show that the voltage-gated calcium channel CaV1.3 and the big conductance calcium-activated potassium (BK) channel are preferentially expressed by electrosensory cells in little skate (Leucoraja erinacea) and functionally couple to mediate electrosensory cell membrane voltage oscillations, which are important for the detection of specific, weak electrical signals. Both channels exhibit unique properties compared with their mammalian orthologues that support electrosensory functions: structural adaptations in CaV1.3 mediate a low-voltage threshold for activation, and alterations in BK support specifically tuned voltage oscillations. These findings reveal a molecular basis of electroreception and demonstrate how discrete evolutionary changes in ion channel structure facilitate sensory adaptation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21401&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21401&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/CJYd51cyJko&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘Monkeytalk’ invites readers into the complex social world of monkeys</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/monkeytalk-invites-readers-complex-social-world-monkeys</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/monkeytalk-invites-readers-complex-social-world-monkeys</link>
	<description>In Monkeytalk, a primatologist evaluates what’s known about monkeys’ complex social lives in the wild.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030217_BB_reviews-monkeytalk_main.jpg?itok=G2iamHwe" length="32726" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: How to speed up peer review; the whipsaw of science news headlines; data-sharing stance sparks resignation request</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48575</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/04/weekend-reads-speed-peer-review-whipsaw-science-news-headlines-data-sharing-stance-sparks-resignation-request/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured more fallout from a citation-boosting episode, and a look at when animal research becomes unnecessary and cruel. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A new study finds that “prior co-authorship relations have a large and significant influence on manuscript handling times, speeding up the editorial decision on average by 19 days.” […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/04/weekend-reads-speed-peer-review-whipsaw-science-news-headlines-data-sharing-stance-sparks-resignation-request/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: How to speed up peer review; the whipsaw of science news headlines; data-sharing stance sparks resignation request&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 14:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: Channel Your Community’s Research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7381</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/if7mLl-86d8/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Channels-Blog-image&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/03/Channels-Blog-image-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/orcid.org/0000-0001-8771-7239&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;orcid.org/0000-0001-8771-7239&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At PLOS, we aim to support academic communities in communicating their research in open and accessible ways. The first of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a new way for specialist communities to communicate, find and read research content, launch this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels provide an innovative way of curating and presenting published research relevant to a scholarly community. Each is curated by a small group of Channel Editors, themselves researchers, who continuously bring together and showcase recently published research content selected from the broad scope of PLOS journals. Importantly, Channel Editors can point to resources, news and commentary from many online sources, including articles published in other journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLOS developed Channels for communities to drive according to their own content priorities, without limitation to any particular journal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With experts at the helm, and content selected by researchers for researchers, we hope to create online venues that become a preferred destination for research communities. To this end, the Channels concept was designed with researchers’ input to adapt to various needs. Channels can be adopted as a resource by researchers in a specialist area, or bring together researchers from different academic backgrounds working towards a common aim. The first three Channels to launch illustrate a variety of applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;VDRR&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7396 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;229&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/03/VDRR-1-300x229.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/vdrrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veteran Disability &amp;amp; Rehabilitation Research Channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was born from a collaboration with the US Department of Veterans Affairs Rehabilitation Research and Development Service, as a new home for the community previously served by the Journal of Rehabilitation Research &amp;amp; Development (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rehab.research.va.gov/jrrd/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JRRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) which ceased publication in 2017. The new Channel, with an expanded international focus, features multidisciplinary research for a global community of researchers and care providers working with veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;OST&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7400 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;209&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/03/OST-300x209.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/open-source-toolkit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source Toolkit Channel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; showcases research from a diverse group of fields that have in common the description of innovative open source software and hardware applications that can be used in research and education. This Channel aims not to serve a specific scientific discipline but to create bridges between vibrant communities that build tools to support democratization and reproducibility of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tuberculosis Channel&lt;/strong&gt;, led by Academic Editors from &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, will launch on World TB Day, March 24th, 2017. This Channel will draw from PLOS journal content covering all aspects of TB from mycobacteriology to computational epidemiologic models, clinical diagnosis and treatment. By integrating these reports with content from a variety of external sources, Channel Editors aim to provide an accessible resource of interest to TB researchers around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are grateful to the Channel Editors who have stepped up enthusiastically to pioneer the use of this new tool for their communities. More PLOS Channels will follow later this year—some are already in preparation. If you have interest in becoming a Channel Editor or see an unmet need in your community for this tool, we welcome your thoughts. We look forward to working with many more communities to help disseminate their work, create useful resources and foster collaboration within and across specialist communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/if7mLl-86d8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 21:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Brain Activity At The Moment of Death</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8593</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8593</link>
	<description>What happens in the brain when we die?



Canadian researchers Loretta Norton and colleagues of the University of Western Ontario examine this grave question in a new paper: Electroencephalographic Recordings During Withdrawal of Life-Sustaining Therapy Until 30 Minutes After Declaration of Death

Norton et al. examined frontal EEG recordings from four critically ill patients at the point where their life support was withdrawn. Here are some details on the four:



Here's the EEG recor</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 20:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Rare triplet of high-energy neutrinos detected from an unknown source</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rare-triplet-high-energy-neutrinos-detected-unknown-source</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rare-triplet-high-energy-neutrinos-detected-unknown-source</link>
	<description>The IceCube Neutrino Observatory spotted three neutrinos within 100 seconds that seem to have come from the same place in the sky.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 18:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/blogposts/030317_ticker_icecube_free.jpg?itok=SmfL34wA" length="21344" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Seeking help in times of economic hardship: access, experiences of services and unmet need</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8660</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/seeking-help-times-economic-hardship-access-experiences-services-unmet-need/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;recession&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/recession-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interviews were conducted with three different groups of people, those who had self-harmed due to employment, financial or benefit concerns, those struggling financially and frontline staff from voluntary and statutory sector organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Barnes and her team discovered that most people found service provision confusing and difficult to access. In addition, benefit sanctions and preexisting mental health problems played a large role and many had the expectation that they should be self-reliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study concludes that interventions are required to identify those in need so that they have guidance and access to practical and reliable advice. Listen to more in this podcast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/seeking-help-times-economic-hardship-access-experiences-services-unmet-need/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Seeking help in times of economic hardship: access, experiences of services and unmet need&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 17:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/recession-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: 3rd retraction appears for fired Pfizer breast cancer researcher</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48546</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/03/3rd-retraction-appears-fired-pfizer-breast-cancer-researcher/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Pfizer has retracted a paper by a former employee who was fired after the company discovered she had been doctoring data. The retraction, in Molecular Cancer Research, is the third of five papers Pfizer asked to retract, after an investigation discovered they contained duplicated images. The papers have been discussed on PubPeer, which is also […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/03/3rd-retraction-appears-fired-pfizer-breast-cancer-researcher/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;3rd retraction appears for fired Pfizer breast cancer researcher&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Choosing the right cyberattack response is a complicated game</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/choosing-right-cyberattack-response-complicated-game</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/choosing-right-cyberattack-response-complicated-game</link>
	<description>Public shaming or retaliation aren’t necessarily the best strategies in the world of cyber warfare, an analysis reveals</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030117_re_cyberattack_free.jpg?itok=ydFSO_8k" length="31354" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Citation-boosting episode leads to editors’ resignations, university investigation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48555</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/03/citation-boosting-episode-leads-editors-resignations-university-investigation/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The fallout from an investigation into alleged citation-boosting at several journals that we first reported on two weeks ago has widened, leading to the resignation of the executive editor of one of the journals, and an investigation at a university in The Netherlands. On February 13, the European Geophysical Union (EGU) announced that an editor […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/03/citation-boosting-episode-leads-editors-resignations-university-investigation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Citation-boosting episode leads to editors’ resignations, university investigation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Video blog: Immunity in the spleen</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8647</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/video-blog-immunity-spleen/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/video-blog-immunity-spleen/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video blog: Immunity in the spleen&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: If you think the Amazon jungle is completely wild, think again</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-think-amazon-jungle-completely-wild-think-again</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-think-amazon-jungle-completely-wild-think-again</link>
	<description>Ancient Amazonians partly or fully domesticated fruit and nut trees that still dominate some forests.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030217_BB_amazon-forest_main.jpg?itok=RwOsDfRN" length="48476" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Gender in science: “an initiative for change”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/gender-in-science-an-initiative-for-change</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/gender-in-science-an-initiative-for-change</link>
	<description>Scientists, policymakers and students converge in a growing movement to boost gender diversity in science</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 09:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Circle time rituals help children beat the Marshmallow Test of self control</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=20174</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/03/circle-time-rituals-help-children-beat-the-marshmallow-test-of-self-control/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Group of kids repeat gesture after the teacher&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-20254&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;20254&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;10&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Group of kids repeat gesture after the teacher in kindergarten class making house with hands above head&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1451833950&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SerrNovik&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Group of kids repeat gesture after the teacher&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Group of kids repeat gesture after the teacher&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-503362524.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-503362524.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-503362524.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/03/circle-time-rituals-help-children-beat-the-marshmallow-test-of-self-control/group-of-kids-repeat-gesture-after-the-teacher/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/thinkstockphotos-503362524.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet, old-fashioned circle time rituals involve young children sitting in a circle with a teacher and copying his or her specific actions as closely as possible. These rituals can seem a bit out of place in today’s culture with its emphasis on the importance of independent thinking, and the ubiquity of interactive educational games employing the latest beeps and whistles of technology. But a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/wol1/doi/10.1111/cdev.12762/abstract&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Child Development&lt;/em&gt; says there is something about the conformity and attention to detail in ritualistic games that makes them a highly effective way to improve children’s executive functioning (their mental nimbleness) and self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-20174&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veronica Rybanska at the University of Oxford and her colleagues tested two groups of 7- and 8-year-old children, one from Slovakia, the other from Vanuatu in the Southwest Pacific. The children first completed tests of their executive functioning and self control. The executive functioning test involved learning to respond accurately to reversed commands, such as touching toes when hearing the command “touch your knees”. The self control test was a version of Walter Mischel’s classic Marshmallow Test: if the children could resist eating a single piece of chocolate for 15 minutes, they could have three afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, for three months, some of the children undertook 35-minutes of circle time games twice per week (others acted as controls and didn’t perform these games). The games involved things like dancing, clapping or learning new traffic light rules, such as stopping for purple rather than red. Crucially, among the children who played the circle time games, half experienced them as rituals. They were told they must follow the actions of the game because “it has always been done this way” or “those are the rules and they must be followed”. The others experienced the games in a more “instrumental” way that emphasised the purpose of the games. For example, they were told “if we do it this way, we will learn how to dance”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the three month period, the children took the tests of executive function and self-control again. The children who’d completed the circle time games showed greater improvements in their executive function and self-control than the control group children, but crucially these gains were larger in the children who experienced the circle time games as ritual. Moreover, the superior improvements in self-control in the ritual group seemed to be explained by their greater increase in executive functioning ability. These effects were similar in Slovakia and Vanuatu even though the latter culture places a greater emphasis on rituals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Far from being a simple matter of ‘mindless’ copying, ritual participation arguably requires the kind of rigorous computation of arbitrary detail and avoidance of normatively proscribed deviation from the script that engages and exercises our executive functioning abilities,” the researchers said. They admitted to the limitations of their study: for one thing, they didn’t measure the children’s behavior during circle time, so it’s not certain the ritual group children really did pay closer attention to the games. Nonetheless, they said there could be educational implications to their results: “the irony may be that in devising strategies for parenting and schooling geared to a world of rapid technological change while neglecting the importance of traditional cultural practices, we may be contributing to a deterioration of young people’s attentive and inhibitive resources, thus promoting impulses toward instant gratification”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/wol1/doi/10.1111/cdev.12762/abstract&quot;&gt;Rituals Improve Children’s Ability to Delay Gratification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20174/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20174/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=20174&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 07:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC-series: February 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8635</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/highlights-bmc-series-february-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;BMCWordle&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2016/07/BMCWordle-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetics: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenet.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12863-017-0477-7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systematically producing color-blind fish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color perception is essential for the survival and reproduction of many animals. This study, published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Genetics&lt;/em&gt;, demonstrates the development of a systematic procedure, using the CRISPR/Cas9 system, for making color blind Japanese rice fish and testing their spectral sensitivity under light- and dark-adapted conditions. This fish model system can prove useful for studying visual systems and vision-dependent behaviour and can potentially be extended to study color perception in other non-mammalian vertebrates. Finally, it could be valuable for the advancement of genetic or regenerative methods to treat human color blindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Health: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4081-6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reducing diabetes risk with weight management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight reduction for individuals at high-risk of diabetes is a key measure and policy paradigm for the prevention of the disease. This observational cohort study by Feldman et al., represents a 10-year follow-up in a group of more than 33,000 Swedish  participants between the ages of 30-60. It demonstrates a strong association between the risk of incident diabetes and the relative weight of the participant in adulthood. Additionally, the authors show that as many as 1 in 5 diabetes cases could be prevented if, at a population level, weight in adulthood is maintained. Finally, it concludes that the combination of the former approach together with moderate weight loss for high-risk individuals would have great potential, from a public health perspective, in diabetes prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychiatry: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-016-1173-2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSRIs versus placebo in patients with major depressive disorder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) are often the first line of treatment for depression. The objective of this study, published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, is to conduct a systematic review assessing the effects of SSRIs versus placebo, ‘active’ placebo, or no intervention in adult participants with major depressive disorder. Meta-analysis data indicate that SSRIs versus placebo seem to have statistically significant effects on depressive symptoms, but according to the authors, the clinical significance of these effects seems questionable and all trials were at high risk of bias. The results show that the harmful effects of SSRIs versus placebo for major depressive disorder seem to outweigh any potentially small beneficial effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image of the month: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmczool.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40850-017-0013-2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characterising a new species: &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis monodelphis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nematode genus &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis&lt;/em&gt; has been integral to our understanding of metazoan biology and has provided key insights into molecular and developmental biology.  In this study, published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, Slos et al. use both morphological and molecular analyses to characterise and describe a new species, &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis monodelphis&lt;/em&gt;. Scanning electron micrographs of &lt;em&gt;Caenorhabditis&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;monodelphis&lt;/em&gt; are utilised to showcase morphological differences between males and females, focusing mainly on genital differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8636&quot; style=&quot;width: 702px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;nematode&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8636 size-full&quot; height=&quot;737&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/nematode.png&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Slos et al. 2017&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evolutionary Biology: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-017-0907-1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating the evolution of reaction norms across tropical butterflies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developmental plasticity, which is considered to have profound macro-evolutionary effects, is omnipresent among plants and animals. This study by van Bergen et al. investigates, using a comparative framework, the evolution of reaction norms for a variety of life history and morphological traits across five related species of mycalesine butterflies from the Old World tropics. It demonstrates that the integrated phenotypic plasticity of a broad suite of traits is shared among species from three geographically independent lineages of mycalesine butterflies, but concurrently, there are examples of evolutionary change where independent traits show different, ‘uncoupled’ patterns of reaction norm evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infectious Diseases: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12879-017-2255-6&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewing the UK management of HIV in pregnancy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential for HIV transmission between a pregnant woman and her unborn child was first recognised in 1982. The prevention, however, of mother to child transmission (MTCT) is still very complex: interventions aim to reduce risk throughout pregnancy, labour, delivery and the neonatal period. Since 2001, the British HIV Association (BHIVA) has produced guidelines to support clinicians in the delivery of care aimed at reducing MTCT. This audit reviews the UK management of HIV in pregnancy, in comparison with the 2012 BHIVA guidelines. Having investigated more than 1400 pregnancies, the study demonstrates a need for services to review their ability to access urgent HIV testing, to strengthen referral pathways between general and specialist antenatal care services and to identify where delays in starting women on antiretroviral therapy are occurring. Finally, local policy should be kept up to date with national guidance to ensure women are able to access the best possible care available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecology: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0119-y&quot;&gt;Do predator cues affect trait variability in marine dinoflagellates?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phenotypic plasticity is commonplace and enables organisms to respond to environmental variations. However, the ability of various genotypes to produce a common, environmentally cued phenotype may differ due to genetic variation between individuals .This study, in &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt;, analysed the plastic response of two genotypes of the marine dinoflagellate &lt;em&gt;Alexandrium fundyense&lt;/em&gt;, in response to grazers or grazer cues, in order to characterise their effect on trait variability. The study demonstrated that selection on different genotypes can occur in the presence of plasticity due to different costs and trade-offs that arise for the respective genotype. The occurrence of multiple environmental cues to respond to in nature might, in fact, equalise the effects of strain-specific trade-offs within populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13104-017-2418-y&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goes back to its roots!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has reaffirmed its focus on publishing research outputs which are useful but often overlooked by traditional research journals such as updates to previous work, additions to established methods, single observations, short null results research proposals and data management plans. To increase clarity and simplicity, we have reduced the number of article types and created ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/submission-guidelines/preparing-your-manuscript/research-note&quot;&gt;Research note&lt;/a&gt;’, the journal’s main article format with a word limit of 2,000 making it a true note article structured as introduction, main text and limitations. Finally, we have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biomedcentral.com/p/introducing-the-new-bmc-research-notes&quot;&gt;expanded the scope&lt;/a&gt; to also welcome submissions on physical and computer sciences, engineering and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/03/highlights-bmc-series-february-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC-series: February 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2016/07/BMCWordle-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Commercialize quantum technologies in five years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543171a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/YXLFrTNgfHQ/543171a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Masoud Mohseni, Peter Read, Hartmut Neven and colleagues at Google's Quantum AI Laboratory set out investment opportunities on the road to the ultimate quantum machines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 171 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543171a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543171a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/YXLFrTNgfHQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Certain birth defects are on the rise since Zika arrived in the U.S.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/certain-birth-defects-are-rise-zika-arrived-us</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/certain-birth-defects-are-rise-zika-arrived-us</link>
	<description>The rate of certain birth defects is much higher in babies born to Zika-infected mothers in the United States, the CDC reports.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/blogposts/030217_LH_zika-birth-defects_main_free.jpg?itok=qp7dZNOG" length="22601" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PLOS Neuroscience Community: Can neuroscience explain a computer? (by Elena Blanco-Suárez)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19182</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/vx8llsia_q8/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;space invaders brains&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/03/space-invaders-brains-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Elena Blanco-Suárez&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most common metaphors in neuroscience is that the brain is like a computer. Yet this comparison fails to illustrate how complex our brains are. The brain, like a computer, receives information and analyzes it. However, there are substantial differences in the way a computer or a brain manages information as well as how and from where it receives the inputs, among many other reasons that render the analogy inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Jonas from UC Berkeley and Konrad Kording from Northwestern University in Chicago took this metaphor a step further in an amusing – though slightly disheartening – &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005268&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article in PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/a&gt;, alluringly titled &lt;em&gt;Could a neuroscientist understand a microprocessor?&lt;/em&gt; Their intention was to confront the possibility that current neuroscience techniques might not be the best to decipher the workings of the brain. To do this they analyzed a microprocessor as if it were a brain. They collected data using standard neuroscience tools to see whether they could infer the way the machine processes information, just like neuroscientists analyze large datasets to untangle brain mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They used three video games, well known to all the 80’s kids reading: Donkey Kong, Space Invaders and Pitfall. Each of these video games represented a different behavioral output from the microprocessor. For the biological equivalent, think of a &lt;em&gt;C. elegans&lt;/em&gt; (the microprocessor) and different behavioral phenotypes (the three video games). Although they acknowledge the limitations of comparing a microprocessor to a living organism’s brain, the authors argue that there are enough similarities to justify the study: both a brain and a microprocessor consist of interconnections of smaller units that can be differentiated and studied individually. They compare the build of the microprocessor to that of a brain, where we find circuits, subdivided into microcircuits, comprised of neurons that make connections through their synapses. Of course, the microprocessor is simpler than a brain in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using neuroscience protocols to study a microprocessor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They used established protocols to analyze diverse features of the microprocessor MOS6502, a model that is very well understood. Using the approach presented in &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/content/4/e04250&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one of their previous papers&lt;/a&gt;, they were able to identify types of transistors within the microprocessor and the connections between them, similar to the study of connectomics in the brain. In the microprocessor they only found one type of transistor, making it far simpler than a brain. However, it was impossible to infer the operation of the microprocessor by just looking at the connectomics. In neuroscience this is even more complicated, since type of cell, synapses, channels and neurotransmitters have to be integrated into the whole picture. The authors stated the importance of the study of connectomics, but emphasized the lack of algorithms to determine the functions of the brain regions assessed, hence the difficulty of understanding the brain through the sole analysis of connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also studied the effect of game performance when they removed one or more transistors from the microprocessor. This is similar to what we do in the lab, when a gene is knocked out to study the effects. They identified the contribution of each transistor to each video game considered, but they could not generalize to the rest of the games without further analysis. According to the authors, these results relate to neuroscience in that it is unlikely that a certain behavior would be triggered without the interaction of different brain circuits/regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the paper, they looked into other aspects of the transistors: tuning, correlations, local field potentials, functional connectivity, spatio-temporal activity, and how they differed depending on the game that was being played. With every set of experiments they concluded that, although interesting and necessary data were drawn, no individual dataset provided a full understanding of how the MOS6502 processes information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better approaches for better conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has to be taken into account that this study of the microprocessor is a lot cleaner than actual neuroscience. We cannot forget brain plasticity and the capability of the brain to repair circuits or compensate for lesions and other impairments. MOS6502 cannot compensate for what the researchers were doing to it, rendering the data much cleaner and clearer than that from neuroscience experiments &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors found their data unsatisfactory&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;as it did not lead to conclusions that accurately explained the function and structure of the microprocessor as they know it. If they had made assumptions about the microprocessor based in the results herein, these might have been erroneous or misleading. This is why they advise caution at interpreting small data sets. The authors insist that better experiments would have helped them to understand the microprocessor. However, what we can learn from this interesting publication is that, although neuroscience is nowadays producing valuable data to understand how our brain is connected, we still fall short of integrating this information at the high level of complexity of the living organism. And per their suggestion, neuroscience might need a better neuroinformatics approach as well as more refined methods for analyzing data to reach reliable and truthful conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, can neuroscientists really understand a microprocessor? Jonas and Kording believe we just need different methods to do so, and that testing these methods in a microprocessor could provide certain validation. But perhaps this study should not be considered as confirmation or rebuttal of the value of neuroscience to understand microprocessors, or even as measurement of the worth of current neuroscientific methods. This study offers additional evidence that brains are not computers. We definitely need a better metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonas E, Kording KP (2017) Could a Neuroscientist Understand a Microprocessor?. PLOS Computational Biology 13(1): e1005268. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005268&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Jonas, and Konrad Kording, ‘Automatic Discovery of Cell Types and Microcircuitry from Neural Connectomics’, eLife, 4 (2015), e04250&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit Elena Blanco-Suárez&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2016/10/headshot-Elena-BlancoSuarez.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;headshot Elena BlancoSuarez&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-18922&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2016/10/headshot-Elena-BlancoSuarez-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elena Blanco-Suárez&lt;/strong&gt; is a postdoc in the molecular neurobiology lab of Nicola Allen, at the Salk Institute in San Diego. She studies novel astrocyte-secreted factors involved in synaptogenesis during development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/vx8llsia_q8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro">PLOS Neuroscience Community</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Winning against a computer isn’t in the cards for poker pros</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/winning-against-computer-isnt-cards-poker-pros</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/winning-against-computer-isnt-cards-poker-pros</link>
	<description>Poker-playing computers beat professional players at heads-up no-limit Texas Hold’em.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030217_EC_AI-Poker_main.jpg?itok=XmKxR-oe" length="34883" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Earth’s mantle may be hotter than thought</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earths-mantle-may-be-hotter-thought</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earths-mantle-may-be-hotter-thought</link>
	<description>Earth’s mantle is warmer than previously thought, suggests a new experiment that better accounts for water content in rocks.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030217_TS_mantle_main_free.jpg?itok=RTtru3DY" length="17133" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researcher who lost whistleblower lawsuit logs 4 more retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48507</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/02/researcher-lost-whistleblower-lawsuit-logs-4-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A brain journal has retracted four papers by a researcher due to image duplications that the university uncovered during an investigation into his work. According to the retraction notice, Wayne State University found that Christian Kreipke had used several images in these articles “to represent different results in grant proposals and/or poster presentations,” and that the data were unreliable. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/02/researcher-lost-whistleblower-lawsuit-logs-4-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher who lost whistleblower lawsuit logs 4 more retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Origin of photosynthesis may go further back than estimates from 50 years ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/origin-photosynthesis-may-go-further-back-estimates-50-years-ago</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/origin-photosynthesis-may-go-further-back-estimates-50-years-ago</link>
	<description>Analyzing ancient rocks has helped push back the date when photosynthetic organisms first emerged by nearly a billion years.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/021617_LH_50ya_main_free.jpg?itok=XKpg6uF_" length="40105" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Detecting emotion of a person from their voice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-03-02:/2017/03/02/detecting-emotion-of-a-person-from-their-voice.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/03/02/detecting-emotion-of-a-person-from-their-voice.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I will discuss the importance of recognising the emotional state of a person from the tone of their voice.  For example, information may be conveyed by the pitch (frequency), tone, and volume of a speaker's voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am interested in investigating how a machine learning method may be able to discriminate between voices conveying varying emotions. I will show how unsupervised techniques (such as PCA) and supervised techniques, such as SVMs, may be able to tackle this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend my contribution to existing research will be in the area of robustness and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 3/03/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 15:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Unexplained abnormalities in stem cells prompt Columbia researchers to pull diabetes paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48516</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/02/unexplained-abnormalities-stem-cells-prompt-columbia-researchers-pull-diabetes-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Columbia University have retracted a 2013 paper in The Journal of Clinical Investigation, after uncovering abnormalities in the stem cell lines that undermined the conclusions in the paper. Last year, corresponding author Dieter Egli discovered he could not reproduce key data in the 2013 paper because almost all the cell lines first author Haiqing Hua used […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/02/unexplained-abnormalities-stem-cells-prompt-columbia-researchers-pull-diabetes-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unexplained abnormalities in stem cells prompt Columbia researchers to pull diabetes paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Will my children survive antimicrobial resistance?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8638</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/will-children-survive-antimicrobial-resistance/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Credit: Rocky Mountain Laboratories,NIAID,NIH Color-enhanced scanning electron micrograph showing Salmonella typhimurium (red) invading cultured human cells.&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/SalmonellaNIAID-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;As if climate change, international terrorism, rising mental ill-health, teenage knife crime, post-Brexit instability and potential superpower tensions were not enough to worry the heck out of us parents, the real spectre of a post-antibiotic era looms. Will my children live as long as I? Will I live as long as my parents or die a lingering death from an untreatable infection picked up in a nursing home which functioned as a reservoir of antibiotic resistance?  In 2013 England’s Chief Medical Officer considered the rise in antimicrobial resistance “a national civil emergency”&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;. In May 2016, the O’Neill “Review on Antimicrobial Resistance (AMR)”&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;,&lt;/sub&gt; sponsored by Welcome Trust and the English Department of Health, produced a plan for  tackling drug-resistance globally  exactly one year after the 68&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; World Health Assembly endorsed the WHO’s global action plan for AMR&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;. Both plans highlighted “strengthening of knowledge through research”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of us with enough miles on our biological clocks, this sounds very familiar. 1998 seemed to be a year signaling a paradigm shift in health priorities with the publication of reports like “The Path of Least Resistance”&lt;sup&gt;4 &lt;/sup&gt;and the European Union’s urgent convocation of the Copenhagen Summit on &lt;sup&gt;“&lt;/sup&gt;The Microbial Threat”&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;. Both highlighted the need for better research to develop a robust evidence base to inform practice and policy. Twenty years on we appear to stand at the edge of the abyss. Yet it would not be fair to say that in the interim there has been no change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8644&quot; style=&quot;width: 289px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pseudomonas_aeruginosa_culture&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8644 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;185&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/Pseudomonas_aeruginosa_culture-300x199.jpg&quot; width=&quot;279&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Sun14916/Wikipedia Pseudomonas_aeruginosa&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;True, much of what we knew then has remained the same. Hands still need to be cleaned, antibiotics prescribed less, narrow spectrum antibiotics preferred, and screening for resistance performed in those patients most likely to suffer severe infection. However we have not advanced much in understanding how to routinely embed these behaviours in clinical practice. Vaccine development has been less promising than hoped. New antibiotic development remains underfunded and unproductive. Despite this, there has been some better research in both the USA and Europe which has included well designed randomized controlled trials&lt;sup&gt;6-8&lt;/sup&gt;. The UK experience  of extra funding for national high-profile political drives  to reduce selected infections through evidence-based policies has been encouraging, with improved hand hygiene&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;, less broad-spectrum antibiotic use&lt;sup&gt;10,11&lt;/sup&gt; and lower infection rates&lt;sup&gt;9-11&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;So what has all this got to do with &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?  Well-designed clinical trials and observational studies inform clinicians and policy makers which interventions work, mainly through published research. However, editors of general medical journals are clear that much published research suffers from poor reporting and methodological flaws which could be avoided through adherence to expert consensus-derived reporting guidelines&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;. It is against this background that I welcome &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Diseases&lt;/em&gt;’ response to an initiative launched by 18 European and American infection control specialists and academics asking infection control journals to endorse those guidelines most relevant to controlling antimicrobial resistance:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.consort-statement.org/&quot;&gt;CONSORT&lt;/a&gt; for randomized control trials, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strobe-statement.org/index.php?id=strobe-home&quot;&gt;STROBE&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strobe-statement.org/index.php?id=strobe-singel-news-view&amp;amp;tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D=1357&amp;amp;cHash=52334cb1c3299d67f6703e13a566035d&quot;&gt;STROME-ID&lt;/a&gt;) for observational epidemiological studies including molecular studies, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prisma-statement.org/&quot;&gt;PRISMA&lt;/a&gt; for systematic reviews and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idrn.org/orion.php&quot;&gt;ORION&lt;/a&gt; for infection control intervention studies (especially interrupted time series) and outbreak reports of nosocomial infection. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BioMed Central&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biomedcentral.com/getpublished/editorial-policies#standards+of+reporting&quot;&gt;editorial policies and standards of reporting&lt;/a&gt; endorse CONSORT, STROBE and PRISMA and all guidelines hosted by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.equator-network.org/&quot;&gt;EQUATOR Network&lt;/a&gt;, including ORION. However &lt;em&gt;BMC Infectious Disease&lt;/em&gt; has now specifically highlighted ORION in its &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcinfectdis.biomedcentral.com/submission-guidelines/preparing-your-manuscript/research-article&quot;&gt;instructions to authors&lt;/a&gt;. My experience of reporting guidelines is that they and their checklists, not only help me review papers but also help me design and report research, if only to anticipate and avoid adverse comment from potential reviewers or grant assessment panels. Indeed, two or more guidelines may be required to cover all aspects of complicated studies. Most infection control journals have endorsed the above guidelines, although the effect of so doing on raising the quality of published research may depend on the rigor which guideline compliance is enforced, a hypothesis worth testing in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, as I enter the last years of my research career, and consider making down-payments on my future nursing home place, I like to think this initiative will result in the high quality research we need being planned and published. If allied to adequate funding of both the research and the clinical implementation of its findings, then maybe my children (and I) might survive antimicrobial resistance.  If climate change and all the rest let us live that long!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt;Davies, S.C. “Annual Report of the Chief Medical Officer, Volume Two, 2011, Infections and the rise of antimicrobial resistance” London: Department of Health (2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt;The Review on Antimicrobial Resistance. Tackling Drug-Resistant Infections Globally: final report and recommendations. May 19 2016. www.amr.org/ acccessed 16 Feb 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;http://www.who.int/antimicrobial-resistance/global-action-plan/en/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4 &lt;/sup&gt;Standing Medical Advisory Committee: Sub-group on Antimicrobial Resistance. ‘The Path of Least Resistance’. Department of Health September 1998.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5 &lt;/sup&gt;Rosdahl VT, Pedersen KB. The Copenhagen recommendations. Report from the invitational EU conference on The Microbial Threat, Copenhagen, Denmark, September 1998. Copenhagen, Denmark: Danish Ministry of Health, and Danish Ministry of Food, Agriculture and Fisheries, 1998.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6 &lt;/sup&gt;Huang SS, Septimus E, Kleinman K, et al. Targeted versus universal decolonization to prevent ICU infection. N Engl J Med 2013;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;Derde LP, Cooper BS, Goossens H, Malhotra-Kumar S, Willems RJ, Gniadkowski M, et al. Interventions to reduce colonisation and transmission of antimicrobial-resistant bacteria in intensive care units: an interrupted time series study and cluster randomised trial. The Lancet Infectious diseases. 2014; 14(1):31–9. doi:10.1016/S1473-3099(13)70295-0 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8 &lt;/sup&gt;Fuller C, Michie S, Savage J, McAteer J, Besser S, et al. (2012) The Feedback Intervention Trial (FIT) — Improving Hand-Hygiene Compliance in UK Healthcare Workers: A Stepped Wedge Cluster Randomised Controlled Trial. PLoS ONE 7(10): e41617. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0041617&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;Stone S, Fuller C, Savage J, Cookson BD, Hayward, et al (2012) Evaluation of the national Cleanyourhands campaign to reduce Staphylococcus aureus bacteraemia and Clostridium difficile infection in hospitals in England and Wales by improved hand hygiene: four year, prospective, ecological, interrupted time series study. : BMJ 344: e3005. doi: 10.1136/bmj.e3005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;Lawes T, Lopez-Lozano JM, Nebot CA et al, Macartney G, Subbarao-Sharma R, Dare CR et al Effects of national antibiotic stewardship and infection control strategies on hospital-associated and community-associated meticillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus infections across a region of Scotland: a non-linear time-series study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2015 Dec;15(12):1438-49. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(15)00315-1. Epub 2015 Sep 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/will-children-survive-antimicrobial-resistance/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Will my children survive antimicrobial resistance?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 14:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/03/SalmonellaNIAID-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: High population density seems to shift us into a future-oriented mindset</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=20086</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/02/high-population-density-seems-to-shift-us-into-a-future-oriented-mindset/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;613445810_2249c2d193_b&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-20151&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;20151&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;613445810_2249c2d193_b&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/613445810_2249c2d193_b.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/613445810_2249c2d193_b.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/613445810_2249c2d193_b.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,660&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/02/high-population-density-seems-to-shift-us-into-a-future-oriented-mindset/613445810_2249c2d193_b/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/03/613445810_2249c2d193_b.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the UK we’re familiar with the practical implications of increasing population density: traffic jams, longer waits to see a doctor, a lack of available housing. What many of us probably hadn’t realised is how living in crowded environment could be affecting us at a deep psychological level, fostering in us a more future-oriented mindset or what evolutionary psychologists call a “slow life history” strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-00749-001/&quot;&gt;their paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, Oliver Sng at the University of Michigan and his colleagues present a range of evidence that shows how this strategy plays out in the more patient ways that we approach our relationships, parenting and economic decisions. In essence, the researchers are proposing that the presence of greater numbers of other people in close proximity prompts us to invest in the future as way to compete more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-20086&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea behind life history theory comes from observing variations in behaviour between and across species, mainly in terms of how they approach reproduction. Species with longer life-spans that live in greater population densities tend to favour more investment in fewer offspring who take more time to develop. In contrast, species living in lower densities and at great risk of predators tend to favour a short-term strategy, for example having as many offspring as early as possible in the hope that at least some will survive. There’s also evidence that the same species, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3892362/&quot;&gt;such as Chinook salmon&lt;/a&gt;, adjust their mating strategies to the short- or long-term depending on the kind of environment they’re in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test how this might play out with humans, Oliver Sng and his team began by comparing the population densities of countries around the world with a range of parenting and relationship-related outcomes. They found that people in more densely populated countries tend to plan more for the future, have fewer children, have them later, invest in more long-term relationships, and place a greater emphasis on education (this pattern held even after accounting for between-country differences in urbanisation, economic development and population size ). The same pattern also applied across US states: those with greater population density expressed a more future-oriented focus, a “quality over quantity” approach in terms of relationships and child-rearing, and placed more importance on education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are problems with how to interpret this kind of correlational data (for instance, there could be unknown factors involved) so the researchers also conducted some experiments. They found that asking participants to read an apparent &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; story about increasing population density in the US led them to favour future financial rewards over more immediate gains in a simple economic game. Listening to the soundtrack of a large human crowd, as opposed to white noise, had a similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also showed that the effects of population density reminders seem to be specific to our stage of life. When undergrad students read the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; article about America’s increasing crowding, as opposed to an article about rising squirrel populations, they tended to say they favoured investing more in fewer relationships, but their answers about how many children they wanted, or how much they prioritised education, were unaffected. In contrast, reading about increasing population density led an older group of participants (average age 30) to say they favoured investing more time and effort in having fewer children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sng and his colleagues said their results are preliminary: we need more data to confirm these effects and also to explore the potential mechanisms behind them. They believe many mechanisms are likely at play, including population density affecting our hormones and brain development, our motivations (for example, leading us to realise that we need to increase our chances of competing successfully in future), and cultural norms, for example mores around sex and relationships. “Much remains to be examined,” they concluded. “We hope this initial foray will generate renewed interest in a topic that has been all but forgotten, and encourage the field of research on density to become a little more crowded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jamescridland/613445810/in/photolist-Wd54U-obpyE3-9dXexz-6MpZ4a-krX2oT-aCb9WE-pLq1SP-5TyWm8-eH5FJ4-aD6Gj8-qxFVKZ-p1TTCb-8tKBYf-6qQAnT-8D1tAt-nFx4zA-7uohKJ-aBTGzv-qxFVNe-pLyMn6-idbdBF-3QBBjX-fc8VxB-djAQ9T-hjzwgU-31TNyy-RWhmDD-fF6fH7-efrNzB-aCf3YS-ojxDXA-iesJDY-9L2oVf-6QjFv-6dhgwF-U7sJv-aUXvp8-4g4Cvc-6S9p48-6Q4X9j-p5X4eW-e3ne6z-mHGa8-wNTau-aDaxEf-8ZAka6-dSsbDY-txJrbN-U7F3V-8EGBc9&quot;&gt;James Cridland/Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-00749-001/&quot;&gt;The Crowded Life Is a Slow Life: Population Density and Life History Strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20086/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/20086/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=20086&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 14:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: New ways to use smartphones for science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/new-ways-to-use-smartphones-for-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/new-ways-to-use-smartphones-for-science</link>
	<description>Smartphones are being used more and more for scientific purposes – by professionals and citizen scientists</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 13:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Video blog: New species of beetle discovered hitchhiking on ants</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8632</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/video-blog-new-species-beetle-discovered-hitchhiking-ants/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/video-blog-new-species-beetle-discovered-hitchhiking-ants/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Video blog: New species of beetle discovered hitchhiking on ants&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Hydrogen volcanoes might boost planets’ potential for life</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hydrogen-volcanoes-might-boost-planets-potential-life</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hydrogen-volcanoes-might-boost-planets-potential-life</link>
	<description>Volcanoes that spew hydrogen could increase the number of potentially habitable planets in the universe.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/022817_AY_hydrogen-volcanoes_main.jpg?itok=g323WLrl" length="29701" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Gut bacteria oversee the special relationship between the green mint leaf beetle and watermint</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8504</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/gut-bacteria-special-relationship-green-mint-leaf-beetle-watermint/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;While feeding on watermint, the green mint leaf beetle metabolizes the plant terpenoids, which are biotransformed and eventually excreted with the frass.&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/pic-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plant-insect interaction and co-adaptation: a question of chemical cross-talk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long course of evolution, plants have evolved a wide range of defense mechanisms against insect herbivores, which can be distinguished into two categories: constitutive defenses and inducible defenses. The former ones are physical and chemical barriers existing before insect attack; the latter ones are direct and indirect defenses that are triggered by the insect attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, direct defenses are plant traits able to directly interfere with attacking insects, whereas indirect defenses comprise plant traits that do not affect the susceptibility of host plants by themselves, but can serve as attractants to natural enemies of attacking insects. The response of insects to plant defenses includes the selective choice of different feeding sites, the alteration of the feeding rate or the induction of detoxifying enzymes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the long course of evolution, plants have evolved a wide range of defense mechanisms against insect herbivores, which can be distinguished into two categories: constitutive defenses and inducible defenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plants that accumulate specialized metabolites like the aromatic plant &lt;em&gt;Mentha aquatica &lt;/em&gt;(the watermint) deter herbivory with a direct defense mechanism, by producing terpenoids in glandular trichomes, which are specialized secretory tissues. Despite the toxic content of such secretory structures, specialized herbivores not only feed on plants bearing these structures, but have also evolved the ability to recognize and be attracted by specific compounds. Therefore, interactions between plants and insects occasionally lead to highly specific relationships, as in the case of &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Chrysolina herbacea &lt;/em&gt;(the mint leaf beetle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The very special relationship between &lt;em&gt;Chrysolina herbacea &lt;/em&gt;and the watermint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8614&quot; style=&quot;width: 255px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mint leaf beetles&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8614 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Mint-leaf-beetles-245x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;245&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chrysolina herbacea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emission of volatile compounds from the glandular trichomes of &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; is mainly characterized by the monoterpene pulegone. This is a potent attractant to &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea, &lt;/em&gt;as shown by olfactometry bioassays. The plant response to &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea&lt;/em&gt; herbivory is the activation of genes for terpenoid biosynthesis, diverting most of monoterpene production from pulegone to menthofuran. The latter compound repels &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea &lt;/em&gt;in bioassay tests. Thus, &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea &lt;/em&gt;is attracted by pulegone produced by undamaged &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt;, but is deterred by the methofuran production by herbivore-infested &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results indicate a differential tolerance of &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; monoterpenes; however, the detoxifying mechanisms and the catabolic/biotransforming ability that allow the insects to tolerate a high amount of ingested terpenoids remained an open question that has only now found some compelling answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How microorganisms can be involved in plant-insect co-adaptation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is recent evidence that microorganisms living in the insect intestinal tract might be involved in biotransformation of ingested leaf volatile terpenoids by activating catabolic and metabolic processes that are absent in insects, hence acting as “microbial brokers”, a strategy that enables phytophagous insects hosting such bacteria to overcome biochemical barriers to herbivory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently described examples are the detoxification of caffeine by gut microbes of the coffee berry borer, and the ability of bark beetles bacterial symbionts to metabolize toxic monoterpenes and diterpene acids produced by the mountain pine beetle in response to herbivore damage. Thus, microbial degradation of plant toxic compounds can occur in insect guts and contribute to the carbon and energy requirements for the host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is recent evidence that microorganisms living in the insect intestinal tract might be involved in biotransformation of ingested leaf volatile terpenoids by activating catabolic and metabolic processes that are absent in insects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, it has been proposed that microbial detoxification may lead to production of pheromonal markers. For instance, some insects feeding on plants that, like &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt;, store 1,8-cineole (a monoterpene with mosquito feeding deterrent and ovipositional repellent activities, and toxic effects against stored-grain beetles) show a marked ability to metabolize it into hydroxyl derivatives that several insects might use as pheromones. This hypothesis extends the possible role of the microorganisms living in the insect intestinal tract, which could be involved in the biosynthesis of semiochemicals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did we find in the watermint-mint bug interaction?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study we first evaluated the chemical patterns of both &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; leaf and frass (insect faeces) volatiles extracted by &lt;em&gt;C. herbacea&lt;/em&gt; males and females feeding on plants. Intriguingly, we observed marked differences between male and female volatiles. The sex-specific chemical pattern of the frass correlated with sex-specific distribution of cultivable gut bacteria. Indeed, all isolated gut bacteria from females belonged to either α- or γ-Proteobacteria, whilst those from males were γ-Proteobacteria or Firmicutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; experiments we then demonstrated that the microbial communities from the two sexes were associated to specific metabolic patterns with respect to their ability to biotransform and/or detoxify &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; terpenoids (including methofuran, menthone, 1,8-cineole, limonene and pulegone), and metabolize them into an array of compounds with possible pheromone activity. Thus, the gut bacteria of the mint leaf beetle influence the volatile blend of herbivory-induced &lt;em&gt;M. aquatica&lt;/em&gt; volatiles in a sex-specific way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that our study may contribute to our current understanding about the plant-insect chemical communication, providing a new perspective on exploitation of bacteria living in insect gut as producers of semiochemicals for sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/gut-bacteria-special-relationship-green-mint-leaf-beetle-watermint/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Gut bacteria oversee the special relationship between the green mint leaf beetle and watermint&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/pic-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Nuclear-mitochondrial mismatch: Divergent evolution and the safety of mitochondrial replacement therapy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8623</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/nuclear-mitochondrial-mismatch-divergent-evolution-safety-mitochondrial-replacement-therapy/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Mohanraj Durairaj, cc Flickr&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/27343753793_20a9ed25c0_o-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The birth prevalence of mitochondrial disease is approximately 1 in 5000, however 1 in 500 carry mutations in their mitochondrial genome. As there is no cure for mitochondrial disease, the immense variability in genetic defects and disease severity has made effective disease management challenging. Therefore prevention of genetic disease transmission from mother to a child using mitochondrial replacement therapy holds significant promise. Mitochondrial replacement therapy involves combining the nuclear DNA from the mother with healthy mitochondria from a donor egg. This technique was originally developed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/46/16765.full&quot;&gt;mice&lt;/a&gt;, validated in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v461/n7262/full/nature08368.html&quot;&gt;primates&lt;/a&gt;, and recently the birth of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newscientist.com/article/2107219-exclusive-worlds-first-baby-born-with-new-3-parent-technique/&quot;&gt;first ‘three person’ baby&lt;/a&gt; was reported in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, evolutionary biologists have raised concerns about the safety of mitochondrial replacement which are largely centered on the idea that nuclear and mitochondrial genomes evolved concurrently, and therefore mitochondria from one individual or population may not be compatible with nuclear material from another. Indeed as human populations have migrated and become distinct, as have the distribution of mitochondrial &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;gene groups inherited from the mother (mitochondrial &lt;/span&gt;haplotypes). This is illustrated in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3539-3&quot;&gt;figure from the article&lt;/a&gt; (below), which shows the global distribution of mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) haplogroups and highlights the immense variability and how different populations are dominated by distinct regional haplotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8626&quot; style=&quot;width: 979px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Adapted from Rishishwar and Jordan 2017: Map indicating the names and locations of the 1000 genome populations studied, together with pie charts showing the relative frequencies of distinct mtDNA haplogroups for each population. &quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8626&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/mtnDNA-blog-image.gif&quot; width=&quot;969&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Figure 2A from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3539-3&quot;&gt;Rishishwar and Jordan 2017&lt;/a&gt;: Map indicating the names and locations of the 1000 genome populations studied, together with pie charts showing the relative frequencies of distinct mtDNA haplogroups for each population.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deleterious implications of incompatibility and nuclear-mitochondrial mismatch have been indicated by studies in model organism such as mice and invertebrates. For example, although mice with mismatched mitochondrial and nuclear genomes survived into adulthood they showed reduced physical performance, learning and growth. However, as these animals are generated by repeated inbreeding, divergent mitochondria are introduced into highly inbreed lines, and therefore these model organism studies do not reflect the human condition where breeding between populations is common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3539-3&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;therefore aimed to gain an idea of the extent of nuclear-mitochondrial divergence that can be tolerated in a single individual and gain an idea of how often ‘swapping’ has occurred in human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using data from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internationalgenome.org/&quot;&gt;1000 Genomes Project&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cephb.fr/hgdp/&quot;&gt;Human Genome Diversity Project,&lt;/a&gt; the researchers were able to observe and quantify the extent of naturally occurring nuclear-mitochondrial mismatch seen in 3,547 healthy individuals across over 58 populations on 5 continents. As human genomic diversity has been shaped by natural selection, harmful combinations of nuclear-mitochondrial genomes should have been eliminated and therefore not observed in the existing healthy population sampled in this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis showed that generally the genetic distance between nuclear DNA (nDNA) and mtDNA sequences, which is reflective of evolutionary relationships and migration, were highly correlated. This is what would be expected based on their co-evolution in different human populations. However, analysis also showed that even individuals with very similar nDNA genomes can have highly divergent mtDNA. For example, in Puerto Rico 67% of the sampled population have mtDNA of Native American origin and 13% carry mtDNA haplotypes of European origin. In contrast, analysis of nDNA in the same population showed the reverse with 72% European ancestry and only 13% Native American ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings demonstrated that mitochondrial and nuclear genomes from divergent populations can coexist in healthy individuals, indicating that mismatched nDNA/mtDNA combinations are not deleterious or subjected to purifying selection. This holds great significance for the future prospects of this technique as it suggests nuclear-mitochondrial mismatches are not likely to jeopardize the or safety of mitochondrial replacement therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/02/nuclear-mitochondrial-mismatch-divergent-evolution-safety-mitochondrial-replacement-therapy/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nuclear-mitochondrial mismatch: Divergent evolution and the safety of mitochondrial replacement therapy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 08:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/27343753793_20a9ed25c0_o-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: How rival bots battled their way to poker supremacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21580</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/DkBU67HURP4/nature.2017.21580</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial-intelligence programs harness game-theory strategies and deep learning to defeat human professionals in two-player hold 'em.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 160 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21580&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21580&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/DkBU67HURP4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: How the fallout from Trump's travel ban is reshaping science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21579</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/RlKAffMylqQ/nature.2017.21579</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers are cutting short travel, ending collaborations and rethinking their US ties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 157 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21579&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21579&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/RlKAffMylqQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Amazon rainforest was shaped by an ancient hunger for fruits and nuts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21576</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/s8bUmRaLBG4/nature.2017.21576</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;People living in the area thousands of years ago may have changed the forest around them in ways that are still visible today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21576&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21576&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/s8bUmRaLBG4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Dying woolly mammoths were in ‘genetic meltdown’</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21575</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/KvDWPAIlF4g/nature.2017.21575</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Genomic study of extinction in progress may offer insights for modern conservation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21575&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21575&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/KvDWPAIlF4g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Colorectal cancer is on the rise among younger adults</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/colorectal-cancer-rise-among-younger-adults</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/colorectal-cancer-rise-among-younger-adults</link>
	<description>Colorectal cancer rates in the United States have increased in people younger than 50.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 22:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030117_TI_colorectal-cancer_main.jpg?itok=FM_WyG5-" length="26475" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Wild elephants clock shortest shut-eye recorded for mammals</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wild-elephants-clock-shortest-shut-eye-recorded-mammals</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wild-elephants-clock-shortest-shut-eye-recorded-mammals</link>
	<description>Among mammals, wild elephants may need the least amount of sleep, new measurements suggest.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 19:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/03/main/articles/030117_SM_elephant-sleep_main.jpg?itok=D49VEI0l" length="45301" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Oldest microfossils suggest life thrived on Earth about 4 billion years ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-microfossils-suggest-life-thrived-earth-about-4-billion-years-ago</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/oldest-microfossils-suggest-life-thrived-earth-about-4-billion-years-ago</link>
	<description>A new claim for the oldest microfossils on Earth suggests that life may have originated in hydrothermal vents, but some scientists have doubts.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022817_MR_oldest-fossil_main.jpg?itok=SxjqKDlA" length="25720" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Keeping your information secure with SOC 2-compliant IT infrastructure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1037</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/03/soc2/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-1038 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;215&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/download.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;235&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you have ever felt reluctant to outsource projects to a service provider because you are worried about sharing proprietary information, you should know that Science Exchange’s mission is to help assuage those concerns. Our dedicated Legal and Engineering teams obtain all of the certifications and meet all the regulatory requirements that your businesses require. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOC 2 Certification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Recently, Science Exchange was granted &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssae-16.com/soc-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;SOC 2 certification&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; (Service Organization Control 2, Type 2), a strenuous t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;est and report on the effectiveness of a service organization’s controls&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. This meant that external auditors reviewed many of the critical processes in our business to make sure our systems complied with five key principles.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Principles of SOC 2 compliance:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Security: Access to our system requires authorization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Availability: Our system operates as we have committed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Processing integrity: Processing occurs completely, on time, accurately, and when authorized.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Confidentiality: Information designated as “confidential” is specifically protected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;You can read more details on these principles and their implementation on the official &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssae-16.com/soc-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;SOC 2 page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does SOC 2 certification mean for Science Exchange users?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Any information shared through the Science Exchange website or via email to a scienceexchange.com address is kept completely confidential.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Examples of information we keep confidential:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Proposed experiments and collaborations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Information on proprietary (i.e., unpublished) materials and methods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Experimental results/data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Personal identifying information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Financial information and payment details&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Of course, SOC 2 Type 2 certification is an ongoing process. We will be audited again and again to make sure that your contractual agreements executed with Science Exchange, as well as any revisions to it, remain confidential. We will periodically test our systems for vulnerability and unauthorized access, and we will regularly back up data, keeping backup logs readily available. These are just a few examples of the tireless work we do to minimize the risk inherent in outsourced R&amp;amp;D, helping you advance their research faster.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Visit and bookmark our &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/compliance&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Compliance page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; to stay abreast of Science Exchange’s ongoing commitment to your security.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 17:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When you have 94 retractions, what’s two more?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48399</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/01/94-retractions-whats-two/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Attention Joachim Boldt: The 1990s are calling, and they want their papers back. The Annals of Thoracic Surgery has retracted two papers from the early 1990s on which Boldt was the first author – bringing the retraction tally for the disgraced German anesthesiologist to 96, by our count. Both articles were found to contain manipulated […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/01/94-retractions-whats-two/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When you have 94 retractions, what’s two more?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 16:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Faked data, plagiarism, no co-author okays…yeah, this paper’s been retracted</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48433</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/01/faked-data-plagiarism-no-co-author-okays-yeah-papers-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher in South Korea has retracted a 2016 paper on which he is listed as senior author because a former student wrote and published the article without his permission. According to the retraction notice, the former student also fabricated data and plagiarized “a substantial amount of material” from previous papers published by the senior and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/03/01/faked-data-plagiarism-no-co-author-okays-yeah-papers-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Faked data, plagiarism, no co-author okays…yeah, this paper’s been retracted&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: Free the journals</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1379</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/free-the-journals/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;These days, academic journals serve two purposes: to organize peer review, and to make an editorial selection. With internet and in particular “preprint” servers (eg &lt;a href=&quot;http://biorxiv.org/&quot;&gt;biorxiv&lt;/a&gt;), journals are no longer necessary for distributing academic papers. It is also worth reminding that the peer review system has not always been organized in the way it is currently organized, ie with several external reviewers, multiple revision rounds, etc. For example, Nature only introduced formal peer review in 1967. Before that, the selection would be done internally by the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two missions, organizing peer review and making an editorial selection, are currently coupled. But this is neither necessary, nor a good thing. It is obvious that this coupling is not necessary. One could easily imagine a system where papers are submitted to a mega-journal (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot;&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://peerj.com/&quot;&gt;PeerJ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://f1000research.com/&quot;&gt;F1000 Research&lt;/a&gt;), which organizes the peer review, and then journals (e.g. Nature or Cell) make their editorial selection based on perceived “impact”, possibly using the reviews. Instead, authors must submit to each journal separately until their paper is accepted, and reviewers are asked both to check the scientific standards, which is the alleged purpose of peer review, and to judge the perceived importance of papers, which is an editorial task. This results in frustration for the authors, unnecessary delays and tremendous waste of resources. Thus, it is not a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a peer review system is organized (eg by mega-journals), the remaining role of journals is then editorial selection, and this could be done separately. Once we realize that, it becomes clear that very little infrastructure should be needed to run a journal. A journal issue is then just a list of papers selected by an editor, put online with the appropriate links and editorial comments. I propose that every scientist, or lab, or possibly group of interest, starts their own journal, which I will call “&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/about-this-free-journal/&quot;&gt;free journal&lt;/a&gt;” (see my related posts &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/a-vision-of-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/my-new-year-resolution-to-help-move-science-to-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;). Free journals are not tied to any commercial interest; they are self-managed academic journals. Crucially, the editor makes a personal selection based on her readings, papers that she personally thinks are interesting. This means in particular that, in contrast with most journals, the editor is highly qualified. The selection is meaningful, not a collection of thumbs up/down made by disparate reviewers based on vague criteria (“impact”). It also implies that it is totally acceptable for the editorial selection to include “preprints”: the editor is a peer and therefore any featured paper is by definition peer reviewed (ie, as in Nature before 1967). I have made my own &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/&quot;&gt;free journal of theoretical neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; in this spirit. I have collected &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/how-to-make-a-free-journal/&quot;&gt;some technical advice &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/how-to-make-a-free-journal/&quot;&gt;on how to make one&lt;/a&gt;, and I would be happy to receive any suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottomline is: it is very easy to make a free journal. On the technical side, one essentially needs to use a blogging system, eg WordPress. This automatically generates an RSS feed (eg one post per issue). I also put all the comments associated to the selected papers on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubpeer.com/&quot;&gt;PubPeer&lt;/a&gt;, with a link to the journal; this way, anyone using their plugin automatically sees that the papers have been selected in the journal when looking at them on pubmed, for example. On the editorial side, it actually represents little work, and I believe that this little amount is actually quite interesting work to do. Every scientist reads and annotates papers. All that is required to run a free journal then, is to set half a day in the month to put your notes together into a post. This helps organizing your bibliographical notes, and it is helpful for your colleagues and your students. One could also imagine coupling this writing with the lab’s journal club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please leave me a note if you are making your own free journal and I would be happy to link it from my journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;My free journal: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/&quot;&gt;Brette’s &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.romainbrette.fr/&quot;&gt;free journal of theoretical neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Transgender children are at greater risk of mental health problems</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/transgender-children-are-greater-risk-mental-health-problems</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/transgender-children-are-greater-risk-mental-health-problems</link>
	<description>The Trump administration has rescinded federal protections for transgender kids in public schools, a move that the American Academy of Pediatrics condemns.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/022817_LS_trans-bathroom_main.jpg?itok=g9Bj7UKD" length="14997" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Ecology Image Competition Announcement 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8625</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/01/bmc-ecology-image-competition-announcement-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;2016's overall winner by Davide Gaglio, the striking landscape of the Kgalagadi Transfrontier Park during sunrise.&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2016/08/SA-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that the 5th annual &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; image competition launches today! We are calling for ecologists around the world to submit their images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created the competition as a chance for ecologists to share their research and photographic skills, and celebrate the intersection of art and science. The four previous competitions (the overall winners of which can be seen on this page) have certainly achieved this, providing us with superb images demonstrating the complex web of interactions that ecologists are dedicated to unravelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winning images from previous years have attracted substantial attention not just from ecologists but also from the wider public, featuring in international media outlets such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2016/aug/09/bmc-ecology-image-competition-2016-the-winners-in-pictures&quot;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/getting-big-picture-bmc-ecology-image-competition-winners/&quot;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-33718151&quot;&gt;the BBC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging the competition will be the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/about/editorial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Section Editors&lt;/a&gt;, who are experts in biodiversity, ecosystems, ecological models, and behavioral ecology. The overall winner will be chosen by a special guest judge, whose identity will be announced later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall winner will receive a cash prize of £250 (~ €300/$325), while the runner-up will receive £100 (€125/$150). Additional prizes of £50 (€65/$75) will be awarded for those images selected by the Section Editors that best represent their section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_5510&quot; style=&quot;width: 2010px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The overall winner from 2014, “A Namaqua rock mouse (Aethomys namaquensis, Muridae) getting dusted with pollen of the Pagoda Lily (Whiteheadia bifolia, Hyacinthaceae) while lapping nectar at the flowers.” &quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5510&quot; height=&quot;1446&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2014/08/Overall-winner-Sticky-snack-for-mice-by-Petra-Wester-compressed2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The overall winner from 2014, by Petra Wester, “A Namaqua rock mouse (&lt;em&gt;Aethomys namaquensis&lt;/em&gt;) getting dusted with pollen of the Pagoda Lily (&lt;em&gt;Whiteheadia bifolia&lt;/em&gt;) while lapping nectar at the flowers.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to submit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is affiliated with a research institution can enter.  We ask that entries be submitted to one of the five categories listed below &lt;strong&gt;and that they depict a specific ecological interaction&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behavioral and physiological ecology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conservation ecology and biodiversity research&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community, population, and macroecology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Landscape ecology and ecosystems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theoretical ecology and models&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will consider all images from photos to data visualizations, or a mixture of both – as long as they are striking, meaningful, and creative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email your images to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0066cc;&quot;&gt;bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line “&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology Image Competition&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_6793&quot; style=&quot;width: 4010px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2015's overall winner, by Mohamed Shebl, “Palestinian sunbird female forages on Echinops sp.”&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-6793&quot; height=&quot;3000&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2015/07/Figure-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4000&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;2015’s overall winner, by Mohamed Shebl, “Palestinian sunbird female forages on &lt;em&gt;Echinops sp&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following information must be included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Section:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description (Max. 300 words):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;File type:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data attribution (if applicable):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Affiliation:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact details of Research Institute:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I agree to release this image under a Creative Commons License:  Y/N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter handle (optional):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please attach your image entry to your email. All images must conform to the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A minimum 300dpi (1831 x 1831 pixels for a raster image).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In one of the allowable formats – EPS, PDF (for line drawings), PNG, TIFF,  JPEG, BMP, DOC, PPT [&lt;em&gt;Please note that it is the responsibility of the author(s) to obtain permission from the copyright holder to reproduce figures or tables that have previously been published elsewhere.&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with our policies on open access, entry to the competition implies release of the images under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0066cc;&quot;&gt;creative commons license&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, to allow file sharing with proper attribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting regular updates on the competition throughout the coming months, so don’t forget to keep up to date by reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0066cc;&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or by following us on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BMC_series&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0066cc;&quot;&gt;@BMC_series&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing date for entries is &lt;strong&gt;31st May 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, with winners being announced in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_2006&quot; style=&quot;width: 778px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2013's overall winner, by Moritz Muschick, &amp;quot;Timema poppensis perfectly camouflaged on its host, the Redwood Sequoia sempervirens&amp;quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-2006&quot; height=&quot;942&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2013/03/175_Overall-winner.jpg&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;2013’s overall winner, by Moritz Muschick, “&lt;em&gt;Timema poppensis&lt;/em&gt; perfectly camouflaged on its host, the redwood &lt;em&gt;Sequoia&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;sempervirens&lt;/em&gt;“&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the links below to see a full list of winning and highly commended images from the past four years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6785-13-6&quot;&gt;2013 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-014-0024-6&quot;&gt;2014 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-015-0053-9&quot;&gt;2015 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-016-0090-z&quot;&gt;2016 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/01/bmc-ecology-image-competition-announcement-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Ecology Image Competition Announcement 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 10:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2016/08/SA-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Psychologists uncover a new self-serving bias – if it’s my theory, it must be true</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19958</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/01/psychologists-uncover-a-new-self-serving-bias-if-its-my-theory-it-must-be-true/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cool character&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-20061&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;20061&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS REBEL T4i&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait of a confident classically handsome male model holding a pipe in upscale clothing&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1370253062&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;CURAphotography&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cool character&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cool character&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-178141261.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-178141261.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-178141261.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3500,2333&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/03/01/psychologists-uncover-a-new-self-serving-bias-if-its-my-theory-it-must-be-true/cool-character/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-178141261.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at the research literature on self-serving biases, it’s little surprise that critical thinking – much needed in today’s world – is such a challenge. Consider three human biases that you may already have heard of: most of us think we’re better than average at most things (also known as illusory superiority or the Lake Wobegon Effect); we’re also prone to “confirmation bias”, which is favouring evidence that supports our existing views; and we’re also susceptible to the “endowment effect” which describes the extra value we place on things, just as soon as they are ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17470218.2015.1099162&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt; by Aiden Gregg and his colleagues at the University of Southampton extends the list of known biases by documenting a new one that combines elements of the better-than-average effect, confirmation bias and the endowment effect. Gregg’s team have shown that simply asking participants to imagine that a theory is their own biases them to believe in the truth of that theory – a phenomenon that the researchers have called the Spontaneous Preference For Own Theories (SPOT) Effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19958&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across three studies, the researchers asked hundreds of participants to imagine a fictional planet in a distant solar system, inhabited by various creatures some of which are predators and others prey. Focusing on two of the creatures on the planet – Niffites and Luppites – the participants were either told to imagine that they (that is, the participant himself or herself) had a theory that the Niffites were the predators and the Luppites were their prey, or that somebody called Alex had this theory. This background scenarios was chosen to be neutral and unconnected to existing beliefs, and the hypothetical “ownership” of the theory by some of the participants was intended to be as superficial and inconsequential as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the researchers presented the participants with a series of seven facts relevant to the theory. The first few were mildly supportive of the theory (e.g. Niffites are bigger), but the last few provided strong evidence against (e.g. Luppites have been observed eating the dead bodies of Niffites). After each piece of evidence, the participants were asked to rate how likely it was that the theory was true or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way the participants interpreted the theory in the light of the evidence was influenced by the simple fact of whether they’d been asked to imagine the theory was theirs or someone else’s. When it was their own theory, they more stubbornly persisted in believing in its truth, even in the face of increasing counter-evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This spontaneous bias toward one’s own theory was found across the studies: when different names were used for the creatures (Dassites and Fommites); whether testing happened online or in groups in a lecture room; regardless of age and gender; and also when an additional control condition stated that the theory was no one’s in particular, as opposed to being Alex’s. The last detail helps clarify that the bias is in favour of one’s own theory rather than against someone else’s. Surprisingly perhaps, the bias wasn’t found to be stronger in participants who scored higher for other forms of self-serving bias such as narcissism or claiming to be familiar with non-existent words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistical terms, the size of the bias that participants showed toward their “own” theory was modest, meaning that the practical implications of these new findings are probably limited (though the basic principle – that we’re biased towards our own theories – certainly seems relevant to understanding the wrangles over facts and truth going on in the media these days). Gregg and his colleagues said that the more important point was the theoretical implications of their results. The fact it was so easy to induce this bias in the participants, even based on such minimal personal connection to the theory, “only underlines how exquisitely sensitive to self-enhancing biases the human mind actually is,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17470218.2015.1099162&quot;&gt;The SPOT effect: People spontaneously prefer their own theories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19958/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19958/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19958&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 09:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Self-injury: Breaking down the myths</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8615</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/01/self-injury-breaking-myths/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;iStock&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000041687012_XXXLarge-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stereotypes are widely held beliefs about the characteristics and behaviors of a group of individuals that rarely reflect reality. There are many negative stereotypes associated with mental health, most of which can be attributed to a lack of understanding; these stereotypes have led to strong social stigma attached to mental ill health, which often has a negative effect on the lives of people with mental health problems. In particular, there are lots of negative stereotypes and myths attached to self-harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth: Self-injury isn’t common&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact numbers of how many people self-harm in the general population is hard to determine. Available research likely misrepresents how common self-harm is; published studies are usually based on people who either seek help at a hospital, or from their primary healthcare provider, after harming themselves (so called clinical samples). However, a lot of people who self-harm do not seek help; meaning that these clinical samples are not representative of self-injury rates in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published rates of non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI) vary hugely between studies; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24422986&quot;&gt;recent meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; found that many of the differences in prevalence rates reported in non-clinical samples are likely due to different definitions of self-harm behaviors and different methods of assessment between studies. After adjustment for methodological factors, the researchers calculated the pooled lifetime prevalence of NSSI to be 17.2% among adolescents, 13.4% among young adults, and 5.5% among adults. As these figures show, people of all ages self-injure – it is not just a teenage thing – but there is far less data available about the rates of self-injury in adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8618&quot; style=&quot;width: 252px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;CHRISTIAAN TONNIS, Flickr CC &quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8618 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/8881851404_684d369c59_z-242x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;242&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Female Warrior #17 – CHRISTIAAN TONNIS, Flickr CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth: Only women self-harm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is often assumed that women and girls are more likely to engage in self-harm, however the evidence in the published literature is conflicting, depending on the country, age range and type of sample (e.g. clinical, college, community) studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=25795294&quot;&gt;recent meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt;, which included 120 studies that contain demographically diverse samples, suggests that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=25795294&quot;&gt;women are slightly more likely than men to engage in NSSI&lt;/a&gt;”, but the overall rate of NSSI identified among males (26.36%) was still remarkably high. They also found that “the gender difference was larger in clinical samples compared to both community and college samples”, suggesting that males who engage in NSSI may be less likely to seek out help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth: People who self-harm are suicidal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-harm is sometimes viewed as a suicide attempt by people who don’t understand it. By its very definition the term NSSI describes the intentional destruction of one’s own body tissue without suicidal intent, and for purposes not socially sanctioned. For the majority of people who self-harm it is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17014942&quot;&gt;emotion regulation strategy&lt;/a&gt; – it’s about trying to cope with difficult feelings and circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is a relationship between self-harm and suicide – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25617686&quot;&gt;those who self-harm are at greater risk than the general population&lt;/a&gt; – many more people self-harm than commit suicide. However, some people who self-harm also have suicidal feelings and might attempt to take their own life, which is why self-harm must always be taken seriously!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/03/01/self-injury-breaking-myths/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Self-injury: Breaking down the myths&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 07:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000041687012_XXXLarge-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Neurofeedback Training For Insomnia No Better Than Sham</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-5378829079242321288</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/wrWXsCnYdoU/neurofeedback-training-for-insomnia-no.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nQLMYWpD0fE/WLQHWMj44ZI/AAAAAAAAMCc/Poc3yv3rO0kwsGfsY5Y5YR3oy_3gIt3bACLcB/s1600/neurofeedback%2Bheader.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nQLMYWpD0fE/WLQHWMj44ZI/AAAAAAAAMCc/Poc3yv3rO0kwsGfsY5Y5YR3oy_3gIt3bACLcB/s400/neurofeedback%2Bheader.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2016.164&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neurofeedback training&lt;/a&gt; (NFT) is a procedure that tries to shape a participant's pattern of brain  activity by providing real-time feedback, often in the form of a video game combined with other sensory stimuli that provide rewards when the “correct” state is achieved. The most common form of NFT uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroencephalography&quot; title=&quot;Electroencephalography&quot;&gt;EEG&lt;/a&gt; (brainwave) activity recorded non-invasively from the scalp. The EEG is a complex mixture of neural oscillations of different frequencies. Specific frequency bands are targeted for enhancement or reduction, so the participant can learn to modulate their own brain activity. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An overview of the neurofeedback process is shown below. Signals are recorded from sensors, processed, and classified. The calculated signal is then presented to  the subject via feedback in one or more sensory modalities. Participants can learn to modulate their neural function, and  complete the loop when the feedback is processed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;- click on image for a larger view -&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8CseEVR2Ox8/WLYNzPBUSVI/AAAAAAAAMCs/Gj5hykuQUFEwAL0LphlkwFZut-6bbrRoACLcB/s1600/Neurofeedback%2Bin%2BNRN.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;143&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8CseEVR2Ox8/WLYNzPBUSVI/AAAAAAAAMCs/Gj5hykuQUFEwAL0LphlkwFZut-6bbrRoACLcB/s320/Neurofeedback%2Bin%2BNRN.png&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;modified from Fig 1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2016.164&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sitaram et al., 2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/b&gt; The methods included here are electroencephalography (EEG), &lt;span&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;agnetoencephalography (MEG) and invasive electrocorticography (ECoG)&lt;span&gt;. MVPA, multivariate patterns of activity. FFT, fast Fourier transformation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In one study, participants were trained to reduce the amplitude of alpha oscillations, with a goal of increasing long-range temporal correlations  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw285&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ros et al., 2016&lt;/a&gt;). Here's a description of the training procedure:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;For online training, the EEG signal was ... band-pass filtered to extract alpha (8–12 Hz) amplitude with an epoch size of 0.5 s. Here, subjects were rewarded upon reduction of their absolute alpha amplitude... Visual feedback was clearly displayed on a monitor via 1) a dynamic bar graph at the center of the screen whose height was proportional to real-time alpha fluctuations and 2) a “Space Race” game, where a spaceship advanced through space when amplitude was below threshold, and became stationary when above threshold. No explicit instructions were given on how to achieve control over the spaceship, and all participants were told to be guided by the visual feedback process.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In a sham condition, the participants were shown feedback recorded from another subject in an earlier session  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw285&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ros et al., 2016&lt;/a&gt;). Having a sham (or placebo) condition is critical for demonstrating that any gains in performance (or increases in long-range temporal correlations, in this example) are due to self-regulation of specific EEG features learned during training, and not from some generic aspect of the procedure.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In academic articles, neurofeedback is often called closed-loop brain training, perhaps to distinguish it from neurofeedback &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;therapy&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (also NFT). A recent paper in &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2016.164&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Nature Reviews Neuroscience&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; discussed experimental applications of NFT&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and theories of the underlying mechanisms. Animal studies have demonstrated that rats and monkeys are capable of modulating the firing rates of small groups of neurons. Models of neurofeedback learning include instrumental (operant) conditioning, motor learning, global workspace theory, and skill learning. Exciting and important research ventures that capitalize on NFT are applications to brain-computer interfaces (BCI) and brain-machine interfaces (BMI), which have allowed paralyzed individuals to &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/content/6/e18554#fig1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;type&lt;/a&gt; and move prosthetic hands.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Psychiatric applications of NFT have been more problematic. First, you have to correctly identify the frequency band(s) that are abnormal in a clinical population. Then you must have a principled method for selecting the NFT protocol. Finally, you must demonstrate that your specific NFT protocol is superior to sham feedback (in a randomized, controlled trial). Unfortunately, this is rarely done.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Neurofeedback therapy has received critical coverage from the press in recent weeks. The new U.S. Secretary of Education, billionaire &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Betsy_DeVos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Betsy DeVos&lt;/a&gt;, has a major financial stake in an NFT company called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neurocorecenters.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neurocore&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; ran two articles critical of both DeVoss's conflict of interest and of the supposed benefits of NFT. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.nytimes.com/2017/01/20/business/dealbook/betsy-devos-neurocore.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Betsy DeVos Won’t Shed Stake in Biofeedback Company, Filings Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ms. DeVos and her husband promote Neurocore heavily on the website for Windquest Group, a family office the couple use to manage some of their many investments...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the claims that Neurocore’s methods can help children improve their performance in school could present a conflict for Ms. DeVos if she is confirmed as education secretary — especially given that the company is moving to expand its national reach.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.nytimes.com/2017/01/30/us/politics/betsy-devos-neurocore-brain-centers.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Betsy DeVos Invests in a Therapy Under Scrutiny&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;. . .&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Neurocore has not published its results in peer-reviewed medical literature. Its techniques — including mapping brain waves to diagnose problems and using neurofeedback, a form of biofeedback, to treat them — are not considered standards of care for the majority of the disorders it treats, including autism. Social workers, not doctors, perform assessments, and low-paid technicians with little training apply the methods to patients, including children with complex problems.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;And Neurocore is in no way unique.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Hundreds of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=neurofeedback+center&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neurofeedback Centers&lt;/a&gt; offer cures for everything from A to T by merely wearing a few electrodes and playing a computer game for 20-30 sessions (and $2,000-3,000).  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ADD / ADHD&lt;br /&gt;Addiction&lt;br /&gt;Alzheimer’s Disease&lt;br /&gt;Anger Management&lt;br /&gt;Anxiety&lt;br /&gt;Attachment Disorders&lt;br /&gt;Autism&lt;br /&gt;Bipolar Disorder&lt;br /&gt;Borderline Personality Disorder&lt;br /&gt;Chronic Pain&lt;br /&gt;Conduct Disorders&lt;br /&gt;Depression&lt;br /&gt;Dyslexia&lt;br /&gt;Epilepsy / Seizures&lt;br /&gt;Fibromyalgia&lt;br /&gt;Insomnia / Sleep Disorders&lt;br /&gt;Learning Disorders&lt;br /&gt;Lyme Disease&lt;br /&gt;Memory Loss&lt;br /&gt;Migraines&lt;br /&gt;Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder &lt;br /&gt;OCD / Tourrette’s&lt;br /&gt;Parkinson’s&lt;br /&gt;Pre-Menstrual Syndrome&lt;br /&gt;Stress / PTSD&lt;br /&gt;Schizophrenia&lt;br /&gt;Sleep Disorders&lt;br /&gt;Stroke&lt;br /&gt;Substance Abuse&lt;br /&gt;Tourette’s Syndrome &lt;br /&gt;Traumatic Brain Injury&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pitches are often targeted to concerned parents, but there is little to no evidence that the therapy offered at most of these centers is based on sound scientific research. As mentioned, double-blind, placebo controlled clinical trials are rarely conducted. &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ca-central-1.amazonaws.com/razlab.org/publications/Preprint_AMP_ThibaultRaz.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Thibault and &lt;/span&gt;Raz&lt;/a&gt; (2017) have been particularly vocal about the lack of rigor in published studies, as well as the inflated claims of successful treatment.&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Advocates of neurofeedback make bold claims concerning brain regulation, treatment of disorders, and mental health. Decades of research and thousands of peer-reviewed publications support neurofeedback using electroencephalography (EEG-nf); yet, few experiments isolate the act of receiving feedback from a specific brain signal as a necessary precursor to obtain the purported benefits. Moreover, while psychosocial parameters including participant motivation and expectation, rather than neurobiological substrates, seem to fuel clinical improvement across a wide range of disorders, for-profit clinics continue to sprout across North America and Europe. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's how Neurocore describes its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neurocorecenters.com/treatment/sleep/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Natural Sleep Disorder Therapy&lt;/a&gt; for insomnia:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Neurofeedback. Natural treatment for sleep disorders &amp;amp; insomnia.&lt;/h4&gt;Neurocore’s approach to treating insomnia and sleeping disorders  starts by looking at the brain. Using advanced qEEG technology, we  measure your brainwaves to help identify the cause of the problem. We  also monitor your heart rate and evaluate how in sync it is with your  breathing pattern. Your unique neurometrics yield a customized  neurofeedback training program that will teach your brain to  self-regulate. The result is a brain that’s calibrated for better  ongoing recovery, which means better sleep for you.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But the Neurocore “neurometrics” are not obtained from a clinical sleep study (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28118865&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;polysomnography&lt;/a&gt;) which measures not only brain and heart activity, but also muscle activity, eye movements, and respiration. They haven't identified the “cause of the problem”. It could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleepfoundation.org/insomnia/content/what-causes-insomnia&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sleep apnea&lt;/a&gt; or another medical condition.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/brain/awx011&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brand new evidence&lt;/a&gt; indicates that targeted, sensorimotor-rhythm (SMR) NFT for insomnia is no better than sham feedback. Earlier work had suggested that training to increase 12-15 Hz activity over the sensorimotor cortex could improve sleep by enhancing sleep spindles, which are in the same 12-15 Hz frequency range. In the new study, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/brain/awx011&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schabus et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; took 25 patients with insomnia and administered 12 sessions of real neurofeedback and 12 sessions of sham neurofeedback, also called placebo feedback training (PFT):&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Importantly, during the NFT condition, participants had to enhance EEG amplitudes in the SMR range between 12 and 15 Hz, whereas during the PFT sessions participants had to enhance random frequency ranges between 7 and 20 Hz (but not the 12–15 Hz SMR range); importantly within a PFT session only one frequency was trained and rewarded. The reason for choosing this kind of placebo or sham protocol was to involve patients to a similar degree as in NFT, yet with no specific frequency being rewarded systematically. Rewarding another frequency systematically could have resulted in undesired effects on EEG and behaviour that would render the PFT control condition suboptimal.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Outcome variables were objective (EEG) and subjective measures of sleep quality. A forthcoming commentary from &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ca-central-1.amazonaws.com/razlab.org/publications/Brain2017_PostPrint_ThibaultLifshitzRaz.docx.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thibault et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; summarizes the results in a nifty cartoon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-j4RzESr009Y/WLZTssDTepI/AAAAAAAAMDA/kcAHfjqPBEA0Zd-KPiQ7_3XnLMhtV-A1wCLcB/s1600/comparing%2Bregular%2Band%2Bsham%2Bneurofeedback.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-j4RzESr009Y/WLZTssDTepI/AAAAAAAAMDA/kcAHfjqPBEA0Zd-KPiQ7_3XnLMhtV-A1wCLcB/s400/comparing%2Bregular%2Band%2Bsham%2Bneurofeedback.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As expected, when participants received genuine neurofeedback, they were able to significantly increase power in the SMR frequency band. This was not the case during sham neurofeedback sessions. Genuine neurofeedback did not alter objective measures of sleep quality (nor did sham). The most important result came in the patient ratings of subjective sleep quality. &lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;Genuine SMR neurofeedback improved subjective sleep measures, BUT SO DID SHAM NEUROFEEDBACK. This suggests that any benefit obtained from NFT was due to a placebo effect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Although this was a small study with some complications (e.g., nine of the 25 patients were “misperception” insomniacs with no objective indicators of insomnia), the results were informative about the cause of subjective improvements — they were non-specific in nature and did not rely on training SMR activity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In their commentary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ca-central-1.amazonaws.com/razlab.org/publications/Brain2017_PostPrint_ThibaultLifshitzRaz.docx.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thibault et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; refer to NFT as a &lt;b&gt;superplacebo&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Whether real or sham, neurofeedback demands high engagement and immerses patients in a seemingly cutting-edge technological environment over many recurring sessions. ... In this regard, neurofeedback may represent an especially powerful form of placebo intervention—a kind of &lt;b&gt;superplacebo&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Amusingly, they define &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;superplacebo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; as “A treatment that is actually a placebo although neither the prescribing practitioner nor the receiving patient is aware of the absence of evidence to recommend it therapeutically.” If everyone thinks neurofeedback treatment works, it is more likely to do so, even though it bears no relation to self-regulation of selective neural activity. Future studies with refined NFT protocols may yet “tune” the brain in a desired direction, but for now... buyer beware.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Reading&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sitn.hms.harvard.edu/flash/2017/brain-training-future-psychiatric-treatment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brain training: The future of psychiatric treatment?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.edweek.org/edweek/inside-school-research/2017/01/devos-associated_company_alleg.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DeVos-Associated Company Alleges Brain-Training Autism 'Fix'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnotes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The paper also reviewed neurofeedback studies that use hemodynamic measures. NFT based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_magnetic_resonance_imaging&quot; title=&quot;Functional magnetic resonance imaging&quot;&gt;fMRI&lt;/a&gt; is a newer (and more expensive) development that won't be covered here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neurocorecenters.com/treatment/adhd/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neurocore claims&lt;/a&gt;: “Our ADHD Outcomes*  90% report fewer or less frequent ADHD symptoms.   85% experience a clinically important reduction of ADHD symptoms.  76%  achieve non-clinical status.  53% no longer meet symptomatic thresholds  for ADHD. ”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ros T, Frewen P, Théberge J, Michela A, Kluetsch R, Mueller A, Candrian  G, Jetly R, Vuilleumier P, Lanius RA. (2016). Neurofeedback tunes scale-free  dynamics in spontaneous brain activity. &lt;i&gt;Cerebral Cortex&lt;/i&gt;. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw285&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;10.1093/cercor/bhw285&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Brain&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3A%2F10.1093%2Fbrain%2Fawx011&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Better+than+sham%3F+A+double-blind+placebo-controlled+neurofeedback+study+in+primary+insomnia&amp;amp;rft.issn=&amp;amp;rft.date=2017&amp;amp;rft.volume=&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=&amp;amp;rft.epage=&amp;amp;rft.artnum=&amp;amp;rft.au=Manuel+Schabus%2C+Hermann+Griessenberger%2C+Maria-Teresa+Gnjezda%2C+Dominik+P.J.+Heib%2C+Malgorzata+Wislowska%2C+Kerstin+Hoedlmoser&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Neuroscience&quot;&gt;Manuel Schabus, Hermann Griessenberger, Maria-Teresa Gnjezda, Dominik P.J. Heib, Malgorzata Wislowska, Kerstin Hoedlmoser (2017). Better than sham? A double-blind placebo-controlled neurofeedback study in primary insomnia. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Brain&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/brain/awx011&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.1093/brain/awx011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Nature+Reviews+Neuroscience&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1038%2Fnrn.2016.164&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Closed-loop+brain+training%3A+the+science+of+neurofeedback&amp;amp;rft.issn=1471-003X&amp;amp;rft.date=2016&amp;amp;rft.volume=18&amp;amp;rft.issue=2&amp;amp;rft.spage=86&amp;amp;rft.epage=100&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Fdoifinder%2F10.1038%2Fnrn.2016.164&amp;amp;rft.au=Sitaram%2C+R.&amp;amp;rft.au=Ros%2C+T.&amp;amp;rft.au=Stoeckel%2C+L.&amp;amp;rft.au=Haller%2C+S.&amp;amp;rft.au=Scharnowski%2C+F.&amp;amp;rft.au=Lewis-Peacock%2C+J.&amp;amp;rft.au=Weiskopf%2C+N.&amp;amp;rft.au=Blefari%2C+M.&amp;amp;rft.au=Rana%2C+M.&amp;amp;rft.au=Oblak%2C+E.&amp;amp;rft.au=Birbaumer%2C+N.&amp;amp;rft.au=Sulzer%2C+J.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Neuroscience&quot;&gt;Sitaram, R., Ros, T., Stoeckel, L., Haller, S., Scharnowski, F., Lewis-Peacock, J., Weiskopf, N., Blefari, M., Rana, M., Oblak, E., Birbaumer, N., &amp;amp; Sulzer, J. (2016). Closed-loop brain training: the science of neurofeedback. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 18&lt;/span&gt; (2), 86-100. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2016.164&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.1038/nrn.2016.164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thibault RT, Lifshitz M, Raz A. (2017). Neurofeedback or Neuroplacebo? &lt;i&gt;Brain&lt;/i&gt;, in press. &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ca-central-1.amazonaws.com/razlab.org/publications/Brain2017_PostPrint_ThibaultLifshitzRaz.docx.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thibault RT, Raz A. (2017). The psychology of neurofeedback: Clinical intervention even if applied placebo. &lt;i&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/i&gt;, in press. &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ca-central-1.amazonaws.com/razlab.org/publications/Preprint_AMP_ThibaultRaz.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=wrWXsCnYdoU:JQGbvylrE1I:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/wrWXsCnYdoU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 05:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Peer-review activists push psychology journals towards open data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21549</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/w30eyQb2M1g/nature.2017.21549</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Editor asked to resign from journal for saying he’ll review only papers whose data he can see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 161 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21549&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/w30eyQb2M1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Protect rights at automated borders</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543034a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/eoHMTbmrC10/543034a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Gemma Galdon Clavell calls for checks and balances to avoid the indiscriminate sharing of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 34 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543034a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543034a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/eoHMTbmrC10&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Migration tracking is a mess</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543032a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/7Lmu9A4pb_Q/543032a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Monitoring technologies only add to the political noise over managing mobility, warns Huub Dijstelbloem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 32 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543032a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543032a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/7Lmu9A4pb_Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Boost visas for foreign entrepreneurs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543029a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/48pJiKDX--M/543029a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Strict immigration policies stifle innovation and job creation, cautions Vivek Wadhwa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 29 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543029a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543029a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/48pJiKDX--M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Hunted, haunted, stateless and scared: the stories of refugee scientists</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543024a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y6pCyDepsfQ/543024a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Displaced researchers face huge challenges making lives abroad, even if they find work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 24 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543024a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543024a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y6pCyDepsfQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: What the numbers say about refugees</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543022a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Wpm9g5flxCc/543022a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest concentrations of displaced people lie far from the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 22 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543022a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543022a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Wpm9g5flxCc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Human migration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543021a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/WMTJv7zFkWU/543021a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A special issue explores the intersection of science and migration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 21 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/543021a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/543021a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/WMTJv7zFkWU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cancer epigenetics: Reading the future of leukaemia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21894</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/anFHXIxK4gw/nature21894</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The identification of the regulatory protein ENL as essential to an aggressive form of leukaemia provides insight into transcriptional regulation and highlights potential avenues for therapy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21894&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21894&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/anFHXIxK4gw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cell biology: Sort and destroy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21892</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/0n8wX2zrp-4/nature21892</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Aggregates are aberrant, non-functional forms of protein that often build up in cells in response to stress. Organelles called mitochondria have now been found to be active players in the clearance of these protein aggregates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21892&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/0n8wX2zrp-4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cytosolic proteostasis through importing of misfolded proteins into mitochondria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21695</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Dtoqx7x6sWg/nature21695</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Loss of proteostasis underlies ageing and neurodegeneration characterized by the accumulation of protein aggregates and mitochondrial dysfunction. Although many neurodegenerative-disease-associated proteins can be found in mitochondria, it remains unclear how mitochondrial dysfunction and protein aggregation could be related. In dividing yeast cells, protein aggregates that form under stress or during ageing are preferentially retained by the mother cell, in part through tethering to mitochondria, while the disaggregase Hsp104 helps to dissociate aggregates and thereby enables refolding or degradation of misfolded proteins. Here we show that, in yeast, cytosolic proteins prone to aggregation are imported into mitochondria for degradation. Protein aggregates that form under heat shock contain both cytosolic and mitochondrial proteins and interact with the mitochondrial import complex. Many aggregation-prone proteins enter the mitochondrial intermembrane space and matrix after heat shock, and some do so even without stress. Timely dissolution of cytosolic aggregates requires the mitochondrial import machinery and proteases. Blocking mitochondrial import but not proteasome activity causes a marked delay in the degradation of aggregated proteins. Defects in cytosolic Hsp70s leads to enhanced entry of misfolded proteins into mitochondria and elevated mitochondrial stress. We term this mitochondria-mediated proteostasis mechanism MAGIC (mitochondria as guardian in cytosol) and provide evidence that it may exist in human cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21695&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21695&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Dtoqx7x6sWg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Transcription control by the ENL YEATS domain in acute leukaemia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21688</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/plYRmv6ctR4/nature21688</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Recurrent chromosomal translocations producing a chimaeric MLL oncogene give rise to a highly aggressive acute leukaemia associated with poor clinical outcome. The preferential involvement of chromatin-associated factors as MLL fusion partners belies a dependency on transcription control. Despite recent progress made in targeting chromatin regulators in cancer, available therapies for this well-characterized disease remain inadequate, prompting the need to identify new targets for therapeutic intervention. Here, using unbiased CRISPR–Cas9 technology to perform a genome-scale loss-of-function screen in an MLL-AF4-positive acute leukaemia cell line, we identify ENL as an unrecognized gene that is specifically required for proliferation in vitro and in vivo. To explain the mechanistic role of ENL in leukaemia pathogenesis and dynamic transcription control, a chemical genetic strategy was developed to achieve targeted protein degradation. Acute loss of ENL suppressed the initiation and elongation of RNA polymerase II at active genes genome-wide, with pronounced effects at genes featuring a disproportionate ENL load. Notably, an intact YEATS chromatin-reader domain was essential for ENL-dependent leukaemic growth. Overall, these findings identify a dependency factor in acute leukaemia and suggest a mechanistic rationale for disrupting the YEATS domain in disease. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21688&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21688&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/plYRmv6ctR4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: ENL links histone acetylation to oncogenic gene expression in acute myeloid leukaemia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21687</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/A_Qka2M8dZo/nature21687</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Cancer cells are characterized by aberrant epigenetic landscapes and often exploit chromatin machinery to activate oncogenic gene expression programs. Recognition of modified histones by ‘reader’ proteins constitutes a key mechanism underlying these processes; therefore, targeting such pathways holds clinical promise, as exemplified by the development of bromodomain and extra-terminal (BET) inhibitors. We recently identified the YEATS domain as an acetyl-lysine-binding module, but its functional importance in human cancer remains unknown. Here we show that the YEATS domain-containing protein ENL, but not its paralogue AF9, is required for disease maintenance in acute myeloid leukaemia. CRISPR–Cas9-mediated depletion of ENL led to anti-leukaemic effects, including increased terminal myeloid differentiation and suppression of leukaemia growth in vitro and in vivo. Biochemical and crystal structural studies and chromatin-immunoprecipitation followed by sequencing analyses revealed that ENL binds to acetylated histone H3, and co-localizes with H3K27ac and H3K9ac on the promoters of actively transcribed genes that are essential for leukaemia. Disrupting the interaction between the YEATS domain and histone acetylation via structure-based mutagenesis reduced the recruitment of RNA polymerase II to ENL-target genes, leading to the suppression of oncogenic gene expression programs. Notably, disrupting the functionality of ENL further sensitized leukaemia cells to BET inhibitors. Together, our data identify ENL as a histone acetylation reader that regulates oncogenic transcriptional programs in acute myeloid leukaemia, and suggest that displacement of ENL from chromatin may be a promising epigenetic therapy, alone or in combination with BET inhibitors, for aggressive leukaemia. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21687&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21687&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/A_Qka2M8dZo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Mediator structure and rearrangements required for holoenzyme formation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21393</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/LzW2n_VdOw0/nature21393</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The conserved Mediator co-activator complex has an essential role in the regulation of RNA polymerase II transcription in all eukaryotes. Understanding the structure and interactions of Mediator is crucial for determining how the complex influences transcription initiation and conveys regulatory information to the basal transcription machinery. Here we present a 4.4 Å resolution cryo-electron microscopy map of Schizosaccharomyces pombe Mediator in which conserved Mediator subunits are individually resolved. The essential Med14 subunit works as a central backbone that connects the Mediator head, middle and tail modules. Comparison with a 7.8 Å resolution cryo-electron microscopy map of a Mediator–RNA polymerase II holoenzyme reveals that changes in the structure of Med14 facilitate a large-scale Mediator rearrangement that is essential for holoenzyme formation. Our study suggests that access to different conformations and crosstalk between structural elements are essential for the Mediator regulation mechanism, and could explain the capacity of the complex to integrate multiple regulatory signals. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21393&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21393&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/LzW2n_VdOw0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Autophagy maintains the metabolism and function of young and old stem cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21388</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/1_OFz3wwKiY/nature21388</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 With age, haematopoietic stem cells lose their ability to regenerate the blood system, and promote disease development. Autophagy is associated with health and longevity, and is critical for protecting haematopoietic stem cells from metabolic stress. Here we show that loss of autophagy in haematopoietic stem cells causes accumulation of mitochondria and an activated metabolic state, which drives accelerated myeloid differentiation mainly through epigenetic deregulations, and impairs haematopoietic stem-cell self-renewal activity and regenerative potential. Strikingly, most haematopoietic stem cells in aged mice share these altered metabolic and functional features. However, approximately one-third of aged haematopoietic stem cells exhibit high autophagy levels and maintain a low metabolic state with robust long-term regeneration potential similar to healthy young haematopoietic stem cells. Our results demonstrate that autophagy actively suppresses haematopoietic stem-cell metabolism by clearing active, healthy mitochondria to maintain quiescence and stemness, and becomes increasingly necessary with age to preserve the regenerative capacity of old haematopoietic stem cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21388&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21388&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/1_OFz3wwKiY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: The molecular architecture of lamins in somatic cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21382</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/lIg6gsSugOE/nature21382</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The nuclear lamina is a fundamental constituent of metazoan nuclei. It is composed mainly of lamins, which are intermediate filament proteins that assemble into a filamentous meshwork, bridging the nuclear envelope and chromatin. Besides providing structural stability to the nucleus, the lamina is involved in many nuclear activities, including chromatin organization, transcription and replication. However, the structural organization of the nuclear lamina is poorly understood. Here we use cryo-electron tomography to obtain a detailed view of the organization of the lamin meshwork within the lamina. Data analysis of individual lamin filaments resolves a globular-decorated fibre appearance and shows that A- and B-type lamins assemble into tetrameric filaments of 3.5 nm thickness. Thus, lamins exhibit a structure that is remarkably different from the other canonical cytoskeletal elements. Our findings define the architecture of the nuclear lamin meshworks at molecular resolution, providing insights into their role in scaffolding the nuclear lamina. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21382&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21382&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/lIg6gsSugOE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Evidence for early life in Earth’s oldest hydrothermal vent precipitates</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21377</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/eCTaRdo9WQs/nature21377</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Although it is not known when or where life on Earth began, some of the earliest habitable environments may have been submarine-hydrothermal vents. Here we describe putative fossilized microorganisms that are at least 3,770 million and possibly 4,280 million years old in ferruginous sedimentary rocks, interpreted as seafloor-hydrothermal vent-related precipitates, from the Nuvvuagittuq belt in Quebec, Canada. These structures occur as micrometre-scale haematite tubes and filaments with morphologies and mineral assemblages similar to those of filamentous microorganisms from modern hydrothermal vent precipitates and analogous microfossils in younger rocks. The Nuvvuagittuq rocks contain isotopically light carbon in carbonate and carbonaceous material, which occurs as graphitic inclusions in diagenetic carbonate rosettes, apatite blades intergrown among carbonate rosettes and magnetite–haematite granules, and is associated with carbonate in direct contact with the putative microfossils. Collectively, these observations are consistent with an oxidized biomass and provide evidence for biological activity in submarine-hydrothermal environments more than 3,770 million years ago. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 543 60 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21377&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21377&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/eCTaRdo9WQs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: An atlas of human long non-coding RNAs with accurate 5′ ends</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21374</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/bLAFGZQOk1o/nature21374</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are largely heterogeneous and functionally uncharacterized. Here, using FANTOM5 cap analysis of gene expression (CAGE) data, we integrate multiple transcript collections to generate a comprehensive atlas of 27,919 human lncRNA genes with high-confidence 5′ ends and expression profiles across 1,829 samples from the major human primary cell types and tissues. Genomic and epigenomic classification of these lncRNAs reveals that most intergenic lncRNAs originate from enhancers rather than from promoters. Incorporating genetic and expression data, we show that lncRNAs overlapping trait-associated single nucleotide polymorphisms are specifically expressed in cell types relevant to the traits, implicating these lncRNAs in multiple diseases. We further demonstrate that lncRNAs overlapping expression quantitative trait loci (eQTL)-associated single nucleotide polymorphisms of messenger RNAs are co-expressed with the corresponding messenger RNAs, suggesting their potential roles in transcriptional regulation. Combining these findings with conservation data, we identify 19,175 potentially functional lncRNAs in the human genome. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21374&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21374&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/bLAFGZQOk1o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Scientists may work to prevent bias, but they don’t always say so</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/scientists-may-work-prevent-bias-they-dont-always-say-so</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scicurious/scientists-may-work-prevent-bias-they-dont-always-say-so</link>
	<description>Scientists may do the work to prevent bias in their experiments — but they aren’t telling other scientists about it, two new studies show.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 20:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/022717_BO_bias-animals_main.jpg?itok=8f2nBvdh" length="17911" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Ankur Sinha: Using Wallabag to manage your online reading list</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:ankursinha.in,2017-02-28:/blog/2017/02/28/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</guid>
	<link>http://ankursinha.in/blog/2017/02/28/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Edit (28 February 2017): Earlier today, it was &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/02/27/mozilla-acquires-pocket/&quot;&gt;announced that Mozilla had acquired Pocket&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://bugzil.la/1343006&quot;&gt;plans to gradually release the Pocket source code under Open Source licenses&lt;/a&gt;.  I guess &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; will remain as a self hosted solution, but given an improved integration of Pocket with Firefox, I may move back to it in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always have quite a bit on my pending list to read - academic papers, blogs, planets, and the sort. Usually, when I go through the planets, such as the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fedoraplanet.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://planet.gnome.org/&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; or the two neuroscience planets I use - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/&quot;&gt;neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt;, I don't have the time to read all the articles right then. I used to either bookmark links, or note them down somewhere to read later. One day, though, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you save the article to read later and makes it available to you on multiple devices. It's extremely convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the one issue with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is that it isn't &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&quot;&gt;Free software&lt;/a&gt;. So, like I do, I went looking for an alternative. After a few hours, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It's written in PHP, and is licensed under the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://tldrlegal.com/license/mit-license&quot;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite easy to deploy, and there's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; where you can get some help too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You either enter the URL in the Wallabag page manually, or you can use the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/wallabagger/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/wallabagger/gbmgphmejlcoihgedabhgjdkcahacjlj&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/wallabagger/?display=en&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; addon - it let's you right click a page or a link and &quot;Wallabag.it!&quot;. There's also a bookmarklet, which you can use with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/5digits/dactyl&quot;&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt;, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code bash literal-block&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Add to ~/.pentadactylrc
&lt;/span&gt;command! wallabagit -description &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Add to wallabag&quot;&lt;/span&gt; open javascript:&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;var%20url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;location.href&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;var%20wllbg&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;window.open&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'https://app.wallabag.it/bookmarklet?url='&lt;/span&gt;%20+%20encodeURI&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'_blank'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;})()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag fetches the text of the page and stores it for you so that you can read it later. You can even organise your saved pages with tags and the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing the Wallabag main page&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a page that I'm trying to read later, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing an article in Wallabag&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played with a deployment, but decided not to deploy and maintain an instance myself. Instead, I signed up for the instance Wallabag have here - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite cheap - they have an offer going too at the moment - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en/news/wallabagit&quot;&gt;only 9€ for an entire year&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag uses a the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fivefilters.org/content-only/&quot;&gt;FiveFilters Full Text RSS tool&lt;/a&gt; to extract the text and other data from web pages. Some websites require special instructions to tell the tool what information needs to be extracted - this tends to happen with a few academic websites. There's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fivefilters/ftr-site-config&quot;&gt;repository of such config files here&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you do run into a website that isn't rendering properly, you can &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://doc.wallabag.org/en/master/user/errors_during_fetching.html&quot;&gt;troubleshoot the issue and submit a config file too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you decide to deploy an instance yourself, or use &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;, I think it's a really useful tool to have. Of course, don't forget to install the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.gaulupeau.apps.InThePoche&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;app on your phone&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 20:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml">ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Saturn’s ‘Death Star’ moon may not conceal an ocean after all</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/saturn-death-star-moon-may-not-conceal-ocean-after-all</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/saturn-death-star-moon-may-not-conceal-ocean-after-all</link>
	<description>A lack of cracks on Mimas suggests that the icy moon of Saturn doesn’t conceal a subsurface ocean of liquid water.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/022817_mimas_free.jpg?itok=1HshEADK" length="25735" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When does animal research become unnecessary and cruel? A paper’s methods give a biologist pause</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48497</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/28/animal-research-become-unnecessary-cruel-papers-methods-give-biologist-pause/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Microbiologist Elies Bik is well-known for applying a close eye to studies, and has spent years anonymously submitting reports on plagiarism and image duplication to journal editors. Last year, she published an analysis of work, with troubling results – that 1 in 25 biomedical papers contains inappropriate duplications in images. She’s never stopped reading papers […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/28/animal-research-become-unnecessary-cruel-papers-methods-give-biologist-pause/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;When does animal research become unnecessary and cruel? A paper’s methods give a biologist pause&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Stuck in limbo: What happens to papers flagged by journals as potentially problematic?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48480</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/28/stuck-limbo-happens-papers-flagged-journals-potentially-problematic/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Expressions of concern, as regular Retraction Watch readers will know, are rare but important signals in the scientific record. Neither retractions nor corrections, they alert readers that there may be an issue with a paper, but that the full story is not yet clear. But what ultimately happens to papers flagged by these editorial notices? […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/28/stuck-limbo-happens-papers-flagged-journals-potentially-problematic/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Stuck in limbo: What happens to papers flagged by journals as potentially problematic?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: DNA may offer rapid road to Zika vaccine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-may-offer-rapid-road-zika-vaccine</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-may-offer-rapid-road-zika-vaccine</link>
	<description>Researchers are pursuing multiple vaccine strategies for blocking Zika infection.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_mr_zika-vaccine_feat_free.jpg?itok=SQBre8Vg" length="28911" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: There’s a psychological case for paying female managers more than male managers, or giving them more holiday</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19922</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/28/theres-a-psychological-case-for-paying-female-managers-more-than-male-managers-or-giving-them-more-holiday/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Red Businesswoman Silhouette, Black Business People Group Team Concept&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19943&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19943&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Red Businesswoman Silhouette, Black Business People Group Team Concept Vector Illustration&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;gmast3r&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Red Businesswoman Silhouette, Black Business People Group Team Concept&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Red Businesswoman Silhouette, Black Business People Group Team Concept&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-484693620.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-484693620.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-484693620.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1970,1522&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/28/theres-a-psychological-case-for-paying-female-managers-more-than-male-managers-or-giving-them-more-holiday/red-businesswoman-silhouette-black-business-people-group-team-concept/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-484693620.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women are still underrepresented in managerial positions, particularly at the top of organisations. It’s not just that women are unable to attain these positions due to discrimination or access to resources. There’s also evidence that suggests these positions may be less attractive to women, as having a senior job tends to increase life satisfaction for men &lt;a href=&quot;http://https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11205-009-9560-4&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;but not for women&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; this could lead to women exiting such career paths or shying away from them even if well qualified. &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10902-016-9832-z&quot;&gt;New research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Happiness Studies&lt;/em&gt; asks a simple, but important question: why are women managers less happy than their male counterparts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19922&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hilke Brockmann and her colleagues drew on a large German survey conducted between 1984-2011 involving data from 27,000 non-managers and 3174 managers, a third of whom were women. The survey featured questions about life satisfaction, pay and spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, female managers reported slightly lower life satisfaction than their male counterparts, consistent with past research. They also seemed to find higher pay less rewarding than men. Based on correlations between life satisfaction and pay across male and female managers, on the researchers’ estimate it would take an extra €12,000 of pay to boost a woman’s life satisfaction by the same amount that a man would gain from an extra €5,000 of pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is consistent with previous evidence that suggests men value money particularly highly against other benefits like more free time. Also, highly educated ambitious women are likely to settle down with romantic partners who are in similar careers and – especially if their partner is male – who may earn more than them. This means female managers can be in a situation where further gains in their own income matter less, given their net household worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brockmann and her colleagues expected and found that spare time would have a stronger association with happiness for women managers than men. One reason for this is women tend to have less free time than men, as they often take on greater responsibility for caring duties within a household. As managerial promotions often involve sacrificing free time for money, this deal is going to be less attractive for many women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Brockmann’s team found that caring less about money and more about time was at the heart of female managers’ dissatisfaction. Their analysis showed that if it were not for those factors, women would be &lt;em&gt;happier&lt;/em&gt; in managerial roles than men, which suggests that the nature of managerial work is not a problem for women, but how it is structured and compensated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also looked at the issue of whether female managers are more adversely affected than male managers by the decision to delay having children in pursuit of their careers. They found some evidence to support this, in that between the ages of 35 and 45 (when fertility tends to decline in women) childless female managers felt significantly less satisfied with their lives than female managers who’d had children and male managers who were childless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brockmann and her colleagues pointed out that the lack of gender parity at senior management levels isn’t solved by simply bringing women into the boardroom, as this may just consign them to an unhappy stay. A major problem is that in most working cultures leadership positions “require a non-stop lifelong commitment to extra-long working hours and early career path-dependencies” which may repel women who particularly value their free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One solution for companies who want to attract more female managers would be to build in more breathing space for their leadership positions – after all, successful entrepreneurs can &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/im-jason-fried-ceo-of-basecamp-and-this-is-how-i-work-1790556608&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;build businesses on 40 hours a week&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – and to provide other “temporal rewards” like flexible career paths, especially to help younger women more easily juggle family and work ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10902-016-9832-z&quot;&gt;Why Managerial Women are Less Happy Than Managerial Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19922/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19922/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19922&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 10:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: Optimism on Rare Disease Day: With Research, Possibilities are Limitless</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7366</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/LI2hhBWFtk0/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Rdd_blog-image&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/02/Rdd_blog-image-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eurordis.org/news/official-rare-disease-day-2017-video-out-now&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2008 in Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rarediseases.org/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2009 in the US&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the last day of February is marked as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rarediseaseday.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rare Disease Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In less than 10 years, Rare Disease Day (and #RareDiseaseDay) has grown from a centralized effort to bring attention to these disorders by patient organizations in Europe to an international awareness and action day that includes patients, legislators, research funders, scientists and clinicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that 350 million people worldwide suffer from rare diseases, defined regionally according to prevalence. In the European Union a rare disease is one that affects less than 1 in 2,000 patients while in the United Kingdom the qualification is less than 50,000 patients and in the United States the classification is less than 200,000 patients. Regardless, rare diseases usually have a genetic basis and are frequently progressive, disabling and with time, life-threatening. There are currently more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://globalgenes.org/rare-diseases-facts-statistics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7,000 different types of rare diseases and disorders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, according to the rare disease patient advocacy organization Global Genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those interested in general concepts related to rare disease and treatments or drug development can look to recent PLOS articles covering “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0170365&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clinical Practice Guidelines for Rare Diseases: The Orphanet Database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,” “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0164681&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Profitability and Market Value of Orphan Drug Companies: A Retrospective, Propensity-Matched Case-Control Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;” and “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0140002&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Access to Orphan Drugs: A Comprehensive Review of Legislations, Regulations and Policies in 35 Countries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rarediseaseday.org/page/news/2017-theme-research&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theme of Rare Disease Day 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with the slogan “&lt;strong&gt;With research, possibilities are limitless.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research published in PLOS journals is a testament to the dedication of scientists working on these diseases that often have less funding and attention than other biomedical issues, and the willingness of these scientists to go beyond publishing Open Access to make their data available for the rare disease community is critical to accelerate a path forward to uncover treatments and cures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWM1bn9e4KU&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rare Disease Day Sharing Data&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-7367 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;151&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/02/Rare-Disease-Day-Sharing-Data-300x151.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Image Credit: MyGene2.org; video frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, one of this year’s finalists for the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openscienceprize.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Open Science Prize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, given for unique insights developed from shared data, is described in this video “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWM1bn9e4KU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MyGene2: Accelerating Gene Discovery with Radically Open Data Sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.” Researchers at the University of Washington created the web portal MyGene2 as a place for people with rare genetic mutations to connect with others that share the condition and with researchers interested in their particular mutation. Michael Bamshad, PLOS author and professor and chief of the Division of Genetic Medicine in the Department of Pediatrics at the University of Washington &amp;amp; Seattle Children’s Hospital, describes this Open Science resource in a RARECast podcast interview, “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/rarecast/helping-patients-with-the-same-undiagnosed-genetic-condition-find-each-other&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Helping Patients with the Same Undiagnosed Genetic Condition Find Each Other&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.” Research from Bamshad’s group also includes &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; articles on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/authors?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0065834&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;implications of fine-scale patterns of population ancestry on rare variant genome-wide association studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0024745&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;genetic variation and risk for symptomatic West Nile Virus infection and disease progression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt; article discussing &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1005963&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mutations and a rare-disease inheritance model applied to congenital heart disease&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to data sharing, opportunities to improve diagnoses stem from genetic sequencing advances, as described in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1006081&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;improving the identification of cancer-associated genes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0146040&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;co-occurrence of rare diseases and resolution of a complex phenotype by next-gen sequencing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rare Disease Day is a chance to draw attention to the research and policies needed to advance understanding of these disorders that challenge the lives of so many. This year’s theme, “with research, possibilities are limitless” meshes well with the community PLOS serves as a science, technology and medicine Open Access publisher. A small sample of new research on rare diseases from PLOS authors is highlighted below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friedreich’s Ataxia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0165788&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Disruption of Higher Order DNA Structures in Friedreich’s Ataxia (GAA)n Repeats by PNA or LNA Targeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0153574&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lymphoblast Oxidative Stress Genes as Potential Biomarkers of Disease Severity and Drug Effect in Friedreich’s Ataxia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0062807&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stem Cells from Wildtype and Friedreich’s Ataxia Mice Present Similar Neuroprotective Properties in Dorsal Root Ganglia Cells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Progeria&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1005231&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Myopathic Lamin Mutations Cause Reductive Stress and Activate the Nrf2/Keap-1 Pathway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0169189&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Novel Lamin A Mutant Responsible for Congenital Muscular Dystrophy Causes Distinct Abnormalities of the Cell Nucleus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0001269&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Mutant Form of Lamin A that Causes Hutchinson-Gilford Progeria Is a Biomarker of Cellular Aging in Human Skin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaucher’s disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1005944&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Glucocerebrosidase Deficiency in Drosophila Results in α-Synuclein-Independent Protein Aggregation and Neurodegeneration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitochondrial diseases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1005779&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MPV17 Loss Causes Deoxynucleotide Insufficiency and Slow DNA Replication in Mitochondria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0148709&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GDF-15 Is Elevated in Children with Mitochondrial Diseases and Is Induced by Mitochondrial Dysfunction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/LI2hhBWFtk0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Why requesters love Sourcing Manager &amp; neuroscientist, Zev Wisotsky</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1032</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/02/meet_zev/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;At Science Exchange, our Masters’ and Ph.D.-level sourcing managers will help you find the right service provider for your project. Based on glowing customer testimonials, we know that our sourcing managers are one of our company’s greatest assets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Let’s get to know them better! We’ll start with customers’ favorite, Zev Wisotsky. Trained in neuroscience, he devoted his graduate research to studying taste detection in insects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zev&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1033 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Zev-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We love working with you, you are amazing…Thanks for everything you do.”&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;— &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Researcher at Gilead Sciences, to Zev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured Sourcing Manager:&lt;/strong&gt; Zev Wisotsky, Ph.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expertise: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Neuroscience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why requesters keep coming back to him: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Zev embodies excellence in customer service. That rare combination of empathy, patience, dedication, and hyper-organization comes together in Zev, seasoned with a dash of effortless communication and a sauce of good humor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;One request he is proud of being able to source: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Zev is particularly proud to have once located some difficult-to-find tuberculosis blood and peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) samples for a client that was not able to find them. This allowed our client to further their research. They were also excited to be able to start their project quickly once they joined Science Exchange.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How he solved one tough sourcing challenge: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;There was one overseas shipping error where Zev was able to coordinate with the client and service provider to fix and reship samples with minimal extraneous costs and time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experience (education and/or prior roles): &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Zev graduated from University of California Riverside with a degree in Neuroscience, investigating and characterizing the cellular mechanisms involved in taste detection using fruit fly and mosquito. He then completed postdoctoral research at Stanford investigating the role of brain regions involved in fear memory and addiction through silencing different brain circuits optogenetically.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Likes: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bicycling, singing and playing music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dislikes: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Traffic and stale cake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;So…. do flies like beer or water? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The answer is in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2011/11/25/142708527/beer-or-water-for-flies-that-s-an-easy-choice&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;NPR article about Zev’s research!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 19:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Coauthor’s past misconduct prompts dep’t chair to retract Diabetes study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48463</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/27/coauthors-past-misconduct-prompts-dept-chair-retract-diabetes-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A department chair of a Swedish university asked to retract a 2010 study in Diabetes after none of the authors could explain image-related ambiguities. The matter prompted particular attention because the paper’s first author, Pontus Almer Boström, had been found guilty of scientific misconduct by the University of Gothenburg in 2012, after Jan Borén noted some irregularities in […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/27/coauthors-past-misconduct-prompts-dept-chair-retract-diabetes-study/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Coauthor’s past misconduct prompts dep’t chair to retract Diabetes study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 17:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Bacteria genes offer new strategy for sterilizing mosquitoes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bacteria-genes-offer-new-strategy-sterilizing-mosquitoes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bacteria-genes-offer-new-strategy-sterilizing-mosquitoes</link>
	<description>Two genes in Wolbachia bacteria could be used to sterilize mosquitoes that transmit Zika.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022717_EE_wolbachia_main.jpg?itok=AAb2x1d3" length="16202" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Eating disorders: the importance of early intervention</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8605</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/27/eating-disorders-importance-early-intervention/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Courtney Emery, Flickr CC&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/5523425885_0900138aae_b-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eating disorders (EDs) are severe mental illnesses with a complex and largely unknown etiology. EDs encompass a variety of disorders, including anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa, and binge eating disorder. Anorexia nervosa is characterized by self-starving, intense fear of gaining weight and disturbance in self perceived weight or shape. Patients with bulimia nervosa suffer from recurrent binge-eating episodes (the consumption of abnormally large amounts of food in a relatively short period of time) with a sense of loss of control, followed by feelings of guilt and shame, which leads the person to compensatory behaviors (self-induced vomiting, over-exercising, use of laxatives or diuretics). These patients usually maintain normal weight, unlike anorexic ones. Binge eating disorder is characterized by eating excessive amounts of food, often when not hungry, without the compensatory behaviors of bulimia nervosa. As a result, patients are often overweight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8608&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;BEAT - https://www.b-eat.co.uk/&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-8608&quot; height=&quot;94&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/EDAW_17_original-small-300x94.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.b-eat.co.uk/&quot;&gt;beat – beating eating disorders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aetiology of these disorders appears to be multifactorial: genetic, biological, socio-cultural, and psychological factors can contribute to their development and maintenance. The course of EDs is often relapsing and in a substantial proportion of cases protracted with a treatment-resistant disorder sometimes occurring. EDs are severe illnesses for a number of reasons: mortality is high, risk of suicidality is high, quality of life is poor, short- and long-term organic consequences strongly impact patients’ lives, and psychiatric comorbidity (mostly depression, anxiety, and personality disorders) is endemic to sufferers. As a result, EDs tend to appear as a treatment conundrum; although research is proposing interesting novel treatment approaches with encouraging results. Treatments are challenging mostly for anorexia nervosa: no current medications are able to reverse the core symptoms which exist, and long and costly hospitalizations are frequently needed. Duration of illness is a relevant factor in treatment response; adolescents with anorexia nervosa seem to benefit more from outpatient treatments than adults do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This said, it is key to recognize ED symptoms as soon as possible because an early intervention could be crucial with respect to treatment response and outcome. If EDs are caught in time, treatments can be decisive to change their course and to reduce the risk of stigma, complications, and death. Primary prevention is fundamental, potentially involving families, teachers and personal trainers, to name just a few. Know what to look for – Weight loss, refusal to eat certain foods, anxiety about gaining weight or being “fat”, excessive and rigid exercise regimens are fundamental first signs of an eating disorder that can be recognized early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8609&quot; style=&quot;width: 1060px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;beat&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8609 size-full&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Untitledsmall.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.b-eat.co.uk/&quot;&gt;beat – beating eating disorders &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more …. catch up on &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/sections/eating-disorders&quot;&gt;latest Eating disorders articles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/27/eating-disorders-importance-early-intervention/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Eating disorders: the importance of early intervention&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 15:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/5523425885_0900138aae_b-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
