<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Former VA postdoc committed misconduct, banned from agency research for four years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=69021</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/24/former-va-postdoc-committed-misconduct-banned-from-agency-research-for-four-years/</link>
	<description>A former postdoc at the U.S. VA Health Care System in Albuquerque, N.M., committed misconduct in three papers, the agency announced today. Alba Chavez-Dozal, who studied the basic science underpinnings of infectious diseases, had three papers retracted between 2015 and 2016. In findings dated July 18, 2018, but released today, the VA said that Chavez-Dozal, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/24/former-va-postdoc-committed-misconduct-banned-from-agency-research-for-four-years/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Former VA postdoc committed misconduct, banned from agency research for four years&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 16:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Balancing expectation and reality: intervention fidelity, trauma, and women with histories of incarceration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10391</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/24/balancing-expectation-and-reality-intervention-fidelity-trauma-and-women-with-histories-of-incarceration/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/AdobeStock_79346044-3-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ajot.aota.org/article.aspx?articleid=1851585&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research concept of fidelity&lt;/a&gt;  is a critical component for any health intervention holding itself to a high standard. In terms of the scientific method, this means we want to ensure that when we deliver any kind of intervention, that we replicate it as close to the same way each time, with each group, with minimal variation. Yet, this assumption of fidelity also means an assumption of a certain kind of audience that receives interventions – one that is predictable. An audience without trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kumc.edu/she&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sexual Health Empowerment (SHE) project&lt;/a&gt;, we worked directly with close to 200 women with histories of incarceration to deliver a cervical health promotion intervention.  The SHE team has had years of experience working with women both in and outside of jails. Critical for our work is the constant awareness of the trauma the women we serve bring into the room. From sexual and domestic violence to drug addiction and homelessness, women with histories of incarceration are statistically more likely than most populations to have histories of extensive trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One study suggests as many as 86 percent of women in prison have been sexually assaulted. Three quarters of women who have been incarcerated have also been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.correctionalassociation.org/issue/domestic-violence&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;abused by an intimate partner&lt;/a&gt;. This doesn’t even take into account the trauma and abuse that can occur once women actually enter incarceration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, health educators delivering interventions with women in the criminal justice system must be able to address the unique dynamics of any group and the individuals in these groups, responding in real time to any needs that arise during intervention delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, our staff were all trained in emotional grounding techniques that help women move from a state of heightened high emotion to one of calmness.  We employed these techniques regularly during intervention delivery, when conversations got heated, when participants got upset, or when we all needed comfort.  We were prepared to answer any manner of questions and we were lucky to have clinicians (nursing students and faculty) present during the intervention sessions to answer questions about complicated, real-time health needs. In SHE, we worked from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211335517300669&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;manualized intervention&lt;/a&gt;, yet had to be flexible in order to address the women’s needs and questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The health educators delivering the intervention always had to keep the sessions moving, … building rapport, and delivering intervention content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did this in the highly structured and simultaneously chaotic environment of a county jail. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0617-x?utm_source=BMC_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=Blog&amp;amp;utm_content=DavFal-BMC-BMC_Women%27s_Health-Public_Health-Global&amp;amp;utm_campaign=BMCS_USG_JULY2018_intervention_fidelity&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In our article on intervention fidelity in jails&lt;/a&gt;, we highlight both the nature of women’s questions and the jail itself as challenges to fidelity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were obligated to work with the rules of the jail facility as a condition of being granted access. Such access necessitated flexibility on our parts, working with correctional officers present in the room during private discussions about health, or stopping the intervention if events like lockdowns at the jail precluded our ability to continue. We also had to work around the loss of participants to events within the criminal justice process such as court hearings and disciplinary procedures, or in some cases real-time medical care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some days there was a constant movement of people in and out of the session, as we described in our fidelity fieldnotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; “At different points during the session, a male guard, a woman who looked like an administrator type, and two nurses entered. Our women were also up and moving around throughout the session—heating coffee in the microwave, getting water—all while our facilitator was talking. One woman disappeared during a bathroom break. We don’t know where she went or why she didn’t return. Two other women went to the desk and visited with the nurses in the middle of the session: one of them had her blood pressure checked. The other seemed to be having something on her foot examined.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The health educators delivering the intervention always had to keep the sessions moving, while sensing the feelings of participants and others in the room, protecting confidentiality, building rapport, and delivering intervention content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jails, like many community settings, are imperfect environments for fidelity in intervention delivery.  Yet the women who move through jails have extremely high health needs, and therefore bear the burden of significant physical and mental health disparities, making intervention delivery in these settings and for these populations highly necessary.  But delivery of interventions must be considered in the context of everyday realities and therefore realistic expectations for fidelity must be set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/24/balancing-expectation-and-reality-intervention-fidelity-trauma-and-women-with-histories-of-incarceration/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Balancing expectation and reality: intervention fidelity, trauma, and women with histories of incarceration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 13:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/AdobeStock_79346044-3-1-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: 2018/19 Ryerson University Library and Archives OER Grants | Ryerson University Library &amp; Archives</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://library.ryerson.ca/blog/2018/07/2018-19-ryerson-university-library-and-archives-oer-grants/</guid>
	<link>https://library.ryerson.ca/blog/2018/07/2018-19-ryerson-university-library-and-archives-oer-grants/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Ryerson University Library and Archives (RULA) is pleased to announce its 2018/19 RULA Open Educational Resources (OER) Grants to encourage the creation and adoption of open educational resources. OER are learning materials that are openly licensed such that they are freely available to be adapted, copied, and shared. OER can be: courses, modules, textbooks, multimedia, assessments, and supplementary materials.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OER shown to improve grades, not just cut costs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://edscoop.com/oer-shown-to-improve-grades-university-of-georgia-report</guid>
	<link>https://edscoop.com/oer-shown-to-improve-grades-university-of-georgia-report</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;A University of Georgia study found that open educational resources improved end-of-course grades for undergraduates and lowered D, F and withdrawal rates.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “[T]he data and findings…are unreliable:” Authors explain how a refutation came to be published in the same journal as the original</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68925</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/24/the-data-and-findings-are-unreliable-authors-explain-how-a-refutation-came-to-be-published-in-the-same-journal-as-the-original/</link>
	<description>A group of tiny, all-female animals called bdelloid rotifers has long fascinated scientists. Among other questions, of course, is: Why haven’t they gone extinct, if they can’t mix up their genes? In 2016, a group of authors published a paper in Current Biology claiming to show that rotifers could swap DNA the way bacteria do. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/24/the-data-and-findings-are-unreliable-authors-explain-how-a-refutation-came-to-be-published-in-the-same-journal-as-the-original/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;“[T]he data and findings…are unreliable:” Authors explain how a refutation came to be published in the same journal as the original&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Planck satellite’s picture of the infant universe gets its last tweaks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/planck-satellite-picture-infant-universe-gets-final-tweaks</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/planck-satellite-picture-infant-universe-gets-final-tweaks</link>
	<description>Scientists have released the last big result from the cosmic microwave background experiment Planck.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/072018_EC_planck_feat.jpg?itok=47bx0T-H" length="59545" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: How do we know Unpaywall won't be acquired? - Impactstory blog</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.impactstory.org/independent/</guid>
	<link>http://blog.impactstory.org/independent/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;We’re often asked: How do we know Unpaywall won’t be acquired?  What makes Unpaywall (and the company behind it, Impactstory) different than Bepress, SSRN, Mendeley, Publons, Kopernio, etc?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Impact of Social Sciences – A variety of strategies and funding approaches are required to accelerate the transition to open access. But in all, authors are key</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2018/07/23/a-variety-of-strategies-and-funding-approaches-are-required-to-accelerate-the-transition-to-open-access-but-in-all-authors-are-key/</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2018/07/23/a-variety-of-strategies-and-funding-approaches-are-required-to-accelerate-the-transition-to-open-access-but-in-all-authors-are-key/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;More than two decades of work towards liberating scholarly publishing from paywalled constraints has left many within the scholarly community exploring ways to accelerate the transition to open access. Not all institutions or author communities will agree upon which strategies or funding approaches to undertake, and nor do they need to. But whichever strategy is pursued, having university faculty lead the charge represents the most effective way forward. Rachael G. Samberg, Richard A. Schneider, Ivy Anderson and Jeff MacKie-Mason share the University of California’s range of open access policy and advocacy materials, and highlight some potential next steps that may be of use to faculty and author communities.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Paleontologists have ID’d the world’s biggest known dinosaur foot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/paleontologists-identify-worlds-biggest-known-dinosaur-foot</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/paleontologists-identify-worlds-biggest-known-dinosaur-foot</link>
	<description>Bigfoot has been found in Wyoming. It’s not a hairy, apelike creature; it’s a dinosaur.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/072318_CM_bigfoot-dinosaur_feat.jpg?itok=8cy9yUO1" length="12160" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Higher ed and Wikipedia go great together / Boing Boing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://boingboing.net/2018/07/23/wikinost.html</guid>
	<link>https://boingboing.net/2018/07/23/wikinost.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Chronicle of Higher Education profiles LiAnna Davis, Wikipedia Education's director, who forges alliance with colleges and their faculty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educators have long had a fraught relationship with Wikipedia: a combination of the encyclopedia's willingness to accept claims of expertise without citations to facts; as well as lazy students' propensity for copying out of the encyclopedia and failing to follow references; along with confusion about whether a world-editable encyclopedia could be a reliable source all conspired to make some academics queasy and mistrustful.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 10:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Call for Peer Reviewers: Open Textbooks Pilot Program (deadline 8/6/18) | LINCS Community</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.lincs.ed.gov/bulletin/call-peer-reviewers-open-textbooks-pilot-program-deadline-8618</guid>
	<link>https://community.lincs.ed.gov/bulletin/call-peer-reviewers-open-textbooks-pilot-program-deadline-8618</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The U.S. Department of Education, Office of Postsecondary Education, is seeking peer reviewers to read and evaluate discretionary grant applications for the Open Textbooks Pilot program.  This pilot program supports projects at institutions of higher education (IHEs) that create new open textbooks or expand the use of open textbooks while maintaining or improving instruction and student learning outcomes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open Science - Documentos de Google</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1F9DOYM2zd4rnUYuM7tEdD6opacSCR5gzZcWmF0qZjig/edit</guid>
	<link>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1F9DOYM2zd4rnUYuM7tEdD6opacSCR5gzZcWmF0qZjig/edit</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;span&gt;We drafted commitments for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.canada.ca/en/4plan/creating-canadas-4th-plan-open-government-2018-20&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Canada’s 2018-20 National Action Plan on Open Government&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, and we’d like your feedback. We want to hear if you think we got it right, as well as your ideas on how we could strengthen the plan. You can provide your feedback until August 13, 2018.&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 09:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: COS Blog: Using OSF in the Lab</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://cos.io/blog/using-osf-lab/</guid>
	<link>https://cos.io/blog/using-osf-lab/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;One of the challenges in shifting to more open research practices is finding examples to give you an idea of where to start. To address this challenge we are introducing a new series of example projects meant to illustrate some of OSF's capabilities and to collect tips and tricks from researchers in different fields.  The first of these is the OSF Example Lab project that demonstrates how researchers from multiple fields are using OSF to tie together and organize entire labs.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: First survey of its kind for 50 years finds most Americans still think they have above average intelligence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34314</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/24/first-survey-of-its-kind-for-50-years-finds-most-americans-still-think-they-have-above-average-intelligence/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34315&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-517465807.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34315&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34315&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;10&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A nerdy looking guy contemplates his next move.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1412892862&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;benstevens&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;24&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Studious young man ponders intently&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Studious young man ponders intently&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-517465807.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-517465807.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-517465807.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/24/first-survey-of-its-kind-for-50-years-finds-most-americans-still-think-they-have-above-average-intelligence/studious-young-man-ponders-intently/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-517465807.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;“… the least intelligent tend to be the most overconfident”&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A systematic survey in the US of people’s beliefs about their own intelligence – the first for 50 years – has shown that was true then is also the case in the modern era: a majority of people think they are smarter than average.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, led by Patrick Heck from the Geisinger Health System and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0200103&quot;&gt;published in PLOS One&lt;/a&gt;, combined an online survey and phone survey, with each involving 750 people reflecting a cross-section of the US population, balanced in terms of sex, age, education levels and race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across both surveys, 65 per cent of participants agreed with the statement “I am more intelligent than the average person.” Around 70 per cent of men versus 60 per cent of women made the above-average claim, and a similar pattern was found in the young and old. There were also no clear racial differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research accords with both the half-century old study from the Russell Sage Foundation, and more recent research that suggests there is an overconfidence bias in the general population. The trouble is that most of the work following the Foundation’s study has often come from self-selecting or convenience samples that are unlikely to be representative of the wider population, or from students, who may be special cases, struggling, for instance, to envisage what the average person is like from their campus existence.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new surveys also validate another cornerstone of overconfidence research: that the least intelligent tend to be the most overconfident. While university graduates (who are typically one standard deviation higher than average in intelligence) collectively tended to slightly underestimate their intelligence, those participants whose highest qualification was a high school diploma collectively over-shot in estimating theirs. Heck’s team conclude “that American’s self-flattering beliefs about intelligence are alive and well several decades after their discovery was first reported.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0200103&quot;&gt;65% of Americans believe they are above average in intelligence: Results of two nationally representative surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 08:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Pediatricians warn against chemical additives in food for kids</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pediatricians-warn-against-chemical-additives-food-kids</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pediatricians-warn-against-chemical-additives-food-kids</link>
	<description>Common food additives found in meats, plastic packaging or metal cans may contain chemicals that harm children’s health.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 22:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/072318_LR_pediatric-chemicals_feat.jpg?itok=_9MAEZNU" length="42966" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: From green to gold to diamond: open access’s return to social justice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://library.ifla.org/2220/1/092-raju-en.pdf</guid>
	<link>http://library.ifla.org/2220/1/092-raju-en.pdf</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This paper will be presented at IFLA WLIC 2018 in August 2018. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open access movement is underpinned by a philanthropic purpose of sharing research output for the betterment of society. In rolling out this noble cause, social justice imperative located within the movement was destined to disrupt the current publishing model. From its fledgling stages ‘foundationalised’ by the green route via institutional repositories, the open access movement has grown to include the gold route and now it can boast the diamond route. The ‘library as a publisher’ service brings to the fore and consolidates the social justice imperative of open access. Researchers, in this growing service model, are supported by their desire to share their research output for the growth of research and to find solutions to the myriad of challenges that beset society. Diamond open access publishing, which is the focus of this paper, itself is slowly gaining traction making libraries distinctive drivers of open access. The University of Cape Town Libraries is an exemplar of an academic library that is offering a diamond open journal and monograph publishing service. The driver of the Libraries’ ‘library as a publisher’ service is the return to the social justice imperatives of open access. In rolling-out its ‘library as a publisher’ service, UCT Libraries provides a service that makes content easily accessible to African researchers, addressing African challenges. The service provided returns to the core principles of open access, that is, sharing content for the betterment of society. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 18:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: How the Brain Perceives Colors?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23848</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/07/23/how-the-brain-perceives-colors/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Color vision is the ability to distinguish different wavelengths of electromagnetic radiation. Color vision relies on a brain perception mechanism that treats light with different wavelengths as different visual stimuli (e.g., colors). Usual color insensitive photoreceptors (the rods in human eyes) only react to the presence or absence of light and do not distinguish between specific wavelengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can argue that colors are not real—they are “synthesized” by our brain to distinguish light with different wavelengths. While rods give us the ability to detect the presence and intensity of light (and thus allow our brain to construct the picture of the world around us), specific detection of different wavelengths through independent channels gives our view of the world additional high resolution. For instance, red and green colors look like near identical shades of grey in black and white photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An animal with black and white vision alone won’t be able to make a distinction between, let’s say, a green and red apple, and won’t know which one tastes better before trying them both based on color. Evolutionary biologists believe that human ancestors developed color vision to facilitate the identification of ripe fruits, which would obviously provide an advantage in the competitive natural world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why certain wavelengths are paired with certain colors remains a mystery. Technically, color is an illusion created by our brain. Therefore, it is not clear if other animals see colors the same way we see them. It is likely that, due to shared evolutionary history, other vertebrates see the world colored similarly to how we see it. But color vision is quite common across the vast animal kingdom: insects, arachnids, and cephalopods are able to distinguish colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of colors do these animals see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human color vision relies on three photoreceptors that detect primary colors—red, green, and blue. However, some people lack red photoreceptors (they are “bichromates”) or have an additional photoreceptor that detects somewhere between red and green colors (“tetrachromates”). Obviously, having only 3 photoreceptors doesn’t limit our ability to distinguish other colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each photoreceptor can absorb a rather broad range of wavelengths of light. To distinguish a specific color, the brain compares and quantitatively analyses the data from all three photoreceptors. And our brain does this remarkably successfully—some research indicates that we can distinguish colors that correspond to wavelength differences of just 1 nanometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scheme works in largely the same way in most higher vertebrate animals that have color vision. Although the ability to distinguish between specific shades varies significantly between the species, with humans having one of the best color distinguishing abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, invertebrates that have developed color vision (and vision in general) completely independently from us demonstrate remarkably different approaches to color detection and processing. These animals can have a exceptionally large number of color receptors. The mantis shrimp, for instance, has 12 different types of photoreceptors. The common bluebottle butterfly has even more—15 receptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it mean that these animals can see additional colors unimaginable to us? Perhaps yes. Some of their photoreceptors operate in a rather narrow region of light spectrum. For instance, they can have 4-5 photoreceptors sensitive in the green region of the visual spectrum. This means that for these animals the different shades of green may appear as different as blue and red colors appear to our eyes! Again, the evolutionary advantages of such adaptations are obvious for an animal living among the trees and grasses where most objects, as we see them, are colored in various shades of green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers tried to test if a more complicated set of visual receptors provide any advantages for animals when it comes to the distinguishing between main colors. The findings show that this is not necessarily the case, at least not for the mantis shrimp. Despite the impressive array of receptors detecting light in a much broader part of the electromagnetic spectrum compared to humans, the shrimp’s ability to distinguish between colors that great in comparison to us. However, they determine the colors fast. This is probably more important for practical purposes, as mantis shrimps are predators. A large number of photoreceptors allows for their quick activation at specific wavelengths of light and thus communicate directly to the brain what specific wavelength was detected. In comparison, humans have to assess and quantify the signals from all three photoreceptors to decide on a specific color. This requires more time and energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from employing a different number of photoreceptors to sense light of specific wavelengths, some animals can detect light that we humans are completely unable to see. For example, many birds and insects can see in the UV part of the spectrum. Bumblebees, for instance, have three photoreceptors absorbing in the UV, blue, and green regions of the spectrum. This makes them trichromates, like humans, but with the spectral sensitivity shifted to the blue end of the spectrum. The ability to detect UV light explains why some flowers have patterns visible only in this part of the spectrum. These patterns attract pollinating insects, which have an ability to see in this spectral region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of animals can detect infrared light (the long wavelength radiation) emitted by heated objects and bodies. This ability significantly facilitates hunting for snakes that are usually looking for small warm-blooded prey. Seeing them through IR detecting receptors is, thus, a great tool for slow-moving reptiles. The photoreceptors sensitive to IR radiation in snakes are located not in their eye but in “pit organs” located between the eyes and nostrils. The result is still the same: snakes can color objects according to their surface temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this brief article shows, we humans can see and analyze only a small portion of the visual information available to other creatures. Next time you see a humble fly, think about how different it perceives the same things you are both looking at!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skorupski P, Chittka L (2010) Photoreceptor Spectral Sensitivity in the Bumblebee, &lt;em&gt;Bombus impatiens&lt;/em&gt; (Hymenoptera: Apidae). PLoS ONE 5(8): e12049. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0012049&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0012049&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoen HH, How MJ, Chiou TH, Marshall J. (2014) A different form of color vision in mantis shrimp. Science 343(6169):411-3. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.1245824&quot;&gt;10.1126/science.1245824&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen P-J, Awata H, Matsushita A, Yang E-C and Arikawa K (2016) Extreme Spectral Richness in the Eye of the Common Bluebottle Butterfly, &lt;em&gt;Graphium sarpedon&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Front. Ecol. Evol&lt;/em&gt;. 4:18. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fevo.2016.00018&quot;&gt;10.3389/fevo.2016.00018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arikawa, K., Iwanaga, T., Wakakuwa, M., &amp;amp; Kinoshita, M. (2017) Unique Temporal Expression of Triplicated Long-Wavelength Opsins in Developing Butterfly Eyes. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Neural Circuits&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;11&lt;/em&gt;, 96. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.3389/fncir.2017.00096&quot;&gt;10.3389/fncir.2017.00096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: https://pixabay.com/en/butterfly-3d-blue-mushroom-forest-2049567/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new kind of spray is loaded with microscopic electronic sensors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-kind-spray-loaded-microscopic-electronic-sensors</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-kind-spray-loaded-microscopic-electronic-sensors</link>
	<description>For the first time, researchers have built circuits on microscopic chips that can be mixed into an aerosol spray.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071918_MT_aerosol-electronics_feat.jpg?itok=jVxs3R6r" length="9322" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: China's new research rules will shackle Xi's innovation drive - Nikkei Asian Review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/China-s-new-research-rules-will-shackle-Xi-s-innovation-drive</guid>
	<link>https://asia.nikkei.com/Opinion/China-s-new-research-rules-will-shackle-Xi-s-innovation-drive</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The State Council's measures also imply an ambivalence to publishing in prestigious international journals. One leading Chinese newspaper recently noted that for scientists to publish their results in journals such as Nature, Science or Cell, they will have to submit primary research data to enable the replication of their findings and prevent falsification and fraud -- a type of sharing discouraged under the new rules.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: China is restricting the export of science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://plus.google.com/u/0/+PeterSuber/posts/fCnMr6Bf5uj</guid>
	<link>https://plus.google.com/u/0/+PeterSuber/posts/fCnMr6Bf5uj</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;From Yojana Sharma in University World News (July 20, 2018): 'China’s new regulations restricting the ‘export’ of scientific data collected within the country and asserting that any research for publication in international journals must first be approved by a new, yet to be set up authority, are causing uncertainty and concern for many researchers who are working in collaboration with China.' ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before Americans pile on, as if this kind of blunder could never occur in a country with a constitutional right to freedom of the press, recall a similar move by the George W. Bush administration during the height of paranoia after the 9/11 attacks....&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Court orders journal to retract a paper after supplement seller sues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68771</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/23/journal-flags-fertility-paper-after-company-wins-court-order/</link>
	<description>An Italian court has ordered a journal to retract a paper. But it hasn’t just yet. Instead, the Journal of Ovarian Research has published an expression of concern about the 2012 paper, replete with obfuscating legal language. Here’s the text: Pursuant to a decree of the Tribunal of Catania, First Civil Section, LJ Pharma SRL … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/23/journal-flags-fertility-paper-after-company-wins-court-order/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Court orders journal to retract a paper after supplement seller sues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open Access in the Field of Cultural Studies: The Performance and Prospects of Open Cultural Studies – OpenCulture</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://oc.hypotheses.org/1173</guid>
	<link>https://oc.hypotheses.org/1173</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Prof. Toby Miller, the Editor-in-Chief of Open Cultural Studies, discusses how this Open Access, per-review journal has evolved since its launch, its positioning as a mega-journal in its academic field and its prospects in the years to come.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Possible business models for the OA journals from the small scientific communities | Zenodo</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1311954</guid>
	<link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.1311954</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Discussing possible business models of OA journals without Article Processing Charges (APC).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: The ‘blessing’ of a diagnosis: Information poverty in an information-rich world</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/partners-in-health-canada-spark/the-blessing-of-a-diagnosis-information-poverty-in-an-information-rich-world-a67c42bf5d40</guid>
	<link>https://medium.com/partners-in-health-canada-spark/the-blessing-of-a-diagnosis-information-poverty-in-an-information-rich-world-a67c42bf5d40</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Information poverty refers to the inability to access information as a result of not having the required skills or materials. These deficits may occur due to a lack of information (e.g. no national resources on cancer) or a poor information infrastructure (e.g. no access to the internet).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open science in Europe: from principles to practice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@osimod/open-science-in-europe-from-principles-to-practice-71961fe80d00</guid>
	<link>https://medium.com/@osimod/open-science-in-europe-from-principles-to-practice-71961fe80d00</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;It is clear that today, open science is no longer the far-fetched objective of a few evangelists, but a challenge for all stakeholders. Both public and private funders are increasingly adopting open access and open data frameworks.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: UB research lab studies how university courses can be more ‘open’ - UB Now: News and views for UB faculty and staff - University at Buffalo</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.buffalo.edu/ubnow/stories/2018/07/open-educational-resources.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.buffalo.edu/ubnow/stories/2018/07/open-educational-resources.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Graduate School of Education has joined the SUNY-wide effort to reduce the costs of higher education by launching an Open Education Research Lab dedicated to replacing high-priced textbooks and other costly materials by studying the use of open or free educational materials that can be downloaded, edited or shared&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Was tun, wenn der DEAL nicht kommt? - JuSER</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://juser.fz-juelich.de/record/844792</guid>
	<link>http://juser.fz-juelich.de/record/844792</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): What to do if the DEAL does not come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Abstract: In Übereinstimmung mit den Zielen von OA2020, der Open-Access-Richtlinie der Helmholtz-Gemeinschaft und der eigenen Open Access-Strategie strebtdas Forschungszentrum Jülich (FZJ) die Transformation des Publikationswesens in den Open Access an. Der Abschluss von DEAL-Verträgen wäre dafür einwichtiger Schritt, [...]&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;Abstract: In accordance with the goals of OA2020, the Helmholtz Association's Open Access Policy and its own open access strategy, Forschungszentrum Jülich (FZJ) is aiming to transform publishing from open access. The conclusion of DEAL contracts would be an important step in this [...]&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: How FOAM is revolutionizing medical education –  | dcook4real</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://dcook4real.wordpress.com/2018/07/22/how-foam-is-revolutionizing-medical-education/</guid>
	<link>https://dcook4real.wordpress.com/2018/07/22/how-foam-is-revolutionizing-medical-education/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Both Thoma and CanadiEM are leaders in a movement called FOAM, or FOAMed: free open access medical education. The term refers to any free educational material about medicine on the Internet, and includes thousands of online resources: blogs, podcasts, videos—even Wikipedia might count as FOAM. It allows anyone to publicly weigh in on new research or share their clinical wisdom, and makes reams of information available to an audience that may never have otherwise had access to it. To some extent, FOAM is disrupting the nature and hierarchy of medical education, a change that people find both exciting and worrisome&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: New data red tape could hamper international research - University World News</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.universityworldnews.com/article.php?story=20180720072113906</guid>
	<link>http://www.universityworldnews.com/article.php?story=20180720072113906</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;China’s new regulations restricting the ‘export’ of scientific data collected within the country and asserting that any research for publication in international journals must first be approved by a new, yet to be set up authority, are causing uncertainty and concern for many researchers who are working in collaboration with China.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: What would the plebs want with research literature?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://promotingoa.blogspot.com/2018/07/what-would-plebs-want-with-research.html</guid>
	<link>http://promotingoa.blogspot.com/2018/07/what-would-plebs-want-with-research.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;So today's topic shall be making information more accessible, and whether Open Access has a role to play. I was told in my PhD interview that this is an area of the established literature so lets see what we find.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The giant iceberg that broke from Antarctica’s Larsen C ice shelf is stuck</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-iceberg-broke-antarctica-larsen-c-ice-shelf-stuck</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-iceberg-broke-antarctica-larsen-c-ice-shelf-stuck</link>
	<description>A year ago, an iceberg calved off of the Larsen C ice shelf. The hunk of ice hasn’t moved much since, and that has scientists keeping an eye on it.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/072018_LR_larsen-c_feat.jpg?itok=3hdHA8ER" length="28296" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Systematic review: puberty suppressing drugs do not alleviate gender dysphoria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34271</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/23/systematic-review-puberty-suppressing-drugs-do-not-alleviate-gender-dysphoria/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-694909590.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34273&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34273&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Studio shot of young Asian transgender teenage boy against gray background horizontal shot&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Studio shot of young Asian transgender teenage boy against gray background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Studio shot of young Asian transgender teenage boy against gray background&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-694909590.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-694909590.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-694909590.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/23/systematic-review-puberty-suppressing-drugs-do-not-alleviate-gender-dysphoria/studio-shot-of-young-asian-transgender-teenage-boy-against-gray-background/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-694909590.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinicians treating teenagers with gender dysphoria, the teens themselves, and their parents, are faced with a dilemma – puberty suppressing drugs and hormonal treatments will likely make it easier for the adolescent to gender transition in due course, and the earlier that process begins, the more effective it is likely to be. However, intervening earlier comes with a greater risk that the teen may later de-transition (that is, change their mind about wanting to transition to the other gender), leaving them with potentially irreversible bodily changes caused by the hormonal treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/141/4/e20173742&quot;&gt;systematic review&lt;/a&gt; published recently in the journal &lt;em&gt;Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;, adding to this clinical dilemma is a dearth of quality data on the physical and psychosocial effects of hormonal treatments on gender dysphoric teenagers and young adults. The limited evidence that is available provides only “qualified support” for these treatments, the review concludes, and while puberty suppressors have some benefits, they do not actually alleviate gender dysphoria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34271&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings – based on an exhaustive search of any and all relevant studies published between 1946 and 2017 – are published at a time when the medical and allied professions have shifted toward an increasingly “affirmative” approach toward gender dysphoria, one that at the extreme involves encouraging the process of transition at the very first signs of the condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British Psychological Society’s own &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bps.org.uk/sites/default/files/images/rep_92.pdf&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; from 2012 propose offering “a series of [five] staged treatments”, to give time for the young person to consider their options, beginning with psychological exploration and escalating, if the dysphoria persists, to the use of puberty suppressing hormones and culminating in surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/102/11/3869/4157558&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; of the Endocrine Society (an International body based in Washington DC) are more affirmative: “We suggest that clinicians begin pubertal hormone suppression after girls and boys [diagnosed with gender dysphoria] first exhibit physical changes of puberty”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the new review reveals how this advice is based on extremely limited evidence. When it comes to teens and young adults aged under 25, we simply do not yet know much about the psychosocial effects of pubertal suppressors (including gonadotropin-releasing analogs which suppress the development of secondary sexual characteristics) and hormonal treatments (both gender-affirming hormones and cross-hormonal treatments, such as anti-androgens, which counter the effects of testosterone, and progestins, which suppress the menses).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denise Chew at the University of Melbourne and her colleagues identified only thirteen relevant studies, and most of these involved small samples, only two featured a control group, and none involved blinding or randomisation (the gold standard approach for medical trials).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limited evidence available suggests that these interventions are “relatively safe” in terms of their physical side-effects, although there is no long-term data (including potential adverse effects on fertility). Where short-term side-effects occur, these can include, among others, hot flushes, fatigue, weight gain and, most concerning, changes to bone mass density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puberty suppressors appear to be effective at having their intended physical effect – that is, preventing pubertal changes associated with the person’s sex assigned at birth. They also have emotional and behavioural benefits, such as reducing depression. Crucially, however, they do not alleviate gender dysphoria (one study even found a trend in the opposite direction and increased negative body image). The researchers said this is “probably not surprising” given that puberty suppressing drugs “cannot be expected to lessen the dislike of existing physical sex characteristics associated with an individual’s birth-assigned sex nor satisfy their desire for the physical sex characteristics of their preferred gender”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, gender affirming treatments and cross-hormonal treatments are successful, to a degree, in achieving the intended physical changes in line with the desired gender. However, these often do not match the hopes of the person with gender dysphoria – for instance, oestrogen led to a degree of breast growth that most of those treated found unsatisfactory. There are some cognitive effects to consider – for instance, after taking puberty suppressing drugs, teenagers born male but seeking to transition to female, subsequently showed poorer performance on tests of executive functioning and mental rotation. Perhaps most concerning – especially given &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/17/most-children-and-teens-with-gender-dysphoria-also-have-multiple-other-psychological-issues/&quot;&gt;the psychological vulnerability of many teens with gender dysphoria&lt;/a&gt; – there is simply no data on the psychosocial effects of these treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lack of data is in the context of a growing concern among some psychologists that the affirmative approach may have gone too far. For example, psychologist Dianne Berg, Co-Director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sexualhealth.umn.edu/national-center-gender-spectrum-health&quot;&gt;National Center for Gender Spectrum Health&lt;/a&gt; in the US (which advocates an affirmative approach), told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/07/when-a-child-says-shes-trans/561749/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recently “Under the motivation to be supportive and to be affirming and to be nonstigmatizing, I think the pendulum has swung so far that now we’re maybe not looking as critically at the issues as we should be.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One critical issue that has yet to be addressed by research at all, is what the effects are of hormonal treatments on teens who later de-transition. As of now, Chew and her team say there are “no known studies to date in which researchers have reported the rates and circumstances under which transgender youth cease their hormonal therapy in an unplanned manner or the risk of subsequent regret.” While the researchers say their review provides “qualified support” for the use of puberty suppressors and hormonal treatments, they conclude that more better quality and long-term research is essential, including data on the psychological effects of these interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://pediatrics.aappublications.org/content/141/4/e20173742&quot;&gt;Hormonal Treatment in Young People With Gender Dysphoria: A Systematic Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bps.org.uk/sites/default/files/images/rep_92.pdf&quot;&gt;BPS Guidelines and Literature Review for Psychologists Working Therapeutically with Sexual and Gender Minority Clients&lt;/a&gt; [pdf]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/gender-dysphoria/&quot;&gt;Gender dysphoria&lt;/a&gt; [Information from NHS Choices]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2018/07/when-a-child-says-shes-trans/561749/&quot;&gt;When Children Say They’re Trans&lt;/a&gt; [recent in-depth article in &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.childline.org.uk&quot;&gt;Childline&lt;/a&gt;  [support and guidance for children and young people aged under 19]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.samaritans.org&quot;&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; [support and guidance for anyone]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 08:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Tarantino &amp; Finelli: i plagiatori di Napoli</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=25557</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/23/tarantino-finelli-i-plagiatori-di-napoli/</link>
	<description>Plagiarism and self-plagiarism used to be an easy way for career advancement for many ruthless and entitled academics. It became a bit more difficult now, in the times of internet where automatic software can flush out a cheater in a matter of minutes. Provided of course, the scholarly publishers care about such things. And in … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/23/tarantino-finelli-i-plagiatori-di-napoli/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Tarantino &amp;amp; Finelli: i plagiatori di Napoli&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 05:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: &quot;Cluster Failure&quot;: fMRI False Positives Revisited</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9624</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9624</link>
	<description>Two years ago, a paper by Swedish neuroscientist Anders Eklund and colleagues caused a media storm. The paper, Cluster Failure, reported that the most widely used methods for the analysis of fMRI data are flawed and produce a high rate of false positives.



As I said at the time, Cluster Failure wasn't actually making especially new claims because Eklund et al. had been publishing quite similar results years earlier - but it wasn't until Cluster Failure that they attracted widespread attent</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 14:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open and Shut?: Falling prey to a predatory OA publisher: Individual failure or community problem?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882.post-8316705550031050526</guid>
	<link>https://poynder.blogspot.com/2018/07/falling-prey-to-predatory-oa-publisher.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Depending on whom you speak to, so-called predatory publishing is a serious threat to the scientific record, a minor irritant, or an elitist misunderstanding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin-right: 1em; text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-e1DOhbjosFc/W1HAvjOEXiI/AAAAAAAAeko/rQIG0hQaaSsCMBCvMI7q7wSskA3BdNyywCLcBGAs/s1600/512px-%25D8%25AD%25D9%2588%25D8%25B1%25D8%25B3_%25D9%2585%25D8%25B5%25D8%25B1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;600&quot; data-original-width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-e1DOhbjosFc/W1HAvjOEXiI/AAAAAAAAeko/rQIG0hQaaSsCMBCvMI7q7wSskA3BdNyywCLcBGAs/s200/512px-%25D8%25AD%25D9%2588%25D8%25B1%25D8%25B3_%25D9%2585%25D8%25B5%25D8%25B1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Courtesy Azizofegypt &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.en&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Thus, while some &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.4open-sciences.org/articles/fopen/abs/2018/01/fopen180001s/fopen180001s.html&quot;&gt;argue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that predatory publishers represent “the dark dangerous force” of scholarly publishing, others &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://davidwojick.blogspot.com/2016/09/predatory-versus-low-cost.html&quot;&gt;insist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that, by contrast, they have introduced valuable low-cost journals that have levelled the playing field for less privileged members of the research community. As such, the latter say, the journals they publish would be better described as “&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/d/msg/osi2016-25/ZNes8t0yaAM/0wNCplDZAgAJ&quot;&gt;new wave journals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;” or examples of “&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GinnyBarbour/status/1016921343101526016&quot;&gt;innovation in publishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”, not predatory journals. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Others &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.triple-c.at/index.php/tripleC/article/view/867/1041&quot;&gt;argue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that any harm predatory publishers do is small and has been significantly overblown by the enemies of open access, or that the problem is “&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/spotlight-on-the-oaspa-board-lars-bjornshauge/&quot;&gt;not as big now as it once was&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Yet others maintain that the &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scielo.br/pdf/aabc/2018nahead/0001-3765-aabc-201820170959.pdf&quot;&gt;real predators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: windowtext;&quot;&gt; of scholarly publishing are legacy subscription publishers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, who have been &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2011/aug/29/academic-publishers-murdoch-socialist&quot;&gt;robbing the research community blind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for years and are now &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a&gt;corrupting open science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;These complexities point to a central problem in any discussion of predatory publishing: no one is able to adequately define (or agree on a definition of) the phenomenon. And yet however one defines it, it is clearly casting the research community in a &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ndr.de/der_ndr/presse/More-than-5000-German-scientists-have-published-papers-in-pseudo-scientific-journals,fakescience178.html&quot;&gt;bad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/sciences/article/2018/07/19/la-france-fait-partie-des-gros-contributeurs-aux-revues-scientifiques-douteuses_5333431_1650684.html&quot;&gt;bad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indianexpress.com/article/india/inside-indias-fake-research-paper-shops-pay-publish-profit-5265402/&quot;&gt;bad&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;light.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Hugely controversial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Whatever the truth (and likely predatory publishing is some mix of the above) the topic is a hugely controversial one and engenders bitter disputes. For instance, the person who coined the term predatory publisher –  &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeffrey_Beall&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Beall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; – has been the recipient of a constant stream of verbal attacks and legal threats, not least because he created the foundational blacklist of what he calls “potential, possible, or probable predatory scholarly open-access publishers”. Beall also regularly publishes articles (e.g. &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://triple-c.at/index.php/tripleC/article/view/525/514&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) in which he maintains that predatory publishing is a direct consequence of open access, and that OA has as a result &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.4open-sciences.org/articles/fopen/abs/2018/01/fopen180001s/fopen180001s.html&quot;&gt;thrown scholarly publishing into “crisis mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Many were not surprised, therefore, when last year Beall’s site &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2017/01/17/bealls-list-potential-predatory-publishers-go-dark/&quot;&gt;disappeared overnight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. And shortly afterwards he &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeffrey_Beall#cite_note-1&quot;&gt;left his post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; at the University of Colorado without explanation (that I am aware of). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;[&lt;b&gt;Update 22&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;nd&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt; July&lt;/b&gt;: On the same day I posted this an interview with Beall was published in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Indian Express&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt; in which he offered &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://indianexpress.com/article/india/jeffrey-beall-american-librarian-predatory-publishers-threaten-scientific-integrity-are-embarrassment-to-india-5266858/&quot;&gt;his explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; as to why he left his job.]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;To add to the confusion, as concern grew, and both blacklists (e.g. Beall’s list, now &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2017/07/25/cabells-new-predatory-journal-blacklist-review/&quot;&gt;Cabells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and whitelists (e.g. the &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/&quot;&gt;Directory of Open Access Journals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) began to appear, a new problem emerged: even if an OA publisher tries to be honest and straightforward and has the papers submitted to it assessed in a diligent manner, it may at any point (and for whatever reason) be deemed by the community to be predatory. As a result, all those researchers who have published with it can expect to suffer reputational damage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Given these complexities, I plan to use the term predatory publishing in this article in a very specific way. I will be referring to those OA publishers who clearly and deliberately trick researchers &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;– essentially, by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;failing to provide the promised (or even a meaningful) service and/or deceiving them about the nature of that service, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;simply in order to extract money from them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I will not name any publishers, or journals, but simply refer to some of the deceptive practices they engage in that I know take place. I know they take place because I am regularly contacted by the victims of such unethical behaviour, and these victims share with me the details of what has happened to them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, for instance, the publishers/journals I am talking about often do not inform authors at the point of submission that they will be charged an APC if their paper is accepted. And they often tell them (or imply) that the papers they publish are properly peer-reviewed where in reality they are not. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It’s true, there are also some dishonest researchers who deliberately seek out predatory publishers in order to bulk up their CVs. Nevertheless, I have been contacted by a sufficiently large number of scholars who have been tricked by unscrupulous OA publishers that I am confident there is a serious problem out there. And it leads me to believe that a great many of the researchers who publish in these journals are hapless victims of a scam.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In my view, predatory publishing (or whatever you choose to call it) is a serious problem and a solution will eventually have to be found. Here, however, I am concerned primarily with the victims of predatory publishers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;The consequences can be serious&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When authors fall victim to a predatory publisher the consequences can be serious. Not only will they be conned into handing over (usually public) money for a service that is never (or very inadequately) provided, but (more seriously for them) their reputation (and likely their career) may be negatively impacted as a result. Unsurprisingly, therefore, victims of predatory publishers experience a great deal of anguish, anger and resentment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What surprises me is that while no one can agree on what predatory publishing is, or how prevalent or damaging it is, there nevertheless appears to be a consensus that if anyone falls victim to one of these publishers they have only themselves to blame. In other words, it is viewed as an individual failure. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;By contrast, I view predatory publishing as a community problem. And, as such, I believe the community has a responsibility to come up with a solution for those researchers who become victims. After all, as I &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2015/09/predatory-publishing-modest-proposal.html&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; three years ago, predatory publishing could not exist without the co-operation of the research community – e.g. by universities and funders encouraging researchers to engage in pay-to-publish gold OA, and by (often senior) researchers agreeing to join the editorial boards of journals they know little or nothing about, in which they are unlikely ever to publish themselves, and for which they will probably never do any reviewing or editorial work. (Yes, I know, some researchers say they are listed on EBs without having opted-in, but many clearly do volunteer, if only because it adds another line to their CVs) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;To my mind, the community&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;s apparent lack of concern for the victims of predatory publishing represents a moral failure on its part. Certainly, that was the conclusion I reached recently when – during the same week – I was contacted by two different researchers from two different continents (neither, by the way, were from the global South, which is commonly said to be where most victims of predatory publishing are based).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In both cases, the researchers (and their co-authors) had inadvertently submitted papers to predatory publishers. As a result, both had quickly discovered that if you mistakenly submit a paper to a predatory publisher it can be difficult to extricate yourself from what is inevitably a distressing situation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is difficult because the victims of a predatory publisher are likely to discover what has happened only after their paper has been published, or when they receive an invoice (for sometimes thousands of dollars) with a demand that they pay up ASAP. The realisation that they have been conned will, of course, make them angry. But the more distressing moment comes when they realise that their name and reputation are now forever linked to a predatory publisher – unless they can persuade the publisher to take their paper down again. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The first researcher who contacted me realised something had gone wrong when the manuscript that he and his co-authors had submitted was returned to them with no peer review reports attached and no suggested changes. There was, however, a note to say that it had been accepted, and could they please pay the attached invoice. They later learned that the paper had already been published.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Quickly realising what had happened, and desperate to recover the situation, the authors agreed to pay the publisher the journal’s full APC (over $2,000) – not for publishing their paper, but for taking it down. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Even then, they discovered that several copies of the paper had been posted on the publisher’s site and one was still publicly available. In addition, copies (with the publisher’s name attached) were proliferating across the Web, including on a number of paper sharing sites (Oh the joys of CC BY!). They had emailed me in the hope that I could offer some advice, and perhaps approach the publisher on their behalf.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The second author who contacted me had likewise realised that he and his co-authors had submitted their latest paper to a predatory journal. And even though they refused to pay the publication fee, their paper was published. In addition, they discovered that the publisher was seeking to get it indexed on &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Since the journal in question is listed in PubMed, as are a number of the publisher’s other journals, this was a real possibility.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fortunately, after I became involved the first paper was fully removed from the publisher’s web site, and the second one had a retraction notice attached to it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As I say, I know these things go on because over the past 7 years I have had many researchers like these contact me with tales of the nefarious deeds that predatory publishers engage in. Interestingly, sometimes they turn to me only after their university’s counsel has failed to resolve the situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I have always been happy to try and help, but I have also always been aware that even though I am often able to resolve the situation, I cannot provide a scalable solution. It is a time-consuming process and I am just one person working on their own. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;That is one reason why I believe a community solution is essential, but it is certainly not the most compelling one. The more important reason is that since it is the wider research community that has created the monster that predatory publishing has become the community has a responsibility to help the victims. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;Aside from the fact that many members of this community are willing to sit on the editorial boards of predatory journals, the community supports and promotes the pay-to-publish business model that created the conditions for predatory publishing. And when the problem became apparent the community either denied there was a problem or simply sat on its hands and allowed the problem to grow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;But who should organise a community solution?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;COPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;One organisation that could surely play a useful role is the Committee on Publication Ethics (&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/&quot;&gt;COPE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;). This is an organisation, after all, that says it is “committed to educate and support editors, publishers and those involved in publication ethics with the aim of moving the culture of publishing towards one where ethical practices becomes the norm, part of the publishing culture.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As it happens I discovered last year that in 2016 COPE published a &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/case/withdrawal-accepted-manuscript-predatory-journal&quot;&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; exemplifying the kind of deceptive practices predatory publishers engage in, and in which it mooted a solution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The COPE case study points out that because, as a rule, predatory publishers do not ask for copyright to be assigned to them, authors are able to demand that their paper is taken down. Once they have done that, the case study adds, they can then resubmit the paper to a “legitimate journal” with an editorial note explaining what had happened. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;COPE goes on to explain how the author highlighted in the case study wrote to the predatory journal that had tricked her to say, “Immediately remove my article from your website. If you do not do so immediately, I will take legal action”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;When the publisher asked for the name of the article and the journal in which it had been published, the author provided the information and repeated that she would proceed with legal action if the article was not removed from the journal’s website by a given date. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The case study concludes by saying that the author, “will now proceed with submission to a legitimate journal, and the editor of the legitimate journal is comfortable that duplicate publication is no longer a problem.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leaving aside the fact that predatory publishers are routinely robbing the public purse, this might, at first sight, seem a practical solution for victims. After all, the sole objective of a predatory publisher is to make money, not “&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.universityaffairs.ca/career-advice/career-advice-article/tips-to-avoid-predatory-journals-and-conferences/&quot;&gt;to advance knowledge and share new scientific and research findings following an established and rigorous peer review process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”. Having been paid an APC, the publisher will have achieved that objective. And if an author refuses to pay up the publisher can hold the paper hostage until a withdrawal fee is paid. Ironically, the worse the publisher’s reputation the more leverage it has in demanding a high withdrawal fee since the more desperate researchers will be to dissociate themselves from it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;However, having a predatory publisher take down a captured paper only solves half the problem for the victim; in order to recover the situation the author also needs to find an alternative journal willing to republish it. The case study might seem to imply that this is a formality. But is it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Curious to find out, I suggested to one of the researchers who contacted me that he try the method proposed in the COPE case study. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;“Your current submission cannot be considered further”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A few weeks later the author reported back to say that he had sent his paper to a widely recognised OA publisher, and had received the following reply: “Unfortunately, once a paper has been formally published anywhere, even in a predatory journal without the author’s agreement, it still counts as a double submission and therefore your current submission cannot be considered further by us.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Part of the problem may have been that the author contacted the legitimate journal before his paper had been removed from the predatory journal. Nevertheless, if the editor who replied had read the COPE case study (and accepted its argument) a more helpful reply would surely have gone along the lines of, “I am sorry to hear that this has happened to you. Can I suggest you ask the predatory publisher to take down your paper? Once that has been done I would be happy to consider sending it out for review.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, I emailed the editor and copied in COPE. I referred to the case study and asked whether the publisher of the journal was a member of COPE. I also asked why the editor seemed unwilling to help authors who have fallen victim to a predatory publisher (in contrast to the publisher in the COPE case study).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The editor replied that the publisher he represented was indeed a member of COPE and “follows COPE guidelines in dealing with cases of publication ethics.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;He added, however, “the COPE advice to which you refer was given at a COPE forum in response to a specific case submitted by a member and reflects the discussion at that forum. This advice is not necessarily applicable to other cases, as stated on COPE’s website”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Again, this did not seem to be a very helpful response. Sadly, however, when COPE replied it simply echoed the journal editor. “The intention behind posting Forum case discussions is to provide a guide on how to manage a similar case, but we do note that advice on a specific case may not necessarily be applicable to other, even similar, cases. COPE attempts to reflect all of the discussion of that case when we post Forum case discussions online which, quite often, present and explore opposing opinions and viewpoints. We’d advise anyone reflecting on records of cases discussed at COPE Forum to consider all the points of discussion noted to see whether it is applicable to their own case.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Personally, I could see no difference between the situation I had contacted COPE about and the situation described in the case study, but it is possible I am not privy to all the facts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I responded by asking to be pointed to COPE’s advice to editors and publishers on how to deal with situations like the one discussed in the case study. To this COPE replied, “COPE is a founding partner and active participant of the &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thinkchecksubmit.org/&quot;&gt;Think.Check.Submit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; campaign and we actively support and promote that initiative when responding to the conversation around predatory publishing.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Unfortunately, that did not answer my question. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;COPE also sent me a copy of a report it had published and helpfully highlighted for me areas in the report that discussed predatory publishing. Again, however, this was a discussion of the issues of predatory publishing, not practical advice to editors and publishers on what to do when a victim approaches them looking for a legitimate home for their paper. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;“What continues to puzzle me,” I replied, “is that COPE appears to have no published policy or advice for editors or journals on what to do when a researcher finds him/herself in the position outlined in your case study (which you say is not advice). I am sure the Think. Check. Submit idea is a good one, but it is of no use whatsoever for researchers who have been (for whatever reason) entrapped by a predatory publisher.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I added, “Does COPE really not intend to publish specific advice on what editors/ journals/ publishers should do in this situation, which I know is very common because many authors contact me who find themselves in it.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I also copied the journal editor into the email and informed him that I had been in contact with the predatory publisher, who said he was going to take down the paper from his site. Would the editor be willing to reconsider the paper once it had been taken down?, I asked.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Beginning the dialogue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The editor replied, “I am unable to discuss individual manuscripts with anyone who is not an author on the manuscript, therefore I cannot comment on the specifics of this case. However, in light of this information, we will be reaching out to the authors to investigate further.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shortly afterwards, the author who had asked for my help emailed me to say that the publisher had agreed to reconsider a revised submission of his paper “on a semi-urgent basis.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Separately, COPE emailed me to say, “COPE recently held its biannual meeting where this issue was raised and discussed further. It has been agreed to consider what advice COPE can provide in these circumstances and we are beginning the dialogue with our members to decide how best to approach the issue.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is hard not to feel that such a dialogue should have begun long ago, but better late than never perhaps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;With luck, COPE will eventually fashion a solution, or at least &lt;i&gt;publish some advice&lt;/i&gt; for editors and journals, if only to encourage them to treat the victims of predatory publishing with more sympathy than they currently experience.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;From a selfish point of view, it would certainly be useful if every time a researcher contacted me for assistance and/or advice I could point them to the COPE web site for the help they need. If nothing else this could avoid my having to spend my time emailing publishers on behalf of individuals whom (so far as I can see) no one else currently seems willing to help. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A community solution would also be timely as I am finding it increasingly difficult to get the attention of predatory publishers – I assume because they are having to put more and more effort into handling complaints from their victims!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;What frustrates me is that people are happy to rail against predatory publishers, to argue over whether blacklists or whitelists are preferable, or to dismiss predatory publishing as no more than an anti-OA slur, but they continue to insist that the victims are the authors of their own fate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As I say, my view is that the wider research community should not be leaving these people hanging in the wind but helping them. After all, it is a wind that the community set in motion the day it embraced and promoted pay-to-publish gold OA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I also find it somewhat high-minded and hypocritical for publishers to parrot &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;Think.Check.Submit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; every time the topic of predatory publishing comes up. How many researchers know about this initiative? Of those who do, how many can say that using it prevented them from being stung, or that its advice is as useful as claimed?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is worth noting, for instance, that the Think.Check.Submit site says that one sign of a journal’s legitimacy is if it is “indexed in services that you use”. As I noted, one of the journals I was approached about recently is listed in PubMed. Indeed, it would appear that other predatory journals are still listed in PubMed too, as may be the case with DOAJ (despite it having &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/open-access-index-delists-thousands-of-journals-1.19871&quot;&gt;delisted thousands of predatory journals from its service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in 2016). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As further evidence of how difficult it is to navigate the world of predatory publishing, we could note that the University Grants Commission (&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ugc.ac.in/&quot;&gt;UGC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) in India has &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journosdiary.com/2017/09/05/india-ugc-white-list-predatory-journals/&quot;&gt;struggled to weed out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; predatory journals from its whitelist of approved journals. (See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://indianexpress.com/article/india/sc-lakhotia-professor-emeritus-at-bhu-universities-ugc-responsible-for-relaxed-attitude-to-predatory-journals-5266866/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Half solution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;More importantly, Think.Check.Submit is of no use to those unfortunate enough to discover that they have been already scammed. As such, it is a half-solution at best. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Clearly more needs to be done.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The COPE case study suggests one possible way forward. However, its solution requires more work than should surely be necessary. More importantly, it requires the co-operation of the scammers, making it a morally suspect solution, and a somewhat fragile one at that. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Surely there is a better way? I think so. Earlier this year, for instance, it was &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AJOLinfo/status/1001751743099785216?s=19&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on Twitter that papers captured by predatory journals “could be published a second time in [a] legitimate journal once [a] scam [has been] proven, and &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crossref.org/&quot;&gt;CrossRef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; could consider changing the &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doi.org/&quot;&gt;DOI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to the legit later one.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The appeal of this approach is that there would be no need to go through the time-consuming and painful process of persuading predatory publishers to take down papers, or in fact to engage with them at all. As I understand it, the idea is that an appeal would be made to, say, CrossRef or COPE, and if that appeal was successful the paper could be republished in a legitimate journal, at which point the article DOI would be re-assigned to the version published in the latter version. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Such a solution would be another timely development since both the research community and publishers are currently grappling with the issue of versioning in the online environment, particularly as the preprint movement gathers pace (see &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@OmnesRes/biorxiv-a-postprint-server-944359ac65d4&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for instance, and &lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemediacentre.org/the-preprint-dilemma-good-for-science-bad-for-the-public-a-discussion-paper-for-the-scientific-community&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The point is that there is only ever one “&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;version of record&lt;/span&gt;” (&lt;span class=&quot;MsoHyperlink&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://publishingsupport.iopscience.iop.org/questions/article-versions/&quot;&gt;VoR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and (as I understand it) this is signalled by means of its DOI. In the case of predatory publishing, therefore, presumably the DOI could (as suggested on Twitter) be re-assigned to the VoR and the predatory publisher’s version left to fester. Perhaps the DOI assigned to the predatory version could even be deactivated or turned off in some way, leaving it to wallow in relative obscurity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;But I am no expert in these matters and no doubt more thought would need to be given to the matter by wiser heads than mine. Either way, the DOI, CrossRef and COPE would seem to me to be essential partners in any solution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let us hope that COPE will indeed take this forward and finally begin to offer hope to those isolated and lonely individuals who discover they have been conned.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot; style=&quot;line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;These people are the collateral damage of the pay-to-publish business model devised and promulgated by influential publishers like PLOS and BMC and subsequently endorsed and promoted by the research community. It’s time for the community to hold out a helping hand to the victims of predatory pubishing. If it cannot do this I do not think it can justifiably call itself a community any longer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 06:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Richard Poynder)</author>
  <source url="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/7961882/posts/default">Open and Shut?</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: “Chronic compulsive writing syndrome;” a new way to respond to rejection; rewards for a center that doesn’t yet exist</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68817</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/21/weekend-reads-chronic-compulsive-writing-syndrome-a-new-way-to-respond-to-rejection-rewards-for-a-center-that-doesnt-yet-exist/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured, unfortunately, a likely DDOS attack that kept our site dark … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/21/weekend-reads-chronic-compulsive-writing-syndrome-a-new-way-to-respond-to-rejection-rewards-for-a-center-that-doesnt-yet-exist/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: “Chronic compulsive writing syndrome;” a new way to respond to rejection; rewards for a center that doesn’t yet exist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, scientists took baby steps toward selecting sex</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-scientists-took-baby-steps-toward-selecting-sex</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-scientists-took-baby-steps-toward-selecting-sex</link>
	<description>In 1968, scientists figured out how to determine the sex of rabbit embryos.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/070918_BO_50YA_IVF_free.jpg?itok=Ba0r_tZh" length="21762" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Is Social Media the Bad Guy? Redefining Beauty in a Digital World</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23831</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/07/20/is-social-media-the-bad-guy-redefining-beauty-in-a-digital-world/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We’re living in an age of hyper-connectivity where social media is being widely used by almost every age group in the world. It’s connected people from all corners of the planet and given us the opportunity to have global conversations about practically any subject, event, or news piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, many mental health and behavioral experts believe that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/04/09/the-effects-facebook-breaks-and-on-stress-and-well-being/&quot;&gt;social media has had a negative impact on the psychological well-being&lt;/a&gt; of those who use it because it gives people the illusion of being popular based solely on how many “likes” and “friends” they have on their profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologists have also observed that social media exacerbates the tendency for frequent users to develop a skewed impression of the world which is seldom accurate or healthy. Young girls and women, for example, may develop unrealistic standards when it comes to their looks and bodies based on what they see on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But instead of labeling social media as the bad guy, I see it as a double-edged sword. The eventual effect that it has on your life really comes down to how you use it and for what purpose. The Internet is a neutral and open platform that levels the playing field when it comes to having access to knowledge that could help us live healthier, productive, and more fulfilling lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone wants to avoid the negative impact that social media could have on her self-image, they need to become more conscious of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/02/20/digital-dieting-to-prevent-life-destroying-internet-addiction/&quot;&gt;media diet&lt;/a&gt;. If they follow social media accounts and blogs run by people and institutions that are shallow and appearance-focused, such as Instagram models and celebrity fashion and gossip related profiles, it can hurt them if they aren’t mindful of its probable impact on them, especially on a subconscious level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The negative impact of social media can be avoided if people are guided towards adopting a more empowering and all-encompassing &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/02/07/beauty-is-in-the-brain-of-the-beholder/&quot;&gt;standard of beauty&lt;/a&gt; which includes all aspects of being—intellect, aspirations, passions, talents and her morals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, they will be naturally drawn towards developing an identity that isn’t solely based on outward appearances but on character—this, in turn, will influence the use of social media for noble purposes that will expand the mind and provide a platform to express creative potential and to make a difference. In other words, we need to take an inside-out approach when it comes to combating the potentially harmful effects of social media, or any other forms of media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/pixel2013-2364555/&quot;&gt;pixel2013&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Medical ethicist: “I now understand that I should not have been re-using material”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68719</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/20/medical-ethicist-i-now-understand-that-i-should-not-have-been-re-using-material/</link>
	<description>A researcher in medical ethics has retracted two papers within the last two years after admitting to reusing material from previous publications. Ezio Di Nucci, based at the University of Copenhagen, claims he “had misunderstood the relevant practices.” The first retraction, issued in 2017 by the Journal of Value Inquiry, notes the paper “constituted the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/20/medical-ethicist-i-now-understand-that-i-should-not-have-been-re-using-material/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Medical ethicist: “I now understand that I should not have been re-using material”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: You’re living in a new geologic age. It’s called the Meghalayan</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/living-new-geologic-age-called-meghalayan</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/living-new-geologic-age-called-meghalayan</link>
	<description>The newly defined Meghalayan Age began at the same time as a global, climate-driven event that led to human upheavals.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071918_BG_holocene_feat.jpg?itok=JhomoyAJ" length="57644" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: Revues prédatrices : quel est le problème ?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1522</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/revues-predatrices-quel-est-le-probleme/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Un &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/sciences/article/2018/07/19/alerte-mondiale-a-la-fausse-science_5333374_1650684.html&quot;&gt;récent article du Monde&lt;/a&gt; alerte sur un phénomène qui prend de l’ampleur dans l’édition scientifique : les revues prédatrices (voir aussi l’&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/idees/article/2018/07/19/la-gangrene-de-la-fausse-science_5333560_3232.html&quot;&gt;éditorial&lt;/a&gt;). Il s’agit d’éditeurs commerciaux qui publient des articles scientifiques en ligne, contre rémunération, sans aucune éthique scientifique, en particulier en acceptant tous les articles sans qu’ils soient revus par des pairs. De manière similaire, les &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/sciences/article/2018/07/19/le-business-juteux-des-simili-conferences-scientifiques_5333429_1650684.html&quot;&gt;fausses conférences&lt;/a&gt; se multiplient ; des entreprises organisent des conférences scientifiques dans un but purement commercial, sans se soucier de la qualité scientifique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En réaction, certaines institutions commencent à monter des « listes blanches » de journaux à éviter. C’est compréhensible, puisque le phénomène a un coût important. Mais la réponse néglige le problème fondamental. Il faut se rendre à l’évidence : l’éthique commerciale (recherche du profit) n’est pas compatible avec l’éthique scientifique (recherche de la vérité). Les entreprises dont on parle ne sont pas illégales, à ma connaissance. Elles organisent des conférences qui sont réelles ; elles publient des journaux qui sont réels. Simplement, elles ne se soucient pas de la qualité scientifique, mais de leur profit. On considère cela comme immoral ; mais une entreprise commerciale n’a pas de dimension morale, il s’agit simplement d’une organisation dont le but est de générer du profit. On ne peut s’attendre à ce que les intérêts commerciaux correspondent comme par magie exactement aux intérêts scientifiques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt; Le problème de l’édition commerciale&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceci est vrai aux deux extrémités du spectre de la publication académique : pour les journaux prédateurs comme pour les journaux prestigieux. L’article parle de « fausse science » ; mais la plupart des cas de fraude scientifique ont été révélés dans des journaux prestigieux, pas dans des journaux prédateurs – qui de toutes façons ne sont pas lus par la communauté scientifique (voir par exemple &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2018.00037&quot;&gt;Brembs (2018)&lt;/a&gt; pour le lien entre qualité méthodologique et prestige du journal). Pour les journaux commerciaux prestigieux, la stratégie commerciale des éditeurs est non pas de maximiser le nombre d’articles publiés, mais de maximiser le prestige perçu de ces journaux, qui servent ensuite d’appâts pour vendre les collections de journaux de l’éditeur. Autrement dit, c’est une stratégie de marque. Cela passe notamment par une sélection drastique des articles soumis, opérée par des éditeurs professionnels, c’est-à-dire pas par des scientifiques professionnels, sur la base de l’importance perçue des résultats, poussant ainsi une génération de scientifiques à gonfler les prétentions de leurs articles. Cela passe par la promotion auprès des institutions publiques de métriques douteuses comme le facteur d’impact, et plus généralement la promotion d’une mythologie de la publication prestigieuse, à savoir l’idée fausse et dangereuse qu’un article doit être jugé par le prestige du journal dans lequel il est publié, plutôt que par sa valeur scientifique intrinsèque – qui elle est évaluée par la communauté scientifique, pas par un éditeur commercial, ni même par deux scientifiques anonymes. En proposant d’éditer des listes de mauvais journaux, on ne résout pas le problème car l’on adhère implicitement à cette logique perverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il suffit de regarder les marges dégagées par les grandes multinationales de l’édition scientifique pour comprendre que le modèle commercial n’est pas adapté. Pour Elsevier par exemple, les marges sont de l’ordre de 40%. La simple lecture de ce chiffre devrait nous convaincre immédiatement que l’édition scientifique devrait être gérée par des institutions publiques, du moins non commerciales (par exemple des sociétés savantes, comme c’est le cas d’un certain nombre de journaux). Quel est la justification pour faire appel à un opérateur commercial pour gérer un service public, ou n’importe quel service ? La motivation est que la compétition permet de diminuer les coûts et d’améliorer la qualité. Or si les marges sont de 40%, c’est que visiblement la compétition n’opère pas. Pourquoi ? Simplement parce que lorsqu’un scientifique soumet un article, il ne choisit pas le journal en fonction du prix ni même du service rendu (qui est en réalité essentiellement rendu par des scientifiques bénévoles), mais en fonction de la visibilité et du prestige du journal. Il n’y a donc pas de compétition sur les prix. Le pire qui pourrait arriver pour un éditeur commercial est que les articles scientifiques soient jugés à leur valeur intrinsèque plutôt que par le journal dans lequel ils sont publiés, parce qu’alors ce modèle commercial unique s’effondrerait et les journaux seraient en compétition sur les prix et les services qu’ils doivent fournir, comme n’importe quelle autre entreprise commerciale. C’est le pire qui puisse arriver aux éditeurs commerciaux, et le mieux qui puisse arriver à la communauté scientifique. Voilà pourquoi les intérêts commerciaux et scientifiques sont divergents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quoi qu’il en soit, il faut se rendre à l’évidence : des marges aussi énormes signifient que le modèle commercial est inefficace. Il faut donc cesser immédiatement de faire appel à des journaux commerciaux. Ce n’est pas très difficile : les institutions publiques sont tout à fait capables de gérer des journaux scientifiques ; il en existe et depuis longtemps. Un exemple récent est &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/&quot;&gt;eLife&lt;/a&gt;, un des journaux les plus innovants actuellement en biologie. Cela ne devrait pas être très étonnant : le cœur de l’activité des journaux, à savoir la relecture des articles, est déjà faite par des scientifiques, y compris chez les éditeurs commerciaux qui font appel à leurs services gratuitement. Cela ne veut pas dire que l’on ne peut pas faire appel à des entreprises privées pour fournir des services, par exemple héberger des serveurs, gérer les sites web, fournir de l’infrastructure. Mais les journaux ne doivent plus appartenir à des sociétés commerciales, dont l’intérêt est de gérer ces journaux comme des marques. L’éthique scientifique n’est pas compatible avec l’éthique commerciale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment faire ? En réalité c'est assez évident. Il s’agit pour les pouvoirs publics d’annuler la totalité des abonnements aux éditeurs commerciaux et de cesser de payer des droits de publication à ces éditeurs. De nos jours, il n’est pas difficile d’avoir accès à la littérature scientifique sans passer par les journaux (par les prépublications ou ‘preprints’ ou simplement en écrivant aux auteurs qui sont généralement ravis que l’on s’intéresse à leurs travaux). L’argent économisé peut être réinvesti en partie dans l’édition scientifique non commerciale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt; Le mythe de la revue par les pairs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je veux maintenant en venir à une question d’épistémologie plus subtile mais fondamentale. Quel est au fond le problème des revues prédatrices ? Clairement, il y a le gaspillage d’argent public. Mais l’article du Monde pointe également des problèmes scientifiques, à savoir le fait que de fausses informations sont propagées, sans avoir été vérifiées. L’éditorial parle en effet de ‘la sacro-sainte « revue par les pairs »’, qui n’est pas effectuée par ces revues. Mais est-ce vraiment le problème fondamental ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’idée que ce qui fait la valeur d’un article scientifique est qu’il a été validé par la relecture par les pairs avant publication est un mythe tenace mais néanmoins erroné. Cela est faux d’un point de vue empirique, et d’un point de vue théorique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D’un point de vue empirique, à tout instant, il existe dans la littérature des conclusions contradictoires à propos d’un grand nombre de sujets, publiées dans des revues traditionnelles. Les cas de fraude récents concernent des articles qui ont pourtant subi une relecture par les pairs. Mais c’est le cas aussi d’une quantité beaucoup plus importantes d’articles non frauduleux, mais dont les conclusions ont été contestées par la suite. L’histoire des sciences est remplie de théories scientifiques contradictoires et coexistantes, d’âpres débats entre scientifiques. Ces débats ont lieu, justement, après publication, et le consensus scientifique se forme généralement assez lentement, pratiquement jamais sur la base d’un seul article (voir par exemple &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imre_Lakatos#Research_programmes&quot;&gt;Imre Lakatos&lt;/a&gt; en philosophie des sciences, ou &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Structure_of_Scientific_Revolutions&quot;&gt;Thomas Kuhn&lt;/a&gt;). Par ailleurs, les résultats scientifiques sont également souvent diffusés dans la communauté scientifique avant publication formelle ; c’est le cas aujourd’hui avec les prépublications (« preprints » en ligne), mais c’était déjà partiellement le cas auparavant avec les conférences. L’article publié reste la référence parce qu’il fournit des détails précis, notamment méthodologiques, mais la contribution des relecteurs sollicités par les journaux n’est dans la plupart des cas pas essentielle, d’autant que celle-ci n’est généralement pas rendue publique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D’un point de vue théorique, il n’y a aucune raison que la relecture par les pairs « valide » un résultat scientifique. Il n’y a rien de magique dans la revue par les pairs : simplement deux, parfois trois scientifiques donnent leur avis éclairé sur le manuscrit. Ces scientifiques ne sont pas plus experts que ceux qui vont lire l’article lorsqu’il sera publié (je parle bien sûr de la communauté scientifique et pas du grand public). Le fait qu’un article soit publié dans un journal ne dit pas grand chose en soi de la réception des résultats par la communauté ; lorsqu’un article est rejeté d’un journal, il est resoumis ailleurs. La publication finale n’atteste absolument pas d’un consensus scientifique. Par ailleurs, lorsqu’il s’agit d’études empiriques, les relecteurs n’ont pas en réalité la possibilité de vérifier les résultats, et notamment de vérifier s’il n’y a pas eu de fraude. Tout ce qu’ils peuvent faire, c’est vérifier que les méthodes employées semblent appropriées, et que les interprétations semblent sensées (deux points souvent sujets à débat). Pour valider les résultats (mais pas les interprétations), il faudrait au minimum pouvoir refaire les expériences en question, ce qui suppose le temps et l’équipement nécessaire. Ce travail indispensable est fait (ou tenté), mais il n’est pas fait au moment de la publication, ni commissionné par le journal. Il est fait après publication par la communauté scientifique. Le travail de « vérification » (mot inapproprié car il n’y a pas de vérité absolue en science, ce qui la distingue justement de la religion) est le travail de fond de la communauté scientifique, ce n’est pas le travail ponctuel du journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est cette idée reçue qu’il faut déconstruire : que le travail de revue interne au journal « valide » d’une certaine manière les résultats scientifiques. Ce n’est pas le cas, cela n’a jamais été le cas, et cela ne peut pas être le cas. La validation scientifique est la nature même de l’entreprise scientifique, qui est un travail collectif et de longue haleine. On ne peut pas lire un article et conclure « c’est vrai »; il faut pour cela l’intégrer dans un ensemble de connaissances scientifiques, confronter l’interprétation à des points de vue différents (car toute interprétation requiert un cadre théorique).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’est justement cette idée reçue que les journaux prestigieux tentent au contraire de consolider. Il faut y résister. L’antidote est de rendre public et transparent le débat scientifique, qui actuellement reste souvent confiné aux couloirs des laboratoires et des conférences. On prétend que la relecture par les pairs valide les résultats scientifiques, mais ces rapports ne sont la plupart du temps pas publiés ; et quid des rapports non publiés lorsque l’article est rejeté par un journal ? Comment savoir alors ce qu’en pense la communauté ? Il faut au contraire rendre public le débat scientifique. C’est par exemple l’ambition de sites comme &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubpeer.com/&quot;&gt;PubPeer&lt;/a&gt;, qui a mis à jour un certain nombre de fraudes, mais qui peut être utilisé simplement pour le débat scientifique de manière générale. Plutôt que de conditionner la publication à un accord confidentiel de scientifiques anonymes, il faut au contraire inverser ce système : publier l’article (c’est en fait déjà le cas par la prépublication), puis solliciter les avis de la communauté, qui seront également publiés, argumentés, discutés par les auteurs et le reste de la communauté. C’est ainsi que les scientifiques, mais également le plus grand public, pourront obtenir un vision plus juste de la valeur scientifique des articles publiés. La revue par les pairs est un principe fondamental de la science, oui, mais pas celle effectuée dans la confidence par les journaux, celle au contraire effectuée au grand jour et sans limite de temps par la communauté scientifique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 10:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Three-week diary study: sex today increases sense of meaning in life tomorrow</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34303</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/20/three-week-diary-study-sex-today-increases-sense-of-meaning-in-life-tomorrow/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-935542814.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34306&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34306&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Modern Muslim woman relaxing at home after the breakfast. Young Middle Eastern woman sitting next to the window and smiling.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1511705163&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0015625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait of Middle Eastern young woman at home near window&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Portrait of Middle Eastern young woman at home near window&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-935542814.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-935542814.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-935542814.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2019,1485&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/20/three-week-diary-study-sex-today-increases-sense-of-meaning-in-life-tomorrow/portrait-of-middle-eastern-young-woman-at-home-near-window/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-935542814.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes for a good life? Current psychological theory highlights the importance of relationships, belonging and having a sense of purpose. Gratitude, forgiveness, generosity and self-compassion often get a mention too. According to a team of psychologists at George Mason University, there is however a glaring omission. Sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In theoretical models of well-being, sex is rarely discussed and in many seminal articles, ignored,” they write in their &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-25711-001&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;em&gt;Emotion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd Kashdan and his colleagues have attempted to correct this oversight with a three-week diary study, in which they looked at the associations between sex frequency and quality and not only positive mood, but also sense of meaning in life. “If an individual gains sexual access to a romantic partner, this should raise momentary affect … and increase one’s sense of self-worth or meaning in life,” they predicted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34303&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-hundred and fifty-two college students (116 women; average age 24; 63 per cent in a monogamous romantic relationship) completed a diary each night for three weeks, in which they recorded their positive and negative moods that day, how meaningful their life felt, and any sexual activity they’d had since the last entry (this was interpreted broadly, from passionate kissing to intercourse), including how pleasurable and intimate it had been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous survey research has found that people who report having more sex also report being happier, but most of this evidence is based on cross-sectional data so it’s not clear if sex really makes people happy or if being happy encourages sex. With their methodology, Kashdan and his team were able to unravel cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found that having sex on one day was associated with more positive mood states the following day, and also a greater feeling that life is meaningful (the converse wasn’t true – positive moods or more meaning in life one day was not associated with more sex the next). The overall pattern of findings were the same for men and women. Explaining their findings, the researchers said that “Meaning in life often arises when an individual feels their basic need for belonging is met with someone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the nature of the sexual experience, greater sexual pleasure, but not greater intimacy, was associated with better mood the next day. Kashdan’s team said this adds to growing evidence “… that often hedonic pleasures and motives are as important to cultivating a good life as deep, meaningful or virtuous activity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether participants were in a relationship or not didn’t make too much difference to the findings. What mattered more was whether they described their relationship as more intimate – if they did, the association between sex and next-day well-being gains was stronger.  The researchers interpreted this as suggesting that “simply being in a committed relationship is insufficient to derive benefits from pleasurable activities”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only fly in the ointment for the well-being benefits of sex was that, specifically for participants who had only been in their current relationship for a short time, sex on one day was associated with more negative mood states the next. This could be a “regression to the mean”, the researchers suggested, because people in a new relationship are likely to show more daily reactivity – “on the day they had sex, negative affect is probably lower and the change to the next day is greater”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study is limited by its reliance on college students whose relationships, sex lives and life experiences are bound to be different than for middle-aged and older people. Also, while the three-week diary design has advantages over cross-sectional surveys, it still provides only a narrow snapshot of a person’s life. Nonetheless, Kashdan and his team believe their study makes an important contribution. “To understand the full scope of human flourishing, research on well-being needs to incorporate more rigorous scientific inquiries of sexual behaviour,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-25711-001&quot;&gt;Sexuality leads to boosts in mood and meaning in life with no evidence for the reverse direction: A daily diary investigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 08:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Yourbrainhealth: Dealing with dementia. Everything you need to know [Infographic].</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5608</guid>
	<link>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/dealing-with-dementia-everything-you-need-to-know-infographic/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please include attribution to encorecarehomes.co.uk with this graphic.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.encorecarehomes.co.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dealing With Dementia&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://encorecarehomes.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Dementia-Infographic.jpg&quot; width=&quot;924px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/dealing-with-dementia-everything-you-need-to-know-infographic/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Dealing with dementia. Everything you need to know [Infographic].&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 23:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/">Your Brain Health</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Over authors’ objections, PLOS ONE retracts paper claiming Shroud of Turin showed evidence of trauma</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68705</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/19/over-authors-objections-plos-one-retracts-paper-claiming-shroud-of-turin-showed-evidence-of-trauma/</link>
	<description>A year ago, PLOS ONE published a study claiming that there was strong evidence that a person wrapped in the Shroud of Turin — according to lore, the burial shroud of Jesus Christ — had suffered “strong polytrauma.” Today, they retracted it. According to the retraction notice for “Atomic resolution studies detect new biologic evidences on … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/19/over-authors-objections-plos-one-retracts-paper-claiming-shroud-of-turin-showed-evidence-of-trauma/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Over authors’ objections, PLOS ONE retracts paper claiming Shroud of Turin showed evidence of trauma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 22:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Shallow reef species may not find refuge in deeper water habitats</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/shallow-reef-species-may-not-find-refuge-deeper-water-habitats</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/shallow-reef-species-may-not-find-refuge-deeper-water-habitats</link>
	<description>Coral reefs in deep-water ecosystems may not make good homes for species from damaged shallow reefs.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 19:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071918_LR_coral-reef_feat.jpg?itok=UDYdFYcV" length="57915" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new ankylosaur found in Utah had a surprisingly bumpy head</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-ankylosaur-found-utah-had-surprisingly-bumpy-head</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-ankylosaur-found-utah-had-surprisingly-bumpy-head</link>
	<description>The spiky, fossilized skull of a newly discovered dinosaur species may be a road map to its ancestors’ journey to North America.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071818_cm_akainacephalus_feat_illustration.jpg?itok=g33D46-F" length="43651" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This colorful web is the most complete look yet at a fruit fly’s brain cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-complete-look-yet-fruit-fly-brain-cells</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-complete-look-yet-fruit-fly-brain-cells</link>
	<description>Scientists compiled 21 million images to craft the highest-resolution view yet of the fruit fly brain.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 15:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_scivis_fly-brain_feat.jpg?itok=_x5S7Hj3" length="35999" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Are non-breadwinners more likely to cheat? 2015 study said yes; newly corrected version says “maybe”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://retractionwatch.com/?p=68621</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/19/are-non-breadwinners-more-likely-to-cheat-2015-study-said-yes-newly-corrected-version-says-maybe/</link>
	<description>A few years ago, you may remember some news headlines discussing a study that suggested people — especially men — are more likely to cheat if their spouses earn more money. Well, it turns out those findings are less convincing than they initially appeared. But they’re not getting retracted. In a six-page correction notice, author … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/19/are-non-breadwinners-more-likely-to-cheat-2015-study-said-yes-newly-corrected-version-says-maybe/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Are non-breadwinners more likely to cheat? 2015 study said yes; newly corrected version says “maybe”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: One particle’s trek suggests that ‘spacetime foam’ doesn’t slow neutrinos</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrinos-travel-light-speed-not-slowed-spacetime-foam</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrinos-travel-light-speed-not-slowed-spacetime-foam</link>
	<description>Neutrinos and light travel at essentially the same speed, as predicted.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_EC_neutrino-speed_feat.jpg?itok=LIZYfdfw" length="29222" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: What is computational neuroscience? (XXXII) The problem of biological measurement (2)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1519</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxxii-the-problem-of-biological-measurement-2/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxxi-the-problem-of-biological-measurement-1/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I have pointed out differences between biological sensing and physical measurement. A direct consequence is that it is not so straightforward to apply the framework of control theory to biological systems. At the level of behavior, it seems clear that animal behavior involves control; it is quite documented in the case of motor control. But this is the perspective of an external observer: the target value, the actual value and the error criterion are identified with physical measurements by an external observer. But how does the organism achieve this control, from its own perspective?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the organism does not do, at least not directly, is measure the physical dimension and compare it to a target value. Rather, the biological system is influenced by the physical signal and reacts in a way that makes the physical dimension closer to a target value. How? I do not have a definite answer to this question, but I will explore a few possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us first explore a conventional possibility. The sensory neuron encodes the sensory input (eg muscle stretch) in some way; the control system decodes it, and then compares it to a target value. So for example, let us say that the sensory neuron is an integrate-and-fire neuron. If the input is constant, then the interspike interval can be mapped back to the input value. If the input is not constant, it is more complicated but estimates are possible. There are various studies relevant to this problem (for example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0925231204000177&quot;&gt;Lazar (2004)&lt;/a&gt;; see also the work of &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1003258&quot;&gt;Sophie Denève, e.g. 2013&lt;/a&gt;). But all these solutions require knowing quite precisely how the input has been encoded. Suppose for example that the sensory neuron adapts with some time constant. Then the decoder needs somehow to de-adapt. But to do it correctly, one needs to know the time constant accurately enough, otherwise biases are introduced. If we consider that the encoder itself learns, e.g. by adapting to signal statistics (as in the efficient coding hypothesis), then the properties of the encoder must be considered unknown by the decoder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can the decoder learn to decode the sensory spikes? The problem is it does not have access to the original signal. The key question then is: what could the error criterion be? If the system has no access to the original signal but only streams of spikes, then how could it evaluate an error? One idea is to make an assumption about some properties of the original signal. One could for example assume that the original signal varies slowly, in contrast with the spike train, which is a highly fluctuating signal. Thus we may look for a slow reconstruction of the signal from the spike train; this is in essence the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scholarpedia.org/article/Slow_feature_analysis&quot;&gt;slow feature analysis&lt;/a&gt;. But the original signal might not be slowly fluctuating, as it is influenced by the actions of the controller, so it is not clear that this criterion will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus it is not so easy to think of a control system which would decode the sensory neuron activity into the original signal so as to compare it to a target value. But beyond this technical issue (how to learn the decoder), there is a more fundamental question: why splitting the work into two units (encoder/decoder), if the function of the second one is essentially to undo the work of the first one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative is to examine the system as a whole. We consider the physical system (environment), the sensory neuron, the actuator, and the interneurons (corresponding to the control system). Instead of seeing the sensory neuron as involved in an act of measurement and communication and the interneurons as involved in an act of interpretation and command, we see the entire system as a distributed dynamical system with a number of structural parameters. In terms of dynamical systems (rather than control), the question becomes: is the target value for the physical dimension an attractive fixed point of this system, or more generally, is there such a fixed point? (as opposed to fluctuations) We can then derive complementary questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;robustness: is the fixed point robust to perturbations, for example changes in properties of the sensor, actuator or environment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;optimality: are there ways to adjust the structure of the system so that the firing rate is minimized (for example)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;control: can we change the fixed point by an intervention on this system? (e.g. on the interneurons)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the problem becomes one of designing a spiking system that has an attractive fixed point in the physical dimension, with some desirable properties. Framing the problem in this way does not necessarily require that the physical dimension is explicitly extracted (“decoded”) from the activity of the sensory neuron. If we look at such a system, we might not be able to identify in any of the neurons a quantity that corresponds to the physical signal, or to the target value. Rather, physical signal and target value are to be found in the physical environment, and it is a property of the coupled dynamical system (neurons-environment) that the physical signal tends to approach the target value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 10:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Empowering women from low socioeconomic backgrounds to combat obesity: MyBFF@home study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10371</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/19/empowering-women-low-socioeconomic-backgrounds-combat-obesity-mybffhome-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/feature-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obesity is a global threat and it is one of the risk factors associated with diabetes, hypertension and heart disease. It is a growing problem among women in Malaysia and other Asian countries, where the prevalence of obesity among women is much higher than among men. Various methods of weight reduction are reported in the literature and these include diet modification, physical activity or exercise regime, behavioral intervention and the use of self-monitoring weight loss tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2014, we carried out a quasi-experimental study for weight loss intervention among 328 overweight and obese housewives who lived in low cost housing (People’s Housing Project) in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. The study is called My Body is Fit and Fabulous at Home (MyBFF@home) and it was conducted for 12 months. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-18-supplement-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MyBFF@home&lt;/a&gt; is one of the government efforts to combat obesity problems among adults in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our study aims to empower overweight and obese women to participate in the weight loss intervention and to make several changes to their current lifestyle. In this study, changes in body weight, nutrient intake, body fat, glucose level, lipid profile, health literacy, quality of life and other clinical parameters were monitored and findings of the MyBFF@home are reported in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-18-supplement-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Supplement of MyBFF@home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10373&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10373 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/1-300x195.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Source: Image belongs to MyBFF@home as part of the research project&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the MyBFF@home study, we gave women in the intervention group a modest weight loss package consisting of four individual diet counseling sessions, monthly group exercise, dumb bell exercise (at home) and three self-monitoring tools (pedometer, food diary and physical activity diary). The control group only received seven group seminars related to women’s health and two self-monitoring tools (food diary and physical activity diary). We then compared the health outcomes between the groups (before and after) in the intervention and maintenance phases. The overview of the MyBFF@home can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0589-x&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Introduction article of MyBFF@home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the study, we found the readiness among the participants to participate in the weight loss program was more than 90% and the motivation level was also good. After 6 months, we detected several changes in body composition, blood pressure level, lipid profile, health literacy level and other parameters among the participants in both groups. These changes were discussed in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-18-supplement-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Supplement of MyBFF@home&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discovered some interesting findings based on the data analyses. After 6 months, there were some changes in the body weight of the participants in both groups. Weight changes among the participants in the intervention group were greater than the control group. However, these changes were not sustained during the maintenance phase (after 12 months). Although there were no significant changes in overall weight between the two groups, we found that participants in the intervention group showed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0595-z&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;significant increase in their muscle mass compared to before the intervention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also found some changes in quality of life among the participants before and after the intervention. Overweight and obese housewives experienced &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0591-3&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;significant improvements in the Health Related Quality of Life (HRQOL) scores after the intervention phase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10374&quot; style=&quot;width: 215px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10374 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/2-205x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;205&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Source: Image belongs to MyBFF@home as part of the research project&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting finding regards health literacy, which is linked to an individual’s knowledge, motivation and behavior in everyday life. We measured the health literacy level among all participants using the modified Newest Vital Sign (NVS) questionnaire and we found that the health literacy level among the participants in both groups was low at the beginning of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 6 months (weight loss intervention phase), the NVS score in both groups had increased compared to before intervention. However, in the maintenance phase we found that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12905-018-0596-y&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NVS score of participants in the intervention group had increased further compared to the control group&lt;/a&gt;. This finding indicated that participants in the intervention group were more likely to sustain their behavioral change in everyday life and this could be explored further in the future research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To our knowledge, MyBFF@home is the first and largest community-based intervention study among women from low socioeconomic background. Despite some limitations, MyBFF@home has empowered overweight and obese women to combat obesity and to self-monitor their daily diet and physical activities. It is our hope that the findings of the MyBFF@home could support various stakeholders in the obesity prevention program for women in Malaysia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoyed this blog? You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcwomenshealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/supplements/volume-18-supplement-1?utm_source=BMC_blog&amp;amp;amp;utm_medium=Blog&amp;amp;amp;utm_content=DavFal-BMC-BMC_Women's_Health-Public_Health-Global&amp;amp;amp;utm_campaign=BMCS_USG_JULY2018_MyBFF_athome_study&quot;&gt;access the supplement here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/19/empowering-women-low-socioeconomic-backgrounds-combat-obesity-mybffhome-study/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Empowering women from low socioeconomic backgrounds to combat obesity: MyBFF@home study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 09:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/feature-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Searching for the fundamental mental processes that cut across diagnostic categories, driving confusion and distress</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34296</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/19/searching-for-the-fundamental-mental-processes-that-cut-across-diagnostic-categories-driving-confusion-and-distress/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_34297&quot; style=&quot;width: 1550px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-667879250.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34297&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34297&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A man with his head lowered shattering showing mental health issues. Anxiety, depression and mindfulness awareness concept.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mental health&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mental health&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-667879250.jpg?w=845?w=820&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-667879250.jpg?w=845?w=240&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-667879250.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1550,1935&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/19/searching-for-the-fundamental-mental-processes-that-cut-across-diagnostic-categories-driving-confusion-and-distress/mental-health-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-667879250.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;A new paper in Journal of Clinical Psychology is the just the latest to take a trans-diagnostic approach to mental health&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of psychiatric diagnoses keep on growing, with perhaps ten times as many categories now as there were 50 years ago. This may in part reflect our growing knowledge, which is welcome. But the sheer density of diagnoses makes it difficult for researchers or clinicians to see the wood for the trees, and it encourages them to settle into silos. It would be advantageous for clinical research and practice if we could introduce some elegance to our understanding. A recent movement in psychology and psychiatry is seeking to do exactly this. It follows evidence that, in the words of US psychologists Robert Kruger and Nicholas Eaton in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4329885/&quot;&gt;2015 review&lt;/a&gt;, “many mental disorders are manifestations of relatively few core underlying dimensions.” In the latest foray from this movement, the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Clinical Psychology&lt;/i&gt; has published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22585?c&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; outlining another potential core feature: the repetitive occurrence of negative thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34296&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proliferation of psychiatric diagnoses was baked in from the beginning. Modern psychiatry sought to apply the burgeoning medical model to the mind, treating madness as illness. Physical illnesses are considered as discrete categories, even if they produce overlapping symptoms like a fever, because we can point to their distinct microbial origins.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has influenced how we approach mental health, meaning someone struggling could be diagnosed with a phobia and also with an eating disorder and maybe separately with depression (and anxiety, and another eating disorder, and another phobia, and OCD…ad infinitum). We bracket these issues out as if they each originate from their own unique strain of mind bacteria. But mental disorders are rooted in dysfunctional mental processes, of which there are only so many. If we put aside the disease model and look for these processes, maybe we can get to a more solid and elegant foundation.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example would be internalising-externalising. In internalising disorders such as depression, OCD, anxiety and bulimia, the individual tends to draw problems inwards to an inappropriate degree; issues are suppressed or privately managed using ineffective or unhealthy strategies. Meanwhile, externalising disorders like pyromania, kleptomania, and conditions like oppositional defiant disorder or conduct disorder, all involve manifesting problematic thoughts or emotions by projecting them onto the world.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According Kruger and Eaton’s landmark review, these aren’t just convenient labels: they may actually be more informative than the specific diagnoses. For instance, suicide risk may be better predicted by internalising in all its forms than a specific diagnosis like depression. Similarly, externalising behaviour of any kind is a strong predictor of other forms of externalising, suggesting that it might sometimes be useful to think of the problem &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; externalising, which can manifest in different ways depending on contextual factors.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, this division is too simple to explain everything about mental health. But in interaction with some other features, perhaps we can start to arrive at a complete model that cuts across diagnostic categories while also capturing the richness of psychiatric conditions. What other relevant factors are there? &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/01/30/different-psychiatric-symptom-dimensions-have-opposite-associations-wit&quot;&gt;We recently covered work&lt;/a&gt; that suggested another potential trans-diagnostic structure: meta-cognition, the ability to judge your cognitive ability. People who were more anxious or depressed showed more accuracy, but less confidence, in how they judged their performance on a mental task, whereas those who tended towards compulsive behaviour (such as those with schizophrenia or OCD) showed overconfidence and did less well. In our piece we described how this pattern can account for patterns of behaviour found in the real world, such as pessimism and jumping to conclusions, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-07-19 09.46.01.png&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-34299 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34299&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-07-19 09.46.01&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/screenshot-2018-07-19-09-46-01.png?w=845?w=372&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/screenshot-2018-07-19-09-46-01.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/screenshot-2018-07-19-09-46-01.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;372,222&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/19/searching-for-the-fundamental-mental-processes-that-cut-across-diagnostic-categories-driving-confusion-and-distress/screenshot-2018-07-19-09-46-01/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/screenshot-2018-07-19-09-46-01.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in the most recent example, Deanna Kaplan and her team at the University of Arizona suggest another trans-diagnostic feature: “maladaptive repetitive thought”. This is found across many mental health disorders, typically accompanied by a sense that the thoughts are uncontrollable, a negative flavour, and a fixation on&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;seeking rather than solving problems. Consider the ruminative thoughts that characterise depression, the worries that surge up in anxiety, and the obsessive thoughts that drive OCD. Kaplan’s team suggest that these different manifestations should be thought of as variations on a key theme, often differing simply in whether the thoughts are focused on the past, present or future.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers note that their model helped them to draw connections to other related phenomena such as the problematic grief phenomenon of yearning, which pulls you into the past towards a desire that cannot be satisfied. They also see parallels in somatic hypervigilance, the constant monitoring of bodily sensations for any cause for alarm. Again, the same features come up: negative valence, uncontrollability, and seeking of problems, in this case in the present moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not news that unwelcome thoughts are a frequent feature of poor mental health. But as with the internalising and externalising dimensions, it’s possible that grouping mental health problems that share repetitive thought processes could offer fresh way of looking at the root causes of people’s difficulties. It could be that the core problems driving all psychological disorders are countable on our fingers – if so, and if we can identity these core processes, then it will be easier to understand how they develop, and to apply advances from one area of treatment to another, as well as to see when doing so would be ill-advised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, consider how the three features of internalising/externalising, meta-cognitive judgment and repetitive thought processes could be used to organise our understanding of the recently proposed diagnostic category of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/25/people-with-maladaptive-daydreaming-spend-an-average-of-four-hours-a-day-lost-in-their-imagination/&quot;&gt;maladaptive daydreaming&lt;/a&gt;, whereby people are compulsively drawn to their daydreams at the cost of their psychological health. This certainly seems to involve internalising, and could involve overconfident misjudgment of whether the daydreaming is beneficial. And what is a daydream if not an extended, imagistic form of thought (much like a yearning)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we may be on the verge of a real advance in psychiatry, akin to the turn from individual symptoms to mental syndromes we made one hundred years ago. By looking past surface issues and gripping the fundamental mental processes that drive confusion and distress, we might be better placed to remedy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/jclp.22585?c&quot;&gt;Maladaptive repetitive thought as a transdiagnostic phenomenon and treatment target: An integrative review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 08:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: ToxiLatin 2018: The Exciting Frontier of Toxicology Research in Brazil and the World</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10325</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/19/toxilatin-2018-exciting-frontier-toxicology-research-brazil-world/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Toxilatin-2018-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://toxilatin2018.com/en/presentation/&quot;&gt;ToxiLatin&lt;/a&gt; was held at the Universidade Federal do Grande do Sul campus in Porto Alegre, Brazil.  Parallel talks in English and Portuguese were given on the toxic effects of heavy metals, nanomaterials, and pesticides. ToxiLatin aims to disseminate scientific knowledge to everyone in spite of academic wealth, a goal in which they share with BMC, with the ultimate goal to decrease noncommunicable diseases and reduce the socioeconomic disparities of these diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10329&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10329&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/ToxiLatin-2018-picture-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;From Left to Right: Ben Ragen (Editor BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology), Solange Cristina Garcia (Organizer), Daiana Silva Avila (Co-Organizer), Michael Aschner (Section Editor BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the conference, the brilliant and charismatic organizer of the conference, Solange Cristina Garcia (Professor of Toxicology at the Federal university of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil), gave a pointed and poignant introduction about ToxiLatin and toxicology research in Brazil, a country of over 207 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this opening address she discussed the 2014 founding of AstoxiLatin (Latin American Association of Environmental, Experimental and Nanomaterial Toxicology). The formation of this society was motivated, mainly, due to the lack of policy and availability of antidotes for cyanide exposure in people affected by the tragic Kiss nightclub fire in Santa Maria, Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Dr. Garcia’s address she discussed the political, social, and financial challenges facing the fifth most populated country in the world as well as the significant cuts in scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nanotoxicology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nanomaterials and their toxic potentials received a significant amount of attention at ToxiLatin this year. Nanomaterials include substances such as polymers, metals, carbon nanotubes, and silicas and are omnipresent. They can be found in body lotions, shampoos, toothpaste, paint, antiperspirants, sunscreen and many other substances humans constantly encounter and dispose of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When assessing the risks of nanomaterials, simply measuring the amount of nanomaterials is challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When assessing the risks of nanomaterials, simply measuring the amount of nanomaterials is challenging. After disposal, nanomaterials can be found in water, sludge and soil. These different substrates create challenges in accurately measuring the presence of nanomaterials, which is necessary to determine how nanomaterials behave in the environment and if there are potential damaging effects on the environment and organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10330&quot; style=&quot;width: 270px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Nanomaterials&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-10330&quot; height=&quot;234&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Nanomaterials-300x270.png&quot; width=&quot;260&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Nanomaterials&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measuring nanomaterial levels is critical since exposure can have negative health consequences. Nanoparticles are unstable structures and have immunotoxic potential. Exposure to nanoparticles activates the immune system, and has been shown to cause release of cytokines including IL-1β.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ToxiLatin and Toxicology Publishing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpharmacoltoxicol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I had the honor of participating in a roundtable of Editors discussing publishing in toxicology.  Also present at the roundtable was Dr. Kai Savolainen, Editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/home/het&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Human &amp;amp; Experimental Toxicology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Dr. Michael Aschner, Editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/neurotoxicology&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NeuroToxicology &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;and a Section Editor for the ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpharmacoltoxicol.biomedcentral.com/articles/sections/toxicology&quot;&gt;Toxicology&lt;/a&gt;’ section in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpharmacoltoxicol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this roundtable, which was particularly important for students, we discussed the importance of journal selection, intriguing titles, strong hypotheses and abstracts, and journal formats.  We had an honest discussion of predatory journals, the current state of the challenges in finding reviewers, and dealing with reviewers’ split decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One critical topic discussed was the conflict researchers in financially starved scientific communities, such as Brazil, experience when deciding to publish in an open access journal or to buy necessary experimental compounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One critical topic discussed was the conflict researchers in financially starved scientific communities, such as Brazil, experience when deciding to publish in an open access journal or to buy necessary experimental compounds. Of importance, I stated that when publishing in BMC, finances should not be a prohibitive factor in publishing in our journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ToxiLatin and &lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology&lt;/em&gt; Collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year ToxiLatin and &lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology&lt;/em&gt; have teamed up to publish a supplement of articles related to the conference.  Attendees were encouraged to submit extended abstracts and, after careful vetting and BMC’s standard rigorous peer-review process, an exciting collection of toxicology-related articles will be published at the end of the 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s ToxiLatin was incredibly successful, and its promise of furthering the field of toxicology will continue at the next conference in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/19/toxilatin-2018-exciting-frontier-toxicology-research-brazil-world/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ToxiLatin 2018: The Exciting Frontier of Toxicology Research in Brazil and the World&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 08:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Toxilatin-2018-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Former KI rector Dahlman-Wright: stones in a glass house</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=25451</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/19/former-karolinska-rector-dahlman-wright-stones-in-a-glass-house/</link>
	<description>The irony is rich. Just last month, the Swedish Karolinska Institutet (KI) announced the results of the investigation into papers by their former guest professor Paolo Macchiarini and his right-hand man Philipp Jungebluth. The two were found guilty of research misconduct and their plastic trachea transplant papers were set for retraction, where at least the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/19/former-karolinska-rector-dahlman-wright-stones-in-a-glass-house/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Former KI rector Dahlman-Wright: stones in a glass house&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How a variation on Botox could be used to treat pain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-variation-botox-could-be-used-treat-pain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-variation-botox-could-be-used-treat-pain</link>
	<description>Drugs that incorporate modified botulinum toxin provide long-term pain relief, a study in mice finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 19:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_AC_botox-pain_feat.jpg?itok=Mluz5wq_" length="28863" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New ‘Poké Ball’ robot catches deep-sea critters without harming them</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pokemon-robot-catches-deep-sea-critters-safely</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pokemon-robot-catches-deep-sea-critters-safely</link>
	<description>A machine that gently catches and releases animals underwater could help researchers take a more detailed census of the deep sea.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_MT_submarine-poke-ball.jpg?itok=vAm_XlrH" length="25561" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This amber nugget from Myanmar holds the first known baby snake fossil</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/amber-nugget-myanmar-holds-first-known-baby-snake-fossil</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/amber-nugget-myanmar-holds-first-known-baby-snake-fossil</link>
	<description>Amber preserves the delicate bone structure of a 99 million year old baby snake.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 18:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071818_lh_baby-snake_feat.jpg?itok=8MRr4e0y" length="40556" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: VIDEO: How Facebook Preys on Our Mental Health</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23788</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/07/18/video-how-facebook-preys-on-our-mental-health/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In an ironic turn, the recent controversy surrounding Facebook and Cambridge Analytica eclipsed another controversy brewing months before. As 2017 came to close, the million-dollar question surrounding the company was, &lt;em&gt;Does Facebook make us depressed?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in December, even Facebook itself posted an article on its official blog, titled, &lt;em&gt;Hard Questions: Is Spending Time on Social Media Bad For Us? &lt;/em&gt;The post cites a number of studies that prove spending time on &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/04/09/the-effects-facebook-breaks-and-on-stress-and-well-being/&quot;&gt;Facebook can threaten well-being&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One study from the University of San Diego and Yale found that people who clicked on four times as many links or liked twice as many posts as the average person reported decreased mental health in a survey. A broader study found that increases in “likes clicked,” “links clicked,” or “status updates” was associated with decreases in mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But though these studies might prove &lt;em&gt;that &lt;/em&gt;Facebook brings us down, they don’t ask the important question of &lt;em&gt;how &lt;/em&gt;Facebook brings us down. For a more thorough dive into what truly addict us to the site, ultimately leaving us feeling unsatisfied, check out this video, which explains the subject in depth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video presents arguments from two former employees, Sean Parker and Chamath Palihapitiya, who claim that Facebook was designed to prey on its users’ neurochemical reward systems. Dopamine, the chemical released in the brain during certain activities, such as exercising, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/01/31/daytime-nap-productivity-and-brain-functions/&quot;&gt;finishing tasks&lt;/a&gt; at work, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/01/12/food-and-mood-how-they-influence-each-other/&quot;&gt;finding food&lt;/a&gt;, has also been found to surge during social interactions. The brain desires cooperation and connection, so it sends reward signals in the form of dopamine when this cooperation or connection occurs. It could be something as simple as carrying a couch up a flight of stairs with a friend, or as profound as telling your partner you love her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the brain cannot distinguish between, an interaction in real life and one on Facebook in terms of dopamine release, these rewards systems are integral to Facebook’s interface. Even the little red notification, or the ping sound we’ve all become accustomed to, produce a similar dopamine release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key insight in the video is that Facebook knows these dopamine hits are essential to their business model, the main driving force bringing people back to the site over and over and over again. Knowing this, they’ve ramped up notifications over the years, spiking our dopamine levels for something as mundane and uninteresting as someone having gone “live” a few hours ago, or a belated birthday, or even just to tell you that you haven’t posted in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens, then, is a uniquely modern phenomenon. Your brain is rewarding you with dopamine for a successful social interaction, but in reality, no genuine connection has occurred, creating a disconnect between the chemical reward system in your brain and your actual lived experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, Facebook can depress its users in a number of ways. People often assume others’ lives are happier than theirs because of how their friends present themselves online. Teen brains are now trained to be distracted based on the interface alone. But this feeling, the dopamine hit followed by immediate disappointment with the reality of a meaningless notification, seems central to the deflating feeling Facebook can produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shakya, H., &amp;amp; Christakis, N. (2017). Association of Facebook Use With Compromised Well-Being: A Longitudinal Study. American Journal Of Epidemiology. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/aje/kww189&quot;&gt;10.1093/aje/kww189&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verduyn, P., Lee, D., Park, J., Shablack, H., Orvell, A., &amp;amp; Bayer, J. et al. (2015). Passive Facebook usage undermines affective well-being: Experimental and longitudinal evidence. Journal Of Experimental Psychology: General, 144(2), 480-488. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/aje/kww189&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;10.1037/xge0000057&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 15:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A university is revoking a student’s PhD — but not because of misconduct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=68243</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/18/a-university-is-revoking-a-students-phd-but-not-because-of-misconduct/</link>
	<description>Earlier this month, Tokushima University in Japan announced it was revoking a student’s PhD degree — but for a somewhat unusual reason. The student didn’t appear to commit misconduct. Rather, the authors discovered a series of errors that invalidated the paper’s central conclusion. The case has us wondering about how universities should respond when they … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/18/a-university-is-revoking-a-students-phd-but-not-because-of-misconduct/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A university is revoking a student’s PhD — but not because of misconduct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Artificial Intelligence Resource Center</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ai-resource-center</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/ai-resource-center</link>
	<description>Free access to research and expert commentary on AI, machine learning and related technologies — updated 19 July 2018</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 11:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: What is computational neuroscience? (XXXI) The problem of biological measurement (1)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1514</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxxi-the-problem-of-biological-measurement-1/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We tend to think of sensory receptors (photoreceptors, inner hair cells) or sensory neurons (retinal ganglion cells; auditory nerve fibers) as measuring physical dimensions, for example light intensity or acoustical pressure, or some function of it. The analogy is with physical instruments of measure, like a thermometer or a microphone. This confers a representational quality to the activity of neurons, an assumption that is at the core of the neural coding metaphor. I explain at length why that metaphor is misleading in many ways in an essay (Brette (2018) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/07/13/168237&quot;&gt;Is coding a relevant metaphor for the brain?&lt;/a&gt;). Here I want to examine more specifically the notion of biological measurement and the challenges it poses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This notion comes about not only in classical representationalist views, where neural activity is seen as symbols that the brain then manipulates (the perception-cognition-action model, also called sandwich model), but also in alternative views, although it is less obvious. For example, one alternative is to see the brain not as a computer system (encoding symbols, then manipulating them) but as a control system (see Paul Cisek’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cisek.org/pavel/Pubs/Cis1999.pdf&quot;&gt;behavior as interaction&lt;/a&gt;, William Powers’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perceptual_control_theory&quot;&gt;perceptual control theory&lt;/a&gt;, Tim van Gelder’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/behavioral-and-brain-sciences/article/the-dynamical-hypothesis-in-cognitive-science/C121F1B65A534F3E7A27075EE489AD1E&quot;&gt;dynamical view of cognition&lt;/a&gt;). In this view, the activity of neurons does not encode stimuli. In fact there is no stimulus per se, as Dewey pointed out: “the motor response determines the stimulus, just as truly as sensory stimulus determines the movement.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple case is feedback control: the system tries to maintain some input at a target value. To do this, the system must compare the input with an internal value. We could imagine for example something like an idealized version of the stretch reflex: when the muscle is stretched, a sensory feedback triggers a contraction, and we want to maintain muscle length constant. But this apparently trivial task raises a number of deep questions, as more generally the application of control theory to biological systems. I suppose there is a sensor, a neuron that transduces some physical dimension into spike trains, for example the stretch of a muscle. There is also an actuator, which reacts to a spike by a physical action, for example contracting the muscle with a particular time course. I chose a spike-based description not just because it corresponds to the physiology of the stretch reflex, but also because it will illustrate some fundamental issues (which would exist also with graded transduction, but less obviously so).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have a neuron, or a set of neurons, which receive these sensory inputs and send spikes to the actuator. For this discussion, it is not critical that these are actually neurons; we can just consider that there is a system there, and we ask how this system should be designed so as to successfully achieve a control task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major issue here is that the control system does not directly deal with the physical dimension. At first sight, we could think this is a minor issue. The physical dimension gets transduced, and we could simply define the target value in the transduced dimension (eg the current). But here we see that the problem is more serious. What the control system deals with is not simply a function of the physical dimension. More accurately, transduction is a nonlinear dynamical system influenced by a physical signal. The physical signal can be constant, for example, while the transduced current decays (adaptation) and the sensory neuron outputs spike trains, i.e., a highly variable signal. This poses a much more serious problem than a simple calibration problem. When the controlled physical value is at the target value, the sensory neuron might be spiking, perhaps not even at a regular rate. The control system should react to that particular kind of signal by not acting, while it should act when the signal deviates from it. But how can the control system identify the target state, or even know whether to act in one or the opposite direction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptation in neurons is often depicted as an optimization of information transmitted, in line with the metaphor of the day (coding). But the relevant question is: how does the receiver of this “information” knows how the neuron has adapted? Does it have to de-adapt, to somehow be matched to the adaptive process of the encoding neuron? (This problem has to do with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2018/07/13/168237&quot;&gt;dualistic structure of the neural coding metaphor&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are additional layers of difficulty. We have first recognized that transduction is not a simple mapping from a physical dimension to a biological (e.g. electrochemical) dimension, but rather a dynamical system influenced by a physical signal. Now this dynamical system depends on the structure of the sensory neuron. It depends for example on the number of ionic channels and their properties, and we know these are highly plastic and indeed quite variable both across time and across cells. This dynamical system also depends on elements of the body, or let’s say more generally the neuron’s environment. For example, the way acoustical pressure is transduced in current by an inner hair cell depends obviously on the acoustical pressure at the eardrum, but that physical signal depends on the shape the ear, which filters sounds. Properties of neurons change with time too, development and aging. Thus, we cannot assume that the dynamical transformation from physical signal to biological signal is a fixed one. Somehow, the control system has to work despite this huge plasticity and the dynamical nature of the sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pause for a moment and outline a number of differences between physical measurements, as with a thermometer, and biological measurements (or “sensing”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The physical meter is calibrated with respect to an external reference, for example 0°C is when water freezes, while 100°C is when it boils. The biological sensor cannot be calibrated with respect to an external reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The physical meter produces a fixed value for a stationary signal. The biological sensor produces a dynamical signal in response to a stationary signal. More accurately, the biological sensor is a nonlinear dynamical system influenced by the physical signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The physical meter is meant to be stable, in that the mapping from physical quantity to measurement is fixed. When it is not, this is considered an error. The biological sensor does not have fixed properties. Changes in properties occur in the normal course of life, from birth to death, and some changes in properties are interpreted as adaptations, not errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From these differences, we realize that biological sensors do not provide physical measurements in the usual sense. The next question, then, is how can a biological system control a physical dimension with biological sensors that do not act as measurements of that dimension?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 10:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Move over, Hubble. This sharp pic of Neptune was taken from Earth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/move-over-hubble-sharp-pic-neptune-was-taken-earth</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/move-over-hubble-sharp-pic-neptune-was-taken-earth</link>
	<description>A new strategy at the Very Large Telescope lets astronomers take space telescope–quality pictures from the ground.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_LG_neptune_feat.jpg?itok=mIPqkZbD" length="10084" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Hackers aim to take the stress out of medical student rotations</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hackers-aim-to-take-the-stress-out-of-medical-student-rotations</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hackers-aim-to-take-the-stress-out-of-medical-student-rotations</link>
	<description>These Elsevier Hacks winners are building an app that turns data into advice about the student’s hospital assignment</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 09:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Underestimating the power of gratitude – recipients of thank-you letters are more touched than we expect</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34283</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/18/underestimating-the-power-of-gratitude-recipients-of-thank-you-letters-are-more-touched-than-we-expect/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-499263415.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34287&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34287&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;a long haired brunette reading something moving on a white document or letter and laughing or smiling&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1403449136&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Giulio Fornasar&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;78&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;girl touched by something she read&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;girl touched by something she read&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-499263415.jpg?w=845?w=683&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-499263415.jpg?w=845?w=200&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-499263415.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1414,2121&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/18/underestimating-the-power-of-gratitude-recipients-of-thank-you-letters-are-more-touched-than-we-expect/girl-touched-by-something-she-read/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-499263415.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there: feeling so grateful to a friend or colleague that we hatch the idea of sending them a thank-you message. But then we worry about how to phrase it. And then we figure it probably won’t mean much to them anyway; if anything it could all be a bit awkward. So we don’t bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this sound familiar? According to a pair of US psychologists, a common failure of perspective means that a lot of us underestimate the positive impact on others (and ourselves) of expressing gratitude, meaning that we miss out on a simple way to improve our social relations and wellbeing. Based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797618772506&quot;&gt;their series of experiments in &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kumar-amit.com&quot;&gt;Amit Kumar&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Texas at Austin and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kumar-amit.com&quot;&gt;Nicholas Epley&lt;/a&gt; at Booth School of Business at the University of Chicago conclude that “expressing gratitude might not buy everything, but it may buy more than people seem to expect”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34283&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research involved hundreds of participants, some recruited to take part at the psych lab and others online via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk survey website. The format through some of the experiments was broadly similar. Participants were asked to write a letter of thanks via email to someone who had touched their life in a meaningful way, including expressing what the person had done and how it had affected their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across these experiments, the participants were asked to make various predictions about how the recipient would feel and perceive them. Meanwhile, the researchers made contact with the recipients to find out how they actually felt and what they actually thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The senders of the thank-you letters consistently underestimated how positive the recipients felt about receiving the letters and how surprised they were by the content. The senders also overestimated how awkward the recipients felt; and they underestimated how warm, and especially how competent, the recipients perceived them to be. Age and gender made no difference to the pattern of findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other experiments showed that these same misjudgments affect our willingness to write thank-you messages. For instance, participants who felt less competent about writing a message of gratitude were less willing to send one; and, logically enough, participants were least willing to send thank-you messages to recipients who they felt would benefit the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kumar and Epley believe that this asymmetry between the perspective of the potential expresser of gratitude and the recipient means that we often refrain from a “powerful act of civility” that would benefit both parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar dynamic could also play out in other situations. “If people engaging in prosocial actions are more concerned about competence than those benefiting from them, then our experimental results should be just one example of a broader tendency,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A methodological limitation is that the researchers were unable to reach all letter recipients and it’s possible those less impressed by the thank-you note were less willing to take part in the research. However, the available data don’t back this up – for instance, the mis-predictions of the expressers of gratitude were just as great in the experiments in which more recipients took part (therefore reducing the risk that only happy recipients had participated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are intriguing findings that complement other work by Epley and colleagues showing how our fear of awkwardness can lead us to misjudge what is in our own best interests, such as underestimating &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/08/15/were-happier-when-we-chat-to-strangers-but-our-instinct-is-to-ignore-them/&quot;&gt;how much we will enjoy interacting with strangers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797618772506&quot;&gt;Undervaluing Gratitude: Expressers Misunderstand the Consequences of Showing Appreciation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 08:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Cancerous Statistics, by Alla Astakhova</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=25298</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/18/cancerous-statistics-by-alla-astakhova/</link>
	<description>Russian officials found an ingenious way to cure cancer and to impress their autocratic president Putin: they simply rig statistics. More people die of cancer than actually officially suffer from it. Elsewhere, dead patients disappear or, according to statistics, live forever. This was reported by the Russian independent health journalist Alla Astakhova on her site, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/07/18/cancerous-statistics-by-alla-astakhova/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Cancerous Statistics, by Alla Astakhova&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: An ancient swimming revolution in the oceans may have never happened</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/devonian-swimming-revolution-oceans-may-have-never-happened</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/devonian-swimming-revolution-oceans-may-have-never-happened</link>
	<description>Swimmers may not have suddenly dominated the oceans during the Devonian Period after all: New analyses suggest they took over much more gradually.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 23:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071718_CG_nekton-fish_feat.jpg?itok=rS72JWDq" length="32793" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: LI-COR Collaborates With Science Exchange to Offer Online Access to its Molecular Imaging Services</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1676</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/07/li-cor-collaborates-with-science-exchange-to-offer-online-access-to-its-molecular-imaging-services/</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1676&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-5c676c69 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;5c676c69&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-10d8656 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;10d8656&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-40e6cb6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;40e6cb6&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;PALO ALTO, Calif.–(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BUSINESS WIRE&lt;/a&gt;)–Science Exchange, the &lt;i&gt;leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, announces a collaboration with LI-COR Biosciences to offer a suite of molecular imaging services based on LI-COR’s pioneer work in near-infrared fluorescence as a detection method.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based in Lincoln, Nebraska, LI-COR Biosciences is a world leader in innovative imaging systems for proteomics and pre-clinical research. With more than 25 years of experience in providing molecular imaging technologies worldwide, the company now offers a broad range of custom research services for scientists. From development through screening, LI-COR is positioned to lend wide-ranging R&amp;amp;D assistance to scientists with a special emphasis on western blot reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Working with Science Exchange allows us to reach key researchers focusing on pre-clinical and clinical translation applications,” says Greg Biggs, CEO of LI-COR. “Building on our established expertise in Western blot assays, protocol, and probe development and optimization, we can now offer our unique expertise in expanded areas of focus for custom services including validation, manufacturing, and analytical chemistry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Teaming up with LI-COR provides researchers with access to unique, in some cases, one of a kind services and products,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “LI-COR has a clear leadership role in advancing imaging technology especially in the use of near-infrared detection.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;bw-release-story&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;b&gt;About LI-COR Biosciences&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;LI-COR Biosciences is a pioneer in the development of near-infrared fluorescence labeling and detection systems for such areas as drug discovery, genomics, and small animal &lt;i&gt;in vivo&lt;/i&gt; imaging. LI-COR provides the complete solution for quantitative Western blots with its Odyssey® Infrared Imaging Systems, C-DiGit® Chemiluminescent Blot Scanner, Image Studio&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt; analysis software, unique IRDye® secondary antibodies, and reagents. For small animal imaging the company offers BrightSite&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt; near-infrared fluorescent probes or bioluminescence on the Pearl® Trilogy imaging system. LI-COR IRDye near-infrared dyes are being used in human clinical trials for potential therapeutic and diagnostic applications including cancer treatments and surgical visualization. For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.licor.com%2Fbio&amp;amp;esheet=51834096&amp;amp;newsitemid=20180710005813&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=www.licor.com%2Fbio&amp;amp;index=3&amp;amp;md5=7a4f91bb4886ed1cea5c8f74281f0089&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.licor.com/bio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 19:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Spike: The pitfalls of persistence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3f0b6d8e5a1e</guid>
	<link>https://medium.com/the-spike/the-pitfalls-of-persistence-3f0b6d8e5a1e?source=rss----c92c31591e3a---4</link>
	<description>&lt;h4&gt;Why your brain makes bad decisions sometimes&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*3ihSuVpUB703Yo245QA2_g.jpeg&quot; /&gt;Try and try till you succeed may not always be the best advice. (Photo credit: Raeesa Gupte)&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“I hated the movie but decided to suffer through it because I had paid for the ticket…in 3D!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“The store was overpriced but I bought the dress because I drove all the way out there.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“His business isn’t doing well but he’s sticking with it because he’s invested so much time and money in it already!”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? How many times have you persisted at a task that you know deep down is an exercise in futility?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In theory, decisions should be made based on the magnitude of future benefits for the decision-maker. However, in the real world we often make decisions based on the magnitude of past resources that have already been expended and cannot be recovered (time and money). This “sunk costs” phenomenon makes us persist with our original choices even in the face of better alternatives. If it makes you feel any better, we aren’t the only species susceptible to the sunk costs fallacy. Scientists have discovered that bad decision-making is an evolutionary glitch and exists even in animals other than humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to test if animals make bad decisions based on sunk costs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of Minnesota used a clever &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/361/6398/178&quot;&gt;experimental setup to test susceptibility to sunk costs&lt;/a&gt; across three species: mice, rats, and humans. For rats and mice, they exploited their natural tendency to forage for food. So they designed a “restaurant” for rodents where the menu consisted of four flavors of food pellets: plain, grape, chocolate, and banana (yum!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each flavor was served at a different table that had a decision-making area (offer zone) and a wait-for-the-food area (wait zone). While in the decision-making area, a tone was played that indicated how long the animal would have to wait before it got the food. The wait time varied randomly between 1-30 seconds. Here, they had the choice to either enter the wait area or skip that table and move to the next one. In the wait area, sound tones counted down to indicate how much time was left before the animal would get the food pellet. Here, the animal could choose to wait for the food or to leave at any time and move to the next table. If they left the wait area before the time ran out, they could not return to that particular flavor without going through all the other flavor tables in the restaurant first. Here’s a schematic to explain the experimental setup:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/625/1*7eYZbfm1l8P-KiF4Zffw4g.png&quot; /&gt;Credit: Sensitivity to “sunk costs” in mice, rats, and humans. Sweis BM et al., Science, 2018.&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to quantify bad decision-making influenced by sunk costs in humans?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Netflix-loving, instant streaming-craving Homo Sapiens, scientists modified the foraging task slightly. Knowing how we can all forego food and sleep while binge-watching our favorite shows online, they modeled a web-surfing task for human participants. To ensure that results could reliably be compared across species, they retained the overall basic premise of the rodent experiments while modifying it to sufficiently motivate our superior human brains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Subjects could view short videos in one of four galleries under the following categories: dance, accidents, landscapes, or kittens. They were shown how long they would have to wait for the video to download which varied randomly between 1–30 seconds. For each video they could opt to watch the video or skip and move on to the next viewing gallery (similar to the offer zone in the rodent test). Once they clicked on the “stay” option and decided to watch the video, the screen would show a download progression bar indicating how long they would have to wait to view the video (similar to the wait zone in the rodent test). The download could be quit during this wait phase to move on to the next viewing gallery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/619/1*SLRpJdZ2t63goBxElznGvg.png&quot; /&gt;Credit: Sensitivity to “sunk costs” in mice, rats, and humans. Sweis BM et al., Science, 2018.&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what’s the verdict?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that mice, rats, and humans all fell prey to the sunk cost effect. The more time that rodents spent in the wait area awaiting the food pellet, the more likely they were to persist till the end. Similarly, the longer that humans waited for the video to download, the more likely they were to stay till it finished downloading to watch it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, it turned out that the time rodents and humans took to decide on the offer had no impact on how much they then persisted in waiting for it. Only when they had committed to a particular flavor food pellet or video did their probability of persisting till the very end increase. These experiments show that we keep track of effort invested in waiting, not deciding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, the longer they waited for their chosen reward, the more likely they were to persist till the end. In short, the more resources (time/money/energy) you commit to a particular task, the stronger your resolve to stay the course even if it is to your own detriment! On the other hand, the amount of time spent waiting correlated positively with how much the reward was valued. For example, after consuming the food pellet rodents lingered longer at the table where they spent a longer time waiting and humans rated videos that took longer to download as more enjoyable. Now you know why you cherish an outcome you worked really hard for more than an easy victory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why would evolution want you to persist in the face of failure?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists postulate that two distinct decision-making algorithms may be at play in the brain when making choices based on sunk costs. Before committing to a task, the brain has to estimate its value to an organism by predicting future outcomes. This is a complex and difficult process. Therefore, brains of different species may have evolved in a similar manner to use past effort as a measure of predicting future value. Unfortunately, in many real-life scenarios there may only be a very limited correlation between past resources spent and future value to be gained. In such cases the parts of our brain that evolved to minimize wastage of resources kicks in and urges us not to stop till we have achieved our goal. So let’s hope our brains continue to learn and evolve to make better life-choices!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning lemons into lemonade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps evolution has dealt us a raw deal. But there’s a silver lining yet. Understanding the neurological basis of decision-making can have far-reaching implications for developing better educational programs, economic policies, and interventions for psychiatric disorders. For instance, understanding the neurobiology of sunk costs can aid in the treatment of addiction by developing drugs that alter the underlying malfunctioning neuronal circuitry or by use of cognitive behavioral therapy. This is not an unattainable goal given that the one thing we excel at as scientists is persistence!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can follow this crossword-solving, travel-seeking, camera-touting scientist constantly torn between coffee and chai on Twitter &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@NeuroRaeesa&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;@NeuroRaeesa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want more? Follow us at &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Spike&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=3f0b6d8e5a1e&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike/the-pitfalls-of-persistence-3f0b6d8e5a1e&quot;&gt;The pitfalls of persistence&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike&quot;&gt;The Spike&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 16:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://medium.com/feed/the-spike">The Spike - Medium</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Jupiter has 12 more moons than we knew about — and one is bizarre</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-has-12-more-moons-and-one-is-bizarre</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-has-12-more-moons-and-one-is-bizarre</link>
	<description>Astronomers found a dozen previously unknown moons of Jupiter, and one may be a remnant of a larger moon that was all but ground to dust.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071318_LG_jupiter-moons_feat.jpg?itok=mjtx-j9T" length="28519" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Study claiming “abortion reversal” is safe and effective temporarily withdrawn for ethical issues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=68339</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/17/study-claiming-abortion-reversal-is-safe-and-effective-temporarily-withdrawn-for-ethical-issues/</link>
	<description>A journal has temporarily removed a study by a researcher who has long championed a highly controversial “abortion reversal” method over concerns about its ethical approval. The study, “A Case Series Detailing the Successful Reversal of the Effects of Mifepristone Using Progesterone,” appeared in Issues In Law And Medicine in April. Its first author, George … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/17/study-claiming-abortion-reversal-is-safe-and-effective-temporarily-withdrawn-for-ethical-issues/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Study claiming “abortion reversal” is safe and effective temporarily withdrawn for ethical issues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘The Poisoned City’ chronicles Flint’s water crisis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/poisoned-city-chronicles-flint-water-crisis</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/poisoned-city-chronicles-flint-water-crisis</link>
	<description>A new book examines how lead ended up in Flint’s water and resulted in a prolonged public health disaster.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/072118_reviews_flint_feat.jpg?itok=ocGWKZCZ" length="53373" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Massive study finds that a sizeable minority of us are in jobs that don’t fit our primary occupational interests</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34275</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/17/massive-study-finds-that-a-sizeable-minority-of-us-are-in-jobs-that-dont-fit-our-primary-occupational-interests/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-841304270.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34278&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34278&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5DS&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Blurred image of business commuters crossing London Bridge, office buildings with The Shard are visible in the background, London, England&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1475692886&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.25&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Large Group of Businesspeople Walking in London Financial District, Blurred Motion&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Large Group of Businesspeople Walking in London Financial District, Blurred Motion&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-841304270.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-841304270.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-841304270.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/07/17/massive-study-finds-that-a-sizeable-minority-of-us-are-in-jobs-that-dont-fit-our-primary-occupational-interests/large-group-of-businesspeople-walking-in-london-financial-district-blurred-motion/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/gettyimages-841304270.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, our personal traits and interests should affect the jobs we pursue and where we thrive the most. This assumption is baked into the Work Psychology theory of “person-environment fit” and it’s an idea that is foundational to services we depend on like vocational guidance and career planning. But one of its key implications has until now been untested: that people who share the same job role will also have similar job interests. Now a surprising new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0001879118300447&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Vocational Behavior&lt;/i&gt; suggests that for many jobs, this simply isn’t true.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34275&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Michigan State University research team led by Christopher Nye used the Strong Interest Inventory (that measures interest in six areas: Realistic, Investigative, Artistic, Social, Enterprising and Conventional) to determine whether people in the same occupation were similar in terms of which was their top-ranked interest.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among their sample of 67,000 people, across 211 jobs, those in the same occupational role did sometimes show a strong tendency to share the same primary interest – the strongest example being for fine artists, auto mechanics and carpenters, where in each case, 82 per cent of role holders shared the same focus – Artistic for the first and Realistic for the latter two.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But people in other occupations showed much less similarity in interests. For instance, in almost half of the occupations, only the thinnest of majorities tended to share the same interest, meaning that a lot of the time two people in the exact same job often had very different occupational interests.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could the results be skewed by the sample being stacked with people trapped in jobs that they hate? This isn’t plausible, as the study only involved people who were reasonably satisfied in their role and had worked there at least three years.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible the variability was exaggerated by only focusing on the top interest. So in a second study using different occupational samples (58 datasets in total), the research team tried a more sophisticated statistical angle that looked for the degree of alignment between a person’s top three interests and the three interests conventionally considered to characterise the job. Nye’s team found that just over half the jobs showed more alignment than you would expect to see at random, but the remaining 45 per cent were the same or less. What this means is that a sizeable minority of occupations are filled by people who aren’t especially interested in the type of work their role is understood to require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defenders of person-environment fit could rustle up some retorts. You might find people with a poor fit in jobs with low barriers to entry, which are easy to fall into without any forethought. Perhaps if analysis were restricted to challenging vocations with higher barriers to entry, or people staying in jobs for a long time, there would be&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;far more congruence between interests and job roles? In fact, the first study showed no effect of occupational tenure – people longer in jobs did not have a better fit than newer incumbents. And the second study showed that employees in several jobs that require extensive preparation or specialist education also had diverse interests, such as secondary school teacher and even clergy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests we should reconsider the assumption that people are primarily drawn to jobs because of the types of things they want to do. In some cases this is sure to be true, but exceptions abound. Some people chase a job not for what it involves but for the money, or security, or the company they get to keep. And people may find ways to shape jobs around their own interests – called job crafting – or be able to draw from it rewards that may not be obvious to everyone, such as the London Tube station assistant who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/books/reviews/paperback-tunnel-visions-by-christopher-ross-9183130.html&quot;&gt;wrote a book&lt;/a&gt; on how the experience delivered to his philosophical, Investigative interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work may give some careers advisors pause for thought – occupational interests are often used as the easy shorthand to determine recommendations, but a multi-level approach considering personality and broader life goals is preferable. And for ourselves, we should allow our curiosity to be roused. When you’re next at work, why not ask your colleagues what led them to the work they are doing, and what they get from it.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;The answer is likely to surprise you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0001879118300447&quot;&gt;Do ornithologists flock together? Examining the homogeneity of interests in occupations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: A ‘reverse chatbot’ helps med students hone their diagnostic skills</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/a-reverse-chatbot-helps-med-students-hone-their-diagnostic-skills</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/a-reverse-chatbot-helps-med-students-hone-their-diagnostic-skills</link>
	<description>PatientX – created by Elsevier Hacks participants – simulates patient cases, allowing medical students to practice clinical reasoning</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 09:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Sunspot Surprise</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-84</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/OKi3qVSaRWY/scientificamerican0818-84</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 84 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-84&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-84&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Katie Peek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun's dark spots cycle every 11 years—as well as every 88, 200, and 2,400 years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/OKi3qVSaRWY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: 50, 100 &amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-83</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/4zcsn-4eu44/scientificamerican0818-83</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 83 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-83&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-83&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/4zcsn-4eu44&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: That's Life</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-82</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/4QGYvRAOwVM/scientificamerican0818-82</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 82 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-82&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-82&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent research looks at basic bodily functions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/4QGYvRAOwVM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: 23 and We</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-81</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/cUewdBHnms4/scientificamerican0818-81</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 81 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-81&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-81&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limitations of personal genome service testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/cUewdBHnms4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Recommended</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-80</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/hTCCTSecqNA/scientificamerican0818-80</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 80 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-80&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-80&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/hTCCTSecqNA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Termites and Fairy Circles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-74</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/DPlkMLAyltI/scientificamerican0818-74</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 74 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-74&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-74&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Lisa Margonelli&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactions between termites and vegetation explain mysterious patterns throughout the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/DPlkMLAyltI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Art by the Numbers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-68</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/iGS617rzIEQ/scientificamerican0818-68</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 68 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-68&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-68&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Stephen Ornes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images and sculptures inspired by mathematical principles show off the intense beauty of the discipline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/iGS617rzIEQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Monster Waves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-64</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/9dR8g0RvXb4/scientificamerican0818-64</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 64 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-64&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-64&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Chris Dixon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forecasting technology and surfer experience create record rides on the planet's biggest breakers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/9dR8g0RvXb4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Letters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-6</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/p9S9GKn_g5k/scientificamerican0818-6</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/p9S9GKn_g5k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Bringing Darwin Back</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-56</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/tQW9lji8eAA/scientificamerican0818-56</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 56 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-56&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-56&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Adam Piore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows that 60 percent of American teachers avoid or skimp on teaching evolution. A growing movement is trying to change that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/tQW9lji8eAA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Underwater</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-44</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/PsbJkLPmcyE/scientificamerican0818-44</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 44 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-44&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-44&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Jen Schwartz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coastal communities struggling to adapt to rising seas are beginning to do what was once unthinkable: retreat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/PsbJkLPmcyE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: A Sense of Discovery</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-4</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/_Xa3bzaOwzI/scientificamerican0818-4</link>
	<description>&lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 4 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/_Xa3bzaOwzI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Is Dark Matter Real?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-36</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/j2jmjQ8m4WE/scientificamerican0818-36</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 36 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-36&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-36&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Sabine Hossenfelder &amp;amp; Stacy S. McGaugh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astrophysicists have piled up observations that are difficult to explain with dark matter. It is time to consider that there may be more to gravity than Einstein taught us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/j2jmjQ8m4WE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Seventh Sense</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-28</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Gb72ZqiefQU/scientificamerican0818-28</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 28 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-28&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-28&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Jonathan Kipnis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long thought to be divorced from the brain, the immune system turns out to be intimately involved in its functioning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Gb72ZqiefQU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: I'll Have My AI Call Your AI</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-26</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8Rl4k2NPlAs/scientificamerican0818-26</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 26 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-26&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-26&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google's new assistant sounds almost scarily human&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8Rl4k2NPlAs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Ba-Boom! There Goes Your Hearing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-24</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/B9Ra66CFKGY/scientificamerican0818-24</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New discoveries offer hope for noise-induced hearing loss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/B9Ra66CFKGY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Quick Hits</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-23</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/ZZtWWkkLuRo/scientificamerican0818-23</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 23 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-23&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-23&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Maya Miller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/ZZtWWkkLuRo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Body Sense</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/KH6t5Rn1aE4/scientificamerican0818-22b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22b&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22b&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Simon Makin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental technique restores an amputee's lost sense of limb position&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/KH6t5Rn1aE4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: I(KEA), Robot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/TWHo_rxMPDU/scientificamerican0818-22a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22a&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-22a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Larry Greenemeier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new machine can assemble a DIY chair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/TWHo_rxMPDU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Can Logging Help Jaguars?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-20</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/m_4pAGtWjw4/scientificamerican0818-20</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0818-20&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0818-20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Amy Mathews Amos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well-regulated forestry operations may conserve the big cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/m_4pAGtWjw4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Wildfires are making extreme air pollution even worse in the northwest U.S.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wildfires-are-making-extreme-air-pollution-even-worse-northwest-us</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/wildfires-are-making-extreme-air-pollution-even-worse-northwest-us</link>
	<description>America’s air is getting cleaner — except in places that are prone to wildfires.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 19:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/articles/071318_LH_wildfire-air_feat_REV.jpg?itok=_SJKHdnH" length="15430" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Mental Health is Not Just the Absence of Mental Illness</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23514</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/07/16/mental-health-is-not-just-the-absence-of-mental-illness/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In an increasingly globalized and mediatized world, in which mental illness is one of society’s most discussed cultural artifacts, Colleen Patrick Goudreau’s words ring out: “If we don’t have time to be sick, then we have to make time to be healthy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the prevalence of mental health problems, it is clear why. Mental health issues are one of the leading causes of the overall disease burden globally, according to the World Health Organisation. One study reported that mental health is the primary source of disability worldwide, causing over 40 million years of disability in 20 to 29-year-olds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to previous generations, mental illness is now said to surpass the effects of the Black Death. The root causes of the unprecedented rise in people directly affected by mental illness, and the cost of this, can be considered across at least three levels of analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we don’t have time to be sick, then we have to make time to be healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleen Patrick Goudreau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the first level of analysis, the root cause of mental illness is an amalgamation of heredity, biology, environmental stressors, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2010/01/18/coping-with-trauma-lessons-from-resilient-individuals/&quot;&gt;psychological trauma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notions of specific genes being responsible for illness have been supplanted by those of genetic complexity, where various genes operate in concert with non-genetic factors to affect mental illness. That is, health-relevant biology and mental health impact each other in a complex interplay, which is inherently social.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the importance of understanding the social underpinnings of biological risk factors for mental illness, there is a relative paucity of research investigating this topic. Research that does exist, is nevertheless engrossing. For example, one study, of many, found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2006/05/15/anti-stigmatization-social-isolation-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;social isolation&lt;/a&gt; leads to increased risk of coronary heart disease. Since low levels of social integration are related to higher levels of C-reactive protein, a marker of inflammation related to coronary heart disease, social integration is posited to be a biological link between social isolation and coronary heart disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, social support affects physical perception. In a landmark study, researchers demonstrated that people accompanied by a supportive friend or those who imagined a supportive friend, estimated a hill to be less steep when compared to people who were alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mental health, like physical health, is more than the sum of functioning or malfunctioning parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the second level of analysis, the complex bio-social interplay scaffolding mental illness points to the fundamentally chemical underpinnings of human thinking and emotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With recent advances in neuroscience like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c-NMfp13Uug&quot;&gt;Clarity&lt;/a&gt;, we are now able to make the brain optically transparent, without having to section or reconstruct it, in order to examine the neuronal networks, subcellular structures, and more. In short, we can examine mental illness from a biological perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The depth and complexity of the bio-social root of mental illness, however, paints a more nuanced picture than discussed thus far. With such pioneering work, there is an increasingly popular assumption that the brain is the most important level at which to analyze human behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this vein, mental illness perpetuates itself by virtue of the fact that people often consider it to be biologically determined. In turn, a ‘trait-like’ view of mental illness establishes a status quo of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/04/stigma-towards-mental-health-stigma-impacts-vocation/&quot;&gt;mental health stigma&lt;/a&gt; by reducing empathy. Such explanations overemphasize constant factors such as biology and underemphasize modulating factors such as the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the third level of analysis, the obsession with seeing mental health in terms of mental illness reveals the fallible assumption that mental health is simply the absence of mental disorder. However, the problematic landscape of mental health draws on a far wider set of working assumptions. That is, mental health, like physical health, is more than the sum of the functioning or malfunctioning parts. It is an overall well-being that must be considered in light of unique differences between physical health, cognition, and emotions, which can be lost in a solely global evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why do we as a society ponder solving mental illness, which should have been targeted long ago, far more than we consider improving mental health? In part, because when we think of mental health, we think of raising the mean positive mental health of a population, more than closing the implementation gap between prevention, promotion, and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cumulatively, social environments are the lubricating oil to biological predispositions, which influence mental health, such that mental health and physical health should be considered holistically. In this vein, national mental health policies should not be solely concerned with mental disorders, to the detriment of mental health promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth considering how mental health issues can be targeted using proactive behavioral programs. To achieve this, it is pivotal to involve all relevant government sectors such as education, labor, justice, and welfare sectors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a diverse range of existing players, many nonprofits’, educational institutions’, and research groups’ efforts contribute to the solution landscape of mental health promotion. In Ireland, for example, schools have mental health promotional activities such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/20/re-learning-the-joy-of-living-with-journaling-and-meditation/&quot;&gt;breathing exercises&lt;/a&gt; and anger management programs. Nonprofits around the world are increasingly seeing the value of community development programmes and capacity building (strengthening the skills of communities in so they can overcome the causes of their isolation). In addition, businesses are incorporating stress management into their office culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We think of raising the mean positive mental health of a population, more than closing the implementation gap between prevention, promotion and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit to empower people to help themselves joins up these social ventures to teach us that promoting mental health is optimized when it is preventative, occurring before mental illness emerges, and when it is linked to practical skills within a community. Furthermore, these social ventures exemplify how different types of efforts (government, nonprofit, business etc.) cater to different populations, from children to corporates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these social ventures bring hope to the future and underscore the importance of sustainable change, there are still too few programs effectively targeting people, who want to maximize already existent positive mental health not just to resolve or cope with mental health issues. If we continue to take such pride in our successful problem finding and solving of mental illness that we ignore mental illness prevention and mental health promotion, we are at risk of increasing the problem we are trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heffner, K., Waring, M., Roberts, M., Eaton, C., &amp;amp; Gramling, R. (2011). Social isolation, C-reactive protein, and coronary heart disease mortality among community-dwelling adults. Social Science &amp;amp; Medicine, 72(9), 1482-1488. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.016&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lozano, R., Naghavi, M., Foreman, K., Lim, S., Shibuya, K., &amp;amp; Aboyans, V. et al. (2012). Global and regional mortality from 235 causes of death for 20 age groups in 1990 and 2010: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. The Lancet, 380(9859), 2095-2128. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(12)61728-0&quot;&gt;10.1016/s0140-6736(12)61728-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schnall, S., Harber, K., Stefanucci, J., &amp;amp; Proffitt, D. (2008). Social support and the perception of geographical slant. Journal Of Experimental Social Psychology, 44(5), 1246-1255. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jesp.2008.04.011&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jesp.2008.04.011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Wokandapix-614097/&quot;&gt;Wokandapix&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Max Plank Florida Institute for Neuroscience: Convergence of Synaptic Signals is Mediated by a Protein Critical for Learning and Memory</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10920</guid>
	<link>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/convergence-of-synaptic-signals-is-mediated-by-a-protein-critical-for-learning-and-memory/</link>
	<description>&lt;h4&gt;Researchers at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience show that protein Kinase C is a novel information integrator, keeping tabs on the recent history of neighboring synapses while simultaneously monitoring local synaptic input&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the brain, is a complex symphony of perfectly coordinated signaling. Hundreds of different molecules amplify, modify and carry information from tiny synaptic compartments all the way through the entire length of a neuron. The precise interplay of these proteins is critical for normal neuronal function; ultimately allowing the brain to achieve feats like cognition, decision making, and sensory perception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the lab of Ryohei Yasuda at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI), study the elaborate nexus of signaling proteins involved in learning and memory; looking at a unique process called synaptic plasticity, the innate ability of a neural synapse to either strengthen or weaken. Understanding how proteins behave during plasticity is key to unlocking how we learn and how memories are formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a study published in Nature Neuroscience in July 2018, Dr. Lesley Colgan, a Research Fellow in the Yasuda Lab and leading author of the paper, delves into the role that Protein Kinase C (PKC) plays in synaptic plasticity. PKC represents an entire family of 12 distinct kinases, that propagate a biochemical signal through the phosphorylation of target proteins they interact with. While previously implicated in synaptic plasticity, engineering tools sensitive enough to study PKC in the brain has been a major challenge. Yasuda’s team developed a host of sensors that can track the activity of PKCs with unprecedented specificity and sensitivity, probing when and where activation occurs as well as how these enzymes turn on and off. With these powerful sensors, they have been able to look more closely at the role that PKC plays at the single synapse level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One enzyme in the PKC family, PKCα, plays a direct role in facilitating synaptic plasticity. When PKCα activity is perturbed, plasticity is subsequently disrupted; demonstrating that the protein is a critical first step in the initial molecular cascade. PKCα also has very robust activation and is rather spine specific, confining its activity to only the stimulated spine and not spreading to the surrounding dendrites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A unique discovery of the study, found that PKCα acts to integrate two temporally distinctive signaling pathways both known to be critical for synaptic plasticity. The first is BDNF mediated, a slower, diffuse signal developing over minutes and the second, is NMDA receptor mediated calcium influx, a spine-specific signal occurring in a matter of milliseconds and necessary to begin the rapid molecular cascade of synaptic plasticity. Adaptably responding to both of these signals, PKCα is able to sample recent synaptic history and integrate it with current synaptic events, enabling complex processing of information at the single spine level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating these intriguing findings further, the team was able to successfully link molecules to memory, uncovering that PKC&lt;span&gt;α&lt;/span&gt; is required for efficiency of learning. Mice with PKC&lt;span&gt;α&lt;/span&gt; removed from the brain, take a significantly longer amount of time to become proficient at a learning task than counterparts containing intact PKC&lt;span&gt;α&lt;/span&gt; protein. Despite this lengthier learning curve, if given additional training, mice lacking PKC&lt;span&gt;α&lt;/span&gt; will eventually learn the task just as well as wild type mice; supporting the notion that PKC&lt;span&gt;α&lt;/span&gt; is critical for encoding a memory but may not play a significant role in the recall of a memory once it’s established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work represents a substantial advancement in the field, providing integral tools that will enable the disentanglement of complex signaling related to learning and memory. According to Dr. Colgan, “These newly developed sensors will have broad usage in neuroscience and cell biology alike, allowing the study of many complex signaling pathways that PKC has a hand in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was supported by National Institutes of Health, Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience and Max Planck Society. The content of this article is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the funding agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image:&lt;br /&gt;
Model of integration of TrkB and calcium signals to induce PKCα activation in paired and unpaired subthreshold stimulations. A subthreshold stimulus that was unable to induce plasticity was given alone (unpaired) or after a nearby plasticity-inducing stimulation (paired). Unpaired, the stimulus could not activate PKCα or induce plasticity. However, when paired with recent plasticity in a nearby spine, which induces a long-lasting, spreading TrkB activity, this same subthreshold stimulus led to PKCα activation and plasticity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41593-018-0184-3&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;PKCα integrates spatiotemporally distinct Ca&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and autocrine BDNF signaling to facilitate synaptic plasticity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lesley A Colgan, Mo Hu, Jaime A Misler, Paula Parra-Bueno, Corey M Moran, Michael Leitges, Ryohei Yasuda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature Neuroscience, July 16 2018, Early Release.&lt;br /&gt;
DOI: 10.1038/s41593-018-0184-3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Publicity over a memory test Trump took could skew its results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/president-trump-memory-dementia-montreal-cognitive-assessment</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/president-trump-memory-dementia-montreal-cognitive-assessment</link>
	<description>Many media outlets reporting on President Trump’s cognitive assessment test could make it harder for doctors to use the exam to spot dementia.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 15:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/07/main/blogposts/071318_lr_trump_feat.jpg?itok=ix-rFkBR" length="20279" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Spike: Why you should (or shouldn’t) get a PhD in Neuroscience</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/cdb4daf6a248</guid>
	<link>https://medium.com/the-spike/why-you-should-or-shouldnt-get-a-phd-in-neuroscience-cdb4daf6a248?source=rss----c92c31591e3a---4</link>
	<description>&lt;h4&gt;What to consider when you’re considering&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*X-GdSTSuz569RsB95GxGbA.jpeg&quot; /&gt;This is a manta ray brain in a jar and I never said it was pretty (Photo credit: Johnnie Lyman)&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps at some point during your childhood your partially-developed (and frankly, self-absorbed) brain thought to itself, “I wonder how brains work.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps you’ve been doing neuroscience research and although you’d never admit this — you kinda like poking brains. And you kinda think you could do this whole poking thing for a bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, let’s be clear — getting a PhD in neuroscience isn’t the only way to learn about the brain. You could go to the library and take out every book related to neuroscience. You could take &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcb80x.org/&quot;&gt;online courses&lt;/a&gt; in neuroscience, or with some money, you could attend classes at your nearest university.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A PhD in neuroscience gives you more than just facts, though. When it’s done right, you learn a whole array of cognitive and experimental process skills.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;You’ll learn how to assess information, develop arguments, and think critically about work in your field. You’ll also gain know-how about techniques used to conduct your research — anything from loading a matrix up in MATLAB or swiftly picking up a pipette with one hand and filling 100 mini tubes with ridiculously small amounts of highly valuable liquid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These may or may not be skills that are worth your precious time. So the question is: should you spend the next 5.5 years of your life in an intense research program?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A few good reasons why you should get a neuroscience PhD&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll open doors to different careers, and higher (paying) positions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are certain jobs that require a PhD. If you’d like to be a project manager at a pharmaceutical company, for example, you’ll need a PhD. If you want to run a lab or teach at a university, you’ll also need a PhD (and very likely postdoctoral research experience). In other cases, a PhD may earn you higher pay, but not be necessary. For instance, you can be a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2014/09/science-careers-guide-consulting-careers-phd-scientists&quot;&gt;consultant&lt;/a&gt; without a PhD, but it does give you a big advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll — hopefully — gain a lot of self confidence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you work on your PhD, you’ll primarily be working alone, making your own decisions, and grappling with the outcomes of your work. In an ideal scenario, you also have a supportive mentor and labmates, but this isn’t guaranteed. It’ll be lonely at moments, but here’s the upside: you’ll have gained experience working on a significant project that is &lt;em&gt;all yours. &lt;/em&gt;For many folks, that can be a huge confidence booster, and it should be!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll get five years of intense research experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A small portion of the population can say that they’ve worked in a lab at all, better yet for 5.5 years on their own, independent project. This experience will give you insight into the process of science and, when done right, expose you to valuable research skills for the bench and beyond. You’ll likely gain some technical skills, sure, but you’ll also learn how to design experiments and think critically about data and outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A few misguided reasons for getting a PhD in neuroscience&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You want to learn about the brain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t advise spending a sizable chunk of your life in a PhD program because you want to learn. First off, PhD programs &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ashleyjthinks/the-nitty-gritty-about-neuroscience-phd-programs-11bcdd38aa81&quot;&gt;don’t usually have that much coursework&lt;/a&gt;. Most of the learning you’ll do is on your own, and you could do that in many other ways without the opportunity cost of a PhD program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a chorus of professors somewhere maniacally laughing about this subtitle. Completing a PhD doesn’t necessarily mean you’ll make more money — whether you make the big bucks largely depends on your career path. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/emp/chart-unemployment-earnings-education.htm&quot;&gt;Across fields&lt;/a&gt;, people with PhDs &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; make more money than people with Bachelor’s or Master’s degrees, but this doesn’t take into account what those people with PhDs could have done instead. Further, there are plenty of career paths (pharmacy, biotech, data science, and consulting, to name a few) that don’t require a PhD, and pay more than many career paths in academia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;To help people&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the long run, both clinical and basic neuroscience research have an impact on humanity. I firmly believe that. But if you’re the kind of person who wants to feel like they’re doing good &lt;em&gt;on a daily basis&lt;/em&gt; — research isn’t the career for you. The gains in research are long term, and the impacts on human health and society are rarely immediate. You will occasionally talk to a stranger who will commend you on your contributions to society, though. And that’s rather nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;To PhD, or not to PhD?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it really boils down to two reasons why you should get a PhD:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;you’re positive you need a PhD to get to the next step in your career&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you’ll just really, really love 5+ years of intense research and the value that will bring to your life&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If neither of these are true, consider working in a lab for a year or two (e.g. in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/scientific-director/office-of-fellowship-and-training/fellowships-and-training-programs/postbaccalaureate-programs.shtml&quot;&gt;postbaccalaurate program&lt;/a&gt;) to test the waters. If you’re feeling convinced that a neuroscience PhD is for you, stay tuned for another post on getting into a neuroscience program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;This post is the beginning of a conversation&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This piece is part of a series that will eventually morph into a book, tentatively titled “&lt;em&gt;So you want to be a neuroscientist? An honest account of life as a researcher” (Columbia University Press). &lt;/em&gt;The goal is to offer aspiring neuroscientists honest, informative insight about our field as well as education and careers in it. Most importantly, it will reflect the opinions and experience of our entire community — so, I’d greatly appreciate your feedback. What did I miss? What do you disagree with?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=cdb4daf6a248&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike/why-you-should-or-shouldnt-get-a-phd-in-neuroscience-cdb4daf6a248&quot;&gt;Why you should (or shouldn’t) get a PhD in Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-spike&quot;&gt;The Spike&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 13:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://medium.com/feed/the-spike">The Spike - Medium</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Gluten-free turkeys? Paper on dangers of wheat-based diet in birds retracted</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=68245</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/16/gluten-free-turkeys-paper-on-dangers-of-wheat-based-diet-in-birds-retracted/</link>
	<description>The journal Scientifica has retracted a 2016 paper on gut disease in turkeys for a rafter of sins including plagiarism and authors plucked out of thin air. The article, “Role of wheat based diet on the pathology of necrotic enteritis in turkeys,” was purportedly written by a team from Pakistan and France. But it turns … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/07/16/gluten-free-turkeys-paper-on-dangers-of-wheat-based-diet-in-birds-retracted/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Gluten-free turkeys? Paper on dangers of wheat-based diet in birds retracted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Chronic sleep deprivation could be an important driver of depression in young women</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10385</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/16/chronic-sleep-deprivation-important-driver-depression-young-women/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/AdobeStock_149171725-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depression is a common psychological disorder that affects 121 million people worldwide and is the leading cause of disability when measured by years lived with disability (YLDs). Rising rates of depression diagnoses among youth, with about 20% experiencing depression before adulthood, have led many counties to prioritize initiatives that enhance prevention, early identification, and treatment efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression causes persistent feelings of sadness and loss of interest in activities of daily living, impacting overall health and wellbeing. The common misinterpretation of depressed states as transient “normal” phases of adolescence combined with widespread stigma have contributed to the current situation where the vast majority of depressed youth are not being treated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of depression among youth can lead to substance (mis)use, decreased quality of life and suicide. Furthermore, young people who experience depression are also at increased risk of having poor health and economic outcomes in adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Factors that increase the risk of depression in young people include abuse and neglect, chronic physical illness, family history of mental illness, other mental health problems and the experience of stressful life events. It has also been found that female youth develop depression twice as often as young men, although some of this difference is due to the way researchers ask questions when determining symptoms of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what about sleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep is essential for health and proper sleep for young people is critical for proper growth and it it is recommended that young people aged 13-18 years &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleepfoundation.org/press-release/national-sleep-foundation-recommends-new-sleep-times&quot;&gt;sleep 8 to 10 hours&lt;/a&gt; per night. Yet, getting enough sleep is not commonly talked about as a potential determinant of youth depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of the existing studies look at gender differences despite the fact that women and men are known to differ in the developmental course of depression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adolescence is a critical period of development that is marked by substantial reductions to slow wave and rapid eye movement sleep, increases in sleep disturbance, a circadian shift to an evening chronotype and a shortening of total duration of sleep. These neuro-endocrine changes often lead to young people lacking adequate amounts of total sleep. negative consequences of sleep deprivation include mood disturbances, poor academic performance, weight gain, increased food intake, substance use and other poor health behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between short sleep (i.e. poor quantity) and depression in young people has not been well studied. Although some investigators have used prospective study designs that allow for some inference about causality, the majority of work in this area involves cross-sectional designs which measure both sleep deprivation and depression at the same point in time so there is no way to know if disrupted sleep precedes the emergence of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the studies that are somewhat better designed to assess causality frequently measure sleep problems only once and then follow people over time to identify risk of developing depression. Although not conclusive, the results of these types of studies suggest that short sleep duration precedes depression in young people but not the reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the existing studies look at gender differences despite the fact that women and men are known to differ in the developmental course of depression, and they also experience distinct risk factors that are known to influence depression because of their biology and social status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to fill this gap in evidence using data that was collected multiple times from a large &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.basus.ca/&quot;&gt;group of young people in British Columbia (BC), Canada&lt;/a&gt;. We used answers that young people gave to questions about their sleep and awake times to determine whether they were sleep deprived and we calculated this at three time points, roughly 6 months apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design allowed us to determine the extent to which they were chronically sleep deprived. We used this information to study the cumulative effect of chronic sleep deprivation (compared to occasional or no history of sleep deprivation) on the risk of depression from a gender perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our work adds new evidence on the role of repeated sleep deprivation in young people on their risk of depression and how the effect differs by gender.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hypothesis was that chronic sleep deprivation, defined as less than 8 hours per weeknight, would be linked to higher depression levels, and that the relationship would vary between young women and young men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results showed that cumulative sleep deprivation in young women was linked to higher depression scores at the study follow-up, but there was no clear relationship among young men. The size of the effect we found was initially medium when we used simple statistical models of the relationship; however, it was smaller when we also accounted for a number of the factors that are known to influence both depression and sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work adds new evidence on the role of repeated sleep deprivation in young people on their risk of depression and how the effect differs by gender. We believe this is an important area of research that needs more attention, both in terms of thinking about these relationships and in terms of measuring them in a rigorous way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think it is important for young women to be supported in achieving the recommended amount of sleep as a potentially important way of promoting mental health among young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/07/16/chronic-sleep-deprivation-important-driver-depression-young-women/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Chronic sleep deprivation could be an important driver of depression in young women&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 11:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/07/AdobeStock_149171725-1-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
