<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: The stories of supernova 1987A, as told by Science News</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scene/stories-supernova-1987a-told-science-news</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/scene/stories-supernova-1987a-told-science-news</link>
	<description>In the wee hours of February 24, 1987, astronomers caught their first glimpse of supernova 1987A. Science News brings you that story, in multiple ways.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 16:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/2017_SN1987A_free.jpg?itok=BEWGEaO7" length="45853" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Editor steps down from journal while it investigates citation irregularities</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48451</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/24/editor-steps-journal-investigates-citation-irregularities/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The editor of the journal Land Degradation &amp;amp; Development has stepped down amidst an investigation into citation problems at the journal. The editor, Artemi Cerdà of the University of Valencia in Spain, has also disappeared from the list of editors at two journals published by the European Geophysical Union, which recently announced that one of its […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/24/editor-steps-journal-investigates-citation-irregularities/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Editor steps down from journal while it investigates citation irregularities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 16:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Neuroscientist flags errors in his days-old paper “for the sake of science integrity”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48239</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/24/neuroscientist-flags-errors-days-old-paper-sake-science-integrity/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Only days after his paper was published online, a neuroscientist has posted a comment on PubMed alerting readers to several duplication errors. Despite the issues, which the researcher says were introduced into the final manuscript after peer review, he reassured readers that they do not influence the final conclusions in the paper. On February 9, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/24/neuroscientist-flags-errors-days-old-paper-sake-science-integrity/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Neuroscientist flags errors in his days-old paper “for the sake of science integrity”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Marco Craveiro: Nerd Food: Interesting...</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2672427473119923109.post-2594682046580438413</guid>
	<link>http://mcraveiro.blogspot.com/2016/02/nerd-food-interesting.html</link>
	<description>Nerd Food: Northwind, or Using Dogen with ODB - Part II&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with.html&quot;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; of this series, we got our Oracle Express database up and running against Debian Testing. It involved quite a bit of fiddling but we seemed to get there in the end. In Part II we shall now finish the configuration of the Oracle database and set up the application dependencies. On Part III we will finally get to the Dogen model, and start to make use of ODB. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;What's in a Schema?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing we need to do to our database is add the &quot;application users&quot;. This is a common approach to most server side apps, where we tend to have &quot;service users&quot; that login to the database and act upon user requests on their behalf. We can then use audit tables to stamp the user actions so we can monitor them. We can also have application level permissions that stop users from doing silly things. This is of course a step up from the applications in the nineties, where one would have one database account for each user - allowing all sorts of weird and wonderful things such as users connecting directly to databases via ODBC and Excel or Access. I guess nowadays developers don't even know someone thought this to be a good idea at one point. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I say &quot;database user&quot;, most developers exposed to RDBMs immediately associate this to a user account. This is of course how most databases work, but &lt;i&gt;obviously&lt;/i&gt; not so with Oracle. In Oracle, &quot;users&quot; and &quot;schemas&quot; are conflated, so much so it's hard to tell if there is any difference between them. For the purist RDBM user, a schema is a &lt;i&gt;schema&lt;/i&gt; - a collection of tables and other database objects, effectively a namespace - and a user is a &lt;i&gt;user&lt;/i&gt; - a person (real or otherwise) that owns database objects. In Oracle these two more or less map to the same concept. So when you create a user, you have created a schema and you can start adding tables to it; and when you refer to database objects, you prefix them by the user name just as you would if they belonged to a schema. And, of course, you can have users that have no database objects for themselves, but which were granted permission to access database objects from other users. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So our first task is to create two schemas; these are required by the Dogen model which we will use as our &quot;application&quot;. They are: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I had created some fairly basic tests for ODB support in Dogen. Those entities were placed in the aptly named schema &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;. I then decided to extend the schema with something a bit more meaty, which is where &lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt; comes in. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the oldest readers, especially those with a Microsoft background, Northwind is bound to conjure memories. Many of us learned Microsoft Access at some point in the nineties, and in those days the samples were pure gold. I was lucky enough to learn about relational databases in my high-school days, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clipper_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Clipper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DBase&quot;&gt;dBASE IV&lt;/a&gt;, so the transition to Microsoft Access was more of an exercise in mapping than learning proper. And that's where Northwind came in. It was a &quot;large&quot; database, with forms and queries and tables and all sorts of weird and wonderful things; every time you needed something done to your database you'd check first to see how Northwind had done it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now that we are much older, of course, we can see the flaws of Northwind and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/CommunityCallToActionNOTNorthwind.aspx&quot;&gt;call for its abolition&lt;/a&gt;. But you must remember that in the nineties there was no Internet for most of us - even dial-up was pretty rare where I was - and up-to-date IT books were almost as scarce, so samples were like gold dust. So for all of these historic reasons and as an homage to my olden days, I decided to implement the Northwind schema in Dogen and ODB; it may not cover all corner cases, but it is certainly a step up on my previous &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt; tests. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enough about history and motivations. Returning to our SQLPlus from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with.html&quot;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt;, where we were logged in as &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt;, we start first by creating a table space and then the users which will make use of that table space: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create tablespace tbs_01 datafile 'tbs_f01.dbf' size 200M online;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tablespace created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create user basic identified by &quot;PASSWORD&quot; default tablespace tbs_01 quota 100M on tbs_01;&lt;br /&gt;User created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create user northwind identified by &quot;PASSWORD&quot; default tablespace tbs_01 quota 100M on tbs_01;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;User created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remember to replace &lt;code&gt;PASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; with your own passwords. This is of course a very simple setup; in the real world you would have to take great care setting the users and table spaces up, including thinking about temporary table spaces and so forth. But for our simplistic purposes this suffices. Now we need to grant these users a couple of useful privileges - again, for a real setup, you'd need quite a bit more: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create session TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create session TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create table TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create table TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create session TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create session TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create table TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create table TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;If all went well, we should now be able to exit the &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; session, start a new one with one of these users, and play with a test table: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ sqlplus northwind@XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL*Plus: Release 11.2.0.2.0 Production on Fri Feb 24 10:20:10 2017&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1982, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Connected to:&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create table test ( name varchar(10) );&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Table created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; insert into test(name) values ('kianda');&lt;br /&gt;insert into test(name) values ('kianda');&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1 row created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; select * from test;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;NAME&lt;br /&gt;----------&lt;br /&gt;kianda&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; grant select on test to basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; Disconnected from Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;$ sqlplus basic@XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL*Plus: Release 11.2.0.2.0 Production on Fri Feb 24 10:23:04 2017&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1982, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Connected to:&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; select * from northwind.test;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;NAME&lt;br /&gt;----------&lt;br /&gt;kianda&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;This all looks quite promising. To recap, we logged in with user &lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt;, created a table, inserted some random data and selected it back; all looked ok. Then for good measure, we granted the rights to see this test table to user &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;; logged in as that user and selected the test table, with the expected results. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At this point we consider our Oracle setup completed and we're ready to enter the application world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-2&quot;&gt;Enter ODB&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up ODB is fairly easy, especially if you are on Debian: you can simply obtain it from &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;synaptic&lt;/code&gt;. The only slight snag is, I could not find the oracle dependencies (i.e. &lt;code&gt;libodb-oracle&lt;/code&gt;). Likely this is because they depend on OCI, which is non-free, so Debian either does not bother to package it at all or you need some kind of special (non-free) repo for it. As it was, instead of losing myself on wild goose chases, I thought easier to build from source. And since I had to build &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; from source, might as well build &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; (or almost all) to demonstrate the whole process from scratch as it is pretty straightforward, really. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before we proceed, one warning: when it comes to the libraries, best if you either use your package manager &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; build from source. You should probably only mix-and-match if you really know what you are doing; if you do and things get tangled up, it may take you a long while to figure out the source of your woes. Note also that this warning applies to the support libraries but not to the ODB compiler itself. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, the manual approach. I first started by revisiting my previous notes on building ODB; as it happens, I had covered installing ODB from source previously &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/nerd-food-installing-latest-stable-odb.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for version 2.2. However, those instructions have largely bit-rotted at the Dogen end and things have changed slightly since that post, so a revisit is worthwhile. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As usual, we start by grabbing all of the packages from the main &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/products/odb/download.xhtml&quot;&gt;ODB website&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&quot;&gt;odb 2.4.0-1 amd64.deb&lt;/a&gt;: the ODB compiler itself. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the main ODB library, required by all backends. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-pgsql-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the PostgreSQL backend. We don't need it today, of course, but since PostgreSQL is my DB of choice I always install it. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-oracle-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the Oracle backend. We will need this one. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-boost-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the ODB boost profile. This allows using boost types in your Dogen model and having ODB do the right thing in terms of ORM mapping. Our Northwind model does not use boost at present, but I intend to change it as soon as possible as this is a very important feature for customers. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, if you are too lazy to click on links, just use &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ mkdir odb&lt;br /&gt;$ cd odb&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb -O odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;We start with the DEB, as simple as always: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package odb.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 549841 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking odb (2.4.0-1) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up odb (2.4.0-1) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for man-db (2.7.6.1-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;I tend to store locally built software under my home directory, so that's where we'll place the libraries: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ mkdir ~/local&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remember to replace &lt;code&gt;/full/path/to/local&lt;/code&gt; with your installation directory. The process is similar for the other three packages, with one crucial difference: you need to ensure the environment variables are set to place all required dependencies in the include and link path. This is achieved via the venerable environment variables &lt;code&gt;CPPFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;LDFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; (and &lt;code&gt;LD_LIBRARY_PATH&lt;/code&gt; as we shall see). You may bump into &lt;code&gt;--with-libodb&lt;/code&gt;. However, be careful; the documentation states: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If these libraries are not installed and you would like to use their build directories instead, you can use the &lt;code&gt;--with-libodb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;--with-boost&lt;/code&gt; configure options to specify their locations, for example: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --with-boost=/tmp/boost&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;So if you did &lt;code&gt;make install&lt;/code&gt;, you need the environment variables instead. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are the shell commands. First boost; do note I am relying on the presence of Debian's system boost; if you have a local build of boost, which is not in the flags below, you will also need to add a path to it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-boost-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ CPPFLAGS=-I/full/path/to/local/include LDFLAGS=-L/full/path/to/local/lib ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For PostgreSQL again I am relying on the header files installed in Debian. The commands are: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-pgsql-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ CPPFLAGS=-I/full/path/to/local/include LDFLAGS=-L/full/path/to/local/lib ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, Oracle. For this we need to supply the locations of the downloaded drivers or else ODB will not find the Oracle header and libraries. If you recall from the previous post, they are located in &lt;code&gt;/usr/include/oracle/12.1/client64&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib&lt;/code&gt;, so we must augment the flags with those two paths. In addition, I found &lt;code&gt;configure&lt;/code&gt; was failing with errors finding shared objects, so I added &lt;code&gt;LD_LIBRARY_PATH&lt;/code&gt; for good measure. The end result was as follows: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-oracle-2.4.0&lt;br /&gt;$ LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib CPPFLAGS=&quot;-I/full/path/to/local/include -I/usr/include/oracle/12.1/client64&quot; LDFLAGS=&quot;-L/full/path/to/local/lib -L/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib&quot; ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And there you are; all libraries built and installed into our local directory, ready to be used. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-3&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-3&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this part we've configured the Oracle Express database with the application users, and we sanity checked the configuration. Once that was out of the way, we built and installed all of the ODB libraries required by application code. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Part III we will finally start making use of this setup and attempt to connect to the Oracle database. Stay tuned! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;status&quot; id=&quot;postamble&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Created: 2017-02-24 Fri 12:37&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; 25.1.1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org&quot;&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt; mode 8.2.10)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;validation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.w3.org/check?uri=referer&quot;&gt;Validate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Marco Craveiro)</author>
        <enclosure url="http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb" length="" type="text/html"/>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/2672427473119923109/posts/default">Marco Craveiro</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Marco Craveiro: Nerd Food: Northwind, or Using Dogen with ODB - Part II</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2672427473119923109.post-7635453536141077559</guid>
	<link>http://mcraveiro.blogspot.com/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with_24.html</link>
	<description>Nerd Food: Northwind, or Using Dogen with ODB - Part II&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with.html&quot;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; of this series, we got our Oracle Express database up and running against Debian Testing. It involved quite a bit of fiddling but we seemed to get there in the end. In Part II we shall now finish the configuration of the Oracle database and set up the application dependencies. On Part III we will finally get to the Dogen model, and start to make use of ODB. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;What's in a Schema?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing we need to do to our database is add the &quot;application users&quot;. This is a common approach to most server side apps, where we tend to have &quot;service users&quot; that login to the database and act upon user requests on their behalf. We can then use audit tables to stamp the user actions so we can monitor them. We can also have application level permissions that stop users from doing silly things. This is of course a step up from the applications in the nineties, where one would have one database account for each user - allowing all sorts of weird and wonderful things such as users connecting directly to databases via ODBC and Excel or Access. I guess nowadays developers don't even know someone thought this to be a good idea at one point. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I say &quot;database user&quot;, most developers exposed to RDBMs immediately associate this to a user account. This is of course how most databases work, but &lt;i&gt;obviously&lt;/i&gt; not so with Oracle. In Oracle, &quot;users&quot; and &quot;schemas&quot; are conflated, so much so it's hard to tell if there is any difference between them. For the purist RDBM user, a schema is a &lt;i&gt;schema&lt;/i&gt; - a collection of tables and other database objects, effectively a namespace - and a user is a &lt;i&gt;user&lt;/i&gt; - a person (real or otherwise) that owns database objects. In Oracle these two more or less map to the same concept. So when you create a user, you have created a schema and you can start adding tables to it; and when you refer to database objects, you prefix them by the user name just as you would if they belonged to a schema. And, of course, you can have users that have no database objects for themselves, but which were granted permission to access database objects from other users. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So our first task is to create two schemas; these are required by the Dogen model which we will use as our &quot;application&quot;. They are: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I had created some fairly basic tests for ODB support in Dogen. Those entities were placed in the aptly named schema &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;. I then decided to extend the schema with something a bit more meaty, which is where &lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt; comes in. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the oldest readers, especially those with a Microsoft background, Northwind is bound to conjure memories. Many of us learned Microsoft Access at some point in the nineties, and in those days the samples were pure gold. I was lucky enough to learn about relational databases in my high-school days, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clipper_(programming_language)&quot;&gt;Clipper&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DBase&quot;&gt;dBASE IV&lt;/a&gt;, so the transition to Microsoft Access was more of an exercise in mapping than learning proper. And that's where Northwind came in. It was a &quot;large&quot; database, with forms and queries and tables and all sorts of weird and wonderful things; every time you needed something done to your database you'd check first to see how Northwind had done it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now that we are much older, of course, we can see the flaws of Northwind and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/CommunityCallToActionNOTNorthwind.aspx&quot;&gt;call for its abolition&lt;/a&gt;. But you must remember that in the nineties there was no Internet for most of us - even dial-up was pretty rare where I was - and up-to-date IT books were almost as scarce, so samples were like gold dust. So for all of these historic reasons and as an homage to my olden days, I decided to implement the Northwind schema in Dogen and ODB; it may not cover all corner cases, but it is certainly a step up on my previous &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt; tests. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enough about history and motivations. Returning to our SQLPlus from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with.html&quot;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt;, where we were logged in as &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt;, we start first by creating a table space and then the users which will make use of that table space: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create tablespace tbs_01 datafile 'tbs_f01.dbf' size 200M online;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tablespace created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create user basic identified by &quot;PASSWORD&quot; default tablespace tbs_01 quota 100M on tbs_01;&lt;br /&gt;User created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create user northwind identified by &quot;PASSWORD&quot; default tablespace tbs_01 quota 100M on tbs_01;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;User created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remember to replace &lt;code&gt;PASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; with your own passwords. This is of course a very simple setup; in the real world you would have to take great care setting the users and table spaces up, including thinking about temporary table spaces and so forth. But for our simplistic purposes this suffices. Now we need to grant these users a couple of useful privileges - again, for a real setup, you'd need quite a bit more: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create session TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create session TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create table TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create table TO basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create session TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create session TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; GRANT create table TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;GRANT create table TO northwind;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;If all went well, we should now be able to exit the &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; session, start a new one with one of these users, and play with a test table: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ sqlplus northwind@XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL*Plus: Release 11.2.0.2.0 Production on Fri Feb 24 10:20:10 2017&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1982, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Connected to:&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; create table test ( name varchar(10) );&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Table created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; insert into test(name) values ('kianda');&lt;br /&gt;insert into test(name) values ('kianda');&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1 row created.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; select * from test;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;NAME&lt;br /&gt;----------&lt;br /&gt;kianda&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; grant select on test to basic;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant succeeded.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; Disconnected from Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;$ sqlplus basic@XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL*Plus: Release 11.2.0.2.0 Production on Fri Feb 24 10:23:04 2017&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1982, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Connected to:&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; select * from northwind.test;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;NAME&lt;br /&gt;----------&lt;br /&gt;kianda&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;This all looks quite promising. To recap, we logged in with user &lt;code&gt;northwind&lt;/code&gt;, created a table, inserted some random data and selected it back; all looked ok. Then for good measure, we granted the rights to see this test table to user &lt;code&gt;basic&lt;/code&gt;; logged in as that user and selected the test table, with the expected results. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At this point we consider our Oracle setup completed and we're ready to enter the application world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-2&quot;&gt;Enter ODB&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up ODB is fairly easy, especially if you are on Debian: you can simply obtain it from &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;synaptic&lt;/code&gt;. The only slight snag is, I could not find the oracle dependencies (i.e. &lt;code&gt;libodb-oracle&lt;/code&gt;). Likely this is because they depend on OCI, which is non-free, so Debian either does not bother to package it at all or you need some kind of special (non-free) repo for it. As it was, instead of losing myself on wild goose chases, I thought easier to build from source. And since I had to build &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; from source, might as well build &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; (or almost all) to demonstrate the whole process from scratch as it is pretty straightforward, really. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before we proceed, one warning: best if you either use your package manager &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; build from source. You should probably only mix-and-match if you really know what you are doing; if you do and things get tangled up, it may take you a long while to figure out the source of your woes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, the manual approach. I first started by revisiting my previous notes on building ODB; as it happens, I had covered installing ODB from source previously &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcraveiro.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/nerd-food-installing-latest-stable-odb.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for version 2.2. However, those instructions have largely bit-rotted at the Dogen end and things have changed slightly since that post, so a revisit is worthwhile. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As usual, we start by grabbing all of the packages from the main &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/products/odb/download.xhtml&quot;&gt;ODB website&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&quot;&gt;odb 2.4.0-1 amd64.deb&lt;/a&gt;: the ODB compiler itself. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the main ODB library, required by all backends. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-pgsql-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the PostgreSQL backend. We don't need it today, of course, but since PostgreSQL is my DB of choice I always install it. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-oracle-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the Oracle backend. We will need this one. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;libodb-boost-2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;: the ODB boost profile. This allows using boost types in your Dogen model and having ODB do the right thing in terms of ORM mapping. Our Northwind model does not use boost at present, but I intend to change it as soon as possible as this is a very important feature for customers. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, if you are too lazy to click on buttons, just use &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ mkdir odb&lt;br /&gt;$ cd odb&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb -O odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ wget http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz -O libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;We start with the DEB, as simple as always: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package odb.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 549841 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking odb (2.4.0-1) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up odb (2.4.0-1) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for man-db (2.7.6.1-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;I tend to store locally built software under my home directory, so that's where we'll place the libraries: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ mkdir ~/local&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remember to replace &lt;code&gt;/full/path/to/local&lt;/code&gt; with your installation directory. The process is similar for the other three packages, with one crucial difference: you need to ensure the environment variables are set to place all required dependencies in the include and link path. This is achieved via the venerable environment variables &lt;code&gt;CPPFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;LDFLAGS&lt;/code&gt; (and &lt;code&gt;LD_LIBRARY_PATH&lt;/code&gt; as we shall see). You may bump into &lt;code&gt;--with-libodb&lt;/code&gt;. However, be careful; the documentation states: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If these libraries are not installed and you would like to use their build directories instead, you can use the &lt;code&gt;--with-libodb&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;--with-boost&lt;/code&gt; configure options to specify their locations, for example: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --with-boost=/tmp/boost&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;So if you did &lt;code&gt;make install&lt;/code&gt;, you need the environment variables instead. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are the shell commands. First boost; do note I am relying on the presence of Debian's system boost; if you have a local build of boost, which is not in the flags below, you will also need to add a path to it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-boost-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-boost-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ CPPFLAGS=-I/full/path/to/local/include LDFLAGS=-L/full/path/to/local/lib ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-boost-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For PostgreSQL again I am relying on the header files installed in Debian. The commands are: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-pgsql-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-pgsql-2.4.0/&lt;br /&gt;$ CPPFLAGS=-I/full/path/to/local/include LDFLAGS=-L/full/path/to/local/lib ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-pgsql-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, Oracle. For this we need to supply the locations of the downloaded drivers or else ODB will not find the Oracle header and libraries. If you recall from the previous post, they are located in &lt;code&gt;/usr/include/oracle/12.1/client64&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib&lt;/code&gt;, so we must augment the flags with those two paths. In addition, I found &lt;code&gt;configure&lt;/code&gt; was failing with errors finding shared objects, so I added &lt;code&gt;LD_LIBRARY_PATH&lt;/code&gt; for good measure. The end result was as follows: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd ..&lt;br /&gt;$ tar -xaf libodb-oracle-2.4.0.tar.gz&lt;br /&gt;$ cd libodb-oracle-2.4.0&lt;br /&gt;$ LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib CPPFLAGS=&quot;-I/full/path/to/local/include -I/usr/include/oracle/12.1/client64&quot; LDFLAGS=&quot;-L/full/path/to/local/lib -L/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/lib&quot; ./configure --prefix=/full/path/to/local&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;config.status: executing libtool-rpath-patch commands&lt;br /&gt;$ make -j5&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;$ make install&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;snip&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;make[1]: Leaving directory '/path/to/build/directory/odb/2.4/libodb-oracle-2.4.0'&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And there you are; all libraries built and installed into our local directory, ready to be used. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-3&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-3&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this part we've configured the Oracle Express database with the application users, and we sanity checked the configuration. Once that was out of the way, we built and installed all of the ODB libraries required by application code. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Part III we will finally start making use of this setup and attempt to connect to the Oracle database. Stay tuned! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;status&quot; id=&quot;postamble&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Created: 2017-02-24 Fri 12:32&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; 25.1.1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org&quot;&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt; mode 8.2.10)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;validation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.w3.org/check?uri=referer&quot;&gt;Validate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Marco Craveiro)</author>
        <enclosure url="http://www.codesynthesis.com/download/odb/2.4/odb_2.4.0-1_amd64.deb" length="" type="text/html"/>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/2672427473119923109/posts/default">Marco Craveiro</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Olivier Dumon on “Data as a Transformative Lever”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/olivier-dumon-on-data-as-a-transformative-lever</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/olivier-dumon-on-data-as-a-transformative-lever</link>
	<description>In the Huffington Post, an Elsevier technology leader writes about the importance of making big data actionable and transparent</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Newly identified continent Zealandia faces a battle for recognition</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newly-identified-continent-zealandia-faces-battle-recognition</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newly-identified-continent-zealandia-faces-battle-recognition</link>
	<description>Geologists make the case for a new continent, dubbed Zealandia, found largely submerged beneath the southwestern Pacific Ocean.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022217_ts_Zealandia_main_free.jpg?itok=c6c7HQR1" length="41333" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: There’s such a thing as “autism camouflaging” and it might explain why some people are diagnosed so late</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19729</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/24/theres-such-a-thing-as-autism-camouflaging-and-it-might-explain-why-some-people-are-diagnosed-so-late/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man looking into the clouds&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19737&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19737&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/Design Pics RF&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A man looking into the clouds&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A man looking into the clouds&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-97771409.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-97771409.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-97771409.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2122,1413&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/24/theres-such-a-thing-as-autism-camouflaging-and-it-might-explain-why-some-people-are-diagnosed-so-late/a-man-looking-into-the-clouds/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-97771409.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While autism is usually diagnosed in childhood, some people remain “off the radar” for a long time and only receive a diagnosis much later. One possible reason is that they have learned socially appropriate behaviours, effectively camouflaging their social difficulties, including maintaining eye contact during conversations, memorising jokes or imitating facial expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern of behaviour could have serious consequences for the lives of some people with autism. It is easy to imagine that camouflaging demands significant cognitive effort, leading to mental exhaustion over time, and in extreme cases perhaps also contributing to anxiety and depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are gender differences in camouflaging, this could also help explain the well-known male preponderance in autism spectrum disorders. At least part of the gender imbalance may, in fact, stem from an under-diagnosis of autism in girls because they are better at “masking” symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before now, autism camouflaging has not been studied in a systematic and standardised manner: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1362361316671012?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub%3dpubmed&quot;&gt;a recent open-access study&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;em&gt;Autism&lt;/em&gt;, by Meng-Chuan Lai and his colleagues, is the first to offer an operationalisation of camouflaging, which they define as the discrepancy between internal and external states in social-interpersonal contexts. For instance, if an autistic person maintains eye contact during a conversation because they have learnt that this is socially appropriate, even though this clashes with how they really want to behave, this would be an example of camouflaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19729&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lai and his colleagues used clinical instruments that are well established in autism research to measure the contrast between internal and external signs of autism among 30 women and 30 men with an established diagnosis of autism. Both gender groups were matched on age (average age: males 27.2 years and females 27.8 years) and intelligence and were free from intellectual disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers used the Autism Diagnostic Observation Schedule (ADOS), which includes several tasks requiring social interaction with an experimenter, to measure overt behaviour (external state). And they used the Autism Spectrum Quotient (ASQ; a questionnaire assessing autistic traits) and the “Reading the Mind in the Eyes” test (a computerised task that measures social cognitive ability, e.g. inferring how people feel based on their facial expression) to provide information about internal states. Relatively low scores on the ADOS (i.e. few signs of autism), combined with poor performance on the ASQ and the Reading the Mind in The Eyes, was taken as a sign of camouflaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because camouflaging likely comes at considerable cognitive and emotional costs, the researchers also studied their participants’ levels of anxiety and depression, as well as their executive function. Finally, they also used magnetic resonance imaging to scan the structure of their participants’ brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers expected, women with autism had significantly higher camouflaging scores than their male counterparts, although there was considerable variability in both groups. Across the whole sample, higher camouflaging scores were associated with higher levels of depression, but not anxiety. When looking at gender differences, the association between camouflaging and depression remained significant only in the men (so it could be speculated that men are more susceptible to the negative consequences of camouflaging). Conversely, verbal intelligence was not associated with camouflaging in either the whole sample or genders separately. Interestingly, camouflaging correlated with executive function in females, but not males. This indicated that women who camouflaged more tended to have better executive function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extent to which individuals with autism engaged in camouflaging was not related to their age. This indicates that camouflaging may not necessarily increase with greater learning experience, as might be expected with older age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuroanatomical findings differed between sexes, with links between brain structure and camouflaging generally more pronounced in the women. For instance, higher camouflaging was associated with smaller volume in temporal, cerebellar and occipital brain regions in women, but not in men. While there is no easy explanation for this sex difference, it could be speculated that the involved brain areas have a different function in camouflaging for women compared with men. These brain regions are associated with emotional processing, so perhaps they are involved in an emotional component of camouflaging that is more relevant to women. However, this needs to be rigorously examined in future studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is the first to offer systematic, methodologically sound evidence in support of higher camouflaging in women than men with autism. As such, these results support reports from parents or clinicians that hint at better social skills in girls with autism as compared with boys. However, as the study found evidence of men who engaged in camouflaging and women who did not, camouflaging is unlikely to constitute a uniquely female presentation of autism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several points that limit the scope of this study. First, the sample size was modest and only included individuals with an established diagnosis of autism who were free from intellectual disability. To study the “real world” implications of camouflaging, it would have been interesting to study people with sub-threshold autistic scores because camouflaging might be one of the reasons why they have remained below diagnostic threshold in the first place. This information might also be relevant for healthcare professionals in terms of both diagnosis and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the operationalization of camouflaging may be vulnerable to subjective bias: For example, ADOS raters may be guided by implicit gender stereotypes, leading them to give inappropriately high autism scores to girls who behave in more “boyish” ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, this study provides the first systematic definition of camouflaging in individuals with autism and shows that this behaviour is more common in women and men. These clear-cut gender differences highlight the need to consider camouflaging in clinical contexts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1362361316671012?url_ver=Z39.88-2003&amp;amp;rfr_id=ori:rid:crossref.org&amp;amp;rfr_dat=cr_pub%3dpubmed&quot;&gt;Quantifying and exploring camouflaging in men and women with autism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P&lt;strong&gt;ost written for &lt;a href=&quot;http://digest.bps.org.uk&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Helge studied psychology and clinical neurosciences. Since 2014, he is a PhD student in medical neurosciences at Charité University Hospital in Berlin, Germany, with a focus on understanding the role of the immune system in major depression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19729/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19729/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19729&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 09:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Fake stars, panda suits and ants on treadmills</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21541</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/nb-c98S-LXM/nature.2017.21541</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;February’s sharpest science shots, selected by  Nature ’s photo team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21541&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21541&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/nb-c98S-LXM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: A giant neuron found wrapped around entire mouse brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21539</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/f3tzyB-vB_0/nature.2017.21539</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;3D reconstructions show a 'crown of thorns' shape stemming from a region linked to consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21539&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21539&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/f3tzyB-vB_0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Marco Craveiro: Nerd Food: Northwind, or Using Dogen with ODB - Part I</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-2672427473119923109.post-2328739535915925594</guid>
	<link>http://mcraveiro.blogspot.com/2017/02/nerd-food-northwind-or-using-dogen-with.html</link>
	<description>Nerd Food: Northwind, or Using Dogen with ODB - Part I&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my first &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DomainDrivenConsulting/dogen&quot;&gt;Dogen&lt;/a&gt; paying customer, I finally got a chance to work with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com/products/odb/&quot;&gt;ODB&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codesynthesis.com&quot;&gt;Code Synthesis'&lt;/a&gt; amazingly interesting C++ Object-Relational Mapping tool, built on the back of the GCC plugin system. I've personally always been in awe of what Boris Kolpackov has achieved, and, of course, it being a South African company made me all the more keen to use their products. More importantly: the product just seems to rock in terms of polish, features and documentation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Astute readers of this blog will point out that Dogen has been supporting ODB for quite some time. That is indeed true, but since I haven't used this feature in anger, I wasn't sure how good the support really was; our fairly trivial database model (&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DomainDrivenConsulting/dogen/master/projects/input_models/database.dia&quot;&gt;Dia&lt;/a&gt;) explored only a small fraction of what is possible. Now that I finally had a chance to use it in production, I needed to expand the tests and try to replicate the customer's scenario as close as possible. As always in these situations, there was a snag: instead of using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.postgresql.org/&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; - the RDBMS I had originally used in my Dogen tests - they were using Oracle. So my first task was to setup Oracle locally on my beloved Debian Linux. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Never one to miss an opportunity, I decided this adventure was worthy of a quick blog post; it soon turned out to be a series of posts, if I was to do any justice to this strange and wild experiment, through all of its twists and turns. But hopefully it is worth the effort, as it also demonstrates what you can do with Dogen and ODB. And so, here we are. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first part of the series deals with just trying to convince Oracle to run on Debian Testing - something that &lt;i&gt;obviously&lt;/i&gt; Oracle does not support out of the box. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before we proceed, a word to the wise: this is a &lt;b&gt;highly experimental&lt;/b&gt;Oracle setup, which I embarked upon just because I could; follow it at your own peril, and &lt;b&gt;do not use it anywhere near production&lt;/b&gt;. More generally, if you want to stick to the beaten track, use Oracle on RHEL, CentOS or - god forbid - even Windows. All of that said, if like me, you are a Debian person, well, there's not much for it other than to fire off a VM and start looking for those damned faint tracks in the jungle. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-1&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-1&quot;&gt;Alien Worlds&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-1&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The very first stumbling block was Oracle itself. After all, for all the many years of using this RBDMS at work - more than I care to admit in polite company - I suddenly realised I actually never used it at home. Or course, Oracle has supported Linux for a little while now; and the good news is they have a &quot;free&quot; version available: Oracle Database Express Edition (XE). A quick glance at the Oracle website revealed RPM's for 64-bits (Intel only, of course). So before anything else, I decided to brush up my knowledge of Alien. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Alien is a debian package that converts RPMs into DEBs. I've used it in the past for another (lovely) Oracle technology: Java. It had worked wonderfully well then so I thought I'd give it a try. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/RPM/AlienHowto&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Alien HowTo&lt;/a&gt; is pretty straightforward, and so is &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.debian.org/Alien&quot;&gt;Debian's&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, obtain Alien: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;sudo apt-get install alien&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And then apply it to the RPM in question. So the next quest was obtaining those darn RPMs. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, once you move away from the easy world of Free and Open Source Software, things start to get a bit more complicated. Those lovely links you can easy Google for don't actually work until you sign up for an Oracle developer account, asking &lt;i&gt;all sorts&lt;/i&gt; of personal information. Sadly, even listening to Tesla earnings conferences requires registering these days. Undaunted, I filled all required fields, obtained my developer account and returned to download my loot. For Oracle Express it's rather straightforward: there is a grand-total of one package for Linux 64-bit, so you can't really go wrong. Here's the link, just in case: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/database-technologies/express-edition/downloads/index.html&quot;&gt;Oracle Express&lt;/a&gt;: download the 64-bit Linux RPM &lt;code&gt;oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm.zip&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is interesting that they decided to zip the RPM but you can easily unzip it with the &lt;code&gt;unzip&lt;/code&gt; tool. The contents are the RPM Alien expects, plus a few oracle specific files which I decided to ignore for now: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ unzip oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm.zip&lt;br /&gt;Archive:  oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm.zip&lt;br /&gt;   creating: Disk1/&lt;br /&gt;   creating: Disk1/upgrade/&lt;br /&gt;  inflating: Disk1/upgrade/gen_inst.sql&lt;br /&gt;   creating: Disk1/response/&lt;br /&gt;  inflating: Disk1/response/xe.rsp&lt;br /&gt;  inflating: Disk1/oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;From a quick glance at the instructions, it appeared the Oracle Express package contained just the database server - that meant it did not include a command line client, or the APIs to build applications that talk to the database. To be fair, this is not an entirely uncommon approach; Debian also packages the PostgreSQL server separately from the development libraries. But behind &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;synaptic&lt;/code&gt;, installation of packages is all so trivial. Not so when you have to go through lots of detailed explanations of different packages and variations. But; onwards! In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/topics/linuxx86-64soft-092277.html&quot;&gt;Instant client&lt;/a&gt; page, I settled on the downloading the following: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul class=&quot;org-ul&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Basic&lt;/i&gt;: client shared libraries. Package: &lt;code&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-basic-12.1.0.2.0-1.x86_64.rpm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;SQL Plus&lt;/i&gt;: command-line client. Package: &lt;code&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus-12.1.0.2.0-1.x86_64.rpm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;SDK&lt;/i&gt;: header files to compile code. Package: &lt;code&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-devel-12.1.0.2.0-1.x86_64.rpm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;: As it turns out, I was wrong on my original expectations, and you don't really need the SQL Plus package - its already included with Oracle Express. But I only figured it out much later, so I'll leave the steps as I originally followed them. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With all of these packages in hand, I swiftly got busy with Alien, only to also rather swiftly hit an issue: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cd Disk1&lt;br /&gt;$ alien --scripts oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm&lt;br /&gt;Must run as root to convert to deb format (or you may use fakeroot).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yes, sadly you cannot run alien directly as an unprivileged user. I did not wish to start reading up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.debian.org/FakeRoot&quot;&gt;FakeRoot&lt;/a&gt; - seems straightforward enough, to be fair, but hey - so I took the easy way out and ran all the Alien commands as root. Note also the &lt;code&gt;--scripts&lt;/code&gt; to ensure the scripts will also get converted across. This will bring us some other… interesting issues, shall we say, but seems worthwhile doing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Quite a few seconds later (hey, it was a 300 MB RPM!), a nice looking DEB was generated: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# alien --scripts oracle-xe-11.2.0-1.0.x86_64.rpm&lt;br /&gt;oracle-xe_11.2.0-2_amd64.deb generated&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;A rather promising start. For good measure, I repeated the process with all RPMs, all with similar results: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# alien oracle-instantclient12.1-basic_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-basic_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb generated&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# alien oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus-12.1.0.2.0-1.x86_64.rpm&lt;br /&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb generated&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# alien  oracle-instantclient12.1-devel-12.1.0.2.0-1.x86_64.rpm&lt;br /&gt;oracle-instantclient12.1-devel_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb generated&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Voila, all DEBs generated. Of course, as the English love to say, the proof is in the pudding - whatever that means, exactly. So before one can celebrate, you should try to install the generated packages. That can be easily done with our old trusty &lt;code&gt;dpkg&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i oracle-xe_11.2.0-2_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package oracle-xe.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 564824 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack oracle-xe_11.2.0-2_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking oracle-xe (11.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up oracle-xe (11.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Executing post-install steps...&lt;br /&gt;/var/lib/dpkg/info/oracle-xe.postinst: line 114: /sbin/chkconfig: No such file or directory&lt;br /&gt;You must run '/etc/init.d/oracle-xe configure' as the root user to configure the database.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for libc-bin (2.24-8) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for systemd (232-8) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for desktop-file-utils (0.23-1) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for gnome-menus (3.13.3-8) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for mime-support (3.60) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for mime-support (3.60) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;As it turns out, it seems the error for chkconfig is related to setting up the service to  autostart. Since this was not a key requirement for my purposes, I decided to ignore it. The remaining RPMs - or should I say DEBs - installed beautifully: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i oracle-instantclient12.1-basic_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package oracle-instantclient12.1-basic.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 564801 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack oracle-instantclient12.1-basic_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking oracle-instantclient12.1-basic (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up oracle-instantclient12.1-basic (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Processing triggers for libc-bin (2.24-8) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 567895 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up oracle-instantclient12.1-sqlplus (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# dpkg -i oracle-instantclient12.1-devel_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb&lt;br /&gt;Selecting previously unselected package oracle-instantclient12.1-devel.&lt;br /&gt;(Reading database ... 567903 files and directories currently installed.)&lt;br /&gt;Preparing to unpack oracle-instantclient12.1-devel_12.1.0.2.0-2_amd64.deb ...&lt;br /&gt;Unpacking oracle-instantclient12.1-devel (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;Setting up oracle-instantclient12.1-devel (12.1.0.2.0-2) ...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-2&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-2&quot;&gt;Talking to the Oracle&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-2&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, at this point in time we have a bunch of stuff installed in all sorts of random (read: Oracle-like) locations. The database itself is under &lt;code&gt;/u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/&lt;/code&gt;, and all the other packages seemed to have gone into &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/oracle/12.1/client64/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/usr/include/oracle/12.1/client64/&lt;/code&gt;. The first task is now to start the database server. For this we can rely on the scripts we installed earlier on. However, before we proceed, one little spoiler: we need to ensure the scripts can find &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt; at &lt;code&gt;/bin/awk&lt;/code&gt; (these days it lives in &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/awk&lt;/code&gt;). For this we can do a swift (and brutal) hack: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# ln -s /usr/bin/awk /bin/awk&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now we can configure it. I accepted all of the defaults, and setup a suitably sensible password: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# cd /etc/init.d/&lt;br /&gt;# /etc/init.d/oracle-xe configure&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Configuration&lt;br /&gt;-------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;This will configure on-boot properties of Oracle Database 11g Express&lt;br /&gt;Edition.  The following questions will determine whether the database should&lt;br /&gt;be starting upon system boot, the ports it will use, and the passwords that&lt;br /&gt;will be used for database accounts.  Press &amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt; to accept the defaults.&lt;br /&gt;Ctrl-C will abort.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Specify the HTTP port that will be used for Oracle Application Express [8080]:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Specify a port that will be used for the database listener [1521]:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Specify a password to be used for database accounts.  Note that the same&lt;br /&gt;password will be used for SYS and SYSTEM.  Oracle recommends the use of&lt;br /&gt;different passwords for each database account.  This can be done after&lt;br /&gt;initial configuration:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Confirm the password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Do you want Oracle Database 11g Express Edition to be started on boot (y/n) [y]:y&lt;br /&gt;y&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Starting Oracle Net Listener...Done&lt;br /&gt;Configuring database...&lt;br /&gt;Starting Oracle Database 11g Express Edition instance...Done&lt;br /&gt;Installation completed successfully.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Notice how your port 8080 has been hogged. If you are using it for other work, you may need to move the Oracle Application Express server to some other port. At any rate, after this I could indeed see a whole load of Oracle processes running: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ ps -ef | grep oracle&lt;br /&gt;oracle   20228     1  0 22:35 ?        00:00:00 /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/xe/bin/tnslsnr LISTENER -inhe&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21251     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_pmon_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21253     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_psp0_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21257     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_vktm_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21261     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_gen0_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21263     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_diag_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21265     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_dbrm_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21267     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_dia0_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21269     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_mman_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21271     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_dbw0_XE&lt;br /&gt;oracle   21273     1  0 22:36 ?        00:00:00 xe_lgwr_XE&lt;br /&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;To the untrained eye, this seems like a healthy start; but for more details, there are also a bunch of useful logs under the Oracle directories: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# ls -l /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/xe/config/log&lt;br /&gt;ls -l /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/xe/config/log&lt;br /&gt;total 20&lt;br /&gt;-rw-r--r-- 1 oracle dba 1369 Feb 23 22:36 CloneRmanRestore.log&lt;br /&gt;-rw-r--r-- 1 oracle dba 7377 Feb 23 22:36 cloneDBCreation.log&lt;br /&gt;-rw-r--r-- 1 oracle dba 1278 Feb 23 22:36 postDBCreation.log&lt;br /&gt;-rw-r--r-- 1 oracle dba  227 Feb 23 22:36 postScripts.log&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now, at this point in time, if all had gone according to plan we should be able to connect to our new instance. A typical trick in Oracle is to use &lt;code&gt;tnsping&lt;/code&gt; to validate the setup. For this we need to know what to ping, and that is where &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.oracle.com/database/121/NETRF/tnsnames.htm#NETRF260&quot;&gt;TNS Names&lt;/a&gt; comes in handy: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ cat /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/xe/network/admin/tnsnames.ora&lt;br /&gt;# tnsnames.ora Network Configuration File:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;XE =&lt;br /&gt;  (DESCRIPTION =&lt;br /&gt;    (ADDRESS = (PROTOCOL = TCP)(HOST = lorenz)(PORT = 1521))&lt;br /&gt;    (CONNECT_DATA =&lt;br /&gt;      (SERVER = DEDICATED)&lt;br /&gt;      (SERVICE_NAME = XE)&lt;br /&gt;    )&lt;br /&gt;  )&lt;br /&gt;...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The magic word is &lt;code&gt;XE&lt;/code&gt; (the net service name, i.e. what we will be connecting against). Now we can simply do: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ . /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0/xe/bin/oracle_env.sh&lt;br /&gt;$ tnsping XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TNS Ping Utility for Linux: Version 11.2.0.2.0 - Production on 23-FEB-2017 22:52:04&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1997, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Used parameter files:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Used TNSNAMES adapter to resolve the alias&lt;br /&gt;Attempting to contact (DESCRIPTION = (ADDRESS = (PROTOCOL = TCP)(HOST = lorenz)(PORT = 1521)) (CONNECT_DATA = (SERVER = DEDICATED) (SERVICE_NAME = XE)))&lt;br /&gt;OK (0 msec)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Success! Worth noticing that the first step was to call &lt;code&gt;oracle_env.sh&lt;/code&gt; to bring in all the required environment variables of our Oracle setup. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The final test at this stage is to ensure we can connect with SQL Plus. For this we will just rely on the &lt;code&gt;SYSTEM&lt;/code&gt; user. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;example&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$ sqlplus SYSTEM@XE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL*Plus: Release 11.2.0.2.0 Production on Thu Feb 23 22:56:31 2017&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Copyright (c) 1982, 2011, Oracle.  All rights reserved.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter password:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Connected to:&lt;br /&gt;Oracle Database 11g Express Edition Release 11.2.0.2.0 - 64bit Production&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;SQL&amp;gt; select table_name from all_tables where rownum &amp;lt; 4;&lt;br /&gt;select table_name from all_tables where rownum &amp;lt; 4;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;TABLE_NAME&lt;br /&gt;------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;ICOL$&lt;br /&gt;CON$&lt;br /&gt;UNDO$&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And there you go. We have an absolutely minimal, bare-bones setup of Oracle Express running on Debian Linux. Worth bearing in mind that if you want to make use of SQL Plus from within emacs you must make sure you start emacs on a shell that has all the variables defined in &lt;code&gt;oracle_env.sh&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;outline-2&quot; id=&quot;outline-container-sec-3&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;sec-3&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-3&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this first part we simply setup Oracle Express, and the client libraries. We also managed to prove that the setup is vaguely working by connecting to it first at a low-level via TNS ping and then at a proper client level using SQL Plus. The next part will wrap things up with the Oracle setup and then move on to ODB. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;status&quot; id=&quot;postamble&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Created: 2017-02-23 Thu 23:36&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;creator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; 25.1.1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org&quot;&gt;Org&lt;/a&gt; mode 8.2.10)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;validation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.w3.org/check?uri=referer&quot;&gt;Validate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 23:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Marco Craveiro)</author>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/2672427473119923109/posts/default">Marco Craveiro</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PLOS Neuroscience Community: To drink or not to drink, and if you do, how much–for healthy brain aging?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19167</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/9ouQB-SeLho/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;OldManWine&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/02/OldManWine-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wisdom and grace come with age, but so do mental slowing and increased risk for dementia. As the elderly population continues to grow, preserving brain health to maintain independence and quality of life into older age is a pressing concern. Researchers have identified some unsurprising factors that reduce one’s risk for cognitive decline, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4099157/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;education, exercise or a healthy diet&lt;/a&gt;. But a more controversial question that continues to perplex scientists is whether alcohol consumption might also stave off cognitive impairment with age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The aging brain on alcohol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who’s experienced the fatigue and brain fog that follow a night of heavy drinking doesn’t need science to explain the dangers of excessive alcohol intake. These health risks may be especially impactful to the older brain, which is already particularly vulnerable to environmental stressors. However, in moderation, a glass of wine or beer may not only be harmless, but may in fact also confer resilience to the aging brain against cognitive decline. Numerous studies have reported that moderate drinking is associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19546653&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lower rates of dementia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27184039&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;better cognitive performance&lt;/a&gt;, and slower decline in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15659724&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;memory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16247047&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;executive functions&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, not all studies support the notion that a nightcap can help keep the brain sharp into late life. These discrepant findings raise two obvious questions. First, why are some patterns of drinking neurobiologically healthy, while others are toxic? And second, how can we better identify drinking behaviors that promote the healthiest trajectories of cognitive aging?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neuroprotective in moderation, neurotoxic in excess&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In excess, alcohol works as a neurotoxin on many levels. Studies in animals have shown that binging on ethanol &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11981132&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kills neurons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12437579&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;impairs neurogenesis&lt;/a&gt;–the birth of new neurons–in the hippocampus, a region critical to creating new memories. Furthermore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3580328/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alcohol-induced dementia&lt;/a&gt; results from brain damage that occurs with prolonged alcohol abuse. The reasons for the observed &lt;em&gt;benefits&lt;/em&gt; of alcohol are less clear. In contrast to binge drinking, moderate alcohol intake &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16202182&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;increases neurogenesis&lt;/a&gt; and may help &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14600503&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;counteract oxidative stress&lt;/a&gt; in neurons. It’s well documented that what’s good for the heart is good for the brain, and indeed, vascular dysfunction often co-exists with or precipitates many forms of dementia.&lt;img alt=&quot;Wine Resveratrol&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-17974&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2016/01/Wine-Resveratrol-255x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;255&quot; /&gt; A prevailing theory is that the neuroprotective properties of drinking stem largely from their positive effects on cerebrovascular health. Alcohol can reduce risk for &lt;a href=&quot;http://pmj.bmj.com/content/77/914/747.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stroke and heart disease, lower blood pressure and increase HDL (“good”) cholesterol&lt;/a&gt;. However, some evidence that wine is more strongly neuroprotective than other forms of alcohol suggests that resveratrol, a potent antioxidant found in red wine, may also play a role. Although resveratrol &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2857553/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;minimizes dementia pathology&lt;/a&gt; in animals, the extremely high doses required make it unlikely to be the primary source of neuroprotection from alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unraveling healthy drinking patterns for the aging brain &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our aging population to reap the greatest benefit from alcohol, it will be essential to determine patterns of healthy drinking that are optimized for the individual. This will require, foremost, a comprehensive understanding of how alcohol distinctly affects you versus me based on our genetics, sex or lifestyle. For example, alcohol has been found to differentially influence &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15447910&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brain structure&lt;/a&gt; and risk for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC516103/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dementia&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22396249&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cognitive impairment&lt;/a&gt; for those with and without the apolipoprotein E4 gene, a strong risk factor for Alzheimer’s disease. Furthermore, studies have inconsistently reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4271023/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sex differences&lt;/a&gt; in how drinking influences cognitive decline, which may be explained by differences in how men and women metabolize alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite overwhelming evidence that moderate alcohol intake can be healthy for the aging brain, there are striking incongruences across findings–which may be due to differences in study design or confounding factors­–that muddle our understanding of alcohol’s benefits. ‘Survival bias,’ in which healthier individuals participate in studies for longer, is an unavoidable complication in longitudinal studies of aging. This could significantly skew results if unhealthy drinkers drop out early, leaving only “healthy” drinkers to be studied in very old age. Furthermore, most human studies on alcohol and brain aging rely on observed associations, which can be replete with confounding factors. For instance, it’s known that drinkers tend to live more healthy lifestyles (e.g., they may exercise more or follow a Mediterranean diet), or may drink more often simply because they’re more socially active, which alone is known &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19173101&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to be brain-healthy&lt;/a&gt;. What’s more, effects of alcohol on cognitive aging may depend on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12427876&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;type of alcohol&lt;/a&gt; consumed, how alcohol intake is measured, or the definition of “non-drinkers.” Many studies group life-long abstainers together with quitters, who may avoid alcohol due to poor health or may have developed health problems from alcohol abuse. However, my postdoctoral adviser Linda McEvoy, who studies effects of alcohol on brain aging at UC San Diego, explains that “Randomized controlled trials offer a better alternative to more definitely answer the question of how moderate alcohol intake affects cognitive function. Such trials have demonstrated beneficial cardiometabolic effects in those randomized to drink moderate amounts of alcohol.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A prescription for alcohol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite some uncertainties in the research so far, it appears that regular moderate drinking is unlikely to be hazardous to cognitive function and may even support healthy brain aging. Until we have further clarification, McEvoy offers some advice to those hoping to preserve brain health into late life: “If a person consumes alcohol, I would advise drinking moderate amounts of alcohol (one or two drinks) with dinner. If the person does not drink, I would not advise starting. Some individuals have a hard time controlling the amount they drink, and heavy drinking has detrimental effects on brain health and cognitive function.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberg E, Hofstetter CP, Olson L, Brene S. (2005). Moderate ethanol consumption increases hippocampal cell proliferation and neurogenesis in the adult mouse. &lt;em&gt;Int J Neuropsychoparmacol. &lt;/em&gt;8(4):557-67. doi:10.1017/S1461145705005286&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anstey KJ, Mack HA, Cherbuin N. (2009). Alcohol consumption as a risk factor for dementia and cognitive decline: meta-analysis of prospective studies. &lt;em&gt;Am J Geriatr Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 17(7):542-55. doi:10.1097/JGP.0b013e3181a2fd07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antilla T et al. (2004). Alcohol drinking in middle age and subsequent risk of mild cognitive impairment and dementia in old age: a prospective population based study. &lt;em&gt;BMJ&lt;/em&gt;. 329(7565):539. doi:10.1136/bmj.38181.418958.BE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beydoun et al. (2014). Epidemiologic studies of modifiable factors associated with cognition and dementia: systematic review and meta-analysis. &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;. 14:643. doi:10.1186/1471-2458-14-643&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis BJK et al. (2014). The Alcohol Paradox: Light-to-Moderate Alcohol Consumption, Cognitive Function, and Brain Volume. &lt;em&gt;J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci&lt;/em&gt;. 69(12):1528-35. doi:10.1093/gerona/glu092&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;den Heijer T et al. (2004). Alcohol intake in relation to brain magnetic resonance imaging findings in older persons without dementia. &lt;em&gt;Am J Clin Nutr&lt;/em&gt;. 80(4):992-7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ganguli M, Vaner Bilt J, Saxton JA, Shen C, Dodge HH. (2005). Alcohol consumption and cognitive function in late life: a longitudinal community study. &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;. 65(8):1210-7. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000180520.35181.24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hines LM, Rimm EB. (2001). Moderate alcohol consumption and coronary heart disease: a review. &lt;em&gt;Postgraduate Medical Journal. &lt;/em&gt;77(914):747-52. doi:10.1136/pmj.77.914.747&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Krueger KR et al. (2009). Social engagement and cognitive function in old age. &lt;em&gt;Exp Aging Res&lt;/em&gt;. 35(1):45-60. doi:10.1080/03610730802545028&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lap et al. (2009). Heterogeneity in Red Wine Polyphenolic Contents Differentially Influences Alzheimer’s Disease-type Neuropathology and Cognitive Deterioration. &lt;em&gt;J Alzheimers Dis&lt;/em&gt;. 16(1);59-72. doi:10.3233/JAD-2009-0916&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liao SL, Chen WY, Raung SL, Chen CJ. (2003). Ethanol attenuates ischemic and hypoxic injury in rat brain and cultured neurons. &lt;em&gt;Neuroreport&lt;/em&gt;. 14(16):2089-94. doi:10.1097/01.wnr.0000093754.20088.bc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nixon K, Crews FT. (2002). Binge ethanol exposure decreases neurogenesis in adult rat hippocampus. &lt;em&gt;J Neurochem&lt;/em&gt;. 83(5):1087-93.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obernier JA, Bouldin TW, Crews FT. (2002). Binge ethanol exposure in adult rats causes necrotic cell death. &lt;em&gt;Alcohol Clin Exp Res&lt;/em&gt;. 26(4):547-57.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panza F et al. (2012). Alcohol consumption in mild cognitive impairment and dementia: harmful or neuroprotective? &lt;em&gt;Int J Geriatr Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 27(12):1218-38. doi:10.1002/gps.3772&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reas ET, Laughlin GA, Kritz-Silverstein D, Barrett-Connor E, McEvoy LK. (2016). Moderate, Regular Alcohol Consumption is Associated with Higher Cognitive Function in Older Community-Dwelling Adults. &lt;em&gt;J Prev Alzheimers Dis&lt;/em&gt;. 3(2):105-13. doi:10.14283/jpad.2016.89&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ridley NJ, Draper B, Withall A. (2013). Alcohol-related dementia: an update of the evidence. &lt;em&gt;Alzheimers Res Ther&lt;/em&gt;. 5(1):3. doi: 10.1186/alzrt157&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stampfer MJ, Kang JH, Chen J, Cherry R, Grodstein F. (2005). Effects of moderate alcohol consumption on cognitive function in women. &lt;em&gt;N Eng J Med&lt;/em&gt;. 352(3):245-53. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa041152&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truelsen T, Thudium D, Gronbaek M, Copenhagen City Heart Study. (2002). Amount and type of alcohol and risk of dementia: the Copenhagen City Heart Study. &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;. 59(9):1313-9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit https://www.flickr.com/photos/jenny-pics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-17356&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/09/Reas_headshot-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emilie Reas&lt;/strong&gt; received her PhD in Neuroscience from UC San Diego, where she used fMRI to study memory. As a postdoc at UCSD, she currently studies how the brain changes with aging and disease. In addition to her tweets for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/PLOSNeuro&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@PLOSNeuro&lt;/a&gt; she is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/etreas&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@etreas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/9ouQB-SeLho&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 19:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro">PLOS Neuroscience Community</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Score! Bumblebees see how to sink ball in goal, then do it better</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/score-bumblebees-football-insect-social-learning</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/score-bumblebees-football-insect-social-learning</link>
	<description>A first lesson in six-legged soccer tests bumblebees’ ability to learn.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 19:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022217_SM_bee-soccer_main.jpg?itok=wWVlfszY" length="18871" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Bacteria’s amyloids display surprising structure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bacterias-amyloids-display-surprising-structure</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bacterias-amyloids-display-surprising-structure</link>
	<description>Protein clusters made by Staphylococcus aureus bacteria have a surprising new structure.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022317_LH_amyloid_main.jpg?itok=lg8FJVDC" length="41592" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Does labeling bad behavior “scientific misconduct” help or hurt research integrity? A debate rages</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48428</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/23/labeling-bad-behavior-scientific-misconduct-help-hurt-research-integrity-debate-rages/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Is eliminating the concept of “misconduct” a sign of progress in the fight for research integrity, or a step backward? That’s the debate playing out in Australia, where a proposal from national research bodies would make it the latest country to embrace a broader definition of ethical lapses in research, doing away with the term […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/23/labeling-bad-behavior-scientific-misconduct-help-hurt-research-integrity-debate-rages/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Does labeling bad behavior “scientific misconduct” help or hurt research integrity? A debate rages&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 18:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Human genes often best Neandertal ones in brain, testes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-genes-often-best-neandertal-ones-brain-testes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-genes-often-best-neandertal-ones-brain-testes</link>
	<description>Differing activity of human and Neandertal versions of genes may help explain health risks.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022317_TI_neanderthal-gene_main.jpg?itok=RWrqUjeK" length="25630" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “False” results in retracted paper by senator are inaccurate, not fraudulent, say editors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48346</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/23/false-results-retracted-paper-senator-inaccurate-not-fraudulent-say-editors/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, we wrote about a somewhat remarkable retraction, of a 15-year-old paper by a current Illinois senator who used to be a mathematician. At the time, we were a bit perplexed by the language of the notice, which the senator — who helpfully took our call — couldn’t answer, since he wasn’t involved in […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/23/false-results-retracted-paper-senator-inaccurate-not-fraudulent-say-editors/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“False” results in retracted paper by senator are inaccurate, not fraudulent, say editors&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Could the way we talk to children help them remember their science lessons?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19637</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/23/could-the-way-we-talk-to-children-help-them-remember-their-science-lessons/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Little scientist&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19724&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19724&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D750&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Little scientist&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1433416238&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;deucee_&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;60&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Little scientist&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Little scientist&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-489203316.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-489203316.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-489203316.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2119,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/23/could-the-way-we-talk-to-children-help-them-remember-their-science-lessons/little-scientist/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-489203316.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a parent asks their child plenty of “who?”, “what?”, “when?”, “where?”, “why?” questions, encourages them to go into detail and includes open-ended questions, psychologists call this an elaborative style. Past research has shown that children with parents like this tend to remember more experiences from their lives (the opposite parental style is to ask fewer questions in general, and to ask questions that only need a short, basic response). More specific studies have found that parents’ elaborative chat can also help their children remember museum visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022096516302296&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Child Psychology&lt;/em&gt; is the first to apply this line of research to young children’s memories of a recent science lesson. The findings provide tentative evidence that conversing with a child in an elaborative way could help them remember more about their lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19637&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelle Leichtman and her colleagues at the University of New Hampshire, USA, recruited the mothers or fathers of 40 children aged four to six from two schools, one in an upper middle-class area, the other lower middle-class. A scientist visited the children’s schools and gave an engaging, scripted lesson with props about the science of light. That evening, the researchers asked the parents to chat with their child about the lesson in whatever way they found natural, and to record the chat. Six days later, the researchers interviewed each child about the science lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an indirect link between parents’ use of an elaborative conversational style and how much their child remembered of the science lesson six days later. That is, the more elaborative the parents’ questioning, the more details the children tended to recall the evening of the lesson. In turn, children who provided more detail when chatting to their parents also tended to remember more of the lesson (including new details they hadn’t mentioned previously) when chatting to a researcher about the lesson six days later. This was true for children from both schools and regardless of the parents’ own educational background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was only one direct link between parents’ conversational style and children’s later recall in the researcher interview, and that was the amount of descriptive words that the parents used (such as “Was the flashlight &lt;em&gt;blue&lt;/em&gt;?”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research is very preliminary and needs replication. It’s correlational nature means we can’t know if parents are influencing children or if children are influencing parents. It might be both, and certainly, given the wider related research literature, it’s plausible that parents’ conversational style is having an influence. Leichtman and her colleagues highlighted several possible ways parents’ elaborative conversational style might have a benefit, including not only through encouraging greater recall, discussion and ways to connect ideas, but also at a motivational level, “impart[ing] to children a sense that the topic and details are worthy of their attention.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022096516302296&quot;&gt;Talking after school: Parents’ conversational styles and children’s memory for a science lesson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19637/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19637/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19637&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 13:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A preschooler’s bubbly personality may rub off on friends</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/preschooler%E2%80%99s-bubbly-personality-may-rub-friends</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/preschooler%E2%80%99s-bubbly-personality-may-rub-friends</link>
	<description>Scientists caught personality shifts in preschoolers over a year by observing play.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/022117_ls_personalities_main_free.jpg?itok=NMqT8vMn" length="28381" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Physics greats of the 20th century mixed science and public service</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-greats-20th-century-mixed-science-and-public-service</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physics-greats-20th-century-mixed-science-and-public-service</link>
	<description>New biographies highlight Enrico Fermi’s and Richard Garwin’s contributions to science and society.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/030417_reviews_main_free.jpg?itok=Y0qRSY7c" length="49418" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Taking a selfie could dent your self-esteem, unless you share it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19610</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/23/taking-a-selfie-could-dent-your-self-esteem-unless-you-share-it/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;dog selfie in bed&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19625&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19625&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;13&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;french bulldog dog  with  headache and hangover sleeping in bed, taking a selfie for friends and sharing&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1444081554&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;damedeeso&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;dog selfie in bed&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;dog selfie in bed&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-491247530.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-491247530.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-491247530.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1732,1732&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/23/taking-a-selfie-could-dent-your-self-esteem-unless-you-share-it/dog-selfie-in-bed/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-491247530.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking selfies makes us feel self-conscious and sends tremors through our self-esteem, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917300715&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;. One group of undergraduates at Yonsei University in Seoul used their phone’s camera to take a selfie, while a control group photographed a cup on a desk. Afterwards selfie takers showed signs of increased social sensitivity, at least according to a test that involved detecting the direction of arrows on a computer screen. The arrows appeared in locations previously occupied by the features of a face and the idea was that participants would be more focused on these facial features, and thus quicker to detect the arrows, if they were in a socially vigilant state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that selfie takers showed enhanced social sensitivity (they were quicker to detect the arrows) is consistent with the way that our social sensitivity goes up when we are in front of a mirror or when someone else points a video camera at us, making us acutely aware of the imperfections we have on show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, graduate students at the university, used this indirect measure to assess social sensitivity because they thought people might not respond honestly if they were simply asked how they were feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, the researchers used an indirect measure to test if taking a selfie affected participants’ self-esteem, specifically whether it shrunk their written signature compared to its size at the start of the study (&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/23/a-bigger-signature-correlates-with-social-bravado-and-narcissism/&quot;&gt;past research has linked bigger signatures with greater self-esteem&lt;/a&gt;). It did, but only for selfies &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; posted to social media, but simply saved to the phone. The authors speculated that the act of taking a selfie hurts self-esteem by bringing feelings about personal imperfections to the fore, but this wound can be salved through the self-promotional aspect of sharing your image to the wider world. On this reading, selfie-taking is a self-esteem rollercoaster, one that might put you back more or less where you started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917300715&quot;&gt;Selfie and self: The effect of selfies on self-esteem and social sensitivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19610/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19610/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19610&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 10:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Bees learn football from their buddies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21540</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/n_c7tLMggvY/nature.2017.21540</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The insects show sophisticated learning for non-bee related tasks, and can even improve on what they are taught.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21540&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21540&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/n_c7tLMggvY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: African countries mobilize to battle invasive caterpillar</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21527</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1K3Hlt3u62o/nature.2017.21527</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Authorities and researchers ramp up their efforts to tackle the invasive fall armyworm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21527&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21527&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1K3Hlt3u62o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Questions remain about the benefits of taking testosterone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/questions-remain-about-benefits-taking-testosterone</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/questions-remain-about-benefits-taking-testosterone</link>
	<description>For men with low testosterone, the pros and cons of taking hormone replacement therapy are mixed.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 22:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022217_mr_testosterone_free_main.jpg?itok=yytUcXyq" length="22875" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seven Earth-sized planets orbit nearby supercool star</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seven-earth-sized-planets-orbit-nearby-supercool-star</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seven-earth-sized-planets-orbit-nearby-supercool-star</link>
	<description>A planetary system called TRAPPIST-1 has seven Earth-sized planets, three in the habitable zone, researchers report.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022217_ay_7-planet_main1_free.jpg?itok=ri0_jc1m" length="13003" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Science’s questions rarely have clear, easy answers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science%E2%80%99s-questions-rarely-have-clear-easy-answers</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science%E2%80%99s-questions-rarely-have-clear-easy-answers</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses science's complexities.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers amazed by Amasia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-amazed-amasia</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-amazed-amasia</link>
	<description>Quantum spookiness, shifting landmasses and more in reader feedback.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 17:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Instead of starving a cancer, researchers go after its defenses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/instead-starving-cancer-researchers-go-after-its-defenses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/instead-starving-cancer-researchers-go-after-its-defenses</link>
	<description>There may be ways to block tumors from adapting and outrunning the body’s defenses.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 17:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/030417_hypoxia_opener.jpg?itok=4CzjopCH" length="65516" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researcher loses biotech post after reportedly confessing to fraud</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48387</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/22/researcher-loses-biotech-post-reportedly-confessing-fraud/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher has lost his position as a Chief Scientific Officer at a DNA sequencing company after he reportedly confessed to fabricating data in a 2015 paper, now retracted by the Journal of Cell Biology. According to the CEO of Karmagenes, when the company learned about the retraction, the staff “immediately” conferred and decided the researcher […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/22/researcher-loses-biotech-post-reportedly-confessing-fraud/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researcher loses biotech post after reportedly confessing to fraud&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 17:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A new reproducibility fix? Get your work checked before it’s published</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48381</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/22/new-reproducibility-fix-check-work-publishing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Most researchers by now recognize there’s a reproducibility crisis facing science. But what to do about it? Today in Nature, Jeffrey S. Mogil at McGill University and Malcolm R. Macleod at the University of Edinburgh propose a new approach: Restructure the reporting of preclinical research to include an extra “confirmatory study” performed by an independent lab, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/22/new-reproducibility-fix-check-work-publishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A new reproducibility fix? Get your work checked before it’s published&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 14:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Too many stinkbugs spoil the wine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/too-many-stinkbugs-spoil-wine</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/too-many-stinkbugs-spoil-wine</link>
	<description>Stinkbugs can ruin wine if enough are accidentally processed alive with the grapes. Three or fewer stinkbugs per grape cluster don’t have a noticeable effect on red wine.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021417_EE_stinkbug-wine_main.jpg?itok=eCbeNmJX" length="21859" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Resist or avoid? Sad study suggests bullying victims are on their own either way</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19584</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/22/resist-or-avoid-sad-study-suggests-bullying-victims-are-on-their-own-either-way/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19597&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19597&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Colleagues gossiping with sad young businessman in foreground at a bright office&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1425427873&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Wavebreakmedia&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;640&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Office workers gossiping behind a worker who looks downcast&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/22/resist-or-avoid-sad-study-suggests-bullying-victims-are-on-their-own-either-way/office-workers-gossiping-behind-a-worker-who-looks-downcast/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-465387796.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workplace bullying can corrode organisations and wreck individual lives. Research has revealed more and more about effects on victims and the motives of the perpetrators. But bullying is often a performance that demands an audience: you can’t ostracise someone from an empty room, or gossip about them to the wind. So it’s worth looking at the third ingredient in the bullying mix: the bystander. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2016.1152213&quot;&gt;New research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt; takes on this task, looking at the factors that dispose a bystander against bullying victims, and what might encourage them to step in and help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19584&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the Netherlands-based Open University recruited 161 working adults and presented each with a hypothetical workplace vignette, in which the victim was interrupted, belittled, excluded and gossiped about by a bullying colleague. In one condition, the victim was proactive, daring the bully to criticise them to their face or demanding they cease their behaviour. In another, the victim avoided the situation, by skipping out when the bully entered a room, or by taking sick leave to avoid work entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants were cast as bystanders to these contrasting situations, and Roelie Mulder’s team predicted that they would have a more negative view of the avoidant victims. Stigma research shows that people are less sympathetic to the suffering of others when they perceive they haven’t taken opportunities to improve their situation. Consistent with this, participants said they would feel more anger towards an avoidant victim, and considered them to hold much more responsibility for their predicament. Proactive victims were additionally seen as more self-reliant. So it might appear that proactivity is a good move if you want to get bystanders on-side and willing to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, that’s not the case. Participants were also asked to report how likely they would be to step in and help the victim, and they showed no greater willingness to help proactive ones. There’s a grim logic behind this: the more responsible a victim was seen to be for being bullied, the less participants wanted to help. But bystanders were also less likely to help victims they saw as self-reliant, presumably because they felt less of a pressing need to do so. You either don’t need help, or you don’t deserve it, a classic catch-22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proactivity appears admirable from the outside: in past work, most people said they would prefer to stand up to hypothetical bullies, and victims looking back on events often wish they had done so. But the reality is that when we find ourselves in these situations, it isn’t so easy – avoidance is the more common strategy – and what’s more, proactivity isn’t always the wisest choice. If you lose your cool, you could be at risk of formal consequences. And even if you play it well, a confronted bully might just double down on their behaviour. A proactive victim might be the one most in need of help, but bystanders don’t see it that way. So if you’re coming out fighting, bear in mind that you may also need to explicitly ask for help from those who seem sympathetic, but haven’t realised the need to throw their hat into the ring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00224545.2016.1152213&quot;&gt;Workplace mobbing: How the victim’s coping behavior influences bystander responses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19584/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19584/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19584&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Predicting medical students who will struggle based on their admissions characteristics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8554</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/22/predicting-medical-students-will-struggle-based-admissions-characteristics/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000012644846Medium-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many debates about the best way to select people into medical school, but one of the questions I ponder is how do we judge the success of such selection processes? There are a few problems in doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, there’s the ‘restriction of range’ problem. The people who don’t get into medical school are often lost to follow-up. We cannot easily set up an experiment to see how they might have got on in medical school, had they been admitted. This means the students we follow are only those who were successful in the selection process. So, simple correlations between selection measures and intra-medical school measures can usually only distinguish the successful from the very successful. The simplest correlations are between selection measures and assessment outcomes – many have done that, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-016-0779-x&quot;&gt;including us&lt;/a&gt;. It’s helpful but not the whole answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another measure could relate to our social responsibilities – the extent to which our selection processes match the health needs of our societies in which we practise. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nzma.org.nz/journal/read-the-journal/all-issues/2010-2019/2012/vol-125-no-1361/article-crampton&quot;&gt;Otago medical school&lt;/a&gt; has adopted the ‘mirror on society’ principle where we aim for the demographic makeup of the medical school class to match the demographic makeup of our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These areas generally try to predict success, but a third area to research is to predict difficulty. This area was the focus of our article &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12909-017-0879-2&quot;&gt;published this week in &lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Even here though, there are challenges for researchers as, in general, medical students are motivated and capable – so they mostly achieve well in medical school. This means the outcome of interest in our research (students who have difficulty in the course) are relatively infrequent –this is a desirable educational outcome, but it is a hindrance in research design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of a more &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcmededuc.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6920-11-29&quot;&gt;programmatic approach&lt;/a&gt; to assessment at the University of Otago, we keep a fairly close eye on our students and like to have sensitive measures of difficulty – we’d rather find a few who might be struggling but turn out to be doing well, than to miss a few who later get into bother. Our system is more sensitive than specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…we’d rather find a few who might be struggling but turn out to be doing well, than to miss a few who later get into bother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve found that students who are new to the country and have had less time to acculturate are at greater risk of developing problems, as are those with lower academic grades at entry and those with lower scores on the component of an aptitude test that measures understanding people. Men ran into more problems than women but no ethnic group was at greater risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as it pains me to say it, men are at greater risk of running into difficulty during their course but we’re not about to use gender as a selection measure! Although we keep trying to deny it, whichever way we look at it, academic grades still seem to be a good measure of success and difficulty – I guess doctors need to be smart. However, they also need to understand the society in which they will practise and understand people – these are measures on which we should place a greater focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/22/predicting-medical-students-will-struggle-based-admissions-characteristics/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Predicting medical students who will struggle based on their admissions characteristics&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 09:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/iStock_000012644846Medium-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Life expectancy set to hit 90 in South Korea</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21535</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pOyihIJ36ck/nature.2017.21535</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;By 2030, nation’s girls can expect to live to 91, says statistical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21535&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21535&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pOyihIJ36ck&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Why British universities are unlikely to accept invitation to set up campuses in France</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21519</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/KBOclyFu48s/nature.2017.21519</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Paris consortium hopes to lure UK institutions with promise of access to European research funds after Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21519&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21519&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/KBOclyFu48s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: These seven alien worlds could help explain how planets form</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21512</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/28wnMv644wI/nature.2017.21512</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Earth-sized astronomical bounty circles a dim star that flew under the radar of exoplanet researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21512&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21512&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/28wnMv644wI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Inside the Chinese lab poised to study world's most dangerous pathogens</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21487</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BIb8uta8_ZY/nature.2017.21487</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Maximum-security biolab is part of plan to build network of BSL-4 facilities across China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 399 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.21487&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.21487&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BIb8uta8_ZY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: No publication without confirmation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542409a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bPuyrOo6KaQ/542409a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey S. Mogil and Malcolm R. Macleod propose a new kind of paper that combines the flexibility of basic research with the rigour of clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 409 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542409a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542409a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bPuyrOo6KaQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: An epigenetics gold rush: new controls for gene expression</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542406a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/My2sl-fBTLE/542406a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;How rediscovered chemical tags on DNA and RNA are shaking up the field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 406 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542406a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542406a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/My2sl-fBTLE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Daring deep-sea explorers, armyworm offensive and GM-rice theft</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542396a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6aEDz3Wvr2c/542396a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 17–23 February 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 396 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542396a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542396a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6aEDz3Wvr2c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Pluto could be staging a comeback — and it’s not alone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/TSxqvyOQkcA/542392b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A proposal to massively expand the number of bodies called planets raises interesting questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 392 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542392b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/TSxqvyOQkcA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Gene editing in legal limbo in Europe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/thMm-U88qFA/542392a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The European Union is dragging its feet on gene-editing rules and scientists should push the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 392 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/542392a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542392a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/thMm-U88qFA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Immunology: The chronicles of T-cell exhaustion</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21508</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gWUo_98aUMM/nature21508</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;T cells of the immune system often fail to target cancer cells because they enter a dysfunctional state known as exhaustion. Molecular analysis of T-cell exhaustion provides insights into the clinical use of these cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21508&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21508&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gWUo_98aUMM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Biochemistry: Origin of a key player in methane biosynthesis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21507</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gklE6xJPrys/nature21507</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The biosynthesis of a coenzyme in the microbial production of methane has been determined — completing the biosynthetic pathways for the family of compounds that includes chlorophyll, haem and vitamin B 12 .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21507&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21507&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gklE6xJPrys&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Immunology: T-cell tweaks to target tumours</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21506</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/X9dK9uT5P6w/nature21506</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Immune cells known as T cells can destroy tumour cells, but their clinical use requires complex preparation and the cells can lose effectiveness over time. A new approach might improve the efficiency of T-cell therapy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21506&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21506&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/X9dK9uT5P6w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cardiovascular disease: Commonality with cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21505</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/kowT99peu-0/nature21505</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ageing is associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease caused by the rupture of inflamed cholesterol plaques in arteries. It emerges that this might be partly due to genetic mutations that cause cancerous changes in white blood cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21505&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21505&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/kowT99peu-0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Elucidation of the biosynthesis of the methane catalyst coenzyme F430</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21427</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/COJ4dnVXh5M/nature21427</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Methane biogenesis in methanogens is mediated by methyl-coenzyme M reductase, an enzyme that is also responsible for the utilization of methane through anaerobic methane oxidation. The enzyme uses an ancillary factor called coenzyme F430, a nickel-containing modified tetrapyrrole that promotes catalysis through a methyl radical/Ni(ii)-thiolate intermediate. However, it is unclear how coenzyme F430 is synthesized from the common primogenitor uroporphyrinogen iii, incorporating 11 steric centres into the macrocycle, although the pathway must involve chelation, amidation, macrocyclic ring reduction, lactamization and carbocyclic ring formation. Here we identify the proteins that catalyse the biosynthesis of coenzyme F430 from sirohydrochlorin, termed CfbA–CfbE, and demonstrate their activity. The research completes our understanding of how the repertoire of tetrapyrrole-based pigments are constructed, permitting the development of recombinant systems to use these metalloprosthetic groups more widely. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21427&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21427&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/COJ4dnVXh5M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Targeting a CAR to the TRAC locus with CRISPR/Cas9 enhances tumour rejection</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21405</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/9nXAWXGgJa0/nature21405</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Chimeric antigen receptors (CARs) are synthetic receptors that redirect and reprogram T cells to mediate tumour rejection. The most successful CARs used to date are those targeting CD19 (ref. 2), which offer the prospect of complete remission in patients with chemorefractory or relapsed B-cell malignancies. CARs are typically transduced into the T cells of a patient using γ-retroviral vectors or other randomly integrating vectors, which may result in clonal expansion, oncogenic transformation, variegated transgene expression and transcriptional silencing. Recent advances in genome editing enable efficient sequence-specific interventions in human cells, including targeted gene delivery to the CCR5 and AAVS1 loci. Here we show that directing a CD19-specific CAR to the T-cell receptor α constant (TRAC) locus not only results in uniform CAR expression in human peripheral blood T cells, but also enhances T-cell potency, with edited cells vastly outperforming conventionally generated CAR T cells in a mouse model of acute lymphoblastic leukaemia. We further demonstrate that targeting the CAR to the TRAC locus averts tonic CAR signalling and establishes effective internalization and re-expression of the CAR following single or repeated exposure to antigen, delaying effector T-cell differentiation and exhaustion. These findings uncover facets of CAR immunobiology and underscore the potential of CRISPR/Cas9 genome editing to advance immunotherapies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21405&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21405&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/9nXAWXGgJa0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Editing and methylation at a single site by functionally interdependent activities</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21396</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/hRVFe98NUCs/nature21396</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Nucleic acids undergo naturally occurring chemical modifications. Over 100 different modifications have been described and every position in the purine and pyrimidine bases can be modified; often the sugar is also modified. Despite recent progress, the mechanism for the biosynthesis of most modifications is not fully understood, owing, in part, to the difficulty associated with reconstituting enzyme activity in vitro. Whereas some modifications can be efficiently formed with purified components, others may require more intricate pathways. A model for modification interdependence, in which one modification is a prerequisite for another, potentially explains a major hindrance in reconstituting enzymatic activity in vitro. This model was prompted by the earlier discovery of tRNA cytosine-to-uridine editing in eukaryotes, a reaction that has not been recapitulated in vitro and the mechanism of which remains unknown. Here we show that cytosine 32 in the anticodon loop of Trypanosoma brucei tRNAThr is methylated to 3-methylcytosine (m3C) as a pre-requisite for C-to-U deamination. Formation of m3C in vitro requires the presence of both the T. brucei m3C methyltransferase TRM140 and the deaminase ADAT2/3. Once formed, m3C is deaminated to 3-methyluridine (m3U) by the same set of enzymes. ADAT2/3 is a highly mutagenic enzyme, but we also show that when co-expressed with the methyltransferase its mutagenicity is kept in check. This helps to explain how T. brucei escapes ‘wholesale deamination’ of its genome while harbouring both enzymes in the nucleus. This observation has implications for the control of another mutagenic deaminase, human AID, and provides a rationale for its regulation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 494 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21396&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21396&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/hRVFe98NUCs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Reconstitution of the tubular endoplasmic reticulum network with purified components</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21387</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/8Gvbr22RgW8/nature21387</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Organelles display characteristic morphologies that are intimately tied to their cellular function, but how organelles are shaped is poorly understood. The endoplasmic reticulum is particularly intriguing, as it comprises morphologically distinct domains, including a dynamic network of interconnected membrane tubules. Several membrane proteins have been implicated in network formation, but how exactly they mediate network formation and whether they are all required are unclear. Here we reconstitute a dynamic tubular membrane network with purified endoplasmic reticulum proteins. Proteoliposomes containing the membrane-fusing GTPase Sey1p (refs 6, 7) and the curvature-stabilizing protein Yop1p (refs 8, 9) from Saccharomyces cerevisiae form a tubular network upon addition of GTP. The tubules rapidly fragment when GTP hydrolysis of Sey1p is inhibited, indicating that network maintenance requires continuous membrane fusion and that Yop1p favours the generation of highly curved membrane structures. Sey1p also forms networks with other curvature-stabilizing proteins, including reticulon and receptor expression-enhancing proteins (REEPs) from different species. Atlastin, the vertebrate orthologue of Sey1p, forms a GTP-hydrolysis-dependent network on its own, serving as both a fusion and curvature-stabilizing protein. Our results show that organelle shape can be generated by a surprisingly small set of proteins and represents an energy-dependent steady state between formation and disassembly. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21387&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21387&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/8Gvbr22RgW8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Prefrontal cortex output circuits guide reward seeking through divergent cue encoding</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21376</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/txw2c6OSTxM/nature21376</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The prefrontal cortex is a critical neuroanatomical hub for controlling motivated behaviours across mammalian species. In addition to intra-cortical connectivity, prefrontal projection neurons innervate subcortical structures that contribute to reward-seeking behaviours, such as the ventral striatum and midline thalamus. While connectivity among these structures contributes to appetitive behaviours, how projection-specific prefrontal neurons encode reward-relevant information to guide reward seeking is unknown. Here we use in vivo two-photon calcium imaging to monitor the activity of dorsomedial prefrontal neurons in mice during an appetitive Pavlovian conditioning task. At the population level, these neurons display diverse activity patterns during the presentation of reward-predictive cues. However, recordings from prefrontal neurons with resolved projection targets reveal that individual corticostriatal neurons show response tuning to reward-predictive cues, such that excitatory cue responses are amplified across learning. By contrast, corticothalamic neurons gradually develop new, primarily inhibitory responses to reward-predictive cues across learning. Furthermore, bidirectional optogenetic manipulation of these neurons reveals that stimulation of corticostriatal neurons promotes conditioned reward-seeking behaviour after learning, while activity in corticothalamic neurons suppresses both the acquisition and expression of conditioned reward seeking. These data show how prefrontal circuitry can dynamically control reward-seeking behaviour through the opposing activities of projection-specific cell populations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21376&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21376&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/txw2c6OSTxM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Intragenic DNA methylation prevents spurious transcription initiation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21373</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/h9ClTlj5Zog/nature21373</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 In mammals, DNA methylation occurs mainly at CpG dinucleotides. Methylation of the promoter suppresses gene expression, but the functional role of gene-body DNA methylation in highly expressed genes has yet to be clarified. Here we show that, in mouse embryonic stem cells, Dnmt3b-dependent intragenic DNA methylation protects the gene body from spurious RNA polymerase II entry and cryptic transcription initiation. Using different genome-wide approaches, we demonstrate that this Dnmt3b function is dependent on its enzymatic activity and recruitment to the gene body by H3K36me3. Furthermore, the spurious transcripts can either be degraded by the RNA exosome complex or capped, polyadenylated, and delivered to the ribosome to produce aberrant proteins. Elongating RNA polymerase II therefore triggers an epigenetic crosstalk mechanism that involves SetD2, H3K36me3, Dnmt3b and DNA methylation to ensure the fidelity of gene transcription initiation, with implications for intragenic hypomethylation in cancer. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21373&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21373&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/h9ClTlj5Zog&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Complement drives glucosylceramide accumulation and tissue inflammation in Gaucher disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21368</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/a1lENTpzn14/nature21368</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Gaucher disease is caused by mutations in GBA1, which encodes the lysosomal enzyme glucocerebrosidase (GCase). GBA1 mutations drive extensive accumulation of glucosylceramide (GC) in multiple innate and adaptive immune cells in the spleen, liver, lung and bone marrow, often leading to chronic inflammation. The mechanisms that connect excess GC to tissue inflammation remain unknown. Here we show that activation of complement C5a and C5a receptor 1 (C5aR1) controls GC accumulation and the inflammatory response in experimental and clinical Gaucher disease. Marked local and systemic complement activation occurred in GCase-deficient mice or after pharmacological inhibition of GCase and was associated with GC storage, tissue inflammation and proinflammatory cytokine production. Whereas all GCase-inhibited mice died within 4–5 weeks, mice deficient in both GCase and C5aR1, and wild-type mice in which GCase and C5aR were pharmacologically inhibited, were protected from these adverse effects and consequently survived. In mice and humans, GCase deficiency was associated with strong formation of complement-activating GC-specific IgG autoantibodies, leading to complement activation and C5a generation. Subsequent C5aR1 activation controlled UDP-glucose ceramide glucosyltransferase production, thereby tipping the balance between GC formation and degradation. Thus, extensive GC storage induces complement-activating IgG autoantibodies that drive a pathway of C5a generation and C5aR1 activation that fuels a cycle of cellular GC accumulation, innate and adaptive immune cell recruitment and activation in Gaucher disease. As enzyme replacement and substrate reduction therapies are expensive and still associated with inflammation, increased risk of cancer and Parkinson disease, targeting C5aR1 may serve as a treatment option for patients with Gaucher disease and, possibly, other lysosomal storage diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21368&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21368&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/a1lENTpzn14&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The terminator</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542512a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/nKiFpliOJ1g/542512a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Dreams of another world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 512 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542512a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542512a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/nKiFpliOJ1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Molecular biology: RNA editing packs a one-two punch</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542420a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/vPLv5aqfiL4/542420a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Optimal protein synthesis requires bases in transfer RNAs to be modified. A key modification has been shown to involve an unusual two-step mechanism that entails the sequential activities of two enzymes.  See Letter    p.494&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 420 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542420a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542420a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/vPLv5aqfiL4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Stephen E. Fienberg (1942–2016)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542415a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rTtm3DRxkAg/542415a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Statistician who campaigned for better science in court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 415 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542415a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542415a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rTtm3DRxkAg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Peer review: Award bonus points to motivate reviewers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414d</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/HibFA3pNis8/542414d</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 414 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542414d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/HibFA3pNis8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Community support: Locals embrace China nuclear project</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414c</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hdMcuU1BuZw/542414c</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 414 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542414c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hdMcuU1BuZw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Viruses: Model to accelerate epidemic responses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/cetSK71QY60/542414b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 414 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542414b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/cetSK71QY60&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Population statistics: Does child survival limit family size?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/_eIjGmy0_Bw/542414a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 414 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542414a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542414a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/_eIjGmy0_Bw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Books in brief</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542413a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yUq43PyjeUs/542413a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 542 413 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/542413a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/542413a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yUq43PyjeUs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Howler monkeys may owe their color vision to leaf hue</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/howler-monkeys-may-owe-their-color-vision-leaf-hue</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/howler-monkeys-may-owe-their-color-vision-leaf-hue</link>
	<description>Better color vision gives howler monkeys an edge at finding food.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 22:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022117_lh_howlermonkey_main_free.jpg?itok=cqWt7cE-" length="24651" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Power may have passed via women in ancient Chaco Canyon society</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/power-may-have-passed-women-new-mexicos-ancient-chaco-canyon-society</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/power-may-have-passed-women-new-mexicos-ancient-chaco-canyon-society</link>
	<description>DNA points to a 330-year-long reign of a maternal dynasty centered in New Mexico’s Chaco Canyon.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 22:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/022117_BB_chaco-dna_main.jpg?itok=y2l-ek7u" length="53372" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Former postdoc admitted to fraud in cell bio paper, lead author says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48372</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/former-postdoc-admitted-fraud-cell-bio-paper-lead-author-says/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher in Switzerland has retracted her 2015 paper in the Journal of Cell Biology, saying the first author — her former postdoc — admitted to fabricating multiple aspects of the paper. After Sophie Martin of the University of Lausanne couldn’t reproduce the data from another manuscript she was preparing to submit, she contacted her former student, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/former-postdoc-admitted-fraud-cell-bio-paper-lead-author-says/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Former postdoc admitted to fraud in cell bio paper, lead author says&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Low-status chimps revealed as trendsetters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/low-status-chimps-revealed-trendsetters</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/low-status-chimps-revealed-trendsetters</link>
	<description>Outranked chimpanzees trigger spread of useful new behaviors among their comrades.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_BB_chimpanzee_main.jpg?itok=4CBFOwEC" length="37952" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Making the #CancerMoonshot a reality – starting with a conversation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/making-the-cancermoonshot-a-reality-starting-with-a-conversation</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/making-the-cancermoonshot-a-reality-starting-with-a-conversation</link>
	<description>Watch leading researchers talk about how to accelerate cancer care</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 14:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New, greener catalysts are built for speed</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-greener-catalysts-are-built-speed</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-greener-catalysts-are-built-speed</link>
	<description>Researchers are designing catalysts to move chemical reactions without using precious metals, or at least using less of them.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/030417_catalyst_feat_free_rev.jpg?itok=zb4ErLk9" length="28196" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Got “significosis?” Here are the five diseases of academic publishing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48164</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/got-significosis-five-diseases-academic-publishing/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;John Antonakis is psychologist by training, but his research has run the gamut from showing kids accurately predict election outcomes just by looking at candidates’ faces to teaching charisma to people in leadership positions. Now, as the newly appointed editor of The Leadership Quarterly, he’s tackling problems in academic publishing. But his approach is somewhat […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/21/got-significosis-five-diseases-academic-publishing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Got “significosis?” Here are the five diseases of academic publishing&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Episode 9: How To Get The Best From Your Team</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19433</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/21/episode-9-how-to-get-the-best-from-your-team/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_19569&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19569&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19569&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,768&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/21/episode-9-how-to-get-the-best-from-your-team/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/9604099396_c5e8142cf8_b.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/ulianne/9604099396/in/photolist-fCFw9C-9Kh5wK-5EWMqc-9DXH3f-hTTcbf-a3kaC1-8URYWK-84UXz4-9Rouno-ppQ9za-afN6Ze-dH3fTv-fD3srb-9ffNjs-5TTbt5-d79ZWm-8kSUdp-QAxLBZ-9oupmE-RGunuY-eKSrMR-eejV36-MMML3-RnJGEL-nybnGE-bYy4DQ-9fcV52-Gpztu-7R1LZb-8h2QC2-fY2wZR-noxBBT-cTv9Z3-4fwh5k-8v9wjM-cjK8xG-7YGZNc-jTsYyn-8Rt4B2-5XgkmS-ev3b31-bCWhXn-4GcE7q-diyuBG-6wBCat-5XgkzE-j7CbC6-a3GJCZ-a6fyCf-2ZqibA&quot;&gt;Julianne/Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psychcrunch.libsyn.com/episode-9&quot;&gt;This is Episode 9 of &lt;strong&gt;PsychCrunch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the podcast from the British Psychological Society’s Research Digest, sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;. Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;audio class=&quot;wp-audio-shortcode&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; id=&quot;audio-19433-1&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3?_=1&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Can psychology help us work together better in teams?&lt;/strong&gt; Our presenter Christian Jarrett hears about the benefits of appointing a “meta-knowledge champion” for the team, making sure everyone has contact with the team’s “extra miler”, and why you should think carefully about the physical space that you do your teamwork in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guests in order of appearance: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.essec.edu/en/staff/faculty/julija-mell&quot;&gt;Dr Julija Mell&lt;/a&gt; (Essec Business School), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net&quot;&gt;Dr Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (Research Digest writer), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psy.uq.edu.au/directory/index.html?id=1391&quot;&gt;Dr Katherine Greenaway&lt;/a&gt; (University of Queensland).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Studies discussed in the episode&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/09/08/why-your-team-should-appoint-a-meta-knowledge-champion-one-person-whos-aware-of-everyone-elses-area-of-expertise/&quot;&gt;Why your team should appoint a “meta-knowledge” champion – one person who’s aware of everyone else’s area of expertise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/03/23/team-effectiveness-is-disproportionately-influenced-by-your-groups-best-performer-or-extra-miler/&quot;&gt;Team effectiveness is disproportionately influenced by your group’s best performer or “extra-miler”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/05/25/minimalist-anonymous-rooms-are-probably-not-a-good-place-to-do-teamwork/&quot;&gt;Minimalist, anonymous rooms are probably not a good place to do teamwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/ageing-and-society/article/in-home-or-at-home-how-collective-decision-making-in-a-new-care-facility-enhances-social-interaction-and-wellbeing-amongst-older-adults/FBEDCFA8FB9B95D33919BAE18F579B8A&quot;&gt;In home or at home? How collective decision making in a new care facility enhances social interaction and wellbeing amongst older adults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related resources from &lt;em&gt;The Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-24/edition-9/towards-healthier-meetings&quot;&gt;Towards Healthier Meetings&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-25/edition-11/interview-taking-control-your-space&quot;&gt;An Interview With Dr Craig Knight: Taking Back Control Of Your Space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Episode credits&lt;/b&gt;: Presented and produced by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;Dr Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;. Mixing and editing &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffknowler.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Jeff Knowler&lt;/a&gt;. Vox pops Ella Rhodes. PsychCrunch theme music Catherine Loveday and Jeff Knowler. Additional music Zander Sehkri/Zeroday Productions (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pond5.com/stock-music/56374486/reach-impossible-epic-cinematic-orchestral-piano.html&quot;&gt;Pond5&lt;/a&gt;). Art work Tim Grimshaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3&quot;&gt;Check out this episode!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/psychcrunch/id966578696?mt=2&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=75970&amp;amp;refid=stpr&quot;&gt;Subscribe and download via Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/3FGoC927WmEteiFzdepSrR&quot;&gt;Subscribe and listen on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Past episodes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/episode-one.html&quot;&gt;Episode one: Dating and Attraction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/06/episode-two.html&quot;&gt;Episode two: Breaking Bad Habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/10/episode-three.html&quot;&gt;Episode three: How to Win an Argument&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/12/episode-4.html&quot;&gt;Episode four: The Psychology of Gift Giving&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/03/episode-5.html&quot;&gt;Episode five: How To Learn a New Language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/06/episode-6.html&quot;&gt;Episode six: How To Be Sarcastic &lt;img alt=&quot;😉&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/08/episode-7.html&quot;&gt;Episode seven: Use Psychology To Compete Like an Olympian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Episode eight: Can We Trust Psychological Studies?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PsychCrunch is sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;Routledge Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://explore.tandfonline.com/page/beh/bps-psychcrunch&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-10617&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;10617&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;PsychCrunch Banner April 16&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;936,120&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/podcast/psychcrunch-banner-april-16/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/psychcrunch-banner-sept-16-00000003.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Routledge &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/SAGCtSOZXn&quot;&gt;interviewed PsychCrunch presenter Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt; about the aims of the podcast and engaging with the public about psychology research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19433/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19433/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19433&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 12:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://traffic.libsyn.com/psychcrunch/20170220_PsychCrunch_Ep9_Mx2.mp3" length="" type="text/html"/>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Coconut crab pinches like a lion, eats like a dumpster diver</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coconut-crab-pinches-lion-eats-dumpster-diver</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/coconut-crab-pinches-lion-eats-dumpster-diver</link>
	<description>Coconut crabs use their surprisingly powerful claw for more than cracking coconuts.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/020217_SM_coconut-crab_main.jpg?itok=ZB7hg_oD" length="62613" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PubPeer blog: Vigilant scientists</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200</guid>
	<link>http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=vigilant-scientists-2</link>
	<description>In an editorial entitled “Vigilante science”, the editor-in-chief of Plant Physiology, Michael Blatt, makes the hyperbolic claim that anonymous post-publication peer review by the PubPeer community represents the most serious threat to the scientific process today. We obviously disagree. We … &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.pubpeer.com/?p=200&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 11:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blog.pubpeer.com/?feed=atom">PubPeer</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Ankur Sinha: Using Wallabag to manage your online reading list</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:ankursinha.in,2017-02-20:/blog/2017/02/20/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</guid>
	<link>http://ankursinha.in/blog/2017/02/20/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I always have quite a bit on my pending list to read - academic papers, blogs, planets, and the sort. Usually, when I go through the planets, such as the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fedoraplanet.org/&quot;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://planet.gnome.org/&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; or the two neuroscience planets I use - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/&quot;&gt;neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt;, I don't have the time to read all the articles right then. I used to either bookmark links, or note them down somewhere to read later. One day, though, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you save the article to read later and makes it available to you on multiple devices. It's extremely convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the one issue with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/getpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is that it isn't &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&quot;&gt;Free software&lt;/a&gt;. So, like I do, I went looking for an alternative. After a few hours, I ran into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It's written in PHP, and is licensed under the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://tldrlegal.com/license/mit-license&quot;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite easy to deploy, and there's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im/wallabag/wallabag&quot;&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; where you can get some help too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You either enter the URL in the Wallabag page manually, or you can use the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/wallabagger/&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/wallabagger/gbmgphmejlcoihgedabhgjdkcahacjlj&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/wallabagger/?display=en&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; addon - it let's you right click a page or a link and &quot;Wallabag.it!&quot;. There's also a bookmarklet, which you can use with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/5digits/dactyl&quot;&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt;, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code bash literal-block&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Add to ~/.pentadactylrc
&lt;/span&gt;command! wallabagit -description &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Add to wallabag&quot;&lt;/span&gt; open javascript:&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;var%20url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;location.href&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;var%20wllbg&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;window.open&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'https://app.wallabag.it/bookmarklet?url='&lt;/span&gt;%20+%20encodeURI&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'_blank'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;})()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag fetches the text of the page and stores it for you so that you can read it later. You can even organise your saved pages with tags and the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing the Wallabag main page&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a page that I'm trying to read later, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot showing an article in Wallabag&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive align-center&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played with a deployment, but decided not to deploy and maintain an instance myself. Instead, I signed up for the instance Wallabag have here - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite cheap - they have an offer going too at the moment - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://wallabag.org/en/news/wallabagit&quot;&gt;only 9€ for an entire year&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag uses a the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://fivefilters.org/content-only/&quot;&gt;FiveFilters Full Text RSS tool&lt;/a&gt; to extract the text and other data from web pages. Some websites require special instructions to tell the tool what information needs to be extracted - this tends to happen with a few academic websites. There's a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fivefilters/ftr-site-config&quot;&gt;repository of such config files here&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you do run into a website that isn't rendering properly, you can &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://doc.wallabag.org/en/master/user/errors_during_fetching.html&quot;&gt;troubleshoot the issue and submit a config file too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you decide to deploy an instance yourself, or use &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wallabag.it/en&quot;&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;, I think it's a really useful tool to have. Of course, don't forget to install the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.gaulupeau.apps.InThePoche&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;app on your phone&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 20:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml">ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “I placed too much faith in underpowered studies:” Nobel Prize winner admits mistakes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48348</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/placed-much-faith-underpowered-studies-nobel-prize-winner-admits-mistakes/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Although it’s the right thing to do, it’s never easy to admit error — particularly when you’re an extremely high-profile scientist whose work is being dissected publicly. So while it’s not a retraction, we thought this was worth noting: A Nobel Prize-winning researcher has admitted on a blog that he relied on weak studies in a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/placed-much-faith-underpowered-studies-nobel-prize-winner-admits-mistakes/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“I placed too much faith in underpowered studies:” Nobel Prize winner admits mistakes&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 17:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Textbook fail: Rosenhan’s classic “On Being Sane In Insane Places” covered without criticism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19463</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/textbook-fail-rosenhans-classic-on-being-sane-in-insane-places-covered-without-criticism/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19544&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19544&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,681&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/textbook-fail-rosenhans-classic-on-being-sane-in-insane-places-covered-without-criticism/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/16373344899_be8f8a89e1_b.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 1970s, eight mentally well people, including psychologist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Rosenhan&quot;&gt;David Rosenhan&lt;/a&gt;, presented themselves at psychiatric hospitals, where they showed signs of mild anxiety and complained of auditory hallucinations, specifically words like “empty” and “hollow”. All were admitted and either diagnosed with schizophrenia or, in one case, manic depression, and, despite acting “normal” after arrival, they were kept in hospital for an average of 19 days. On discharge all were described as having schizophrenia (or depression) “in remission”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Rosenhan’s classic study “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rosenhan_experiment&quot;&gt;On Being Sane in Insane Places&lt;/a&gt;” which he claimed showed the stigmatising power of psychiatric labels and the inability of psychiatric staff to distinguish normality from supposed abnormality, as have many others since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But from a methodological perspective, the study was problematic for a number of reasons and Rosenhan’s interpretation has been hotly disputed. In their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/50_Great_Myths_of_Popular_Psychology&quot;&gt;highly regarded book on psychology myths&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Lilienfeld&quot;&gt;Scott Lilienfeld&lt;/a&gt; and his co-authors discuss the problem with Rosenhan’s study at length, such as the fact that in the 70s “in remission” was a very rare discharge diagnosis that actually showed psychiatric staff had realised the “pseudo patients” were mentally well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Lilienfeld et al argue that it is a myth that “psychiatric labels cause harm by stigmatising people” and that the overly gullible interpretation of the Rosenhan study has helped propagate this myth. Others may disagree, but it’s at least fair to say that Rosenhan’s study had serious issues and that not all psychologists agree that psychiatric labels are in themselves harmful (consider too &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/09/02/on-being-labelled-schizophrenic-in-the-words-of-the-diagnosed/&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; that’s found that while clients say psychiatric labels can be difficult to deal with, they can also be beneficial in some ways, in terms of helping them understand their experiences and helping them to access appropriate treatments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how is this classic study covered in textbooks relating to clinical psychology and mental health (the sub-discipline usually referred to on university courses as “abnormal psychology”)? In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0098628317692634&quot;&gt;new survey&lt;/a&gt; of 12 contemporary abnormal psych textbooks in the journal &lt;em&gt;Teaching of Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, Jared Bartels and Daniel Peters found that half of them still give space to Rosenhan’s flawed study, but only two include any criticism or alternative interpretation of it at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a small survey and we’re not told the titles of the books, but the findings suggest that the problem of uncritical textbook coverage of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-21/edition-9/foundations-sand&quot;&gt;social psychology’s classic, myth-like studies&lt;/a&gt;, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/23/what-the-textbooks-dont-tell-you-one-of-psychologys-most-famous-experiments-was-seriously-flawed/&quot;&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/10/13/social-psychology-textbooks-ignore-all-modern-criticisms-of-milgrams-obedience-experiments/&quot;&gt;Milgram’s “obedience research”&lt;/a&gt;, may also extend to the realm of classic mental health-related research. Is it that textbook authors are unaware of the criticisms of the Rosenhan study? Possibly, although Bartels and Peters surmise that perhaps authors know of the issues and alternative interpretations, but that these “shortcomings … are considered less important than the edifying message of the stigmatising effect of labels”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0098628317692634&quot;&gt;Coverage of Rosenhan’s “On Being Sane in Insane Places” in Abnormal Psychology Textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/rockandrollfreak/16373344899/in/photolist-qWREZZ-rvnCZs-RG2mfN-e8NXbV-djJ8dQ-chyHGd-RQE5jk-awRCKc-ddhZ8o-bALqJc-e8UznG-bWsF9p-pGsnQV-gF5aT-bAJyhZ-cbHERd-enHVf1-dzMHiz-rNA2yv-oQ7yz5-qkmoHW-dpyYAf-sjqV61-qzJC4g-o8XMcK-dY6898-dKdfEr-eaaUSs-fLWk8J-smj7BE-bpuFRi-fLjFsz-pWwZzz-nvE2D4-QFDjPz-RkYRiw-QFDkVH-RG2kYA-RG2cMf-QFDyoP-saGLma-RJEmpZ-rxSMP2-RJESui-RJEq7t-QFEiMx-QFDgP6-p6c3zj-RRXw7J-RVASf6&quot;&gt;Flickr/Freaktography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19463/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19463/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19463&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 17:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Science of the Rorschach Blots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8562</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8562</link>
	<description>When the psychiatrist Hermann Rorschach blotted ink onto paper to produce a series of abstract patterns, could he have known that nearly 100 years later, the Rorschach test would be a household name?



Although the use of the Rorschach to diagnose mental illness is mostly a thing of the past, research on the test continues. Last week, two new papers were published on the Rorschach blots, including a fractal analysis of the images themselves and a brain scanning study using fMRI.



The</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Paper quickly retracted after author used another group’s work</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48295</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/paper-quickly-retracted-author-used-another-groups-work/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The author of a 2016 paper has agreed to retract it after an investigation revealed that most of the article came from another research group at the same university. According to the notice, the author based the majority of his paper on results generated by other scientists without their permission. Here’s the retraction notice for “Controlled synthesis […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/20/paper-quickly-retracted-author-used-another-groups-work/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paper quickly retracted after author used another group’s work&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Multi-contact synapses for stable networks: a spike-timing dependent model of dendritic spine plasticity and turnover</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-02-20:/2017/02/20/multi-contact-synapses-for-stable-networks-a-spike-timing-dependent-model-of-dendritic-spine-plasticity-and-turnover.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/02/20/multi-contact-synapses-for-stable-networks-a-spike-timing-dependent-model-of-dendritic-spine-plasticity-and-turnover.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ankur Sinha's journal club session where he discusses the pre-print paper, &quot;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1609.05730&quot;&gt;Multi-contact synapses for stable networks: a spike-timing dependent model of dendritic spine plasticity and turnover (Deger, M., Seeholzer, A., Gerstner, W. (2016))&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excitatory synaptic connections in the adult neocortex consist of multiple synaptic contacts, almost exclusively formed on dendritic spines. Changes of dendritic spine shape and volume, a correlate of synaptic strength, can be tracked in vivo for weeks. Here, we present a combined model of spike-timing dependent dendritic spine plasticity and turnover that explains the steady state multi-contact configuration of synapses in adult neocortical networks. In this model, many presynaptic neurons compete to make strong synaptic connections onto postsynaptic neurons, while the synaptic contacts comprising each connection cooperate via postsynaptic firing. We demonstrate that the model is consistent with experimentally observed long-term dendritic spine dynamics under steady-state and lesion induced conditions, and show that cooperation of multiple synaptic contacts is crucial for stable, long-term synaptic memories. In simulations of a simplified network of barrel cortex, our plasticity rule reproduces whisker-trimming induced rewiring of thalamo-cortical and recurrent synaptic connectivity on realistic time scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 25/02/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 14:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Metabolic changes associated with aging skin: genomics reveals anti-aging targets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8589</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/20/metabolic-changes-associated-aging-skin-genomics-reveals-anti-aging-targets/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Pixabay&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/skin-222664_1920-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we age, our cells reduce their ability to regenerate as effectively, pigmentation increases, and wrinkles emerge. All of us experience some form of detriment to the skin, which cosmetic companies seek to re-mediate. For less of us, aging on the skin poses more serious issues such as cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our metabolism is key to supporting the function of the skin, such as the regulation of collagen and water. However, very little is currently known about metabolic alterations in aged skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessing metabolic changes at the genomic level can lead to new solutions to prevent age induced skin disorders. In the scientific community, it is well established that gene expression adaptions and metabolic changes accompany skin degradation. It has been observed that DNA repair capacities reduce, and methylation changes lead to decreased cellular plasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcgenomics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12864-017-3547-3&quot;&gt;Recently published research&lt;/a&gt; from ETH Zurich provides valuable information on the metabolic adaptions of aging skin, and may benefit cosmetic companies to devise new solutions for age induced skin deterioration. These adaptions were observed in young (20-25 year old) and old (55-66 years old) human females by analyzing the RNA and metabolites of their skin’s epidermis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key discovery in the aged skin was the reduction of Q10; a coenzyme present within most animals. Often found within eukaryotic cells, Q10 is protein soluble, and can be seen in the market place as a health supplement for regulating energy in the body. Observed alterations to the processing of glucose (glycolysis), the reduced biosynthesis of protein and the organic compound polyamine are also discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Q10 decreased, there was a rise in the levels of taurine, the bio-marker cresol, and α-CEHC – the vitamin E metabolite. Metabolites for Vitamin E play an important role by providing anti-oxidative functions and preventing oxidative damage induced by UV energy. Most amino acid metabolites accumulated with age, helping to counteract dry skin by promoting moisturization of the epidermis, as the authors discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying metabolome and transcriptome analyses to human epidermal samples has provided insight into the metabolic adaptions associated with skin aging. Various metabolites are observed to have remedial effects on aging skin, which may help improve anti-aging skin products in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/20/metabolic-changes-associated-aging-skin-genomics-reveals-anti-aging-targets/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Metabolic changes associated with aging skin: genomics reveals anti-aging targets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/skin-222664_1920-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Concerning study says psychotherapy research has a problem with undeclared researcher bias</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19408</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/concerning-study-says-psychotherapy-research-has-a-problem-with-undeclared-researcher-bias/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;sharp rise&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19430&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19430&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/Zoonar RF&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sharp rise&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;sharp rise&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/20/concerning-study-says-psychotherapy-research-has-a-problem-with-undeclared-researcher-bias/sharp-rise/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/thinkstockphotos-127001463.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a good doctor encounters research comparing the effectiveness of drugs A and B, she knows to beware the fact that B was created by the people paying the researchers’ salaries. Pharmaceutical industry funding can be complex, but the general principle of declaring financial conflicts of interest is now embedded in medical research culture. Unfortunately, research into psychological therapies doesn’t yet seem to have got its house in order in an equivalent way. That’s according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/6/4/e010606.long&quot;&gt;new open access article&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;em&gt;BMJ Open&lt;/em&gt; which suggests that, while there is less risk in this field of financially-based conflicts, researchers may be particularly vulnerable to non-financial biases, a problem that hasn’t been adequately acknowledged until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19408&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team, led by Klaus Lieb of the University of Mainz, examined 95 systematic and meta-analytic reviews that had evaluated the efficacy of psychological therapies by looking at the weight of evidence across multiple randomised controlled trials. Such reviews are generally used to give a balanced picture of what really works, above and beyond a single trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journals that publish this kind of research tend to be on the look out for financial conflicts of interest that could lead to a bias: for example, if the author of a meta-analysis of Therapy X was a license-holder for that therapy but chose not to declare that interest when reviewing it. Indeed, Lieb and his team found that four out of every five journals they investigated had explicitly asked that such conflicts be declared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But only a third of the journals asked the same of non-financial conflicts of interest, such as a review author being trained in one specific therapy, or otherwise being a particular advocate of one over others. Lieb and his colleagues argue that this presents a real problem because unlike a pharmaceutical researcher who becomes disenchanted with their favoured drug, “psychotherapy researchers who realise that the effect of the therapy to which they are allied is less beneficial than another therapy cannot easily switch their research programme to another therapy (since they have often been trained in that therapy for many years)”. This is especially true if they have been on record as a cheerleader for a particular therapy, or as a critic of its alternatives. Incidentally, at the end of their paper, Lieb and his colleagues act by example, providing a thorough outline of their own therapeutic training and related information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these conflicts may be especially pernicious for psychological therapies, and the fact that so few journals ask for declarations of these kind of allegiances is alarming. Even in cases where journals had asked for this information, only four researchers volunteered it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this just means these conflicts are thankfully rare? This seems unlikely. Lieb’s team found that 34 of the reviews covered at least one and sometimes many more experimental studies authored by the reviewers themselves: not a crime in of itself, but a sign of at least a potential conflict. What’s more, Lieb’s group investigated these 34 reviews using a standard protocol to check for signs of “research allegiance”, that is whether the article betrayed a belief in the superiority of a treatment. Fifteen of the 34 reviews met these criteria, meaning that one or more of the authors had a vested interest in the conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieb and a co-author, Jan von der Osten-Sacken, also read through anonymised versions of all 95 reviews and labelled a conclusion as “spinned” when they felt it wasn’t consistent with the empirical results reported. Based on this, they claimed that reviews they’d identified earlier as having non-financial conflicts also tended to have biased conclusions. However, this link wasn’t statistically significant, so at best this tentative finding indicates something to be studied in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieb’s team emphasise they are not claiming that there is rampant fraud and deliberate misrepresentation. They suspect that “researchers may simply not be seeing the necessity of declaring non-financial interests, or be clear on what this includes”. So it’s incumbent on journals to outline more explicitly what constitutes a conflict of interest, and request and reveal them with more vigilance. Researchers themselves should take to heart the foundation on which the search for truth is built: to let go of your beliefs and be willing to be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/6/4/e010606.long&quot;&gt;Conflicts of interest and spin in reviews of psychological therapies: a systematic review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Contributing Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19408/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19408/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19408&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 10:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Light-induced structural changes and the site of O=O bond formation in PSII caught by XFEL</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21400</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/73_4_HTihfo/nature21400</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Photosystem II (PSII) is a huge membrane-protein complex consisting of 20 different subunits with a total molecular mass of 350 kDa for a monomer. It catalyses light-driven water oxidation at its catalytic centre, the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC). The structure of PSII has been analysed at 1.9 Å resolution by synchrotron radiation X-rays, which revealed that the OEC is a Mn4CaO5 cluster organized in an asymmetric, ‘distorted-chair’ form. This structure was further analysed with femtosecond X-ray free electron lasers (XFEL), providing the ‘radiation damage-free’ structure. The mechanism of O=O bond formation, however, remains obscure owing to the lack of intermediate-state structures. Here we describe the structural changes in PSII induced by two-flash illumination at room temperature at a resolution of 2.35 Å using time-resolved serial femtosecond crystallography with an XFEL provided by the SPring-8 ångström compact free-electron laser. An isomorphous difference Fourier map between the two-flash and dark-adapted states revealed two areas of apparent changes: around the QB/non-haem iron and the Mn4CaO5 cluster. The changes around the QB/non-haem iron region reflected the electron and proton transfers induced by the two-flash illumination. In the region around the OEC, a water molecule located 3.5 Å from the Mn4CaO5 cluster disappeared from the map upon two-flash illumination. This reduced the distance between another water molecule and the oxygen atom O4, suggesting that proton transfer also occurred. Importantly, the two-flash-minus-dark isomorphous difference Fourier map showed an apparent positive peak around O5, a unique μ4-oxo-bridge located in the quasi-centre of Mn1 and Mn4 (refs 4,5). This suggests the insertion of a new oxygen atom (O6) close to O5, providing an O=O distance of 1.5 Å between these two oxygen atoms. This provides a mechanism for the O=O bond formation consistent with that proposed previously. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21400&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21400&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/73_4_HTihfo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Survival of tissue-resident memory T cells requires exogenous lipid uptake and metabolism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21379</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/kIwwIMnAQeg/nature21379</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Tissue-resident memory T (TRM) cells persist indefinitely in epithelial barrier tissues and protect the host against pathogens. However, the biological pathways that enable the long-term survival of TRM cells are obscure. Here we show that mouse CD8+ TRM cells generated by viral infection of the skin differentially express high levels of several molecules that mediate lipid uptake and intracellular transport, including fatty-acid-binding proteins 4 and 5 (FABP4 and FABP5). We further show that T-cell-specific deficiency of Fabp4 and Fabp5 (Fabp4/Fabp5) impairs exogenous free fatty acid (FFA) uptake by CD8+ TRM cells and greatly reduces their long-term survival in vivo, while having no effect on the survival of central memory T (TCM) cells in lymph nodes. In vitro, CD8+ TRM cells, but not CD8+ TCM cells, demonstrated increased mitochondrial oxidative metabolism in the presence of exogenous FFAs; this increase was not seen in Fabp4/Fabp5 double-knockout CD8+ TRM cells. The persistence of CD8+ TRM cells in the skin was strongly diminished by inhibition of mitochondrial FFA β-oxidation in vivo. Moreover, skin CD8+ TRM cells that lacked Fabp4/Fabp5 were less effective at protecting mice from cutaneous viral infection, and lung Fabp4/Fabp5 double-knockout CD8+ TRM cells generated by skin vaccinia virus (VACV) infection were less effective at protecting mice from a lethal pulmonary challenge with VACV. Consistent with the mouse data, increased FABP4 and FABP5 expression and enhanced extracellular FFA uptake were also demonstrated in human CD8+ TRM cells in normal and psoriatic skin. These results suggest that FABP4 and FABP5 have a critical role in the maintenance, longevity and function of CD8+ TRM cells, and suggest that CD8+ TRM cells use exogenous FFAs and their oxidative metabolism to persist in tissue and to mediate protective immunity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature21379&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature21379&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/kIwwIMnAQeg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Enzymes aid rice plants’ arsenic defenses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enzymes-aid-rice-plants-arsenic-defenses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/enzymes-aid-rice-plants-arsenic-defenses</link>
	<description>Rice plant roots have natural defenses against arsenic.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 17:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_LH_arsenic-plants_main.jpeg?itok=atXq05M6" length="69375" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New imaging technique catches DNA ‘blinking’ on</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-imaging-technique-catches-dna-blinking</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-imaging-technique-catches-dna-blinking</link>
	<description>Dye-free imaging technique zooms in below 10-nanometer threshold, allowing new cellular views.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 15:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_RE_DNA-fluorescing_main.jpeg?itok=64sDXaJh" length="20566" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Using Discourse Analysis to Assess Cognitive Decline</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-6283119004927853198</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/tYYDadX2k1g/using-discourse-analysis-to-assess.html</link>
	<description>Figure from Gauthier et al. (2005).


Alzheimer's Disease (AD) and other dementias are progressive neurodegenerative conditions that unfold over time. Subtle symptoms such as forgetfulness and word finding problems may progress to mild cognitive impairment (MCI), and then escalate to full-blown dementia. Recent efforts to classify prodromal states have included automated analysis of spontaneous&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=tYYDadX2k1g:wU76oV88SzQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/tYYDadX2k1g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 12:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Microbes survived inside giant cave crystals for up to 50,000 years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/microbes-survived-inside-giant-cave-crystals-50000-years</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/microbes-survived-inside-giant-cave-crystals-50000-years</link>
	<description>Microbes trapped in crystals in Mexico's Naica mine may represent some of the most distinct life-forms found in Earth so far.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 17:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_AY_mexico-microbes_main.jpg?itok=Qh4NB2Bt" length="28451" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Europa lander mission takes another step toward reality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/europa-lander-mission-takes-another-step-toward-reality</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/europa-lander-mission-takes-another-step-toward-reality</link>
	<description>NASA is working on a possible lander mission in which the main science goal would be to search for signs of life on Jupiter’s moon Europa.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_AY_contamination_main.jpg?itok=mljvwuIS" length="29748" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: The upside of predatory publishers; why no one replicates; the pain of manuscript submission</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48341</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/18/weekend-reads-upside-predatory-publishers-no-one-replicates-pain-manuscript-submission/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a retraction of a state senator’s paper, and an editor busted for citation boosting. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Predatory journals are not desirable, it goes without saying, but the fact that they come about is a sign of a developing market, and a true market in scientific publishing services […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/18/weekend-reads-upside-predatory-publishers-no-one-replicates-pain-manuscript-submission/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: The upside of predatory publishers; why no one replicates; the pain of manuscript submission&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 14:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Common fungus may raise asthma risk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-fungus-may-raise-asthma-risk</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-fungus-may-raise-asthma-risk</link>
	<description>The presence of a fungus in the infant gut can signal development of asthma by age 5.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 22:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021717_RE_fungus-asthma_main.jpg?itok=tYWL0MHb" length="15658" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Juno spacecraft won’t go into shorter orbit around Jupiter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-spacecraft-wont-go-shorter-orbit-around-jupiter</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-spacecraft-wont-go-shorter-orbit-around-jupiter</link>
	<description>Juno will remain in its 53-day orbit around Jupiter due to an issue with two helium check valves, NASA reports.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 21:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021717_juno_ticker_free.jpg?itok=Kv3blDLR" length="28667" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Fantasy of Connecting Two Spinal Cords</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8555</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8555</link>
	<description>A peculiar new paper proposes the idea of &quot;connecting two spinal cords as a way of sharing information between two brains&quot;. The author is Portuguese psychiatrist Amílcar Silva-dos-Santos and the paper appears in Frontiers in Psychology.



Frontiers are a publisher with a troubled history of publishing dubious science. But this paper is unusual, even by Frontiers' standards, because it contains virtually no science at all.

In a nutshell, Silva-Dos-Santos suggests that it would be interest</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 20:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Antarctic sea ice shrinks to record low</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctic-sea-ice-shrinks-record-low</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctic-sea-ice-shrinks-record-low</link>
	<description>The Antarctic sea ice extent has reached a new low just two years after hitting a record high.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 18:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021717_ticker_ts_antarctica_ice_free.jpg?itok=imLjdZWH" length="43804" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Unusual: Neurology removes author dinged for misconduct from 2016 paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48311</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/unusual-neurology-removes-author-dinged-misconduct-2016-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Neurology has partially retracted a 2016 paper, replacing a figure and removing the author who contributed it after he was found guilty of misconduct. The journal has replaced the figure with a new one that confirmed the findings of the original, and swapped the name of Andrew Cullinane with the scientist who constructed the new […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/unusual-neurology-removes-author-dinged-misconduct-2016-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unusual: Neurology removes author dinged for misconduct from 2016 paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Editor resigns from two journals after “considerable” citation boosting attempts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=48321</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/editor-resigns-two-journals-considerable-citation-boosting-attempts/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An editor at two European Geophysical Union journals has resigned following revelations that he or she engaged in citation manipulation — boosting citations to his or her own papers and associated journals. Here’s a letter announcing the news, signed by EGU publication committee chair Hubert Savenije, that ran in several EGU journals earlier this week: […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/02/17/editor-resigns-two-journals-considerable-citation-boosting-attempts/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Editor resigns from two journals after “considerable” citation boosting attempts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: We’re seeking a writer to join our team!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19378</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/were-seeking-a-writer-to-join-our-team/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-19380 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19380&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=223&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1169,868&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/were-seeking-a-writer-to-join-our-team/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40/&quot; height=&quot;223&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/screen-shot-2017-02-17-at-14-45-40.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=223&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Psychology blogger sought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British Psychological Society’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/about-us/&quot;&gt;Research Digest blog&lt;/a&gt;, which keeps hundreds of thousands of people abreast of the latest exciting findings in psychology, is seeking an additional writer. This is a paid staff position, initially on a six-month contract, for seven hours per week. Salary is £32,612 pro-rata, and benefits include paid holiday and access to the Society’s pension scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although based remotely, you’ll work closely with the Research Digest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt; to produce six engaging reports on new psychology studies each month, in a style that entertains and educates. You will show readers how the findings are relevant to their lives, but without resorting to hype. Where appropriate, you should have the confidence and competence to criticise studies.  As one of our writers, you’ll have the satisfaction of seeing your work reach our large international audience and get picked up by the world’s biggest publications, from &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;New York Magazine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally you will already have experience writing about psychology or related fields for the public. And we’ll also need to see documentation that demonstrates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/right-to-work-checklist&quot;&gt;your right to work in the UK&lt;/a&gt;; further information can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bps.org.uk/jobs/society-office-staff-vacancies/society-office-staff-vacancies&quot;&gt;Job Vacancies page on the Society website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send a short email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:christianjarrett@gmail.com&quot;&gt;christianjarrett@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line “Psychology Blogger”, explaining why you are the right person for this role. Include links or attachments representing three examples of your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline is noon (GMT) 10 March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19378/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19378/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19378&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 15:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Helium’s inertness defied by high-pressure compound</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heliums-inertness-defied-high-pressure-compound</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heliums-inertness-defied-high-pressure-compound</link>
	<description>At pressures over a million atmospheres, helium reacts with sodium.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_EC_helium_main.jpg?itok=RaV1wKpi" length="20152" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Citizen scientists are providing stunning new views of Jupiter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-scientists-are-providing-stunning-new-views-jupiter</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-scientists-are-providing-stunning-new-views-jupiter</link>
	<description>A camera aboard NASA’s Juno spacecraft is giving citizen scientists a crack at discovering never-before-seen features of Jupiter.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/blogposts/021617_ay_junocam_feat_free.jpg?itok=IsOjO6EB" length="19038" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: American women seem to be becoming less stereotypically feminine and more dominant</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=19249</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/american-women-seem-to-be-becoming-less-stereotypically-feminine-and-more-dominant/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;we_can_do_it&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-19319&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;19319&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;we_can_do_it&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845?w=791&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845?w=232&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1000,1294&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/02/17/american-women-seem-to-be-becoming-less-stereotypically-feminine-and-more-dominant/we_can_do_it/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/we_can_do_it.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True gender equality may be a work in progress, but since the Women’s Liberation Movement beginning in the 1950s and 60s, there has been a lot of positive change, at least in most industrialised nations: a shift towards women having more control over whether and when to have children, for example, and increased opportunities in education and careers, and less tolerance of sexism (though of course it hasn’t gone away). How might these cultural and social changes have influenced women, in terms of how much they act in stereotypically “feminine” ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10804-016-9243-8/fulltext.html?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; by Constance Jones and her colleagues at California State and San Francisco State Universities in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Adult Development&lt;/em&gt; tried to find out by comparing two cohorts of women, one born in the 1920s and the other featuring “Baby Boomers” born in the 1950s. The findings support past work that’s shown how women tend to change through their lives, and they provide evidence for a generation effect: over time, at least in California, women seem to be becoming less stereotypically feminine – that is, less deferential, and more confident and ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-19249&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 180 women born in the 1920s took the same California Psychological Inventory five times over as many decades, beginning when they were in their 30s and through into their 80s. The researchers were particularly interested in how they scored on the 32 items of the Inventory that measure femininity defined “as being gentle and warm, but also being dependent, and needing reassurance from others”, and how they scored on the 36 items measuring dominance, defined as “being confident, ambitious, assertive, and enterprising”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, 190 women born in the 1950s (actually daughters of the older participants) answered the same questions about their own femininity and dominance, first in 1980s when they were in their 30s, then twice more in their 40s and 50s/60s (taking us up to 2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones and her team found evidence of lifespan changes in both cohorts. Women in both groups tended to become less stereotypically feminine as they got older (with some return to more femininity later in life) and both groups showed signs of greater dominance with increasing age. Statistically speaking, the magnitude of change was modest in effect size. “[The] women appeared to drop constraining negative aspects of the feminine gender role and take on positive cross-gendered qualities with age,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comparing across the two cohorts, the women born in the second half of the twentieth century scored lower on femininity when they first completed the inventory in their 30s as compared with the femininity scores of the women born in the 1920s when they were the same age (a modest group difference in terms of effect size). “Most likely reacting to the Women’s Movement zeitgeist, [the younger cohort] entered young adulthood with less obligation to take on feminine gender constraints in the first place,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the rate of increase in dominance shown by the second generation women through their lives was more rapid than that shown by their mothers. Because of this difference in speed of change, the researchers said “we can expect the younger cohort women to be higher than the older cohort women in dominance when they reach later adulthood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be fascinating to see if and how these trends have continued in Generation X and Millenials. If you reflect on your own family – for example, how you or your sisters compare in femininity and dominance (as defined in this study) with your mother – bear in mind the implications of the parallel changes in these traits through lives and across generations. A young woman today might not seem a lot more dominant and less feminine than her mother is today, but that might be because of the way her mother has changed through her life. The chances are that the young woman is more dominant and less feminine than her mother was at the same age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study has some issues, including a reliance on how participants rated themselves and missing data from some of the survey points, which meant the researchers sometimes had to extrapolate from the scores they did have. Also both cohort samples were fairly small, and perhaps the observed generational changes are unique to the Bay Area of California. That said, Jones and her team pointed out that it was “rare to be able to examine personality change across such as expansive portion of the lifespan (age 20s through the 80s) and to be able to tie two historically important cohorts together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10804-016-9243-8/fulltext.html?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Femininity and Dominance Across the Lifespan: Longitudinal Findings from Two Cohorts of Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feminist_movement#/media/File:We_Can_Do_It!.jpg&quot;&gt;via Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19249/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/19249/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=19249&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 09:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Picking a lemur out of a line-up: introducing LemurFaceID, a facial recognition system for wild lemurs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=8578</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/17/picking-lemur-line-introducing-lemurfaceid-facial-recognition-system-wild-lemurs/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 5&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-5-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picking a face out of a crowd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our closest relatives, primates have long been a focus of research into their behavior and evolution. As many primate species become threatened with extinction, research on wild populations has become even more important, being crucial to conservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long-term studies, following primate social groups over many years, can be especially informative. However, a key requirement for such studies is to consistently and accurately identify different individuals: not always an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional way of identifying individuals is to capture them and attach a tag or collar. This has proven to be an effective technique on a number of successful long-term field studies. However it also comes with drawbacks. Capturing animals can be hard enough with birds or small mammals like rodents; for large primates, it usually involves darting them with a blow-gun or air rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is both expensive and time-consuming, limiting the number of individuals that can be tagged. Of even greater concern, the act of capture itself can be harmful to the animals, whether through damage caused during capture (anything from stress to broken bones), or by disrupting group dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to capturing and tagging is to identify individuals via natural variation in their features, such as scars or skin patterns. This does, however, require considerable skill on the part of observers. Even with extensive training, it is still inevitable that errors will occur in identification both within and between observers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8581&quot; style=&quot;width: 2000px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 1&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8581 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1990&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Examples of different lemur species, demonstrating the facial features that can allow individuals to be accurately identified.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;David Crouse, Rachel Jacobs, Stacey Tecot&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is really needed is a non-invasive identification method that relies less on human perception. The developing field of animal biometrics offers a potential solution, with automated recognition systems showing promise in a number of mammal species. New research, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmczool.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40850-016-0011-9&quot;&gt;published today &lt;/a&gt;in &lt;em&gt;BMC Zoology&lt;/em&gt;, describes the development of such an automated facial recognition system for lemurs: LemurFaceID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who’s that lemur?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study is the result of collaboration between a number of US-based scientists, led by lemur researchers &lt;a href=&quot;http://rachellynjacobs.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Rachel Jacobs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://stecot.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;Stacy Tecot&lt;/a&gt; and biometrics researchers David Crouse and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cse.msu.edu/~jain/&quot;&gt;Anil Jain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their work takes advantage of a well-studied population of red-bellied lemurs. Like all lemurs, the red-bellied lemur is found only on the island of Madagascar. The study population, living in Ranomafana National Park, has been the subject of multiple research projects since the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, a substantial database of known individuals has been built up, based on variation in facial patterns. However, substantial training is required to identify individuals in this way, which led the researchers to develop this new system that can automatically match a photo of a lemur’s face to a database of known individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8582&quot; style=&quot;width: 1700px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lemur fig 2&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-8582 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1129&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-2.png&quot; width=&quot;1690&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Red bellied lemurs. The individual on the right is female, on the left a male, with distinctive white patch of skin around the eyes. Facial patterns are individually variable, allowing researchers to identify individuals&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;J. Falinomenjanahary&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, the researchers had access to 462 images of 80 red-bellied lemur individuals. LemurFaceID requires a researcher to manually locate the eyes in the picture, the critical aspect of this recognition system, as with most human facial recognition systems. Various other alterations are then made to the image (see below for a basic outline of the process) before LemurFaceID automatically compares and matches it to the database of known individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8584&quot; style=&quot;width: 4985px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Flowchart of how LemurFaceID works.&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8584&quot; height=&quot;3430&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-6.png&quot; width=&quot;4975&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Flowchart of how LemurFaceID works.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Crouse et al. 2017&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results show that LemurFaceID has a relatively high level of accuracy (98.7%) in ‘closed set’ mode – i.e. when only tested with pictures of known individuals already included in its database. Accuracy was lower in an ‘open-set’ mode when it was tested with pictures of lemurs not already included in the database. This suggests that, for now, LemurFaceID would be most useful for captive or well-studied wild populations (like this one) where all individuals are known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the researchers are confident that the system can be further improved by the addition of larger datasets of photos and individuals, along with further field testing, eventually improving its ability to distinguish between known and novel individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facing the potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of the project is to provide a non-invasive method to recognise lemurs that does not require extensive training. The potential benefits of such a system are considerable. By reducing the difficulty and cost of long-term monitoring of wild lemur populations, the scope of such studies could be increased with more and better quality data generated in less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have considerable benefit for our knowledge of the evolution of this unique primate radiation, endemic to just a single island, and help us learn more about their social systems. It would also enable improved monitoring of lemur population numbers and demographic structures, helping conservationists better model extinction risk; an important consideration when many lemur species (including the red-bellied lemur) are threatened by human encroachments into their habitat. It could even help fight the illegal pet-trade in lemurs taken from the wild, by allowing law enforcement and tourists to rapidly report sightings and determine the origin of captive lemurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_8585&quot; style=&quot;width: 610px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Example of processing carried out on lemur images.&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-8585&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-Fig8.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Example of processing carried out on lemur images.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Crouse et al. 2017&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These methods could also be adapted to other primates or even other large mammal species with variable facial or skin patterns, such as bears, red pandas, or sloths. Already similar automated facial recognition systems have been developed for &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1186/1687-5281-2013-49&quot;&gt;chimps&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/282/1802/20142284&quot;&gt;guenons&lt;/a&gt;. Such systems could even be combined with automated remote camera traps, increasingly used to monitor populations of hard-to-track wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the researchers’ caution there is no “one size fits all” approach to automated animal facial recognition, it is clearly a technique that will play an ever larger part in our understanding of, and attempts to preserve, the large mammals of our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/02/17/picking-lemur-line-introducing-lemurfaceid-facial-recognition-system-wild-lemurs/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Picking a lemur out of a line-up: introducing LemurFaceID, a facial recognition system for wild lemurs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 09:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/02/Lemur-fig-5-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ceres harbors homegrown organic compounds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ceres-harbors-homegrown-organic-compounds</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ceres-harbors-homegrown-organic-compounds</link>
	<description>NASA’s Dawn spacecraft has detected organic matter — the building blocks of life — on the dwarf planet Ceres, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 19:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_EE_ceres_main.jpg?itok=UKKevWra" length="13935" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Seagrasses boost ecosystem health by fighting bad bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seagrasses-boost-ecosystem-health-fighting-bad-bacteria</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/seagrasses-boost-ecosystem-health-fighting-bad-bacteria</link>
	<description>Seagrasses might reduce bacteria levels in ocean water.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/02/main/articles/021617_lh_seagrass_main.jpg?itok=JYo_eBcf" length="40100" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
