<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lancet retracts and replaces news story about controversial abortion drug</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52707</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/21/lancet-retracts-replaces-news-story-controversial-abortion-drug/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Lancet has retracted a journalist-written piece about a controversial drug used off-label to induce abortions, and replaced it with a corrected version. In the retraction notice, the journal said it “removed the information that we believe to be inaccurate.” The article, first published Oct. 28, 2017, highlights Pfizer’s decision to withdraw the drug, misoprostol, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/21/lancet-retracts-replaces-news-story-controversial-abortion-drug/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lancet retracts and replaces news story about controversial abortion drug&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The dietary habits of the emerald ash borer beetle are complicated</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dietary-habits-emerald-ash-borer-beetle-are-complicated</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dietary-habits-emerald-ash-borer-beetle-are-complicated</link>
	<description>Tests answer some questions about the emerald ash borer’s hidden taste for olive and fringe trees.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_SM_emeraldash_feat.jpg?itok=XKjCyn1y" length="35768" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Reducing the amount of time spent sitting at work; how do we do it and why should we?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9630</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/21/reducing-amount-time-spent-sitting-work/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/Trollback__Company_office-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of us spend the majority of our work day seated at desk jobs, despite the common knowledge that long periods of inactivity can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2458-13-296&quot;&gt;detrimental to our health&lt;/a&gt;.  While some inventions to improve health have been introduced into workplaces, such as sit-stand desks, they fail to take into account worker preferences. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcresnotes.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13104-017-2829-9&quot;&gt;New research published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; investigates the activity preferences of employees in order to better understand how to integrate various measures into the workplace, which may improve the overall health of the office-based workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This nationwide study took place in Germany in the form of an office worker survey, where 2830 adults over the age of 18 took part in the questionnaire with a 53% male and 47% female split. The results give an indication of what workers want; to sit less and stand, walk and undertake physical activity more during their working day. The longer the work day, the less time survey participants wanted to spend sitting and the greater their desire to stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An inactive lifestyle can increase the risk of developing heart disease and certain types of cancer and diabetes.  Inactivity can also decrease &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0140673612610319?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;overall life expectancy&lt;/a&gt;. A recent study found that the ideal amount of time spent standing and undertaking physical activity for our health in a standard 8 hour work day is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://bjsm.bmj.com/content/early/2015/04/23/bjsports-2015-094618&quot;&gt;progression from 2 to 4 hours&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, the study mirrors the results of the &lt;em&gt;BMC Research Notes&lt;/em&gt; study wherein researchers found there was a preference by workers to sit for no more than 4 hours in an 8 hour work day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the desire to remain seated for only half of the working day, workers reported spending on average 70% of their day seated. Changing this behavior requires various interventions and changes to the workplace. Sit-stand desks and other measures to increase standing have often been introduced without taking workers preferences for standing, walking or other physical activity into account, which may give an indication as to why there has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25040784&quot;&gt;limited success&lt;/a&gt; in the overall reduction of sitting time in the workplace. This study indicates that physical activity and walking is preferred to simply standing and on average found that workers would rather spend 46 minutes more each day walking, and 26 minutes more standing in a standard 8 hour work day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9632 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;277&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/Untitled1-300x277.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To integrate potential interventions requires a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1469029215000084&quot;&gt;change in behavior&lt;/a&gt;, a change in the social norms for office workers, a positive attitude as well as personal regulation and control. With the right motivations, such as taking worker preferences into account, a reduction in the amount of time spent sitting at work could be achieved through introducing complimentary countermeasures which may encourage compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interventions should therefore exist with the intention of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/232166545_Fit_or_sit_Is_there_a_psychology_of_sedentary_behaviour&quot;&gt;habit-breaking&lt;/a&gt;. Methods suggested by the researchers include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21767727&quot;&gt;environmental modifications&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26769894&quot;&gt;active design building&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/307623046_Theoretical_Antecedents_of_Standing_at_Work_An_Experience_Sampling_Approach_Using_the_Theory_of_Planned_Behavior&quot;&gt;behavior change strategies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2458-13-1057&quot;&gt;supportive workplace policies&lt;/a&gt; for more physical activity and the continued introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27256708&quot;&gt;sit-stand desks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/21/reducing-amount-time-spent-sitting-work/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Reducing the amount of time spent sitting at work; how do we do it and why should we?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 14:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/Trollback__Company_office-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Publisher issues first retractions for fake peer review, starts new checking policy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52692</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/21/frontiers-issues-first-retractions-fake-peer-review-starts-new-checking-policy/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The publisher Frontiers has retracted four papers in three of its journals after discovering they had been accepted with fake peer reviews. The problem of fake reviews has been on the research community’s radar since at least 2014, and several major publishers—including Springer, SAGE and BioMed Central—have retracted hundreds of papers accepted via fake peer […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/21/frontiers-issues-first-retractions-fake-peer-review-starts-new-checking-policy/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Publisher issues first retractions for fake peer review, starts new checking policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 13:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Even a tiny oil spill spells bad news for birds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/even-tiny-oil-spill-spells-bad-news-birds</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/even-tiny-oil-spill-spells-bad-news-birds</link>
	<description>Just a small amount of crude can make birds less active.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112017_LH_oilspillduckling_feat.jpg?itok=3VJKdSMo" length="29991" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Thinking in a foreign language, we’re less prone to superstition</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32761</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/21/thinking-in-a-foreign-language-were-less-prone-to-superstition/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-84408533.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32764&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32764&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;16&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Ixpress 528C - Hasselblad H1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;121&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1216830707&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;seeD photography&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01055908203125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A black cat, ladder, magpie and broken mirror&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A black cat, ladder, magpie and broken mirror&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-84408533.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-84408533.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-84408533.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1999,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/21/thinking-in-a-foreign-language-were-less-prone-to-superstition/a-black-cat-ladder-magpie-and-broken-mirror/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-84408533.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating in our second language can have some intriguing psychological effects. We swear more freely and linger longer on embarrassing topics than normal. We’re also &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/03/18/how-thinking-in-a-foreign-language-makes-you-more-rational-in-some-ways-but-not-others/&quot;&gt;less susceptible to cognitive biases&lt;/a&gt;. According to psychologist Constantinos Hadjichristidis at the University of Trento, this is because a second language discourages us from relying on intuitive thinking. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17470218.2017.1371780?src=recsys&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, &lt;/i&gt;Hadjichristidis and his colleagues have shown another way that this manifests – when thinking in a foreign language, we’re less prone to superstition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32761&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experiment, 400 native German speakers with proficiency in English imagined themselves in various scenarios, described either in German or English text, about an important day, like the morning before an exam or the day of a job application deadline. Each scenario involved a break in the routine, which was either mundane (like discovering the kitchen sink being blocked or spotting an airplane in the sky), or had a superstitious connotation – negative, like a mirror breaking, or positive, such as spotting a falling star in the sky. Participants rated how positive or negative they would feel in these situations, responding in the same language as the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading and responding in English, rather than German, made no difference to participants’ ratings of how they’d feel following a mundane event, but led to them describing less intense emotional reactions to the events with a superstitious connotation: they said they’d feel less negative about the bad luck events and less positive about the good luck events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s happening here? Intuition depends on easily accessible connections, such as the term “broken mirror” being repeatedly associated with dismay or discomfort. These connections tend to be built in earlier life, and invariably in our native tongue (the German participants in this research had only begun learning English from age 12, on average). When we encounter a concept loaded with superstitious symbolism in our second tongue, we know what it means literally, but the emotional associations don’t come along automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left unchecked, our thinking is always influenced by our intuitions, which means even those who want to live as hard-nosed materialists may find magical thinking creeping in through the side gate. One way to combat this is to monitor the ideas that form and try to expel the unwanted influences. But this research suggests another approach: bar the gate so the influences don’t enter in the first place. For now, this option is only available to bilinguals, but it opens a route for discovering other modes of thinking that are more intuition-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17470218.2017.1371780?src=recsys&quot;&gt;Breaking Magic: Foreign Language Suppresses Superstition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32761/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32761/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32761&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 09:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Please sir, I want some more: an exploration of repeat foodbank use</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9633</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/21/please-sir-i-want-some-more-an-exploration-of-repeat-foodbank-use/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/8719763907_fe86c038f9_z-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, how many people really use foodbanks? The emergence of foodbanks – charitable organizations that provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trusselltrust.org/get-help/emergency-food/food-parcel/&quot;&gt;emergency food&lt;/a&gt; for those in need – represents a shocking manifestation of severe poverty and food insecurity in contemporary Britain. In the absence of more direct information, foodbank use is commonly taken to represent extreme levels of uncertainty in obtaining sufficient, suitable food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people visit foodbanks more than once, they are also counted more than once, so the true prevalence of foodbank use in Britain is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite highly publicized &lt;a href=&quot;http://csi.nuff.ox.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/CSI-28-Food-insecurity-revised.pdf&quot;&gt;growth&lt;/a&gt;, the scale of foodbank use has been subject to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/ld201314/ldhansrd/text/130702-0001.htm&quot;&gt;heated debate&lt;/a&gt;. Food insecurity is associated with poor &lt;a href=&quot;http://jech.bmj.com/content/71/4/324&quot;&gt;mental&lt;/a&gt; and physical health, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://trusselltrust.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/06/OU_Report_final_01_08_online.pdf&quot;&gt;disabilities&lt;/a&gt;, so the recent growth in foodbank use could warn of an escalating nutrition and public health crisis in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work aimed to address a key evidence gap in estimating the scale of foodbank use. The Trussell Trust – Britain’s largest foodbank network – collects &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trusselltrust.org/news-and-blog/latest-stats/&quot;&gt;headline data &lt;/a&gt;on the number of food parcels given to adults and children. However, when people visit foodbanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://wandsworth.foodbank.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/sites/149/2016/05/WANDSWORTH-FOOD-POVERTY-REPORT-2016.pdf&quot;&gt;more than once&lt;/a&gt;, they are also counted more than once, so the true prevalence of foodbank use in Britain is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, each household’s annual number of visits was estimated by cross-referencing the names and addresses of people receiving emergency food from West Cheshire Foodbank. This approach made it possible to identify the unique number of households receiving assistance. This work therefore presents the first attempt to estimate the scale of UK foodbank use among adults and children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that an estimated one per cent of the population of West Cheshire received emergency food between 2013 and 2015. Worryingly, this figure was higher among children. If scaled up, this would equate to approximately 850,000 people in Britain – nearly the population of Liverpool – who rely on emergency food to feed themselves and their families. This proportion rose slightly over time, consistent with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trusselltrust.org/news-and-blog/latest-stats/&quot;&gt;national trends&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9634&quot; style=&quot;width: 837px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9634&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/fig-1.png&quot; width=&quot;827&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Number of unique and total recipients of emergency food in West Cheshire, 2013-2015&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed analyses revealed that the growth in repeat visits outpaced the increase in total visits (see Figure 1), suggesting that foodbank use is becoming more entrenched among certain groups. Repeat visits were more common among working-age and one-person households, groups who have been particularly badly impacted by the recent recession and consequent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0091743516300846&quot;&gt;welfare reform&lt;/a&gt;. This finding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sociology.ox.ac.uk/working-papers/the-impact-of-benefit-sanctioning-on-food-insecurity-a-dynamic-cross-area-study-of-food-bank-usage-in-the-uk.html&quot;&gt;replicates existing research&lt;/a&gt; on the topic and strengthens the evidence linking economic and social policies to foodbank use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If scaled up, this would equate to approximately 850,000 people in Britain – nearly the population of Liverpool – who rely on emergency food to feed themselves and their families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, these results do have some limitations. First, they relate to a single foodbank, which cannot fully represent Britain’s diverse population. Nonetheless, these results are consistent with what is known &lt;a href=&quot;https://westcheshire.foodbank.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/sites/62/2016/07/stillhungry.pdf&quot;&gt;nationally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a localized approach also enabled unique households to be identified, a time-consuming task. The next step to a more complete impression of UK foodbank use would require the same strategy to be repeated among a carefully selected sample of foodbanks – a daunting undertaking that may not be practically possible. This approach would still under-estimate the number of people using foodbanks as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodaidnetwork.org.uk&quot;&gt;independent foodbanks&lt;/a&gt; would not be included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also important to remember that foodbanks are commonly considered a ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/food-aid-research-report&quot;&gt;last resort&lt;/a&gt;’ and used by only a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gowellonline.com/assets/0000/3896/BP28_food_banks_web.pdf&quot;&gt;small minority&lt;/a&gt; of food insecure people, often because people feel &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0038038515594092&quot;&gt;embarrassed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ingentaconnect.com/content/tpp/jpsj/2016/00000024/00000003/art00005&quot;&gt;ashamed&lt;/a&gt;. Separate estimates that between &lt;a href=&quot;http://foodfoundation.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/FoodInsecurityBriefing-May-2016-FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.food.gov.uk/sites/default/files/food-and-you-w4-combined-report.pdf&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt; per cent of people in Britain experience food insecurity demonstrate that foodbank figures drastically underestimate the scale of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new work adds to growing evidence about foodbank use in the UK. Practitioners are increasingly well versed in the problem of food insecurity, and may have seen its effects first-hand: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/hot-topics/practice-news/one-in-six-gps-asked-to-refer-a-patient-to-a-food-bank-in-the-past-year/20005889.fullarticle&quot;&gt;one in six of GPs&lt;/a&gt; reported having been asked to refer patients to foodbanks in 2014. The health consequences of food insecurity are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4592315/pdf/187e429.pdf&quot;&gt;costly to the public purse&lt;/a&gt;. Wide-reaching measures to reduce food insecurity are crucially needed and should especially target the particularly vulnerable groups identified here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/21/please-sir-i-want-some-more-an-exploration-of-repeat-foodbank-use/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Please sir, I want some more: an exploration of repeat foodbank use&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 09:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/8719763907_fe86c038f9_z-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Black academics soon to outnumber white researchers in South Africa</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23030</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/V8F0SMwI-MI/nature.2017.23030</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Legacy of apartheid means academia has remained largely white.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23030&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/V8F0SMwI-MI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Hungary rewards highly cited scientists with bonus grants</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551425a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/WAZzL98w8vg/551425a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some top researchers prosper in Hungary as country tries to improve its international standing in science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 425 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/551425a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551425a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/WAZzL98w8vg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Six-month-old babies know words for common things, but struggle with similar nouns</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-recognize-common-words-6-months</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/babies-recognize-common-words-6-months</link>
	<description>Young babies know a cup of juice from a car, but have a hard time distinguishing more similar nouns, a new study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 21:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/112017_LS_language-learning_main_FREE.jpg?itok=txYGRdXd" length="22090" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: Anytime You’re in Listening Mode: PLOScast Two-year Anniversary</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7860</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/pyCCVM3N-5c/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/11/PLOScast_blog-hero-image_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced world with its onslaught of environmental, societal and political challenges, science-related podcasts can provide an interesting, educational and even entertaining escape. Podcasts bring an interactive, personal approach and sense of intimacy to topics that might be dry when presented in written form. Plus, you can listen during your commute to the lab, library or office, while you’re exercising, cooking, or anytime you’re in headphone mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/ecology/2017/07/31/the-lab-bench-in-stereo-science-and-science-podcasts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;growth in science podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; provides evidence of their potential to deliver important stories to a broad audience. Podcasts are not just about stories, though. Ciencia Puerto Rico (CienciaPR) has increased the amount of culturally relevant scientific news content in Puerto Rico through essays, articles and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1001740&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;articles distributed as podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the University of California considered podcasts as a mechanism to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1000289&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;enhance and accelerate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; research. Podcasts were integral to an early proposal for an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1002632&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;online bioinformatics curriculum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and are an appropriate component to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/article?id=10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000787&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;transform science communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; through incorporation of rich media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PLOS, we’re celebrating the two-year anniversary of our own podcast, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOScast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. According to PLOScast founding host and PLOS staff researcher Elizabeth Seiver, PLOScast was established to give the organization a modern forum for thought leadership in the publishing space, but it quickly moved beyond this boundary. PLOScast engages listeners through interviews with innovators and thought leaders on the changing experiences of scientists in a digital world, the future of academia and its ongoing challenges, and scholarly publishing developments in an increasingly diverse landscape. These are serious issues, and PLOScast approaches them with integrity, diligence and humor. The show explores all things Open (access, peer review and science), including research tools; ideas for improving science communication; and exemplary, practical habits of successful scientists in all disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“PLOScast enables us to discuss issues that are important to scientists, with some of the thought leaders in their fields. It also increases the visibility of the work that the greater scientific community contributes, every day.”—Elizabeth Seiver&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When PLOScast launched at the end of 2015, development involved getting the logistics and day-to-day operations straightened out. None of the team members had experience with podcasting, so they needed to learn the basics, including what kind of equipment was needed, how to edit a sound file, and how to best promote each episode. Over time, the script itself has evolved to better engage the audience and optimize the listener experience. “I try to keep the listener in mind more now,” says Seiver. “I think at the beginning I was more focused on having the conversation itself, but now I try to have a running voice in the back of my mind thinking about the listener, asking ‘will other people understand this reference? Is this what other people want to know about this topic?’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists and those interested in academics are certainly listening—PLOScast has over 16,000 plays in the past two years. With its reputation growing, plans are to diversify beyond the traditional one-on-one interview format and to expand its voice to provide early career researchers (ECRs) an opportunity to participate. The manager of PLOS’ ECR Community, Sara Kassabian, recently joined the PLOScast hosting team (yes, two people make a team), contributing an interview with preprint maven Jessica Polka for her inaugural episode. In “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/10/24/episode26/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How ECRs like Jessica Polka are reinventing science publishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,” Polka goes beyond the topic of preprints to discuss opportunities for ECRs in #scicomm and the role of twitter in creating positive change in #science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top 10 most popular episodes by number of plays cover issues ranging from altmetrics and their history (episode 14) to big data in the social sciences (episode 23) and how to work with public information officers to increase the visibility of your science (episode 8). The top 10 (including number of plays as of October 31, 2017) in order are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/03/21/how-to-communicate-science-an-interview-with-matt-shipman/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 8: How to Communicate Science: An interview featuring Matt Shipman&lt;/a&gt; (969 plays)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/11/16/the-postdoc-crisis-an-interview-with-liz-silva/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 2: The Postdoc Crisis featuring Liz Silva&lt;/a&gt; (856)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/04/18/the-history-of-scientific-publishing-an-interview-with-aileen-fyfe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 9: The History of Scientific Publishing: An interview featuring Aileen Fyfe&lt;/a&gt; (769)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/12/14/episode-3-managing-scientific-data-feat-tracy-teal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 3: Managing Scientific Data featuring Tracy Teal&lt;/a&gt; (738)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/10/19/introducing-ploscast-a-podcast-on-on-science-academia-and-the-future-of-scholarship/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 1 Part 1: Open Peer Review and Scientific Communities&lt;/a&gt; (706)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/12/27/the-science-of-science-part-1-an-interview-with-eamon-duede/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 17 Part 1: The Science of Science featuring Eamon Duede&lt;/a&gt; (694)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/07/07/big-data-in-the-social-sciences-an-interview-featuring-ian-mulvany/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 23: Big Data in the Social Sciences: An interview featuring Ian Mulvany&lt;/a&gt; (668)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/09/19/understanding-altmetrics-an-interview-with-stacy-konkiel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 14: Understanding Altmetrics with Stacy Konkiel&lt;/a&gt; (636)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/05/23/building-taxonomies-an-interview-featuring-bob-kasenchak/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 22: Building Taxonomies: An interview featuring Bob Kasenchak&lt;/a&gt; (598)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/03/28/science-communication-and-critique-an-interview-featuring-hilda-bastian/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 20: Science Communication and Critique: An interview featuring Hilda Bastian&lt;/a&gt; (598)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, PLOScast launched with a broad ranging discussion on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/10/19/introducing-ploscast-a-podcast-on-on-science-academia-and-the-future-of-scholarship/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;c&lt;strong&gt;ollaboration and publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://staffportal.curtin.edu.au/staff/profile/view/Cameron.Neylon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cameron Neylon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, formerly PLOS’ Advocacy Director. Part of this conversation covered bioRxiv, prior to that preprint server’s current phase of rapid growth. The second year began with an interview with James Fraser from UCSF on preprints and their ability to help &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/10/24/the-power-of-preprints-an-interview-with-james-fraser/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;authors stake a claim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on ideas, methods or results. The interview with Polka marks the beginning of year three for PLOScast; as with the rest of the scientific community, preprints are an increasingly central part of PLOS’ conversation on how to move science communication forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark this achievement milestone for PLOScast, we have a new icon that’s fun and quirky yet at its core remains PLOS. We leave listeners around the globe with the top five favorites of the PLOScast crew:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/03/21/how-to-communicate-science-an-interview-with-matt-shipman/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 8: How to Communicate Science: An interview featuring Matt Shipman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/04/18/the-history-of-scientific-publishing-an-interview-with-aileen-fyfe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 9: The History of Scientific Publishing: An interview featuring Aileen Fyfe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/07/07/big-data-in-the-social-sciences-an-interview-featuring-ian-mulvany/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 23: Big Data in the Social Sciences: An interview featuring Ian Mulvany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/11/16/the-postdoc-crisis-an-interview-with-liz-silva/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 2: The Postdoc Crisis featuring Liz Silva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/12/14/episode-3-managing-scientific-data-feat-tracy-teal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Episode 3: Managing Scientific Data featuring Tracy Teal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New PLOScasts are posted monthly; you can find PLOScast on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/ploscast/id499346639?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/public-library-of-science&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen?u=0#/ps/Ilfmckfpqswvpzcedkkis4dbpo4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or sign up for an RSS feed on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOScast main page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so you don’t miss an episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/pyCCVM3N-5c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 18:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Announces Outsourced R&amp;D Partnership with Alector</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1190</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/science-exchange-announces-outsourced-rd-partnership-with-alector/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Science-Exchange-Alector.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Science Exchange-Alector Partnership&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1191&quot; height=&quot;174&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Science-Exchange-Alector-300x174.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 1px solid #338dc8;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PALO ALTO, Calif.–&lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scienceexchange.com%2F&amp;amp;esheet=51718545&amp;amp;newsitemid=20171120005339&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=Science+Exchange&amp;amp;index=1&amp;amp;md5=61a642df6eb9ddef7d99755cbc56ab23&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform and aggregator for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D), today announced a strategic partnership with Alector, a biotech company pioneering the discovery &amp;amp; development of immuno-neurology therapies for neurodegenerative disorders, to provide the company’s scientists access to a private R&amp;amp;D marketplace to accelerate their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Science Exchange platform solves the challenges of R&amp;amp;D outsourcing: we provide scientists with efficient access to a diverse network of qualified suppliers under a single relationship, and at the same time we provide sourcing departments with more information and control over their outsourcing spend,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “We are thrilled to be the provider of Alector’s R&amp;amp;D marketplace and help bring potential treatments for Alzheimer’s disease to patients more quickly and efficiently. Especially following the exciting news on Alector’s partnership with AbbVie to advance therapies for Alzheimer’s disease, it’s clear that Alector has extremely promising drug targets — we’re honored to help accelerate these important discoveries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Science Exchange-powered R&amp;amp;D marketplace enables scientists to instantly order more than 6,000 unique scientific services from the 2,500 CROs, academic labs, and government facilities that are available under a single Science Exchange contract. The partnership also will provide Alector with a platform to effectively manage the company’s outsourced R&amp;amp;D investments, including the ability to track supplier utilization, trends, and performance, which also supports the need for compliance with internal policies and external regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alector is the latest R&amp;amp;D company to choose to partner with Science Exchange, and joins more than 30 enterprise organizations, including 10 of the top 20 pharma companies, that use Science Exchange to more efficiently manage outsourced R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Science Exchange offers a unique platform for connecting with a broad network of qualified scientific service providers,” said Arnon Rosenthal, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Alector. “It is our hope that working with Science Exchange will enable us to more quickly advance discovery and development of novel immuno-neurology therapies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the agreement, Science Exchange will support company-specific governance, approval workflows, and preferred vendors. To minimize the risk frequently associated with outsourcing to external service providers, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.scienceexchange.com%2Ftrust&amp;amp;esheet=51718545&amp;amp;newsitemid=20171120005339&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=Science+Exchange+guarantee&amp;amp;index=2&amp;amp;md5=c0ccaaac6a80714963a7c5d9c3db351d&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Science Exchange guarantee&lt;/a&gt; ensures complete protection of data, assets and performance of agreed-upon services, all backed by a best-in-class, SOC 2-compliant information technology security infrastructure. Science Exchange’s ISO 9001-certified quality assurance system and dedicated regulatory compliance team also support regulated work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise&lt;/a&gt; to request a demo of our award-winning private marketplaces for managing outsourced research and development!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Director of U.S. HHS Office of Research Integrity temporarily removed from post</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52679</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/20/director-u-s-hhs-office-research-integrity-temporarily-removed-post/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;After a tumultuous two years, Kathy Partin is temporarily stepping away from her position as the director of the U.S. Office of Research Integrity. According to an internal personnel announcement forwarded to us, on December 4, Partin will begin a 90-day stint at the Office of the Vice President for Research at the Uniformed Services […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/20/director-u-s-hhs-office-research-integrity-temporarily-removed-post/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Director of U.S. HHS Office of Research Integrity temporarily removed from post&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 16:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Re-Learning the Joy of Living with Journaling and Meditation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23126</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/20/re-learning-the-joy-of-living-with-journaling-and-meditation/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Moving along the treadmill of life, many of us succumb to the ever-present pressures to be faster, stronger, more efficient, and smarter. Perspective on what is happening in our lives is lost. We focus on failure and lacking within ourselves, rather than the abundance and opportunities for growth that surround us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stop taking the time to appreciate the simple pleasures of our lives as we spiral our way into a depleted existence—physically, emotionally, and mentally. Now more than ever, there is a global need to circumvent this pattern of being. We need to learn to unconditionally love and appreciate ourselves just as we are, how we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing Epidemic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, it was believed the cause of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/03/04/less-stress-less-psychosis/&quot;&gt;stress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/20/a-scientific-review-of-hbo-documentary-film-my-depression/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt; was attributable to genetic disposition, personality traits, the existence of stressful events, physical health problems, and substance abuse, as well as serotonin, dopamine, and epinephrine imbalances within the brain. Whilst this is largely still the case, this perception has altered over the last decade or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our fast-paced world, we judge ourselves as harshly as we judge others. We are encouraged and manipulated to compete with others with whom we continually compare ourselves. We try so hard to emulate or exceed expectations placed upon us that we forget our personal needs in the process (no time for that!). Stress and anxiety often manifest as a result as we try and prove our worth to the world, and depression looms when we judge ourselves as falling short of the benchmark that is set for us to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prolonged periods of stress wreak havoc on the human mind and body. Chronic muscle tension leads to tension headaches and migraines. The cardiovascular, respiratory, and endocrine systems become over-taxed and the risk increases for the development of diseases like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/01/03/can-an-anti-asthma-drug-rejuvenate-the-brain/&quot;&gt;asthma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/19/link-between-diabetes-and-alzheimers-disease/&quot;&gt;type 2 diabetes&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/21/cartoon-nuts-reduce-heart-disease-and-death/&quot;&gt;heart disease&lt;/a&gt; (just to name a few).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent times the media has reported stress, anxiety, and depression as reaching epidemic proportions, reportedly attributable to numerous causes including an increase in hours in front of computer screens, national and cultural competitiveness, the exposure to a broadening range of choices due to advances in technology, and the belief that worthiness is related to monetary success.  Additionally, there is a sense of “collective stress” in regards to issues such as climate change and terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness &amp;amp; Self-Reflection &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst living a faster pace, society has forgotten the art of living in the present moment, and yet there is much evidence to support that engaging in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/21/mindfulness-may-be-the-secret-to-staying-healthy/&quot;&gt;mindfulness &lt;/a&gt;and self-reflection enables sufferers to break the cycle of anxiety, stress, and depression as it promotes a greater sense of well-being and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who engage in the art of mindfulness and self-reflection can improve their ability relate to the world around them in a more compassionate and empathetic manner.  A feeling of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/26/learning-how-to-practice-being-grateful-and-reap-the-benefits/&quot;&gt;gratitude&lt;/a&gt;, joy, and abundance is also often a pleasant side effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Value of Meditation &amp;amp; Journaling &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies have shown that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/10/03/writing-away-your-worries/&quot;&gt;journaling &lt;/a&gt;can positively impact a person’s mental health as it allows one to “capture” a thought for long enough to acquire a 360-degree perspective on what that thought is about, where it came from, and how acting on that thought might impact those around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many forms of meditation, like mindfulness meditation, work particularly well with journaling as it takes the mind out of a conscious, judgmental state and into a reflective, sub-conscious state. Such meditative practices smooth the path for writing down thoughts and feelings by prompting less judgment of the thoughts being written down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meditative practice can be merely taking five minutes to go for a walk in the park or to focus on breathing patterns—anything that promotes being in the present moment. Likewise, there are many effective journaling techniques that may help people with &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/10/31/meditate-to-learn-compassion/&quot;&gt;self-reflection&lt;/a&gt; and mindfulness that work well with meditation, and they are not restricted just to writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many, mindfulness can be achieved through writing, art, photography – any means that allows a person to step into a reflective zone. It is for an individual to explore what takes them to that special place where they can set down their emotional and mental baggage to touch base with their soul, and nurturing a sense of gratitude and appreciation for all the simple attainable pleasures within day to day life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Michigan Depression Center, Depression toolkit.org. Journaling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.depressiontoolkit.org/takecare/journaling.asp&quot;&gt;http://www.depressiontoolkit.org/takecare/journaling.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tams, L, Journalling To Reduce Stress (1 May, 2013) Michigan State University Extensiona, &amp;lt; href=&quot;http://msue.anr.msu.edu/news/journaling_to_reduce_stress&quot;&amp;gt;http://msue.anr.msu.edu/news/journaling_to_reduce_stress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hidaka BH, Depression as a disease of modernity: explanations for increasing prevalence, 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3330161/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3330161/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCormack, A, “Lovitude: Trying To Calm The Monkey Mind”, 2016, Peacock Dreaming Publications, Nelson (NZ)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/GDJ-1086657/&quot;&gt;GDJ&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This material does weird things under pressure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/material-does-weird-things-under-pressure</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/material-does-weird-things-under-pressure</link>
	<description>A new metamaterial has a seemingly impossible property: It swells when squeezed.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111717_MT_metamaterial_feat.png?itok=zox62-RS" length="171396" type="image/png"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: After losing two video game-violence papers, co-author’s weapons paper is flagged</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52669</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/20/losing-two-video-game-violence-papers-co-authors-weapons-paper-flagged/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Can seeing a weapon increase aggressive thoughts and behaviors? A meta-analysis on the so-called “weapons effect” has been flagged with an expression of concern by a SAGE journal, after the researchers discovered errors affecting at least one of the main conclusions. The paper found that the presence of weapons increased people’s aggressiveness, but not feelings […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/20/losing-two-video-game-violence-papers-co-authors-weapons-paper-flagged/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;After losing two video game-violence papers, co-author’s weapons paper is flagged&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 13:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Watch NASA’s mesmerizing new visualization of the 2017 hurricane season</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/watch-nasas-mesmerizing-new-visualization-2017-hurricane-season</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/watch-nasas-mesmerizing-new-visualization-2017-hurricane-season</link>
	<description>Swirls of sand, sea salt and smoke make atmospheric currents visible in a new NASA visualization.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111617_CG_hurricaneaerosols_feat.jpg?itok=qOsGnaPE" length="413596" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Life after Harvey: 3 ways science can prepare us for the worst</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/life-after-harvey-3-ways-science-can-prepare-us-for-the-worst</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/life-after-harvey-3-ways-science-can-prepare-us-for-the-worst</link>
	<description>Elsevier's new report provides a quantitative review of global research performance in disaster science</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 11:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: What’s different about the brains of the minority of us who feel other people’s physical pain?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32595</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/20/whats-different-about-the-brains-of-the-minority-of-us-who-feel-other-peoples-physical-pain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;fnhum-11-00507-g003&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-32598&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32598&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;fnhum-11-00507-g003&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/fnhum-11-00507-g003.jpg?w=454&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/fnhum-11-00507-g003.jpg?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/fnhum-11-00507-g003.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;454,389&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/20/whats-different-about-the-brains-of-the-minority-of-us-who-feel-other-peoples-physical-pain/fnhum-11-00507-g003/&quot; height=&quot;257&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/fnhum-11-00507-g003.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=257&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a friend sees you suffering and tells you “&lt;i&gt;I feel your pain&lt;/i&gt;”, it may be more than an expression of empathy. For about a quarter of people, it could be literally true. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28759805&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt;, led by Thomas Grice-Jackson at the University of Sussex, found that 27 per cent of participants experienced so-called “mirror pain” – watching someone falling off a bicycle or receiving an injection, for instance, caused them to experience physical pain of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2017.00507/full&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Human Neuroscience&lt;/i&gt;, the same team of researchers has explored the neurological underpinnings of mirror pain. When some people have this experience, they don’t just show more activity in the so-called “pain matrix” (the network of brain regions linked to the experience of pain), they also show unusual patterns of neural activity that suggest they struggle to distinguish other people’s experience from their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32595&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers studied 44 participants, 18 men and 26 women, who had completed a survey that involved watching 16 movies depicting people experiencing injections and sports injuries, and reporting whether they experienced any pain themselves, and if so, what it was like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty-one of the participants had said they didn’t experience any pain sensations; 13 others were “Sensory/Localiser responders” – they experienced a discrete pain in the same body locations as the injured people in the videos; and the rest were “Affective/General responders” – they described a more whole-body response. For the last group, watching someone getting hurt may trigger a general “nauseating” kind of pain, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers used fMRI to scan all these participants’ brains while they looked at a series of 16 images depicting hands and feet suffering a variety of everyday painful incidents (like fingers being caught in a car door) as well as similar but pain-free images (like a hand closing a car door). After each image, they were asked to rate how much pain they’d experienced, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers expected the Sensory/Localiser types to show more activity in the somatosensory cortices (neural areas involved in processing touch) whereas the Affective/General volunteers would show more activity in affective, motivational brain regions, like the anterior insula. In fact, they didn’t find this. When witnessing pain, both types of mirror pain volunteers showed greater activity in all these regions than the non-responders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, differences between the mirror-pain subgroups emerged in the way that different parts of their brains communicated with each other. When the Sensory/Localiser group witnessed painful incidents, there was greater communication between the anterior insula and the right temporal-parietal junction (rTPJ) regions of their brains, for example. There is evidence from other studies that the rTPJ is involved in representations of the self and “other”. “Our explanation of the Sensory/Localised group is that they systematically fail to attribute shared bodily representations to others,” the researchers wrote. There were hints of distinct patterns of neural communication for the other subgroup, but the researchers admitted: “The explanation for the Affective/General group is presently lacking.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research highlights how there is great variety in our experience of seeing other people in pain. But it’s clear we are only just beginning to understand the brain basis of these different ways of empathising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2017.00507/full&quot;&gt;Consciously Feeling the Pain of Others Reflects Atypical Functional Connectivity between the Pain Matrix and Frontal-Parietal Regions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2017.00507/full&quot;&gt;Grice-Jackson et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;: “Images display within group effects for Pain &amp;gt; No-Pain contrasts for each of the groups.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32595/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32595/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32595&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 09:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: UK government announces research-spending hike ahead of budget</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23028</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/BKqxLSUf-xs/nature.2017.23028</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Pledge to raise country's public research funding to £12.5 billion in 2021–22.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23028&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/BKqxLSUf-xs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Exoplanet hunters rethink search for alien life</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23023</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hSlVg7PWjhM/nature.2017.23023</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Astronomers expand ideas of how chemistry and geology could affect chances for life on other worlds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23023&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hSlVg7PWjhM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Online software spots genetic errors in cancer papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23003</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/OTAl4PvXsxs/nature.2017.23003</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Tool to scrutinize research papers identifies mistakes in gene sequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23003&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/OTAl4PvXsxs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: God in the Brain: the Science of Neurotheology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23114</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/19/god-in-the-brain-the-science-of-neurotheology/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We are the only species on the planet known to practice religion. This feature is universal among humans: there is no nation on Earth that does not practice one or another form of spiritual belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is what makes our brain different so that we practice &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/04/11/does-spirituality-and-religion-guard-against-depression/&quot;&gt;spirituality&lt;/a&gt;? Does religion serve any purpose to our species in terms of benefiting survival and progress? These questions are very philosophical. Many thinkers believe that religiosity is what distinguishes &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; from the rest of the animal kingdom and brought our species to dominate this planet. On the other hand, a large numbers of thinkers believe that religion impedes progress and keeps our society in a barbaric state. There is no doubt that religion played a very important role in early human history: providing the first explanations for the existence of the world around us. The need for such explanation highlights an important step in the development of the brain and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/15/brain-training-can-we-really-enhance-our-cognitive-skills/&quot;&gt;cognitive &lt;/a&gt;processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioral traits might become strengthened by evolution if they bring survival benefits. Researchers think that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/29/neurological-basis-of-altruism/&quot;&gt;altruism&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, is this kind of behavioral trait: it might be disadvantageous for a particular individual at a particular instance, but it brings advantages to the species in general. Altruistic behavior is promoted by the majority of the world’s religions. Therefore, religious practices might have provided evolutionary advantages for early humans in terms of survival too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people are so deeply religious that the system of beliefs they practice shapes their whole life. It would be reasonable to assume that something interesting should be going on in their brain. It is also quite likely that these brain processes are different from the processes in the brains of unbelievers. This is what the new science of neurotheology is aiming to study. Neurotheology investigates the neural correlates of religious and spiritual beliefs. Such studies may help to uncover why some people are more inclined towards spirituality, while others remain deeply skeptical about the whole idea of God’s existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already some interesting findings from the field of neuroscience that can help to open the window into the spiritual brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is no single part of the brain which is “responsible” for an individual’s relationship with their God/s. Like any emotionally intense human experience, religious experiences involves multiple parts and systems of the brain. Several experiments with the use of brain scanners confirm this point of view. In one study, Carmelite nuns were asked to remember their most intense mystical experience while neuroimaging of their brain was conducted. The loci of activation in this experiment were observed in the right medial orbitofrontal cortex, right middle temporal cortex, right inferior and superior parietal lobules, right caudate, left medial prefrontal cortex, left anterior cingulate cortex, left inferior parietal lobule, left insula, left caudate, and left brainstem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, an fMRI study on religious Mormon subjects found areas of activation in the nucleus accumbens, ventromedial prefrontal cortex, and frontal attentional regions. The nucleus accumbens is the brain area associated with reward. It is also involved in emotional responses to  love, sex, drugs, and music. One recent study also identified a number of changes in regional cortical volumes that are associated with several components of religiosity, such as an intimate relationship with God and fear of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears likely that life-changing religious experiences may be linked to changes in brain structure. For instance, one study demonstrated that the brains of older adults who reported such experiences feature a degree of hippocampal atrophy. Hippocampal atrophy is an important factor in the development of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/08/new-target-in-brain-for-treating-depression-the-bmp-pathway/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/22/older-age-dementia-and-circadian-rhythms/&quot;&gt;dementia&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/15/environmental-factors-in-development-of-alzheimers-disease/&quot;&gt;Alzheimer’s disease&lt;/a&gt;. It remains unclear exactly how structural changes in the brain and the level of religiosity relate to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is well known that some drugs simulate spiritual experiences. For instance, psilosybin, the active ingredient in “&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/06/22/magic-mushrooms-for-mental-health/&quot;&gt;magic mushrooms&lt;/a&gt;”, stimulates temporal lobes and mimics religious experiences. This implies that spirituality is rooted in neuronal physiology. It is no wonder that psychoactive compounds are often used in ritualistic and shamanistic practices around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All studies that involve brain imaging of people in specific states suffer from one major limitation: it is hard to be sure that people are actually in that particular state at the time of measurement. For instance, if we measure the brain activity when a subject is supposed to solve a mathematical task, we can’t be 100% sure that his or her mind is not wondering around instead of focusing on the task. The same applies to the measurement of any spiritual state. Therefore, the patterns of brain activation obtained through brain imaging should not be viewed as ultimate proof of any theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various religious practices have the potential to influence our health, in both positive and negative directions. It was noted that religious people, in general, have a lower risk of anxiety and depression. This, in turn, is linked to a stronger immune system. On the other hand, people engaged in religious struggles might experience the opposite effects. Research into the brain’s response to religious practices might help to develop further our understanding of the connection between health and spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beauregard M and Paquette V (2006) Neural correlates of a mystical experience in Carmelite nuns. Neuroscience Letters 405(3):186-90. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2006.06.060&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neulet.2006.06.060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferguson MA et al. (2016) Reward, salience, and attentional networks are activated by religious experience in devout Mormons. Social Neuroscience: 1–13. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080%2F17470919.2016.1257437&quot;&gt;10.1080/17470919.2016.1257437&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Griffiths RR et al. (2006) Psilocybin can occasion mystical-type experiences having substantial and sustained personal meaning and spiritual significance. Psychopharmacology. 187 (3): 268–83; discussion 284–92. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1007%2Fs00213-006-0457-5&quot;&gt;10.1007/s00213-006-0457-5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Griffiths RR et al. (2008) Mystical-type experiences occasioned by psilocybin mediate the attribution of personal meaning and spiritual significance 14 months later. Journal of psychopharmacology. 22 (6): 621–32. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F0269881108094300&quot;&gt;10.1177/0269881108094300&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kapogiannis D et al. (2009) Neuroanatomical Variability of Religiosity. PLoS ONE4(9): e7180. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0007180&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0007180&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kapogiannis D et al. (2009). Cognitive and neural foundations of religious belief. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106(12), 4876–4881. &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0811717106&quot;&gt;http://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0811717106&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owen AD et al. (2011) Religious factors and hippocampal atrophy in late life. PLoS ONE. 6 (3): e17006. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0017006&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0017006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sayadmansour A (2014) Neurotheology: The relationship between brain and religion. Iranian Journal of Neurology, 13(1), 52–55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 16:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new map exhibit documents evolving views of Earth’s interior</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-map-exhibit-documents-evolving-views-earths-interior</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-map-exhibit-documents-evolving-views-earths-interior</link>
	<description>&quot;Beneath Our Feet&quot; puts maps on display to show how people have envisioned and explored Earth’s subsurface.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_reviews_main.jpg?itok=8-ehA8x4" length="32271" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Ethical issues could cost university millions in funding; Stolen bone raises questions; Ingelfinger rides again</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52666</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/18/weekend-reads-ethical-issues-cost-university-millions-funding-stolen-bone-raises-questions-ingelfinger-rides/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a the story of how a nonexistent paper earned 400 ciations, a lawsuit filed against a journal for publishing criticism, and the retraction and replacement of a paper by a group of anti-vaccine advocates. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: Ethically dubious research backed by tech billionaire Peter Thiel could cost a university millions […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/18/weekend-reads-ethical-issues-cost-university-millions-funding-stolen-bone-raises-questions-ingelfinger-rides/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Ethical issues could cost university millions in funding; Stolen bone raises questions; Ingelfinger rides again&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Arecibo Observatory will remain open, NSF says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/arecibo-radio-telescope-nsf</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/arecibo-radio-telescope-nsf</link>
	<description>The iconic Arecibo radio telescope has survived Hurricane Maria and dodged deep funding cuts.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 20:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111717_LG_arecibo_feat.jpg?itok=1MxcNwzo" length="40749" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Skeletons could provide clues to who wrote or protected the Dead Sea Scrolls</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/skeletons-could-provide-clues-who-wrote-or-protected-dead-sea-scrolls</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/skeletons-could-provide-clues-who-wrote-or-protected-dead-sea-scrolls</link>
	<description>Skeletons suggest a group of celibate men inhabited Dead Sea Scrolls site.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 19:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111717_BB_deadseascrolls_feat.jpg?itok=ubS-RHoI" length="38468" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The key to breaking down plastic may be in caterpillars’ guts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/key-breaking-down-plastic-may-be-caterpillar-guts</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/key-breaking-down-plastic-may-be-caterpillar-guts</link>
	<description>Caterpillars that feast on plastic have different gut microbes than those that eat a grain-based diet.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 18:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111617_LH_plodiainterpuctella_feat.jpg?itok=kgS1VMOB" length="32876" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Medicinal Plants and the Brain — St. John’s Wort, Skullcap, and Ashwagandha</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23131</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/17/the-influence-of-medicinal-plants-on-the-brain-part-i/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Medicinal plants still comprise a nebulous cloud in biomedical science. We know they have been used since the dawn of man, but there are precious few good quality scientific studies that support their use. Unlike pharmaceutical drugs, plant medicines consist of many different molecules that interact together in the body to have a variety of, poorly understood, pharmacological effects. Despite variably successful attempts to identify single molecules in plants for drug development, we should acknowledge that the whole is greater than a single part. There is an increasing number of clinical studies which strongly imply that root, leaf, and flower extracts of medicinal plants can influence the brain and are effective at treating cognitive disorders. This article series will examine plants where we have double-blind, placebo-controlled studies to support their medicinal influence on the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. John’s wort&lt;/strong&gt; is a commonly known plant that is native to Europe and yields bright yellow flowers. Its name comes from flowering around St. John’s day on the 24th June. St. John’s wort has been used as long ago as the ancient Greeks, and the physician Dioscorides (40–90AD) used it in the treatment of sciatica. However, St. John’s wort has become known as less of a treatment for nerve pain and more so for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/01/12/sad-and-in-pain-the-link-between-migraine-and-depression/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, with multiple double-blind, placebo-controlled trials confirming its antidepressant properties. Authors typically compare St. John’s wort with mainstream anti-depressant drugs and find it has a preferable side effects profile. It is not without its downsides however, as excessive use has been linked to serotonin syndrome, sun sensitivity, and easy skin burning, and more generally with increased pharmaceutical drug metabolism by the liver. This means St. John’s wort may not be suitable for applications alongside other pharmaceutical drugs, and it is contraindicated with serotonin reuptake inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American skullcap&lt;/strong&gt; is a member of the mint family that is native to North America and grows wild in meadows and swamps. It was used by the Native Americans as a sedative and America’s 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century physicians, the Eclectics, widely used the herb for complaints involving an overactive nervous system such as insomnia, anxiety, and epilepsy. A human double-blind, placebo-controlled study supports skullcap’s application against &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/04/phobias-part-ii-new-social-anxiety-treatments-mdma-testosterone-less-serotonin/&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt;, and a mood elevating effect has also been noted. Herbalist’s view both St. John’s wort and American skullcap as ‘nervine tonics’, meaning that they act upon the nervous system medicinally and are also considered to have a long-term renewing effect. While, this claim is yet to be verified by scientific studies, it certainly warrants further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashwagandha&lt;/strong&gt;, the root of which is a popular home remedy in India, is a plant native to India that is mentioned in the traditional Ayurvedic medical text, the &lt;em&gt;Charaka Samhita&lt;/em&gt;, approximately 2000 years ago. Here it is recommended as a tonic for emancipation, reproductive ability, and longevity. In Ayurveda, it is classified as a ‘rasayana herb’, a class of plant that are considered to restore and support long-term health and that overlaps to some degree with the Western definition of a ‘tonic herb’. Two double-blind, placebo-controlled human studies support ashwagandha’s role in the reduction of anxiety. It’s wide-ranging medicinal properties are supported by two additional well-controlled, human clinical studies on &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/13/pain-in-osteoarthritis/&quot;&gt;osteoarthritis&lt;/a&gt; and subclinical hypothyroidism. The emerging picture is that ashwagandha possesses a wide range of medicinal properties that will likely be better understood in the future. Ashwagandha has been well-tolerated across clinical trials, with a side effect profile similar to placebo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auddy B, Hazra J, Mitra A, Abedon B, and Ghosal S. A standardized Withania somnifera extract significantly reduces stress-related parameters in chronically stressed humans: A double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled study. J Am Nutraceutical Assoc. 2008;11:50–6. Access &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.priceplow.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/withania_review.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brock C, Whitehouse J, Tewfik I, and Towell T. (2014). American Skullcap (Scutellaria lateriflora): A Randomised, Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Crossover Study of its Effects on Mood in Healthy Volunteers. &lt;em&gt;Phytotherapy Research&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;28&lt;/em&gt;(5), 692-698. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.5044&quot;&gt;10.1002/ptr.5044&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Castleman, Michael. “The new healing herbs.” &lt;em&gt;Bantam Book, New York&lt;/em&gt; (2001): 465-471. ISBN: 1605298891&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandrasekhar K, Kapoor J, and Anishetty S. A prospective, randomized double-blind, placebo-controlled study of safety and efficacy of a high-concentration full-spectrum extract of ashwagandha root in reducing stress and anxiety in adults. &lt;em&gt;Indian Journal of Psychological Medicine&lt;/em&gt; 34.3 (2012): 255. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.4103/0253-7176.106022&quot;&gt;10.4103/0253-7176.106022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dannawi M. Possible serotonin syndrome after combination of buspirone and St John’s Wort. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychopharmacology&lt;/em&gt; 16.4 (2002): 401-401. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1177/026988110201600420&quot;&gt;10.1177/026988110201600420&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoffman, David. &lt;em&gt;Holistic herbal&lt;/em&gt;. Element Books, 1988. ISBN: 1852300248&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laakmann G, Schüle C, Baghai T, and Kieser M. St. John’s wort in mild to moderate depression: the relevance of hyperforin for the clinical efficacy. &lt;em&gt;Pharmacopsychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 31.S 1 (1998): 54-59. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-979346&quot;&gt;10.1055/s-2007-979346&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markowitz JS, Donovan JL, DeVane CL, Taylor RM, Ruan Y, Wang JS, and Chavin KD. Effect of St John’s wort on drug metabolism by induction of cytochrome P450 3A4 enzyme. &lt;em&gt;Jama&lt;/em&gt; 290.11 (2003): 1500-1504. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1001/jama.290.11.1500&quot;&gt;10.1001/jama.290.11.1500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramakanth GS, Uday Kumar C, Kishan PV, and Usharani P. A randomized, double blind placebo controlled study of efficacy and tolerability of Withaina somnifera extracts in knee joint pain. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Ayurveda and integrative medicine&lt;/em&gt; 7.3 (2016): 151-157. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaim.2016.05.003&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jaim.2016.05.003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scudder, John. Specific Medication and Specific Medicines, 1870. ISBN: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharma AK, Basu I, and Singh S1. Efficacy and Safety of Ashwagandha Root Extract in Subclinical Hypothyroid Patients: A Double-Blind, Randomized Placebo-Controlled Trial. &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine&lt;/em&gt; (2017). DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1089/acm.2017.0183&quot;&gt;10.1089/acm.2017.0183&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Szegedi A, Kohnen R, Dienel A, and Kieser M. Acute treatment of moderate to severe depression with hypericum extract WS 5570 (St John’s wort): randomised controlled double blind non-inferiority trial versus paroxetine. &lt;em&gt;Bmj&lt;/em&gt; 330.7490 (2005): 503. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.38356.655266.82&quot;&gt;10.1136/bmj.38356.655266.82&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woelk, Helmut. Comparison of St John’s wort and imipramine for treating depression: randomised controlled trial. &lt;em&gt;Bmj&lt;/em&gt; 321.7260 (2000): 536-539. PMCID: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC27467/&quot;&gt;PMC27467&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolfson P and Hoffmann DL. An investigation into the efficacy of Scutellaria lateriflora in healthy volunteers. &lt;em&gt;Alternative therapies in health and medicine&lt;/em&gt; 9.2 (2003): 74. PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12652886&quot;&gt;12652886&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/kerdkanno-1334070/&quot;&gt;kerdkanno&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: PLOS ONE retracts two papers one year after author says he okayed the move</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52643</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/17/plos-one-retracts-two-papers-one-year-author-says-okayed-move/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;PLOS ONE has retracted two 2014 papers from a group of researchers, after an institutional investigation confirmed image duplication. Although the authors initially asked to correct the figures in the two papers, they ultimately agreed with the decision to retract. Mrinal K. Maiti—an associate professor at the Indian Institute of Technology at Kharagpur and corresponding author […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/17/plos-one-retracts-two-papers-one-year-author-says-okayed-move/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE retracts two papers one year after author says he okayed the move&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 16:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: Catching up with the Internet Era: Online data collection for researchers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=590</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/17/590/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In the world we humans spend a great deal of time connected to the internet, this is especially true for younger people – who are growing up surrounded by this technology. You can see this huge change over time in graph from Our World in Data below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_593&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alex post pic1&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-593&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;593&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Alex post pic1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/alex-post-pic1.png?w=474?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/alex-post-pic1.png?w=474?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/alex-post-pic1.png?w=474&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;872,400&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/11/17/590/alex-post-pic1/&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/alex-post-pic1.png?w=474&quot; /&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.worldbank.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://data.worldbank.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, researchers and companies are leveraging this remote access to behaviour to answer questions about how humans behave. Companies have been collecting ‘user data’ for years from online platforms, and using this inferred information about people to improve user experience, and in some cases sell more products to the correct people. The amount of data we are able to collect on behaviour is expanding exponentially, and at the same time so is the quality and modality of this data – as people connect different devices (like activity monitors, clocks, fridges). Wearable sensors are becoming particularly more frequent – often this data is stored using internet-based services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/chart/3370/wearable-device-forecast/&quot; title=&quot;Infographic: The Predicted Wearables Boom Is All About The Wrist | Statista&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Infographic: The Predicted Wearables Boom Is All About The Wrist | Statista&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; src=&quot;https://infographic.statista.com/normal/chartoftheday_3370_Wearable_device_forecast_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/&quot;&gt;Statista&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology and cognitive science is starting to catch up on this trend, as it offers the ability to carry out controlled experiments on a much larger scale. This offers the opportunity to characterise subtle differences, that would be lost in the noise of small samples tested in a lab environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for many the task of running an online experiment is daunting; there are so many choices, and dealing with building, hosting and data processing can be tricky!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Web Browsers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good starting point, and often the most straightforward, is building experiments to work in a web browser. The primary advantage of this is that you can run experiments on the vast majority of computers, and even mobile devices, with no installation overhead. There are some limitations though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compatibility:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Internet Explorer - sigh&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.discourse.org/sitepoint/uploads/default/21195/0bc6a8ea7fc9f167.jpg&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With multiple different web browsers, operating systems, and devices, the possible combinations number in the 1000s. This can lead to unexpected bugs and errors in your experiment. A workaround is to restrict access to a few devices (see below for tips on how to do this in JavaScript) – but this is traded off with how many participants you would like to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web browsers were not designed to run reaction time experiments in, or present stimulus with millisecond precision. Despite this, some research has shown equivalent precision for &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13428-015-0678-9&quot;&gt;Reaction Time&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0109812&quot;&gt;Stimulus Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are very concerned still, you may utilise&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/WebGL_API&quot;&gt; WebGL&lt;/a&gt;, a web graphics engine, which allows you to gain analogous presentation times to native programs, and even use a computer’s graphics card. Although this will be limited by the operating system and hardware of the user!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of tools that can help you with browser experiments. From fee-paying services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://gorilla.sc/&quot;&gt;Gorilla&lt;/a&gt;, which deals with task building, hosting and data management for you, to fully open source projects like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jspsych.org/&quot;&gt;jsPsych&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychopy.org/online/fromBuilder.html&quot;&gt;PsychoPy’s PsychoJS&lt;/a&gt; – which deal with building experiments and data, but not hosting (although &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.psychopy.org/t/wellcome-trust-funding-psychopy-is-going-properly-online/2809&quot;&gt;there are plans to develop a hosting and data storage solution&lt;/a&gt;). All of these offer a graphical user-interface, which allows experiments to be built without any prior knowledge of programming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Unity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;unity&quot; class=&quot; alignright&quot; src=&quot;https://answers.unity.com/storage/temp/56640-screenshot-2015-10-21-15-35-36.png&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One intermediate tool – which we are currently using – is cross platform development environment called &lt;a href=&quot;https://unity3d.com/&quot;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;. Whilst originally intended for creating video-games, Unity can be repurposed for creating experimental apps. The large advantage is an easy capability to build to a vast variety of operating systems and platforms with minimal effort: a Unity project can be built for a web browser, iOS app, Android app, Windows, OSX, Linux…. and so on. You can also gain access to sensor information on devices (hear rate monitors, step counting, microphone, camera), to start to access the richness of information contained in these devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The utility of this tool for experimental research is huge, and apparently appears to be under-utilised – it has an easy to learn interface, and requires minimal programming knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst this post is largely non-instructional, hopefully it has shed some light on the potential tools you can use to start running research online (without employing an expensive web or app developer), or hopefully just piqued your interest a tiny bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to dive in to the murky (but exciting) world of web development, you can also check out a few tips for improving the quality of your online data &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irvine.science/2017/07/23/5-tools-for-improving-online-data-collection/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This exciting post was written by Alexander Irvine, one of the newest members of our lab. Alex previously worked on developing web-based study at Oxford before joining the lab and is experienced in an array of programming languages and tools. Check out his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irvine.science/2017/07/23/5-tools-for-improving-online-data-collection/&quot;&gt;personal website&lt;/a&gt; if you want to read more in-depth about online data collection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/590/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/590/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=590&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: “Profoundly sorry” researcher retracts Alzheimer’s-DDT paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52585</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/17/caught-notice-profoundly-sorry-researcher-retracts-alzheimers-ddt-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Immune response cytokines as potential biomarkers for DDT induced neurodegeneration What Caught Our Attention:  Does exposure to pesticides such as DDT influence the onset of Alzheimer’s? Hard to say, especially after a researcher retracted a recent paper purporting to find a link in mice, a few months after a press release was issued about the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/17/caught-notice-profoundly-sorry-researcher-retracts-alzheimers-ddt-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: “Profoundly sorry” researcher retracts Alzheimer’s-DDT paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 13:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fluorescence could help diagnose sick corals</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fluorescence-could-help-diagnose-sick-corals</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fluorescence-could-help-diagnose-sick-corals</link>
	<description>Diseased corals fluoresce less than healthy corals, and a new analysis technique can help spot the reduced glow.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/120917_scivis_main.jpg?itok=TSvLY9x3" length="35460" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: We are witnessing a renaissance in psychology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32642</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/17/we-are-witnessing-a-renaissance-in-psychology/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-23&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-488610736.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32748&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32748&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman hand pulling open sunny sky cityscape curtain covering stormy city.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;BsWei&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman hand pulling sunny sky cityscapes curtain covering stormy&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woman hand pulling sunny sky cityscapes curtain covering stormy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-488610736.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-488610736.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-488610736.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/17/we-are-witnessing-a-renaissance-in-psychology/woman-hand-pulling-sunny-sky-cityscapes-curtain-covering-stormy/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-488610736.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The future looks bright&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of talk of the crisis in psychology. For decades, and often with the best of intentions, researchers have engaged in practices that have made it likely their results are “false positives” or not real. But that was in the past. The crisis is ending. “We do not call the rain that follows a long drought a ‘water crisis’,” write Leif Nelson at UC Berkeley and Joseph Simmons and Uri Simonsohn at the University of Pennsylvania. “We do not call sustained growth following a recession an ‘economic crisis'”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their paper, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-psych-122216-011836&quot;&gt;due for publication in the &lt;em&gt;Annual Review of Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the trio observe that had any psychologists been in hibernation for the last seven years, they would not recognise their field today. The full disclosure of methods and data, the pre-registration of studies, the publication of negative findings, and replication attempts – all of which help reduce risk of false positives – have increased immeasurably. “The improvements to our field have been dramatic,” they write. “This is psychology’s renaissance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well giving the field of psychology a pep talk, their paper provides a useful review of how we got to this point, the reasons things are getting better, and the ongoing controversies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32642&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crisis before the renaissance &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson and his colleagues believe that starting in 2011, several key developments led to psychology entering a period of self-reflection about its methods. First, a weird, controversial study was published in a prestigious journal. It applied widely used statistical methods to demonstrate “transparently outlandish” effects (our regrettably gullible coverage at the time: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2010/11/12/dramatic-study-shows-participants-are-affected-by-psychological-phenomena-from-the-future/&quot;&gt;Dramatic study shows participants are affected by psychological phenomena from the future&lt;/a&gt;“).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same year there were several &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/07/03/fake-data-or-scientific-mistake/&quot;&gt;fraud scandals&lt;/a&gt;. There was also Nelson and his colleagues’ own &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797611417632&quot;&gt;influential paper&lt;/a&gt; demonstrating how easy it was to use selective reporting and strategic data analysis to extract a ridiculous positive result from random data (in this case, listening to music was shown to decrease your age). They called this approach p-hacking, which is a reference to the fact that psychologists frequently use a statistic known as the p-value – &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/08/09/made-it-an-uncanny-number-of-psychology-findings-manage-to-scrape-into-statistical-significance/&quot;&gt;specifically whether it is below 0.05&lt;/a&gt; – to determine whether their result is statically significant or not. Not long after, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/12/01/questionable-research-practices-are-rife-in-psychology-survey-suggests/&quot;&gt;a survey&lt;/a&gt; of psychology researchers showed that “questionable research practices” indicative of p-hacking were commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson and his colleagues believe that p-hacking helps explain how for several decades psychologists have used underpowered studies with too few participants, and yet succeeded in publishing countless positive results (&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/04/10/serious-power-failure-threatens-the-entire-field-of-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;a similar problem afflicts neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/04/10/serious-power-failure-threatens-the-entire-field-of-neuroscience/&quot;&gt;a similar problem afflicts neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;). “P-hacking has long been the biggest threat to the integrity of our discipline,” they write. Researchers have prodded and pushed their results, dropping participants here, running new trials there, selectively reporting just those conditions that seemed to work. For years, the prevailing ethos was that to succeed you do what you can to extract a positive finding from your experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P-hacking could explain why &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/16/ten-famous-psychology-findings-that-its-been-difficult-to-replicate/&quot;&gt;so many famous findings in psychology have failed to replicate&lt;/a&gt;, often when tested under more rigorous conditions. But this is open to debate, and in some cases ill-tempered argument (the authors of past studies that haven’t replicated have sometimes bristled at the suggestion that they did not conduct their studies robustly enough, or that their findings are not real).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson and his colleagues believe all sides can agree that most researchers are honest and well-intentioned. As self-confessed former p-hackers, they write that “p-hacking is not categorised as such by the researcher who is doing it. It is not something that malevolent researchers engage in while laughing maniacally.” Regardless of how frequent p-hacking has been, Nelson et al. hope that everyone recognises that it’s better to reduce p-hacking. Or put differently, that it’s better to do science in a way that reduces the risk of false-positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The renaissance begins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, a consensus seems to have emerged around this position. Amidst all the drama, a revolution is underway. A key player is the psychologist Brian Nosek at the University of Virginia who helped launch the &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io&quot;&gt;Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;, an online platform that makes it easy to share methods and data online, and then in 2013 he co-founded the Center for Open Science (read &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/05/20/a-replication-tour-de-force/&quot;&gt;our&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/08/27/this-is-what-happened-when-psychologists-tried-to-replicate-100-previously-published-findings/&quot;&gt;coverage&lt;/a&gt; of some of the large-scale replication efforts organised by the Center).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other positive changes include key journals such as &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Social Psychological and Personality Science&lt;/em&gt; implementing the requirement for researchers to disclose all of their measures and manipulations. Even better, pre-registration of methods (publishing your planned methods and hypotheses before you collect your data) is becoming easier and more widespread (two key sites for this are &lt;a href=&quot;https://aspredicted.org&quot;&gt;AsPredicted.org&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io&quot;&gt;Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;), and an increasing number of journals now publish “registered reports”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/head-quarters/2014/may/20/psychology-registration-revolution&quot;&gt;a cause championed by psychologist Chris Chambers in the UK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We expect that in 3-5 years, published pre-registered experimental psychology studies will be either common or extremely common,” write Nelson et al. Some have complained that pre-registered stifles scientific exploration, but Nelson’s team counter “it does not preclude exploration, but it does communicate to readers that it occurred”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has also been a welcome “surge of interest” in &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/11/11/a-recipe-for-attempting-to-replicate-existing-findings-in-psychology/&quot;&gt;replicating&lt;/a&gt; previous studies – one of the main ways to uncover and address the possible effects of p-hacking on previously published research (according to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curatescience.org&quot;&gt;CurateScience&lt;/a&gt; database, 96 per cent of over 1000 replication attempts have been conducted since 2011). With regard to the debates that often ensue after a failed replication attempt (such as whether the replication was similar enough to the original), Nelson et al. propose a compromise: “the burden of proof is on the researcher espousing the least plausible claim”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if the author of the original finding complains that the replication study took place on a different day of the week (and that’s why it didn’t work), it’s beholden on her or him to demonstrate why day of the week should moderate the effect that they originally claimed to have uncovered. On other hand, if the replicators used an obviously inferior manipulation (e.g. in a study testing the effects of hunger, they used just a few minutes without food to induce hunger), it’s up to them to show that the lack of effect persists when hunger is induced in more robust fashion. “Neutral observers often agree on who has the burden of proof,” write Nelson et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue for psychology’s renaissance is how to categorise a replication attempt as a success or failure. In fact, Nelson et al. explain how this is often not straight forward and in many cases it is more fair and accurate to interpret unsuccessful replications as inconclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ongoing debates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other issues going forward include finding optimal ways to check the veracity of collections of prior studies, such as through using a statistical technique known as “p-curve analysis”. No one approach is flawless. More also needs to be done to check for innocent errors (which are extremely common) and outright fraud (thankfully rare, although Nelson’s team say that “for every case of fraud that is identified, there are almost certainly may more that are not”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the simplest solutions is simply to require researchers to post their data and materials online. “Public data posting not only allows others to verify the accuracy of the analyses, but also incentivises authors to more carefully avoid errors,” write Nelson and his colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some readers may be surprised that Nelson et al. don’t welcome all the efforts at reform in psychology. For instance, many have called for a greater emphasis on meta-analyses, in which the findings from many studies are combined. But Nelson’s group argue that this can make matters worse – for instance, biases in the studies can accumulate rather than cancel each other out. “The end result of a meta-analysis is as strong as the weakest link; if there is some garbage in, there is &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; garbage out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson’s team are also sceptical of those who say psychology should &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/11/14/reformers-say-psychologists-should-change-how-they-report-their-results-but-does-anyone-understand-the-alternative/&quot;&gt;ditch p-value based significance testing for other metrics, such as confidence intervals and Bayesian results&lt;/a&gt;. “It is not the [particular] statistic that causes the problem, it is the mindlessness [with which they are relied upon].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Enlightenment is just around the corner”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are healthy debates and they will continue for years to come. For now though, let’s join Nelson and his co-authors in recognising the positive and welcome changes underway in psychological science. “Practices that promise to increase the integrity of our discipline – replications, disclosure, pre-registration – are orders of magnitude more common than they were just a short time ago. And although they are not yet common enough, it is clear that the Middle Ages are behind us, and the Enlightenment is just around the corner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-psych-122216-011836&quot;&gt;Psychology’s renaissance&lt;/a&gt; [Our coverage is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3064811&quot;&gt;an early version of this paper published at SSRN&lt;/a&gt;, the final published version may differ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/07/episode-8-can-we-trust-psychological-studies/&quot;&gt;Listen to our PsychCrunch episode on whether we can trust psychological studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32642/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32642/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32642&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 08:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: The new faces of data science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-new-faces-of-data-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-new-faces-of-data-science</link>
	<description>Today’s data scientists are using interdisciplinary methods to take the field into the future</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 08:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Sex matters in experiments on party drug — in mice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23022</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/QJtKD47kNkM/nature.2017.23022</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ketamine lifts rodents' mood only if administered by male researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23022&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/QJtKD47kNkM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Giant telescope’s mobile-phone ‘dead zones’ rile South African residents</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22998</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/nuCsq0l2FRk/nature.2017.22998</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Sensitive radio dishes of the Square Kilometre Array will affect phone reception — and could harm local economies, say farmers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22998&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22998&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/nuCsq0l2FRk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Current CRISPR gene drives are too strong for outdoor use, studies warn</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/current-crispr-gene-drives-are-too-strong-outdoor-use-studies-warn</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/current-crispr-gene-drives-are-too-strong-outdoor-use-studies-warn</link>
	<description>Self-limiting genetic tools already in development may be able to get around concerns surrounding the use of gene drives.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 20:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111617_SM_genedrive_feat.jpg?itok=seWa3yJP" length="29401" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Excess antielectrons aren’t from nearby dead stars, study says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/excess-antielectrons-not-from-nearby-dead-stars</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/excess-antielectrons-not-from-nearby-dead-stars</link>
	<description>Pulsars might not be behind excess antimatter, gamma-ray observations suggest.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 19:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111617_EC_positron_feat.jpg?itok=igO5W1CD" length="36983" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Colliding black holes are reported for a fifth time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/colliding-black-holes-are-reported-fifth-time</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/colliding-black-holes-are-reported-fifth-time</link>
	<description>LIGO spots another merger, this time with less fanfare.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111617_to_ticker-black-hole_free.jpg?itok=T_g2qGxQ" length="20650" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Criminal Brain: Fact or Fiction?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23105</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/16/criminal-brain-fact-or-fiction/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;When we are confronted with the acts of excessive and unprovoked violence, we can’t help but wonder what is wrong with individuals committing such crimes. Think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/04/18/mass-murderer-psychology-the-patterns-of-horror/&quot;&gt;serial killers&lt;/a&gt;: what motivates them? Both researchers and society, in general, have wanted to know how to explain the extreme brutality observed in some people. In most cases, they have no mental disorders that could explain their behavior. Even without going to the extremes, most of us did at some point in life come across people whose level of aggressiveness seemed beyond any reasonable explanation. Think of a hooligan looking for any excuse to pick a fight and beat someone up. Or a young boy torturing a defenseless animal with a smile on his face.  Multiple theories were invented to this end, ranging from religious explanations (satanic possession) to scientific and psychological theories that involve a variety of mental disorders or problems with brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that excessive aggressiveness and criminal tendency might be heritable traits gained popularity with the publication of Dr. Cesare Lombroso’s book “Criminal Man” in 1878. In the book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/18/decoding-the-neural-pathway-from-psychopathy-to-serial-murder/&quot;&gt;Lombroso &lt;/a&gt;introduced the concept of the “born criminal”. He also developed the field of criminal anthropology that studied specific anatomical differences between normal and criminal individuals. Lombroso’s theory contributed to the science of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/02/15/star-wars-yesterdays-sci-fi-is-todays-reality/&quot;&gt;eugenics &lt;/a&gt;that played a crucial role in the Nazi ideology of selective breeding of a superior race and the policy of exterminating the &lt;em&gt;Untermenschen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Lombroso was eventually proven wrong, the concept that criminal behavior might be linked with genes survived. Evidence that criminal and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/03/who-is-and-is-not-a-violent-sexual-offender/&quot;&gt;violent behaviors &lt;/a&gt;run in some families was a particularly strong argument to investigate the issue further. These investigations produced rather interesting discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question to what degree the predisposition for crime might be genetically determined was first answered by a twin study performed in Denmark. Twins are ideal subjects for genetic research: identical twins have exactly the same sets of genes, while non-identical twins are as similar to each other as usual brothers and sisters. However, both identical and non-identical twins, if brought up together, can be considered as having the same upbringing. The study compared the rate of crime offenses among the identical twins with this rate in non-identical twins. It turned out that a Danish man with an identical twin who has a criminal record is 50% more likely to be an offender himself, as compared with the average Danish man. In non-identical twins, the chances of both of them having the criminal records are 15-30% higher than the average for the population. The findings definitely point to a degree of genetic predisposition. In addition, another study performed in Sweden has shown that when the identical twins were brought up separately, the chances of developing a criminal career were higher among children from parents with criminal records, even when the children were brought up in law-abiding adopted families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twin studies can detect correlations but certainly can’t help in finding out which genes are behind these correlations. The study performed in the Netherlands provided important information on the possible identity of such genes. Researchers have studied genetic defects in one particular family with 14 males spanning 4 generations that displayed an unusually high level of aggression and criminal offenses. The subjects in question had very low IQ (around 85) and were prone to impulsive behavior and physical and sexual violence. The researchers found a specific hereditary defect in the family: the gene for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/12/06/the-science-of-raising-a-friendly-psychopath/&quot;&gt;monoamine oxidase A&lt;/a&gt; (MAOA) was mutated. Mutation prevented the enzyme from working properly. This is important as this enzyme is responsible for breaking down neurotransmitters, including serotonin, dopamine, and noradrenaline. A lack of MAOA activity leads to the rising of neurotransmitter levels in the brain and they, in turn, cause the over-excitation of neurons. The gene for MAOA is located on the X chromosome, and this explains why high levels of aggression were observed only in males. Meanwhile, females have a second X chromosome with the non-mutated functional version of the gene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important question, which sparked fierce ethical debate, is to what extent criminal behavior might indeed be genetically programmed. This is a classic discussion of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/12/06/the-science-of-raising-a-friendly-psychopath/&quot;&gt;nature vs nurture&lt;/a&gt;. To what extent do our genes make us who we are? We easily accept the fact that some people are born smarter or physically stronger than the rest of us. We know that genes are involved in making these individuals who they are. Genes responsible for stronger muscles or better brain connections allow these people to excel where others may struggle. Nonetheless, the idea that some of us are born with a predisposition for a higher level of aggression or reduced empathy appears very unpalatable to many people. However, this idea makes perfect biological sense. We evolved as hunter-gatherers, and at this stage of our evolutionary history, aggressiveness was crucially important for survival. Genetically, we didn’t change since the Stone Age. And this aggressiveness still plays an important role in our society, from competition in the workplace to multiple armed conflicts around the world. Aggression levels, like many other human behavioral traits, can be genetically determined to a degree. This means that there is variability: in some people, the level of aggressiveness is very low, while in others it can be quite high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggressiveness still doesn’t equal crime: although violent crime requires a perpetrator to be aggressive, the two things are not the same. Social factors still play a key role when it comes to the expression of aggressive behavior. It works the same way with other genetic attributes. A born athlete will never reach his Olympic dream and could turn into a couch potato if they don’t train. Most scientists, even the very successful ones, are not born geniuses: they simply worked and studied hard. Similarly, people with a predisposition for higher levels of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/06/20/the-role-of-serotonin-and-glutamine-in-aggression/&quot;&gt;aggression &lt;/a&gt;are at higher risk of becoming criminals when they are exposed to the social factors that lead them in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baum ML (2013) The Monoamine Oxidase A (MAOA) Genetic Predisposition to Impulsive Violence: Is It Relevant to Criminal Trials? Neuroethics 6, 287-306. doi: 10.1007/s12152-011-9108-6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunner HG; Nelen MR; van Zandvoort P; Abeling NGGM; van Gennip AH; Wolters EC; Kuiper MA; Ropers HH; van Oost BA (1993) X-linked borderline mental retardation with prominent behavioral disturbance: phenotype, genetic localization, and evidence for disturbed monoamine metabolism. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 52 (6): 1032–9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8503438&quot;&gt;8503438&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buades-Rotger, M., &amp;amp; Gallardo-Pujol, D. (2014). The role of the monoamine oxidase A gene in moderating the response to adversity and associated antisocial behavior: a review. Psychology Research and Behavior Management, 7, 185–200. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.2147/PRBM.S40458&quot;&gt;10.2147/PRBM.S40458&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christiansen KO. Seriousness of criminality and concordance among Danish twins. In: Hood R, editor. Crime, Criminology and Public Policy. The Free Press; New York: 1974. pp. 63–77.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrington DP, Gundry G, West DJ (1975) The familial transmission of criminality. Med Sci Law 15(3):177-86. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177/002580247501500306&quot;&gt;10.1177/002580247501500306&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hunter P (2010) The psycho gene. EMBO Rep. 11 (9): 667–9. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038%2Fembor.2010.122&quot;&gt; 10.1038/embor.2010.122&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendler, K. S., Lönn, S. L., Morris, N. A., Sundquist, J., Långström, N., &amp;amp; Sundquist, K. (2014). A Swedish national adoption study of criminality. Psychological Medicine, 44(9), 1913–1925. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291713002638&quot;&gt;10.1017/S0033291713002638&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Rose+McDermott&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;McDermott&lt;/a&gt; R et al. (2009) Monoamine oxidase A gene (MAOA) predicts behavioral aggression following provocation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 106, 2118–2123. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0808376106&quot;&gt;10.1073/pnas.0808376106&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor S (2013) Criminal Minds: The Infuence of the Monoamine Oxidase AGenotype and Environmental Stressors on Aggressive Behaviour. Burgmann Journal II, 71-77. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/8745313/Criminal_Minds_The_Influence_of_the_Monoamine_Oxidase_A_Genotype_and_Environmental_Stressors_on_Aggressive_Behaviour&quot;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/TheDigitalArtist-202249/&quot;&gt;TheDigitalArtist&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: WHO asks dozens of journals to correct papers on diagnostic tool developed by former collaborators</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52636</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/asks-dozens-journals-correct-papers-diagnostic-tool-developed-former-collaborators/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In one of the largest such requests we’ve ever heard of, the World Health Organization has asked 46 journals to correct articles that refer to a bone fracture risk diagnostic tool as developed or endorsed by the WHO. By WHO’s count, the tool — known as Fracture Risk Assessment Tool (FRAX), which has come under […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/asks-dozens-journals-correct-papers-diagnostic-tool-developed-former-collaborators/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WHO asks dozens of journals to correct papers on diagnostic tool developed by former collaborators&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A physics journal agreed to retract a paper several months ago. It’s still not retracted.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52606</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/physics-journal-agreed-retract-paper-several-months-ago-still-not-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A physics journal says it has planned for several months to retract a 2006 paper by a prominent researcher with multiple retractions, after a concerned reader notified the editor about extensive duplication. But, more than seven months after receiving the complaint, the journal Thin Solid Films has not yet taken action. So what’s taking so […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/physics-journal-agreed-retract-paper-several-months-ago-still-not-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A physics journal agreed to retract a paper several months ago. It’s still not retracted.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, artificial limbs weren’t nearly as responsive</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-artificial-limbs-werent-nearly-responsive</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-artificial-limbs-werent-nearly-responsive</link>
	<description>Artificial limbs have come a long way since 1967.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/102717_CM_50YA_prosthetic_main.jpg?itok=dt2mynco" length="22789" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Study casts doubt on whether adult brain’s memory-forming region makes new cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/study-casts-doubt-whether-adult-brain-hippocampus-makes-new-cells</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/study-casts-doubt-whether-adult-brain-hippocampus-makes-new-cells</link>
	<description>An examination of 54 human brains suggests that adults don’t grow new neurons in the hippocampus, contrary to several widely accepted studies.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_LS_hippocampus_feat.jpg?itok=_Gvy5Jts" length="91104" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: People who think they exercise less than their peers die earlier, regardless of their actual activity levels</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32582</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/16/people-who-think-they-exercise-less-than-their-peers-die-earlier-regardless-of-their-actual-activity-levels/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32592&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-520166146.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32592&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32592&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;FangXiaNuo&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/16/people-who-think-they-exercise-less-than-their-peers-die-earlier-regardless-of-their-actual-activity-levels/man-with-a-basketball-in-a-locker-room/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Adjusting for actual physical activity, individuals who perceived themselves as less active than others were up to 71 per cent more likely to die in the follow-up period&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organization (WHO), physical inactivity is the fourth-leading risk factor for global mortality, causing an estimated 3.2 million deaths around the world annually. Readers of this blog need no convincing that it’s important to be active every day. But is spending more time on it enough to reduce the risk of early death? Not necessarily. How we perceive this activity turns out to be just as important. We learn of this from the authors of an &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31316-001&quot;&gt;intriguing study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Health Psychology&lt;/i&gt; devoted to physical activity and mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32582&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octavia Zahrt and Alia Crum at Stanford University were inspired by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2007/04/16/is-the-benefit-of-exercise-a-placebo-effect/&quot;&gt;earlier experiment&lt;/a&gt; involving hotel room attendants who completed a 20-minute intervention informing them that their daily work satisfied exercise recommendations and highlighting the benefits of this active lifestyle. This intervention not only shifted room attendants’ perceptions, but also resulted in health improvements including lower blood pressure and reductions in weight and body fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zahrt and Crum examined data from 61,141 Americans (selected to be representative of the general population) to determine whether the way we think about our own physical activity could be of major and long-term significance for health. The data came from the US National Health Interview Survey and the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, which included questions assessing how much exercise individuals think they get compared with their peers. The surveys also asked respondents detailed questions about actual physical activity they had undertaken, and in some cases participants wore an accelerometer to measure their activity objectively. The researchers cross-checked these survey data against the National Death Index records as they stood 21 years after the exercise surveys had been completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers expected, perceived physical activity relative to peers was closely associated with risk of dying. Even after adjusting for actual levels of physical activity, individuals who perceived themselves as less active than others were up to 71 per cent more likely to die in the follow-up period than those who perceived themselves as more active. One can say with confidence that individuals’ perceptions about their level of physical activity were strongly related to their longevity, even after accounting for the effects of actual physical activity and other known determinants of mortality such as smoking or obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few potential explanations. A convincing one is that perceptions can affect motivation. For instance, a room attendant’s awareness that she is getting exercise at work might increase her confidence and commitment to a healthy lifestyle, and motivate her to act on this “active” identity. Conversely, longitudinal research shows that individuals who perceive themselves as unfit compared with their friends are less likely to exercise a year later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another potential mechanism is that perceptions can have emotional consequences. Public health messages often warn of the “life-threatening consequences” of physical inactivity. A person’s perception that she/he is inactive might thus lead to fear and stress about not getting enough exercise, with harmful consequences for health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still another explanation is that our positive beliefs and expectations can directly induce physiological responses, even following inert treatments, as shown by the placebo effect (similarly, negative expectations can lead to a harmful “nocebo effect”). Following this logic, participants in the current research who failed to realise that they were getting good exercise may not have experienced its full physiological benefits. Conversely, negative expectations related to the belief that one is not getting enough exercise could have become self-fulfilling because of nocebo-like effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are not able to give a conclusive answer to the question of which of these mechanisms is most important. Perhaps a constellation of them? Or maybe there is another, unknown process involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the mechanisms at play, what do these results mean for mere mortals, and for those who are involved in promoting an active lifestyle? Instead of working out, should we stand in front of the mirror and repeat to ourselves “I’m an active and physically fit person”? To be clear, the authors warn that their findings don’t mean exercise is unimportant. Separate from the influence of our perceptions, physical activity continues to be a crucial determinant of health. However, a more thorough understanding of these results could help us optimise public health messages, finding the happy medium between highlighting that people need to exercise more, but not to the extent that they become downhearted about the exercise they do get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further studies will doubtlessly bring us more answers, but before that happens, let’s get up, walk away from the desk, and look at our activity with friendlier eyes than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31316-001&quot;&gt;Perceived physical activity and mortality: Evidence from three nationally representative U.S. samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-14208&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;14208&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski – doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=682&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1181,1772&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/24/why-do-we-enjoy-reality-tv-researchers-say-its-more-about-empathy-than-humiliation/tomasz-witkowski-doktor-psychologii-pwsin-20061020fot-k-zuczkowski/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Dr Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tomasz is a psychologist and science writer who specialises in debunking pseudoscience in the field of psychology, psychotherapy and diagnosis. He has published over a dozen books, dozens of scientific papers and over 100 popular articles (some of them in &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;). In 2016 his latest book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Psychology-Led-Astray-Science-Therapy/dp/1627346090&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychology Led Astray: Cargo Cult in Science and Therapy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was published by BrownWalker Press. He blogs at &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32582/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32582/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32582&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 09:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Europe sets priorities for hunting cosmic particles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23019</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y8RXaojuQWQ/nature.2017.23019</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Club of physics funding agencies pushes for projects including a neutrino observatory in the Mediterranean Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23019&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y8RXaojuQWQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: What countries' constitutions reveal about how societies evolve</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23001</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/DuL1ntOcSKE/nature.2017.23001</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Analyses of governing documents from 194 countries could help people fighting for human and environmental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23001&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/DuL1ntOcSKE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Improved diagnostics fail to halt the rise of tuberculosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23000</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/v5vn30w_OSc/nature.2017.23000</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;TB remains a big killer despite the development of a better test for detecting the disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23000&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/v5vn30w_OSc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Arecibo telescope wins reprieve from US government</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22994</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/22kUYtgsobg/nature.2017.22994</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;National Science Foundation will look for partners to provide extra financial support for Puerto Rico facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22994&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22994&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/22kUYtgsobg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cyclin D–CDK4 kinase destabilizes PD-L1 via Cul3SPOP to control cancer immune surveillance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25015</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4cul-bAjJac/nature25015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Treatments that target immune checkpoints, such as the one mediated by programmed cell death protein 1 (PD-1) and its ligand PD-L1, have been approved for treating human cancers with durable clinical benefit1,2. However, many cancer patients fail to respond to anti-PD-1/PD-L1 treatment, and the underlying mechanism(s) is not well understood3–5. Recent studies revealed that response to PD-1/PD-L1 blockade might correlate with PD-L1 expression levels in tumor cells6,7. Hence, it is important to mechanistically understand the pathways controlling PD-L1 protein expression and stability, which can offer a molecular basis to improve the clinical response rate and efficacy of PD-1/PD-L1 blockade in cancer patients. Here, we report that PD-L1 protein abundance is regulated by cyclin D-CDK4 and the Cullin 3SPOP E3 ligase via proteasome-mediated degradation. Inhibition of CDK4/6 in vivo elevates PD-L1 protein levels, largely by inhibiting cyclin D–CDK4-mediated phosphorylation of SPOP and thereby promoting SPOP degradation by APC/CCdh1. Loss-of-function mutations in SPOP compromise ubiquitination-mediated PD-L1 degradation, leading to increased PD-L1 levels and reduced numbers of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) in mouse tumors and in primary human prostate cancer specimens. Notably, combining CDK4/6 inhibitor treatment with anti-PD-1 immunotherapy enhances tumor regression and dramatically improves overall survival rates in mouse tumor models. Our study uncovers a novel molecular mechanism for regulating PD-L1 protein stability by a cell cycle kinase and reveals the potential for using combination treatment with CDK4/6 inhibitors and PD-1/PD-L1 immune checkpoint blockade to enhance therapeutic efficacy for human cancers. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25015&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4cul-bAjJac&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Firing patterns in the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-15:/2017/11/15/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/15/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Julia will present the paper by Naud et al (2008) 'Firing patterns in the AdEx IF model'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article the authors explore the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model as a good tool to simulate large-scale spiking neuron networks.
They show that the AdEx model generates multiple firing patterns in response to the parameter values.
In order to describe the transition from one pattern to another, the phase diagrams are analysed in the article.
To further classify the firing patterns, the transient response to step current is studied.
The analytical solutions are given for continuous adaptation, initial bursting, regular bursting, tonic spiking and irregular spiking as a response to the constant current.
It is also concluded, that the network simulations of a large systems, such as thalamocortical, require the description of different neuron types.
Parameter sets for three neuron types are provided, but further work is needed to extend this to a larger number of neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full article could be found here: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How dad’s stress changes his sperm</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-dad-stress-changes-sperm</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-dad-stress-changes-sperm</link>
	<description>Stress may change sperm via packets of RNA in the epididymis, a mouse study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111517_LS_spermstress_feat.jpg?itok=m4GYdBfl" length="8306" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The brain’s helper cells have a hand in learning fear</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-helper-cells-astrocytes-learning-fear</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-helper-cells-astrocytes-learning-fear</link>
	<description>After a traumatic experience, rat brains release inflammatory signals that come from astrocytes, suggesting a new role for the brain’s “helper” cells.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 19:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_BO_astrocytes_fear_main.jpg?itok=-QbFqRxr" length="45533" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In science, some big risks are worth the rewards</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-some-big-risks-are-worth-rewards</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-some-big-risks-are-worth-rewards</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill says scientists sometimes take risks that can lead to significant rewards and important discoveries.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers inspired by SN 10 scientists’ research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-inspired-sn-10-scientists%E2%80%99-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-inspired-sn-10-scientists%E2%80%99-research</link>
	<description>Readers wanted to know more about the scientists' research who were profiled in &quot;The SN 10: Scientists to watch.&quot;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Haze keeps Pluto cool by kicking heat out to space</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/haze-keeps-pluto-cool-kicking-heat-out-space</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/haze-keeps-pluto-cool-kicking-heat-out-space</link>
	<description>Pluto may be the only place in the solar system whose atmosphere is kept cool by solid hazes, not warmed by gas.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_LG_plutohaze_feat.jpg?itok=RFYal-3_" length="21493" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How Asian nomadic herders built new Bronze Age cultures</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-asian-nomadic-herders-built-new-bronze-age-cultures</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-asian-nomadic-herders-built-new-bronze-age-cultures</link>
	<description>Ancient steppe herders traveled into Europe and Asia, leaving their molecular mark and building Bronze Age cultures.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_nomads_main.jpg?itok=fuuMCUTF" length="30596" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal replaces anti-vaccine paper it retracted for missing conflicts, “number of errors”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52616</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/journal-replaces-anti-vaccine-paper-retracted-missing-conflicts-number-errors/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal retracted a paper about how conflicts of interest might be influencing research into the link between vaccines and autism because — wait for it — the authors failed to disclose conflicts of interest. According to the retraction notice, the editors retracted the paper without the authors’ agreement, because the authors had a host […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/journal-replaces-anti-vaccine-paper-retracted-missing-conflicts-number-errors/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal replaces anti-vaccine paper it retracted for missing conflicts, “number of errors”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 16:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO of Science Exchange Elected to the Board of Directors of the Drug, Chemical &amp; Associated Technologies Association (DCAT)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1185</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/elizabeth-iorns-ph-d-ceo-of-science-exchange-elected-to-the-board-of-directors-of-the-drug-chemical-associated-technologies-association-dcat/</link>
	<description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elizabeth-DCAT-2-Image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Elizabeth Iorns elected to DCAT Board&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1187&quot; height=&quot;179&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elizabeth-DCAT-2-Image-300x179.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, November 15, 2017 &lt;/strong&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services, announced today that Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO of Science Exchange, has been elected to serve her first term on the Board of Directors of the Drug, Chemical &amp;amp; Associated Technologies Association (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dcat.org&quot;&gt;DCAT&lt;/a&gt;) beginning November 1, 2017.  Members of DCAT’s Board of Directors are charged with the important work of guiding the organization’s strategic initiatives and activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to have Dr. Iorns join the Board of Directors,” said DCAT Executive Director Margaret Timony. “She brings a unique mix of leadership experiences that will add a valuable perspective to the board.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am honored to join the board and work together with this great team to address key initiatives related to the pharmaceutical industry,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “Our mission at Science Exchange is to help accelerate innovation and scientific discoveries, and as a scientist myself, I feel joining DCAT’s board is a perfect opportunity for me to share my ideas and insights to support and advance its programs and services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About DCAT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.sidekickopen04.com/e1t/c/5/f18dQhb0S7lC8dDMPbW2n0x6l2B9nMJW7t5XYg1pNBLMW2BFXSH1px69sW5wvxsz56dGNDf3sZLX602?t=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dcat.org&amp;amp;si=6467023554215936&amp;amp;pi=635dcd19-3532-498c-8c9d-33b9023d9790&quot;&gt;Drug, Chemical &amp;amp; Associated Technologies Association (DCAT) &lt;/a&gt;is a not-for-profit, global business development association whose unique membership model integrates both innovator and generic drug manufacturers and suppliers of ingredients, development and manufacturing services, and related technologies. We are committed to provide programs, events and services that help our members meet their business objectives, expand their network of customers and suppliers, and gain insight into industry trends, markets, and those issues impacting pharmaceutical development and manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore Science Exchange’s network of qualified service providers for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/contract-manufacturing-services?indexType=services&quot;&gt;Contract Manufacturing Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/biologics-manufacturing?page=1&quot;&gt;Biopharmaceutical Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/bioprocess-scale-up-development-and-validation?page=1&quot;&gt;Bioprocess Development, Validation and Scaleup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/manufacturing-api?page=1&quot;&gt;Manufacturing, API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/evaluation-of-api-suppliers?page=1&quot;&gt;API Sourcing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 16:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Silver Lab: NeuroMatic 3.0 Released</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://silverlab.org/?p=1757</guid>
	<link>http://silverlab.org/2017/11/15/neuromatic-3-0-released/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neuromatic.thinkrandom.com/&quot;&gt;NeuroMatic&lt;/a&gt;, developed by the Silver Lab’s Jason Rothman, is a collection of WaveMetrics Igor Pro software tools for acquiring, analyzing and simulating electrophysiological data. By merging a wide range of tools into a single package, NeuroMatic facilitates a more integrated style of research. Being open source and of modular design, NeuroMatic allows users to develop their own analysis functions that can be easily incorporated into NeuroMatic’s framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 3.0 is available for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neuromatic.thinkrandom.com/&quot;&gt;free download&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Version 3.0 Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data acquisition via NIDAQ or ITC devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continous, episodic and triggered acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;online analysis during acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import functions for Axograph, Pclamp (ABF) and HDF5 files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scaling, averaging, time-scale alignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;max, min, level, rise/decay time, slope measurements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stability/stationarity analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;event detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waveform template matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spike detection and spike-raster plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inter-spike-interval and peri-stimulus time histograms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curve fitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waveform pulse generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stoichastic synaptic release simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synaptic plasticity simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integrate-and-fire (IAF) simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;single-compartment Hodgkin-Huxley-like simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compact easy-to-use interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extra space for your own buttons and controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modular design as a basis for your own functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semi-automatic macro generation for batch processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s extensive library of built-in functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s publication-quality graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s detailed command history log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Igor runs on Macintosh and Windows computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://silverlab.org/feed/">The Silver Lab</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Oops — paper included proofreader’s query</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52540</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/caught-notice-oops-paper-included-proofreaders-query/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Concise Review: Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Neurodegenerative Diseases What Caught Our Attention: Everyone makes mistakes — but some are more amusing than others. In one recent correction, the publisher (Wiley) admitted to including a proofreader’s query in the published manuscript. But didn’t say what the query was. We looked around, and think we found the added […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/caught-notice-oops-paper-included-proofreaders-query/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Oops — paper included proofreader’s query&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Coconut crabs are a bird’s worst nightmare</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/coconut-crab-bird-attack</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/coconut-crab-bird-attack</link>
	<description>A biologist witnesses a coconut crab taking out a blue-footed booby and documents the balance of the animals in an Indian Ocean archipelago.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111317_SZ_coconutcrab_feat.jpg?itok=MOY5-kjV" length="44086" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Men and women interpret the sexual intent behind dating behaviours very differently</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32548</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/15/men-and-women-interpret-the-sexual-intent-behind-dating-behaviours-very-differently/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-17&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-155442288.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32571&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32571&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;10&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1275660887&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Power of Forever Photography&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;45&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro 70's Couple on a Date at the Roller Rink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Retro 70’s Couple on a Date at the Roller Rink&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2108,1422&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/15/men-and-women-interpret-the-sexual-intent-behind-dating-behaviours-very-differently/retro-70s-couple-on-a-date-at-the-roller-rink/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Men tend to overestimate the sexual intent behind women’s behaviours on a date&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re out one evening with someone you met recently – you take your date’s hand in yours, or compliment your date’s appearance, or you kiss him or her passionately. For each behaviour, how likely is it that you wanted to have sex with that person for the first time? Researchers have put this question to heterosexual women, then they’ve asked men how they would interpret a woman’s intentions if she had behaved in these ways. The contrast in their answers is striking: men judge woman’s sexual intent as much higher than women do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could conclude from this that men read sex into situations where it isn’t there. But another explanation could be that men aren’t far off – it’s just that women under-report their true intentions. Which is closer to the truth? And what about men’s own sexual intentions – do women get those right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-30260-001&quot;&gt;new article&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Personality and Social&lt;/i&gt; Psychology,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;involving hundreds of US participants recruited online, Isabelle Engeler from IESE Business School and Priya Raghubir at New York University shine some light on the different ways men and women interpret the same dating behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32548&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers asked some of their participants what their sexual intent would be if they acted in various ways on a date, and then to estimate the intent of another person of the same or opposite sex if they’d acted in those same ways. Consistent with past research, women’s ratings of their own sexual intention were 23 per cent lower than men’s average estimates of female intent based on the same behaviours and comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out if this might partly be due to women underestimating their own intentions, the researchers reversed the order of the questions for other participants – they first estimated other people’s sexual intentions based on a given set of behaviors, and only after this, stated their own intentions based on their display of the same behaviours. The idea behind reversing the questions is that you normalise the topic and relax the person into answering more honestly when you turn the focus to them (the researchers reasoned that women in particular might feel under pressure to answer in a socially appropriate manner, especially when the first question was focused on them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the question order reversed, women provided higher ratings of their own sexual intent – arguably because they were now answering more honestly. This shrunk the gap between their own and men’s perspective on their intentions to eight per cent. Based on a comparison of women’s answers depending on whether they were asked the question about their own intentions first or second, the researchers’ best guess is that around half of the perspective gap between genders is the result of women underreporting their intent, and the rest due to men’s overestimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about men’s and women’s interpretation of men’s sexual intent? Some past studies suggested that women overestimate male sexual intentions, albeit to a smaller degree than men’s overestimation of women’s intent. In the current research, the standard question sequence reproduced this finding. But in the reversed question sequence, the gap closed, suggesting that any female overestimation of men’s intentions is “entirely (100 per cent) attributable to men underreporting their sexual intentions.” In fact, there was even an indication that women may be underestimating what men really want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results suggest that, at least in a heterosexual context in America, both sexes are wary of public revelation of their sexual intentions, and tend to downplay them. But women are fairly accurate at reading what men are really after. Men, by contrast, are prone to overestimate women’s intentions, in line with their own interests. Engeler and Raghubir conclude that “there seems to remain a substantial gap in how women and men interpret dating situations, which could lead to problematic misunderstandings between dating partners’ intentions in actually wanting to have sex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-30260-001&quot;&gt;Decomposing the Cross-Sex Misprediction Bias of Dating Behaviors: Do Men Overestimate or Women Underreport Their Sexual Intentions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32548/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32548/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32548&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 09:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How is research assessment changing? Watch video highlights from “Transforming Research&quot; conference</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-is-research-assessment-changing-watch-video-highlights-from-transforming-research-conference</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-is-research-assessment-changing-watch-video-highlights-from-transforming-research-conference</link>
	<description>15 experts share their thoughts on mapping science, quantifying uncertainty, and understanding the path dependence of a research field</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 03:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: African scientists get their own open-access publishing platform</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23018</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4EaEcwWaPYE/nature.2017.23018</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Venture will launch next year and seeks to strengthen continent’s science by helping academics share work more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23018&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4EaEcwWaPYE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Hazy skies cool down Pluto</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22996</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PQWJ_Y72ORc/nature.2017.22996</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Complex chemistry in the dwarf planet’s upper atmosphere may explain one of its biggest mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22996&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22996&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PQWJ_Y72ORc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Puerto Rico struggles to assess hurricane’s health effects</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22973</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5JM_0vBs59k/nature.2017.22973</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;While dealing with their own losses, public-health researchers are regrouping to study the aftermath of Hurricane Maria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 282 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22973&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22973&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5JM_0vBs59k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Microbiota: A high-pressure situation for bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24760</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Ekm6fIczY2g/nature24760</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Analyses in mice suggest that dietary salt increases blood pressure partly by affecting some of the microbes that inhabit the gut. The implications of this work for hypertension warrant further study in humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24760&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24760&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Ekm6fIczY2g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cancer immunotherapy: The dark side of PD-1 receptor inhibition</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24759</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/r3x8bfcfBMU/nature24759</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Inhibiting the protein PD-1 can activate T cells that trigger immune responses against tumour cells. But it emerges that, in mice, this immunotherapy exacerbates a cancer that involves the T cells themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24759&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24759&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/r3x8bfcfBMU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Archaeology: Inequality has deep roots in Eurasia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24758</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/YUZujZhgyMI/nature24758</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A study of 64 archaeological sites across four continents shows that the growth of agricultural and political systems provoked economic disparities, more so in Eurasia than in North America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24758&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/YUZujZhgyMI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: PD-1 is a haploinsufficient suppressor of T cell lymphomagenesis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24649</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gv_bwtco9Js/nature24649</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 T cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas are a heterogeneous group of highly aggressive malignancies with poor clinical outcomes. T cell lymphomas originate from peripheral T cells and are frequently characterized by genetic gain-of-function variants in T cell receptor (TCR) signalling molecules. Although these oncogenic alterations are thought to drive TCR pathways to induce chronic proliferation and cell survival programmes, it remains unclear whether T cells contain tumour suppressors that can counteract these events. Here we show that the acute enforcement of oncogenic TCR signalling in lymphocytes in a mouse model of human T cell lymphoma drives the strong expansion of these cells in vivo. However, this response is short-lived and robustly counteracted by cell-intrinsic mechanisms. A subsequent genome-wide in vivo screen using T cell-specific transposon mutagenesis identified PDCD1, which encodes the inhibitory receptor programmed death-1 (PD-1), as a master gene that suppresses oncogenic T cell signalling. Mono- and bi-allelic deletions of PDCD1 are also recurrently observed in human T cell lymphomas with frequencies that can exceed 30%, indicating high clinical relevance. Mechanistically, the activity of PD-1 enhances levels of the tumour suppressor PTEN and attenuates signalling by the kinases AKT and PKC in pre-malignant cells. By contrast, a homo- or heterozygous deletion of PD-1 allows unrestricted T cell growth after an oncogenic insult and leads to the rapid development of highly aggressive lymphomas in vivo that are readily transplantable to recipients. Thus, the inhibitory PD-1 receptor is a potent haploinsufficient tumour suppressor in T cell lymphomas that is frequently altered in human disease. These findings extend the known physiological functions of PD-1 beyond the prevention of immunopathology after antigen-induced T cell activation, and have implications for T cell lymphoma therapies and for current strategies that target PD-1 in the broader context of immuno-oncology. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24649&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24649&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gv_bwtco9Js&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Salt-responsive gut commensal modulates TH17 axis and disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24628</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/lCMZVaJzIMY/nature24628</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 A Western lifestyle with high salt consumption can lead to hypertension and cardiovascular disease. High salt may additionally drive autoimmunity by inducing T helper 17 (TH17) cells, which can also contribute to hypertension. Induction of TH17 cells depends on gut microbiota; however, the effect of salt on the gut microbiome is unknown. Here we show that high salt intake affects the gut microbiome in mice, particularly by depleting Lactobacillus murinus. Consequently, treatment of mice with L. murinus prevented salt-induced aggravation of actively induced experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis and salt-sensitive hypertension by modulating TH17 cells. In line with these findings, a moderate high-salt challenge in a pilot study in humans reduced intestinal survival of Lactobacillus spp., increased TH17 cells and increased blood pressure. Our results connect high salt intake to the gut–immune axis and highlight the gut microbiome as a potential therapeutic target to counteract salt-sensitive conditions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24628&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24628&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/lCMZVaJzIMY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Progress in and promise of bacterial quorum sensing research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24624</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QU2Sxrwt2xY/nature24624</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 This Review highlights how we can build upon the relatively new and rapidly developing field of research into bacterial quorum sensing (QS). We now have a depth of knowledge about how bacteria use QS signals to communicate with each other and to coordinate their activities. In recent years there have been extraordinary advances in our understanding of the genetics, genomics, biochemistry, and signal diversity of QS. We are beginning to understand the connections between QS and bacterial sociality. This foundation places us at the beginning of a new era in which researchers will be able to work towards new medicines to treat devastating infectious diseases, and use bacteria to understand the biology of sociality. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 313 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24624&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24624&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QU2Sxrwt2xY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Genome sequence of the progenitor of the wheat D genome Aegilops tauschii</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24486</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4qGLdNs8lrg/nature24486</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Aegilops tauschii is the diploid progenitor of the D genome of hexaploid wheat (Triticum aestivum, genomes AABBDD) and an important genetic resource for wheat. The large size and highly repetitive nature of the Ae. tauschii genome has until now precluded the development of a reference-quality genome sequence. Here we use an array of advanced technologies, including ordered-clone genome sequencing, whole-genome shotgun sequencing, and BioNano optical genome mapping, to generate a reference-quality genome sequence for Ae. tauschii ssp. strangulata accession AL8/78, which is closely related to the wheat D genome. We show that compared to other sequenced plant genomes, including a much larger conifer genome, the Ae. tauschii genome contains unprecedented amounts of very similar repeated sequences. Our genome comparisons reveal that the Ae. tauschii genome has a greater number of dispersed duplicated genes than other sequenced genomes and its chromosomes have been structurally evolving an order of magnitude faster than those of other grass genomes. The decay of colinearity with other grass genomes correlates with recombination rates along chromosomes. We propose that the vast amounts of very similar repeated sequences cause frequent errors in recombination and lead to gene duplications and structural chromosome changes that drive fast genome evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24486&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24486&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4qGLdNs8lrg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Visualization of chemical modifications in the human 80S ribosome structure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24482</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/PR2FiMkO6_c/nature24482</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Chemical modifications of human ribosomal RNA (rRNA) are introduced during biogenesis and have been implicated in the dysregulation of protein synthesis, as is found in cancer and other diseases. However, their role in this phenomenon is unknown. Here we visualize more than 130 individual rRNA modifications in the three-dimensional structure of the human ribosome, explaining their structural and functional roles. In addition to a small number of universally conserved sites, we identify many eukaryote- or human-specific modifications and unique sites that form an extended shell in comparison to bacterial ribosomes, and which stabilize the RNA. Several of the modifications are associated with the binding sites of three ribosome-targeting antibiotics, or are associated with degenerate states in cancer, such as keto alkylations on nucleotide bases reminiscent of specialized ribosomes. This high-resolution structure of the human 80S ribosome paves the way towards understanding the role of epigenetic rRNA modifications in human diseases and suggests new possibilities for designing selective inhibitors and therapeutic drugs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24482&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/PR2FiMkO6_c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Structural basis of nucleotide sugar transport across the Golgi membrane</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24464</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Sqjpq1uAqC8/nature24464</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Glycosylation is a fundamental cellular process that, in eukaryotes, occurs in the lumen of both the Golgi apparatus and the endoplasmic reticulum. Nucleotide sugar transporters (NSTs) are an essential component of the glycosylation pathway, providing the diverse range of substrates required for the glycosyltransferases. NSTs are linked to several developmental and immune disorders in humans, and in pathogenic microbes they have an important role in virulence. How NSTs recognize and transport activated monosaccharides, however, is currently unclear. Here we present the crystal structure of an NST, the GDP–mannose transporter Vrg4, in both the substrate-free and the bound states. A hitherto unobserved requirement of short-chain lipids in activating the transporter supports a model for regulation within the highly dynamic membranes of the Golgi apparatus. Our results provide a structural basis for understanding nucleotide sugar recognition, and provide insights into the transport and regulatory mechanism of this family of intracellular transporters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24464&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24464&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Sqjpq1uAqC8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Quantitative microbiome profiling links gut community variation to microbial load</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24460</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/YWBx8x-xrQU/nature24460</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Current sequencing-based analyses of faecal microbiota quantify microbial taxa and metabolic pathways as fractions of the sample sequence library generated by each analysis. Although these relative approaches permit detection of disease-associated microbiome variation, they are limited in their ability to reveal the interplay between microbiota and host health. Comparative analyses of relative microbiome data cannot provide information about the extent or directionality of changes in taxa abundance or metabolic potential. If microbial load varies substantially between samples, relative profiling will hamper attempts to link microbiome features to quantitative data such as physiological parameters or metabolite concentrations. Saliently, relative approaches ignore the possibility that altered overall microbiota abundance itself could be a key identifier of a disease-associated ecosystem configuration. To enable genuine characterization of host–microbiota interactions, microbiome research must exchange ratios for counts. Here we build a workflow for the quantitative microbiome profiling of faecal material, through parallelization of amplicon sequencing and flow cytometric enumeration of microbial cells. We observe up to tenfold differences in the microbial loads of healthy individuals and relate this variation to enterotype differentiation. We show how microbial abundances underpin both microbiota variation between individuals and covariation with host phenotype. Quantitative profiling bypasses compositionality effects in the reconstruction of gut microbiota interaction networks and reveals that the taxonomic trade-off between Bacteroides and Prevotella is an artefact of relative microbiome analyses. Finally, we identify microbial load as a key driver of observed microbiota alterations in a cohort of patients with Crohn’s disease, here associated with a low-cell-count Bacteroides enterotype (as defined through relative profiling). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24460&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/YWBx8x-xrQU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Influenza: A broadly protective antibody</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551310a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QnLgRgfIR2o/551310a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A single antibody uses multiple antiviral mechanisms to block the replication of influenza B viruses in mice and ferrets. The development could inform research into improved flu vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 310 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551310a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551310a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QnLgRgfIR2o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Computer science: Visionary of virtual reality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551298a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ykIeA9kPgF4/551298a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Aldo Faisal explores the immersive journey of technology pioneer Jaron Lanier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 298 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551298a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551298a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ykIeA9kPgF4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Economics: How science got a golden ticket</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551297a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/UkdtKIHP0rk/551297a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ehsan Masood hails an account of the mixed implications of governments valuing research as an investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 297 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551297a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551297a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/UkdtKIHP0rk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Bioethics: Justice in genomics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551296a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hz9Brx1gz9k/551296a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Rosario Isasi examines a study on the societal impact of grand sequencing projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 296 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551296a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551296a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hz9Brx1gz9k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These spiders may have the world’s fastest body clocks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks</link>
	<description>Three orb-weaving spiders may have the shortest circadian clocks yet discovered among animals.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 21:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_MQ_circadianspider_feat.jpg?itok=DHOahyNj" length="29463" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Simulating the universe using Einstein’s theory of gravity may solve cosmic puzzles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity</link>
	<description>Better simulating the dense parts of the universe could improve scientists’ view of how the universe evolves.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_lumpy_feat_rev_crop.jpg?itok=5XovTMk_" length="39584" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New camera on Palomar telescope will seek out supernovas, asteroids and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope</link>
	<description>The Zwicky Transient Facility at Palomar Observatory in California will seek supernovas, black holes and asteroids.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111317_LG_zwicky_feat.jpg?itok=xOpxnWJA" length="14347" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: The Puzzle of Multiple Personality Disorder</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23056</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/14/the-puzzle-of-multiple-personality-disorder/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/08/28/behind-the-masks-the-mysteries-of-dissociative-identity-disorder/&quot;&gt;Dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a&gt; (DID, commonly referred to as multiple personality disorder) is well known to the general public through multiple movies and books. However, the disease remains poorly understood and rather mysterious for the medical specialists. The definition of this disorder implies that a patient has at least two distinctive and relatively long-lasting identities (sometimes called “alters”) that manifest themselves in a person’s behavior. Their presence is accompanied by memory impairments that cannot be explained by usual forgetfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are no clear clinical criteria to help in the diagnostics. There is a whole range of dissociative disorders that range from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/22/improve-cognition-with-a-trip-down-memory-lane/&quot;&gt;daydreaming&lt;/a&gt; and lapses in attention to serious pathologies. The diagnostics rely on descriptive data rather than something measurable. This leads to lots of confusion, controversies, and inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the incidence of multiple personality disorder varied wildly. For a long time, the condition was considered among the rarest psychological disorders, with less than 100 cases described before 1944. The incidence of DID rose sharply in the 1970s–1980s, reaching 20,000 by the end of the century. In addition, this growth was accompanied by the increase in the number of alters reported in patients, from just one to 13–16 by the 1980s. These changes in the statistics might have been caused by increasing recognition of the disease symptoms among practitioners, but also led to the growing skepticism in the research community about the very existence of this distinct condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variability on the geographic distribution of this condition is substantial too: the disorder is diagnosed in the US much more frequently than anywhere else. The overwhelming majority of publications on this condition originate from North America, making some researchers believe that DID is a purely American disease confined to this continent. This further adds to the skepticism of many health practitioners: there are no reasons to believe that qualified specialists capable of recognizing this condition are vastly underrepresented in other developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is little clarity regarding what causes the disorder. The iatrogenic hypothesis suggests that DID can be a result of psychotherapeutic treatment, while the traumatogenic hypothesis states that the disease develops as a result of severe &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/09/15/coping-with-trauma-in-netflixs-unbreakable-kimmy-schmidt/&quot;&gt;trauma&lt;/a&gt;, usually in childhood. Some researchers believe that most cases of DID are pseudogenic, i.e., simulated. There is an opinion that many patients want to believe that they have the disorder, to explain the inconsistencies in their own behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence of DID is 5–9 times higher in females compared to males. Again, there is no agreement among specialists regarding what causes such a big gender difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential reasons for the sharp increase in the incidence of DID were examined in the scientific literature. Although there are many possible explanations for this phenomenon, the iatrogenic explanation appears to be the most substantiated. The unusually large number of diagnosis in the 1980s were clustered around a small number of practitioners, many of whom used &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/01/09/the-neurological-mechanisms-behind-hypnosis/&quot;&gt;hypnosis&lt;/a&gt; as a therapeutic tool. It is quite possible that under the influence of hypnosis the patients with a higher level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;suggestibility&lt;/a&gt; may start to believe that they are suffering from split personality disorder, and behave accordingly. The level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;hypnotisability&lt;/a&gt; of people with the diagnosis of DID is known to be the highest among any clinical population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the DID diagnosis numbers also correlated with the growing number of split personality cases in the criminal court cases. The defense on the basis of DID was rarely successful, as it was often assumed that the defenders simply pretend to have the disorder to avoid taking responsibility for their crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opinion exists that the manifestations of DID are simply the consequences of other disorders such as bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and borderline personality disorder. Many patients diagnosed with DID have previous history of these and other psychiatric conditions. Another theory suggests that the manifestations of DID are the consequences of trauma. There is plenty of clinical cases in support of this theory, but not so much statistical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it is well proven that people with DID are at higher risk of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/27/ketamine-for-rapid-treatment-of-depression/&quot;&gt;depression &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/10/back-to-school-suicides/&quot;&gt;suicide&lt;/a&gt;. The patients often suffer from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/24/how-does-post-traumatic-stress-disorder-change-the-brain/&quot;&gt;post-traumatic stress disorder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/22/from-abuse-to-addiction-the-withdrawal-period-makes-the-difference/&quot;&gt;substance abuse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/21/could-brain-stimulation-be-a-therapy-for-anorexia-nervosa/&quot;&gt;eating disorders&lt;/a&gt;. Such statistics are not uncommon in other psychiatric conditions, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, there is a shortage of proper neurological studies of this disorder. Nobody knows what exactly causes it and what kind of changes take place in the brains of patients diagnosed with this disease. The brain imaging data from patients with DID do not reveal any specific diagnostic patterns. Several studies demonstrated that the changes in personality state in the DID patients are associated with certain changes in the blood flow in the brain. There are also differences in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/12/17/exercise-to-keep-your-brain-healthy/&quot;&gt;brain blood flow&lt;/a&gt; patterns between patients with DID and healthy control subjects. It remains uncertain if these differences can be used in the diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of how real the majority of DID cases are is yet to be fully answered. In general, researchers agree that there are cases with very pronounced and obvious manifestations that would be rather hard to explain without invoking the concept of DID. However, when it comes to less severe cases, the diagnostic remains really problematic. This creates a problem for patients, as not knowing the specific diagnosis means the lack of clarity with treating the problem. Also, there is no consensus regarding how to treat the split personality disorder. Various psychotherapeutic and hypnotherapeutic techniques are currently used, but their efficacy remains unknown due to the absence of controlled randomised clinical trials. Clearly, there is a lot of room for further research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maldonado, JR; Spiegel D (2008) Dissociative disorders — Dissociative identity disorder (Multiple personality disorder). In Hales RE; Yudofsky SC; Gabbard GO; with foreword by Alan F. Schatzberg. The American Psychiatric Publishing textbook of psychiatry (5th ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinders AA (2008) Cross-examining dissociative identity disorder: Neuroimaging and etiology on trial. Neurocase. 14 (1): 44–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080%2F13554790801992768&quot;&gt;10.1080/13554790801992768&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris J (1996) Review-Essay: Dissociative Symptoms, Dissociative Disorders, and Cultural Psychiatry. Transcult Psychiatry. 33 (1): 55–68. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F136346159603300104&quot;&gt;10.1177/136346159603300104&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kihlstrom JF (2005) Dissociative disorders. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology. 1 (1): 227–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1146%2Fannurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&quot;&gt;10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atchison M, McFarlane AC (1994) A review of dissociation and dissociative disorders. The Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry. 28 (4): 591–9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3109%2F00048679409080782&quot;&gt;10.3109/00048679409080782&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piper A, Merskey H (2004) The persistence of folly: A critical examination of dissociative identity disorder. Part I. The excesses of an improbable concept. Canadian Journal of Psychiatry. &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt; (9): 592–600. PMID &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15503730&quot;&gt;15503730&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiegel D, Loewenstein RJ, Lewis-Fernández R, Sar V, Simeon D, Vermetten E, Cardeña E, Dell PF (2011) Dissociative disorders in DSM-5. Depression and Anxiety. 28 (9): 824–852. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002%2Fda.20874&quot;&gt;10.1002/da.20874&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52598</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a mystery: How did a nonexistent paper rack up hundreds of citations? Pieter Kroonenberg, an emeritus professor of statistics at Leiden University in The Netherlands, was puzzled when he tried to locate a paper about academic writing and discovered the article didn’t exist. In fact, the journal—Journal of Science Communications—also didn’t exist. Perhaps Kroonenberg’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52589</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, a colleague of emergency medicine doctor Daniel Waxman sent him some newly reported findings that took him by surprise. Waxman knew from the title of a press release about the recent paper — “Nearly Half of U.S. Medical Care Comes From Emergency Rooms” — that something was wrong. Immediately I said, that’s not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ancient spiral galaxy is 11 billion years old</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old</link>
	<description>The most ancient spiral galaxy seen to date is 11 billion years old and could help reveal how galaxies sprout arms.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_LG_spiral-galaxy_est_main_no-black.jpg?itok=DXcU2AYJ" length="33806" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New blood pressure guidelines put half of U.S. adults in unhealthy range</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines</link>
	<description>New hypertension guidelines broaden the range of those considered to have high blood pressure and emphasize lifestyle changes to combat the condition.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_AC_hypertension_main_FREE.jpg?itok=wqMUf2rO" length="22129" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: China fires up next-generation neutron-science facility</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EUma8ce4MBU/nature.2017.22976</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Beam generator puts country in elite company for doing experiments in materials science and other fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 284 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22976&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EUma8ce4MBU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Meet the Neighbors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-94</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/hH2cINbhX8w/scientificamerican1217-94</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 94 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-94&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-94&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Lee Billings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the alien worlds closest to our own are found around the smallest, dimmest nearby stars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/hH2cINbhX8w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: 50, 100 &amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-92</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8D0I97kF1-I/scientificamerican1217-92</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 92 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-92&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-92&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8D0I97kF1-I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Squirrels That Chunk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-90</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Qk2WxzeQY1A/scientificamerican1217-90</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 90 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-90&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-90&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart cookies remember their buried treasure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Qk2WxzeQY1A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Outlawing War</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-88</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/8y-5FR2k8uY/scientificamerican1217-88</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 88 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-88&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-88&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why “outcasting” works better than violence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/8y-5FR2k8uY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Recommended</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-86</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/OIhqrSdtBkg/scientificamerican1217-86</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 86 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-86&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-86&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/OIhqrSdtBkg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: How Captives Changed the World</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-78</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/IUtHk3kWnms/scientificamerican1217-78</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 78 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-78&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-78&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Catherine M. Cameron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stolen people—mostly women and children—were a driving force in the evolution of modern society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/IUtHk3kWnms&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Cloud Conundrum</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-72</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/YumcCw-mOKA/scientificamerican1217-72</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 72 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Kate Marvel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists are beginning to understand whether changing cloud cover will accelerate global warming or slow it down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/YumcCw-mOKA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Ice under Siege</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-7</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/S2s8_5dPbrg/scientificamerican1217-7</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 7 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-7&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-7&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need a treaty to protect the warming Arctic from exploitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/S2s8_5dPbrg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Beetle Resurrection</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-64</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/dxN8FjJrCWw/scientificamerican1217-64</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 317, 64 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican1217-64&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1217-64&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Hannah Nordhaus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil companies want the American burying beetle to be the first recovered insect taken off the U.S. endangered species list. But scientists say comeback claims are wildly exaggerated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/dxN8FjJrCWw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
