<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Google no more: How radiologists are shifting to specialized databases</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/google-no-more-how-radiologists-are-shifting-to-specialized-databases</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/google-no-more-how-radiologists-are-shifting-to-specialized-databases</link>
	<description>Radiologists at a leading hospital in Taiwan are discovering the benefits of tools personalized to their profession</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 10:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Rising temps may mean fewer passengers on airplane flights</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rising-temps-may-mean-fewer-passengers-airplane-flights</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rising-temps-may-mean-fewer-passengers-airplane-flights</link>
	<description>Global warming could force airplanes to carry a lighter load — and fewer passengers —on each flight.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_MT_airplane_main_FREE.jpg?itok=MsefCxZf" length="16177" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 reasons CHORUS is gaining traction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-reasons-chorus-is-gaining-traction</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-reasons-chorus-is-gaining-traction</link>
	<description>Elsevier has made over 3,000 manuscripts available to US partner funding agencies through the CHORUS public access service</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: CRISPR adds storing movies to its feats of molecular biology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/crispr-adds-storing-movies-its-feats-molecular-biology</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/crispr-adds-storing-movies-its-feats-molecular-biology</link>
	<description>Video and images could be stored in living bacteria with a little help from the iconic gene editor, CRISPR.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 23:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/0711217_ht_crisprvideo_free.jpg?itok=du5NneYi" length="35596" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Nature retracts paper by stem cell scientist appealing her dismissal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51000</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/nature-retracts-paper-stem-cell-scientist-appealing-dismissal/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A once-rising star in stem cell biology — who recently lost both her job and a sizable grant — has had a fourth paper retracted. The notice — issued by Nature for a 2006 letter — cites duplicated images, and a lack of raw data to verify the findings. First author Susana Gonzalez — who […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/nature-retracts-paper-stem-cell-scientist-appealing-dismissal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nature retracts paper by stem cell scientist appealing her dismissal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here are Juno’s first close-ups of Jupiter’s Great Red Spot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-first-pictures-jupiter-great-red-spot</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-first-pictures-jupiter-great-red-spot</link>
	<description>The Juno spacecraft swooped just 9,000 kilometers above Jupiter’s Great Red Spot on July 10. Here are the first pictures.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 17:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_JupiterRedSpot-raw_composite_free.jpg?itok=_qtQItFt" length="16185" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Delaware-sized iceberg breaks off Antarctic ice shelf</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/delaware-sized-iceberg-breaks-antarctic-ice-shelf</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/delaware-sized-iceberg-breaks-antarctic-ice-shelf</link>
	<description>An iceberg about the size of Delaware splintered from the Larsen C ice shelf in one of the largest calving events ever recorded.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071217_AY_larsen-c-_main.jpg?itok=d2p06B_7" length="14975" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Are Sleep Apps Effective Tools For Behavioral Change?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22659</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/12/are-sleep-apps-effective-tools-for-behavioral-change/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Smartphones are technological Swiss Army knives – easy to carry and, thanks to apps, able to do almost anything. All you need is a smartphone and an internet connection to unfold a thousand tools. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps make communication, traveling, working, and entertainment easier. And they can also allow us to monitor and manage our health, fitness and lifestyle, or even improve them. There are thousands of health and lifestyle apps – for exercise, for nutrition, for weight loss, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/07/top-meditation-apps/&quot;&gt;meditation&lt;/a&gt;, for overall health, for sleep… Their use is on the rise and they have shown great potential in effectively promoting self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology may actually revolutionize how we take care of ourselves. It can successfully influence behavior and this is empowering in the sense that it offers an opportunity to self-manage our health routines. Apps can be a great aid for lifestyle interventions – they allow us to monitor our behavior and our progress, they can motivate us, give positive reinforcement, and set goals for continued enhancement. A well-designed app, built on scientific background may offer valuable help to behavioral health and lifestyle interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But among the sea of apps, one wonders how many are really effective and how many present evidence-based content and behavioral theory-based interventions. Although it is not clear whether evidence- and theory-based interventions are indispensable for the efficacy of an app, they are known to be effective in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/03/22/changing-the-error-of-our-ways/&quot;&gt;changing behavior&lt;/a&gt;, being, most likely, a predictor of efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional theory-based behavioral modification strategies state that behavioral change can be most successfully achieved when multiple strategic approaches and behavioral constructs are combined; these include informational strategies (creating knowledge); cognitive strategies, such as perceived benefits, barriers and risks; behavioral strategies, such as self-monitoring, realistic goal-setting, self-reward, relapse prevention; emotion-focused strategies, such as stress and negative affect management; and therapeutic interventions such as skill-building, for example. Apps that include such features have been proven more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, app developers are naturally focused on keeping users engaged. Therefore, many app features may tend to favor usability. Also, it is likely that app development may be preferentially aligned with more contemporary &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/10/01/sleep-deprivation-behavior-and-the-young/&quot;&gt;behavioral models&lt;/a&gt;. These postulate that technology can be designed to change user attitudes and behaviors through persuasion and social influence (Persuasive Technology Theory), and that when technology increases motivation and capacity to change, triggers to change behavior are more likely to work (Fogg Behavioral Model).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a reliance on either traditional or contemporary behavioral models does not seem to be the case for most health, fitness and lifestyle apps: a 2011 review revealed that most had insufficient evidence-based content; a 2012 analysis showed a general lack of theory-based strategies; a 2013 study of exercise apps found that, overall, the apps contained few features based on behavioral change theory; another 2013 study reached the same conclusion for weight management apps; a 2015 study reported similar findings for alcohol reduction apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/15/why-do-we-need-to-sleep/&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/a&gt; apps? They are one of the most popular type of lifestyle and health apps, which comes as no surprise – sleep disorders affect millions of people and this creates a huge demand for interventional strategies. But sleep apps are particular in the sense that interventional constructs need to go way beyond motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a new study aimed at determining whether sleep apps follow evidenced-based guidelines or are grounded in behavioral change or persuasive technology theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study included the most downloaded and reviewed sleep apps for both iOS and Android. From the 369 apps found using the term “sleep” (in September 2015), 35 apps met the authors’ inclusion criteria. They scored them based on the presence of behavioral and persuasive technology constructs and correlated these scores with the average user rating for each app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average behavioral construct score was 34%, whereas the average persuasive technology score was 42%, which is not impressive. Realistic goal setting (86%), &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/04/ill-do-it-later-brain-connectivity-predicts-procrastination/&quot;&gt;time management&lt;/a&gt; (77%), and self-monitoring (66%) were the behavioral constructs most commonly included in sleep apps; factors that contributed most to the apps’ persuasiveness were the user interface (94%), provision of positive feedback (54%), and social praise (40%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the authors found a positive association between the presence of behavioral constructs and the apps’ popularity and ratings, showing that a good scientific design is an indication of probable success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also indicates that, since there is still a relatively poor inclusion of theory-based constructs, there is room to grow. Building strong evidence-based apps is likely to result in a real opportunity for effective behavioral intervention and be beneficial to the management of sleep disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(An important side note: one obvious limitation of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/02/22/what-do-smartphones-do-to-the-brain/&quot;&gt;smartphone&lt;/a&gt; apps for sleep management is the well-known negative impact of LED devices on the circadian rhythm and, consequently, on sleep. Something that should be kept in mind while designing a sleep app is the possibility on minimizing one’s interaction with our phone before bedtime.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azar KM, et al (2013). Mobile applications for weight management: theory-based content analysis. Am J Prev Med, 45(5):583-9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797(13)00431-5/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.amepre.2013.07.005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breton E, et al (2011). Weight loss—there is an app for that! But does it adhere to evidence-informed practices? Transl Behav Med, 1(4):523–9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs13142-011-0076-5&quot;&gt;10.1007/s13142-011-0076-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cowan LT, et al (2013). Apps of steel: are exercise apps providing consumers with realistic expectations?: a content analysis of exercise apps for presence of behavior change theory. Health Educ Behav, 40(2):133–9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1090198112452126&quot;&gt;10.1177/1090198112452126&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crane D, et al (2015). Behavior change techniques in popular alcohol reduction apps: content analysis. J Med Internet Res, 17(5):e118. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmir.org/2015/5/e118/&quot;&gt;10.2196/jmir.4060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fogg BJ (2003). Persuasive technology: using computers to change what we think and do (interactive technologies). Morgan Kaufmann, San Francisco. ISBN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/book/9781558606432&quot;&gt;978-1-55860-643-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glanz K, et al (2008). Theory, research, and practice in health behavior and health education. In Glanz K, Rimer B &amp;amp; Viswanath K, Health behavior and health education: Theory, research, and practice (4th ed., pp. 23-40). San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass. ISBN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://eu.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-0470396296,subjectCd-PS72.html&quot;&gt;978-0-470-39629-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grigsby-Toussainta DS, et al (2017). Sleep apps and behavioral constructs: A content analysis. Prev Med Rep, 6: 126–129. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211335517300360&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.pmedr.2017.02.018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higgins JP (2016). Smartphone Applications for Patients’ Health and Fitness. Am J Med, 129(1):11-9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amjmed.com/article/S0002-9343(15)00537-9/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.05.038&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/1haboeri-1922784/&quot;&gt;1haboeri&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “We were devastated:” Authors retract paper after realizing they had used the wrong mice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50981</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/devastated-authors-retract-paper-realizing-used-wrong-mice/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Longtime readers of Retraction Watch may recall a 2011 post about a research team that retracted a paper after realizing that they had ordered the wrong mice. Maureen Gannon and Raymond Pasek of Vanderbilt University contacted us earlier this week to alert us to a similar case: Their retraction, earlier this month, of a 2016 paper […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/devastated-authors-retract-paper-realizing-used-wrong-mice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“We were devastated:” Authors retract paper after realizing they had used the wrong mice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Oscillatory Thoughts: New Voytek Lab paper by Richard Gao!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545.post-8896253189315086132</guid>
	<link>http://blog.ketyov.com/2015/08/new-voytek-lab-paper-by-richard-gao.html</link>
	<description>&lt;span&gt;Voytek Lab Cognitive Science PhD student, Richard Gao, wrote a detailed piece about his new &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;paper, &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interpreting the Electrophysiological Power Spectrum,” published in the peer-reviewed, student-focused “NeuroForum” mini-review section for the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Neurophysiology&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: Calibri; font-size: 13.1999998092651px; line-height: 14.7839994430542px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://voyteklab.com/interpreting-the-electrophysiological-power-spectrum/&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #a19c7c; font-family: Calibri; font-size: 13.1999998092651px; line-height: 14.7839994430542px; text-decoration: none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;float: left; padding: 5px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ResearchBlogging.org&quot; src=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/public/citation_icons/rb2_large_gray.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Neurophysiology&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1152%2Fjn.00722.2015&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Interpreting+the+Electrophysiological+Power+Spectrum&amp;amp;rft.issn=0022-3077&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=0&amp;amp;rft.epage=&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fjn.physiology.org%2Flookup%2Fdoi%2F10.1152%2Fjn.00722.2015&amp;amp;rft.au=Gao%2C+R.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Neuroscience&quot;&gt;Gao, R. (2015). Interpreting the Electrophysiological Power Spectrum &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Neurophysiology&lt;/span&gt; DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1152/jn.00722.2015&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.1152/jn.00722.2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 14:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Bradley Voytek)</author>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/5648062351012720545/posts/default">Oscillatory Thoughts</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Ankur Sinha: Bringing together Gitter, IRC, and Slack channels in one place on Riot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:ankursinha.in,2017-07-12:/blog/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</guid>
	<link>http://ankursinha.in/blog/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;let-s-not-let-our-choice-of-platform-limit-us&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's not let our choice of platform limit us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are usually multiple platforms that provide similar functions. For instance, one can pick between &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitlab.com&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://bitbucket.com&quot;&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt; for collaborative development interfaces, and one certainly should have the freedom to do so. Similarly, one can use different operating systems, web browsers, phones, etc etc etc. But, one must remember is that for a lot of us, these are simply means to an end - not the end themselves. They are tools that facilitate the completion of our goals. Different individuals or teams preferring different platforms should not hamper collaboration under any circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to communcation, different teams use different platforms. Some prefer e-mails - either private or using a mailing list. E-mails work well, but they're often overkill for simpler tasks. They're also not the best mode for quick collaborative development. This is where real-time chat comes in. Most open source communities maintain both mailing lists and chat infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to chat platforms too, there are multiple options. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; are designed to handle large communities and are therefore, usually preferred by open source communities. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; seems to be preferred by smaller teams. There are others - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://mattermost.com&quot;&gt;Mattermost&lt;/a&gt;, for example, but I haven't much experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I've found people wary of hopping on to a different platform simply because it's too much work to set up yet another client that one must then also monitor. While this is understandable, it then has what I consider quite a major downside - limited communication amongst groups that are on different platforms. Fortunately, most platforms support bridges which lets the user connect them with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;riot-bringing-it-all-together-in-once-place&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riot - bringing it all together in once place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Using riot to access IRC, Slack, and Gitter&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; is an Open source platform that uses the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://matrix.org/&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; protocol. It's similar to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, but it's a lot more usable. and what is better, one can integrate &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - so one can interact with users over all these platforms in one place. For example, the image below shows &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im/app/#/room/%23neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org&quot;&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; room  that I've set up on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. But, I've also gone ahead and connected this room to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby&quot;&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby room on Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby&quot;&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby channel on IRC&lt;/a&gt;. So, everyone on any of these platforms can communicate with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Neuroscience-Central/Lobby on Riot integrated with the same room on Gitter.&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the integrations is rather easy too. One needs to go to the integrations tab and set them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Integrations on Riot&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im/desktop.html&quot;&gt;desktop clients&lt;/a&gt; available for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; too. (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/taw/Riot/&quot;&gt;Here's a COPR for Fedora&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/17/5/introducing-riot-IRC&quot;&gt;Here's a great post on opensource.com&lt;/a&gt; discussing &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you're an admin looking to set up a new chat channel - consider setting up on different platforms and integrating them with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - it'll make things a lot easier for your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 12:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml">ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Author “shocked” after top math journal retracts paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50973</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/author-shocked-top-math-journal-retracts-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most prestigious mathematics journals has issued what appears to be its first retraction. The Annals of Mathematics recently withdrew a 2001 paper exploring the properties of certain symmetrical spaces. What prompted this retraction? And why did it occur 16 years after the paper was published? The retraction notice for “Invariant differential […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/author-shocked-top-math-journal-retracts-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author “shocked” after top math journal retracts paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Teeny-weeny star vies for title of smallest known</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/teeny-weeny-star-vies-title-smallest-known</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/teeny-weeny-star-vies-title-smallest-known</link>
	<description>A Saturn-sized star is one of the smallest yet discovered.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_EC_star-ticker_main.jpg?itok=ybKnq8Bw" length="17818" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: What is computational neuroscience? (XXVII) The paradox of the efficient code and the neural Tower of Babel</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1427</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxvii-the-paradox-of-the-efficient-code-and-the-neural-tower-of-babel/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A pervasive metaphor in neuroscience is the idea that neurons “encode” stuff: some neurons encode pain; others encode the location of a sound; maybe a population of neurons encode some other property of objects. What does this mean? In essence, that there is a correspondence between some objective property and neural activity: when I feel pain, this neuron spikes; or, the image I see is “represented” in the firing of visual cortical neurons. The mapping between the objective properties and neural activity is the “code”. How insightful is this metaphor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An encoded message is understandable to the extent that the reader knows the code. But the problem with applying this metaphor to the brain is only the encoded message is communicated, not the code, and not the original message. Mathematically, original message = encoded message + code, but only one term is communicated. This could still work if there were a universal code that we could assume all neurons can read, the “language of neurons”, or if somehow some information about the code could be gathered from the encoded messages themselves. Unfortunately, this is in contradiction with the main paradigm in neural coding theory, “efficient coding”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient coding hypothesis stipulates that neurons encode signals into spike trains in an efficient way, that is, it uses a code such that all redundancy is removed from the original message while preserving information, in the sense that the encoded message can be mapped back to the original message (Barlow, 1961; Simoncelli, 2003). This implies that with a perfectly efficient code, encoded messages are undistinguishable from random. Since the code is determined on the statistics of the inputs and only the encoded messages are communicated, a code is efficient to the extent that it is not understandable by the receiver. This is the paradox of the efficient code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the neural coding metaphor, the code is private and specific to each neuron. If we follow this metaphor, this means that all neurons speak a different language, a language that allows expressing concepts very concisely but that no one else can understand. Thus, according to the coding metaphor, the brain is a Tower of Babel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can this work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Non-White or female bosses who push diversity are judged negatively by their peers and managers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26633</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/12/non-white-or-female-bosses-who-push-diversity-are-judged-negatively-by-their-peers-and-managers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-26648 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26648&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Detailed illustration of diverse business people in different positions in flat style on white background.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=263&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1851,1620&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/12/non-white-or-female-bosses-who-push-diversity-are-judged-negatively-by-their-peers-and-managers/business-team-and-teamwork-concept-set-of-detailed-illustration-of-businesswomen-standing-in-different-positions-in-flat-style-on-white-background-diverse-nationalities-and-dress-styles-vector-illu/&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=263&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first cohort of women leaders began pushing up against the glass ceiling, many hoped it would shatter… but it only cracked. Today fewer than 10 per cent of Fortune 500 companies are led by people from ethnic minority groups and women combined, and although the reasons are manifold, blame has been laid at the feet of the early pioneers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accusation is that successful people from underrepresented groups act as gatekeepers, keeping out others to maintain their special status and to identify with the dominant majority (the most famous example being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2010/11/11/queen-bees-are-the-consequence-not-the-cause-of-sexist-work-places/&quot;&gt;Queen Bee syndrome&lt;/a&gt; where a female boss undermines other women). But &lt;a href=&quot;http://amj.aom.org/content/60/2/771.abstract?etoc&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;i&gt;Academy of Management Journal&lt;/i&gt; suggests a different and very understandable reason that minority members are cautious to show enthusiasm for increasing diversity – because they know it could spell disaster for their own career if they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26633&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international team headed by David Hekman of the University of Colorado recruited 350 American executives from a range of organisations: one in ten of them were non-White and about 30 per cent were women. The executives’ bosses and roughly three of their peers rated them in terms of their competence and performance, including readiness to be promoted, and their diversity-valuing behaviour, an example being “values working with a diverse group of people”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last measure of “promoting diversity” is considered important in most major organisations, as it can provide better coverage of customer needs and can facilitate different ways of thinking. Overall, the findings from the current study were consistent with this: participants who were rated higher for diversity-valuing behaviour were also rated higher for performance and competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was an important exception. For female and non-White executives, the more they valued diversity, the worse they were rated for performance and competence. And the non-White leaders who received very high performance ratings (higher even than the White majority) showed the least interest in diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors argue that this points to an attitudinal bias, whereby most senior staff generally see diversity-promoting behaviour as benign or even worthwhile… except when it comes from minorities, in which case, it triggers concerns of nepotism or of opposition to the interests of the majority and a desire to undermine the status quo. In turn, these concerns may reinforce the minority status of the individual, making stereotypic negative judgments more salient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this explanation, Hekman’s team conducted an experiment: 300 participants recruited from an online database were asked to review a hiring manager’s decision to take on a new Vice President for their organisation, and rate that manager’s competence accordingly. Participants saw photos of the new VP and the hiring manager and they read a transcript of the conversation about the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a female or non-White hiring manager took on a female or minority VP and mentioned improving diversity as a motive, the participants gave them poor ratings, a cost that was not incurred by White male hiring managers making the same decision. This seems to back up the researchers’ theory that minority managers are perceived negatively when they actively promote diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, there are selfish incentives for successful members of minority groups to identify with the higher-status in-group, to be included and welcomed and feel like a member of the elite in good standing. This research suggests that there may also be valid reasons for minority leaders to fear making a show of helping other minority individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hekman’s team discuss a few possible ways to tackle this, and suggest an intriguing approach: to reward any organisational member that hires someone demographically different from them. This rule would apply to everyone, with a sound logic – what might you learn from a second-in-command with a different background to you? – and in practice, its application would increase minority numbers by virtue of the sheer numbers of majority group members seeking out someone different. Whatever the exact approach, one takeaway from this is that it is going to be harder for minorities to promote diversity in organisations, because their motives are going to be taken as suspect. So White men who care about diversity should step up and make the case for it. They are relatively insulated, whereas for others, the case may be simply too costly to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://amj.aom.org/content/60/2/771.abstract?etoc&quot;&gt;Does Diversity-Valuing Behavior Result in Diminished Performance Ratings for Non-White and Female Leaders?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26633/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26633/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26633&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Transparency — the key to trust in peer review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transparency-the-key-to-trust-in-peer-review</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transparency-the-key-to-trust-in-peer-review</link>
	<description>What authors and reviewers want, according to research (and how we’re making it happen)</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 08:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: PLOS Supports Net Neutrality to Ensure Global Access to the Scientific Literature</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7653</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/KCjLjKQr-s0/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/net-neutrality-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PLOS works to remove barriers to public access of scientific research. Typically, these barriers are considered in terms of copyrights and journal subscriptions, but unfettered access to network infrastructure also contributes to supporting readers’ access to scientific literature. In simple terms, unencumbered dissemination of scientific research depends on a fair Internet. The provision of a fair and open Internet lies in the hands of Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and government agencies that regulate these providers. PLOS supports today’s Day of Action in the United States, led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Battle for the Net&lt;/a&gt;, aimed at publicizing the issues surrounding Open Internet Rules and their critical role in maintaining Internet freedoms as currently in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2015, the US Federal Communication Commission (FCC) reclassified broadband providers as common carriers rather than information providers under Title II of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Act_of_1934&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Communications Act of 1934&lt;/a&gt;, the law that continues to regulate modern communication modes such as the Internet. This gave the FCC authority to ensure that established, large corporations including AT&amp;amp;T, Comcast and Verizon can’t block, slow (throttle) or otherwise interfere with Internet traffic. Innovations in online businesses and services, including those of PLOS, have thrived under Title II regulations. Importantly, these regulations in the US provide each and every user of the Internet a guarantee that ISPs and government regulators treat all data on the Internet the same, without discriminating against or charging differentially by user, content, website, platform, application, type of equipment or mode of communication (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;These protections are known as net neutrality; scientists and those working to support the scientific endeavor rely on net neutrality for unprejudiced access to databases, the literature and information services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Allowing ISPs to sort traffic based on content, sender and receiver opens the door for corporate and government censorship which would greatly hinder access to scientific information around the globe.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect against this type of restriction in information flow, the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/policies/open-internet-net-neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EU-wide Net Neutrality rules&lt;/a&gt; were adopted in October 2015 with public guidelines released by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://berec.europa.eu/eng/netneutrality/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Body of European Regulators for Electronic Communications&lt;/a&gt; in late 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the US, the current FCC Commissioner wants to weaken these protections and this could have consequences for all scientists, not just those in the US: a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ccess to information around the world could become pay to play without these protections. &lt;/strong&gt;Services provided by publishers such as PLOS and other providers could be restricted for all our users around the world, unless we pay for priority access to our content. This will affect any Internet traffic that routes through the US, from services relying on servers located in the US to requests that are routed through the US. For instance, most of the Domain Name Server (DNS) requests for South America, Central America and the Carribbean are routed by servers located in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-7655&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/NetNeutPopUp-234x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;234&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, July 12, 2017, is a Day of Action in support of a fair and open Internet. Visitors to the PLOS.org homepage (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plos.org/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.plos.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and active PLOS staff blogs (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Official PLOS Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EveryONE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/biologue/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Biologue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Speaking of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Channels and Collections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/tech/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) will see a message of explanation and letter of support for net neutrality in the form of a pop up window. This message will appear only today, once per site, per device. Visitors to these web pages can choose to either immediately close the pop up by clicking on the x in the upper right or fill in the four boxes to send a message to the FCC in support of its current Open Internet Rules and the efforts to dissuade FCC Chairman Ajit Varadaraj Pai from his plan to roll back these rules. Public comment continues for an additional 60 days following the Day of Action. Form letters or personalized comments may be sent directly from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS is purposefully not placing this notice on any journal content or information pages, so that access to our content is not impeded in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about net neutrality around the globe, visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisisnetneutrality.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.thisisnetneutrality.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; to learn more about the Day of Action visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/KCjLjKQr-s0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 05:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Engineered cell therapy for cancer gets thumbs up from FDA advisers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22304</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/NwhSvawuDxM/nature.2017.22304</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Therapy shows promise in young patients with leukaemia, but safety risks abound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22304&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22304&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/NwhSvawuDxM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ant colonies flow like fluid to build tall towers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22290</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/KHrGNwM_L88/nature.2017.22290</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Insects' structural secrets offer model for designing swarm robots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22290&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22290&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/KHrGNwM_L88&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Lights, camera, CRISPR: Biologists use gene editing to store movies in DNA</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22288</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MKh7wou4GIM/nature.2017.22288</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Technique demonstrated in  E. coli  suggests ways to record key events in a cell's life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22288&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22288&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MKh7wou4GIM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Stop Alzheimer’s before it starts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547153a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/X1XJeuppvRw/547153a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The hunt for treatments to halt Alzheimer’s disease has been frustrating; it is time to trial preventive drugs, urge Eric McDade and Randall J. Bateman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547153a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547153a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/X1XJeuppvRw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: How poverty affects the brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547150a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/i2hurX6ov6Y/547150a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An unprecedented study in Bangladesh could reveal how malnutrition, poor sanitation and other challenges make their mark on child development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 150 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547150a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547150a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/i2hurX6ov6Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Tricks to mute quantum noise aid hunt for gravitational waves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547148a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y4nOuz0W0D8/547148a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Physicists find ways to make LIGO and other gravitational-wave detectors even more sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 148 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547148a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547148a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y4nOuz0W0D8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Panda diplomats, smuggled relics and a nuclear-weapons treaty</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547142a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/uU9NWGxvRRY/547142a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 7–13 July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547142a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547142a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/uU9NWGxvRRY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Proposed US public-health chief is a champion for women and children</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547137b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1b7HnJIUG5E/547137b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In sharp contrast to President Trump, Brenda Fitzgerald has put maternal and child health at the heart of her policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 137 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547137b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547137b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1b7HnJIUG5E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Allelic reprogramming of 3D chromatin architecture during early mammalian development</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23263</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/7d_yqwTlECQ/nature23263</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 In mammals, chromatin organization undergoes drastic reprogramming after fertilization. However, the three-dimensional structure of chromatin and its reprogramming in preimplantation development remain poorly understood. Here, by developing a low-input Hi-C (genome-wide chromosome conformation capture) approach, we examined the reprogramming of chromatin organization during early development in mice. We found that oocytes in metaphase II show homogeneous chromatin folding that lacks detectable topologically associating domains (TADs) and chromatin compartments. Strikingly, chromatin shows greatly diminished higher-order structure after fertilization. Unexpectedly, the subsequent establishment of chromatin organization is a prolonged process that extends through preimplantation development, as characterized by slow consolidation of TADs and segregation of chromatin compartments. The two sets of parental chromosomes are spatially separated from each other and display distinct compartmentalization in zygotes. Such allele separation and allelic compartmentalization can be found as late as the 8-cell stage. Finally, we show that chromatin compaction in preimplantation embryos can partially proceed in the absence of zygotic transcription and is a multi-level hierarchical process. Taken together, our data suggest that chromatin may exist in a markedly relaxed state after fertilization, followed by progressive maturation of higher-order chromatin architecture during early development. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 232 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23263&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23263&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/7d_yqwTlECQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Neurobiology: Synapses get together for vision</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23098</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/NhZRiAqMcuI/nature23098</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A sophisticated analysis in mice of how inputs to neurons from other neurons are distributed across individual cells of the brain's visual cortex provides information about how mammalian vision is processed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23098&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23098&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/NhZRiAqMcuI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Immunology: Nervous crosstalk to make antibodies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23097</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zWg3bk3WILI/nature23097</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Immune cells called T cells help immune-system B cells mature to produce antibodies. This entails signalling between cells using the molecule dopamine — a surprising immunological role for this neurotransmitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23097&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23097&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zWg3bk3WILI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Biomechanics: How fish feel the flow</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23096</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tjJqWZAx_hw/nature23096</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hair-like sensors are suspected to aid fish navigation in complex environments. Laboratory experiments and computational simulations reveal how these sensors can detect water flow to direct the swimming responses of fish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23096&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tjJqWZAx_hw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Synaptic organization of visual space in primary visual cortex</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23019</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WAADPwSSZ00/nature23019</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 How a sensory stimulus is processed and perceived depends on the surrounding sensory scene. In the visual cortex, contextual signals can be conveyed by an extensive network of intra- and inter-areal excitatory connections that link neurons representing stimulus features separated in visual space. However, the connectional logic of visual contextual inputs remains unknown; it is not clear what information individual neurons receive from different parts of the visual field, nor how this input relates to the visual features that a neuron encodes, defined by its spatial receptive field. Here we determine the organization of excitatory synaptic inputs responding to different locations in the visual scene by mapping spatial receptive fields in dendritic spines of mouse visual cortex neurons using two-photon calcium imaging. We find that neurons receive functionally diverse inputs from extended regions of visual space. Inputs representing similar visual features from the same location in visual space are more likely to cluster on neighbouring spines. Inputs from visual field regions beyond the receptive field of the postsynaptic neuron often synapse on higher-order dendritic branches. These putative long-range inputs are more frequent and more likely to share the preference for oriented edges with the postsynaptic neuron when the receptive field of the input is spatially displaced along the axis of the receptive field orientation of the postsynaptic neuron. Therefore, the connectivity between neurons with displaced receptive fields obeys a specific rule, whereby they connect preferentially when their receptive fields are co-oriented and co-axially aligned. This organization of synaptic connectivity is ideally suited for the amplification of elongated edges, which are enriched in the visual environment, and thus provides a potential substrate for contour integration and object grouping. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23019&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WAADPwSSZ00&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: CRISPR–Cas encoding of a digital movie into the genomes of a population of living bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23017</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/G7EJ3oRpoyM/nature23017</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 DNA is an excellent medium for archiving data. Recent efforts have illustrated the potential for information storage in DNA using synthesized oligonucleotides assembled in vitro. A relatively unexplored avenue of information storage in DNA is the ability to write information into the genome of a living cell by the addition of nucleotides over time. Using the Cas1–Cas2 integrase, the CRISPR–Cas microbial immune system stores the nucleotide content of invading viruses to confer adaptive immunity. When harnessed, this system has the potential to write arbitrary information into the genome. Here we use the CRISPR–Cas system to encode the pixel values of black and white images and a short movie into the genomes of a population of living bacteria. In doing so, we push the technical limits of this information storage system and optimize strategies to minimize those limitations. We also uncover underlying principles of the CRISPR–Cas adaptation system, including sequence determinants of spacer acquisition that are relevant for understanding both the basic biology of bacterial adaptation and its technological applications. This work demonstrates that this system can capture and stably store practical amounts of real data within the genomes of populations of living cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23017&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/G7EJ3oRpoyM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cholangiocytes act as facultative liver stem cells during impaired hepatocyte regeneration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23015</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/T2gzkgrg6ZU/nature23015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 After liver injury, regeneration occurs through self-replication of hepatocytes. In severe liver injury, hepatocyte proliferation is impaired—a feature of human chronic liver disease. It is unclear whether other liver cell types can regenerate hepatocytes. Here we use two independent systems to impair hepatocyte proliferation during liver injury to evaluate the contribution of non-hepatocytes to parenchymal regeneration. First, loss of β1-integrin in hepatocytes with liver injury triggered a ductular reaction of cholangiocyte origin, with approximately 25% of hepatocytes being derived from a non-hepatocyte origin. Second, cholangiocytes were lineage traced with concurrent inhibition of hepatocyte proliferation by β1-integrin knockdown or p21 overexpression, resulting in the significant emergence of cholangiocyte-derived hepatocytes. We describe a model of combined liver injury and inhibition of hepatocyte proliferation that causes physiologically significant levels of regeneration of functional hepatocytes from biliary cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23015&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/T2gzkgrg6ZU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A novel mechanism for mechanosensory-based rheotaxis in larval zebrafish</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23014</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/-16dHu_-2oc/nature23014</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 When flying or swimming, animals must adjust their own movement to compensate for displacements induced by the flow of the surrounding air or water. These flow-induced displacements can most easily be detected as visual whole-field motion with respect to the animal’s frame of reference. Despite this, many aquatic animals consistently orient and swim against oncoming flows (a behaviour known as rheotaxis) even in the absence of visual cues. How animals achieve this task, and its underlying sensory basis, is still unknown. Here we show that, in the absence of visual information, larval zebrafish (Danio rerio) perform rheotaxis by using flow velocity gradients as navigational cues. We present behavioural data that support a novel algorithm based on such local velocity gradients that fish use to avoid getting dragged by flowing water. Specifically, we show that fish use their mechanosensory lateral line to first sense the curl (or vorticity) of the local velocity vector field to detect the presence of flow and, second, to measure its temporal change after swim bouts to deduce flow direction. These results reveal an elegant navigational strategy based on the sensing of flow velocity gradients and provide a comprehensive behavioural algorithm, also applicable for robotic design, that generalizes to a wide range of animal behaviours in moving fluids. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23014&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/-16dHu_-2oc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: TFH-derived dopamine accelerates productive synapses in germinal centres</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23013</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/wUJN7VonS48/nature23013</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Protective high-affinity antibody responses depend on competitive selection of B cells carrying somatically mutated B-cell receptors by follicular helper T (TFH) cells in germinal centres. The rapid T–B-cell interactions that occur during this process are reminiscent of neural synaptic transmission pathways. Here we show that a proportion of human TFH cells contain dense-core granules marked by chromogranin B, which are normally found in neuronal presynaptic terminals storing catecholamines such as dopamine. TFH cells produce high amounts of dopamine and release it upon cognate interaction with B cells. Dopamine causes rapid translocation of intracellular ICOSL (inducible T-cell co-stimulator ligand, also known as ICOSLG) to the B-cell surface, which enhances accumulation of CD40L and chromogranin B granules at the human TFH cell synapse and increases the synapse area. Mathematical modelling suggests that faster dopamine-induced T–B-cell interactions increase total germinal centre output and accelerate it by days. Delivery of neurotransmitters across the T–B-cell synapse may be advantageous in the face of infection. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23013&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/wUJN7VonS48&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Open and closed structures reveal allostery and pliability in the HIV-1 envelope spike</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23010</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/hKUHz9VJN58/nature23010</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 For many enveloped viruses, binding to a receptor(s) on a host cell acts as the first step in a series of events culminating in fusion with the host cell membrane and transfer of genetic material for replication. The envelope glycoprotein (Env) trimer on the surface of HIV is responsible for receptor binding and fusion. Although Env can tolerate a high degree of mutation in five variable regions (V1–V5), and also at N-linked glycosylation sites that contribute roughly half the mass of Env, the functional sites for recognition of receptor CD4 and co-receptor CXCR4/CCR5 are conserved and essential for viral fitness. Soluble SOSIP Env trimers are structural and antigenic mimics of the pre-fusion native, surface-presented Env, and are targets of broadly neutralizing antibodies. Thus, they are attractive immunogens for vaccine development. Here we present high-resolution cryo-electron microscopy structures of subtype B B41 SOSIP Env trimers in complex with CD4 and antibody 17b, or with antibody b12, at resolutions of 3.7 Å and 3.6 Å, respectively. We compare these to cryo-electron microscopy reconstructions of B41 SOSIP Env trimers with no ligand or in complex with either CD4 or the CD4-binding-site antibody PGV04 at 5.6 Å, 5.2 Å and 7.4 Å resolution, respectively. Consequently, we present the most complete description yet, to our knowledge, of the CD4–17b-induced intermediate and provide the molecular basis of the receptor-binding-induced conformational change required for HIV-1 entry into host cells. Both CD4 and b12 induce large, previously uncharacterized conformational rearrangements in the gp41 subunits, and the fusion peptide becomes buried in a newly formed pocket. These structures provide key details on the biological function of the type I viral fusion machine from HIV-1 as well as new templates for inhibitor design. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23010&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/hKUHz9VJN58&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Infant viewing of social scenes is under genetic control and is atypical in autism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22999</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/_2R5fah2yZM/nature22999</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Long before infants reach, crawl or walk, they explore the world by looking: they look to learn and to engage, giving preferential attention to social stimuli, including faces, face-like stimuli and biological motion. This capacity—social visual engagement—shapes typical infant development from birth and is pathognomonically impaired in children affected by autism. Here we show that variation in viewing of social scenes, including levels of preferential attention and the timing, direction and targeting of individual eye movements, is strongly influenced by genetic factors, with effects directly traceable to the active seeking of social information. In a series of eye-tracking experiments conducted with 338 toddlers, including 166 epidemiologically ascertained twins (enrolled by representative sampling from the general population), 88 non-twins with autism and 84 singleton controls, we find high monozygotic twin–twin concordance (0.91) and relatively low dizygotic concordance (0.35). Moreover, the characteristics that are the most highly heritable, preferential attention to eye and mouth regions of the face, are also those that are differentially decreased in children with autism (χ2 = 64.03, P &amp;lt; 0.0001). These results implicate social visual engagement as a neurodevelopmental endophenotype not only for autism, but also for population-wide variation in social-information seeking. In addition, these results reveal a means of human biological niche construction, with phenotypic differences emerging from the interaction of individual genotypes with early life experience. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22999&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22999&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/_2R5fah2yZM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Legs-11</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547252a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bpk2Ju44_x4/547252a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Meet the home help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 252 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547252a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547252a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bpk2Ju44_x4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Bioengineering: Bile ducts regenerated</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547171a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/6Kj0Nexp3AM/547171a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The development of a protocol for isolating and expanding the cell population that lines bile ducts has enabled the  in vitro  generation of bioengineered ducts. These can replace native bile ducts when transplanted into mice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 171 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547171a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547171a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/6Kj0Nexp3AM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Gene editing: CRISPR book review — Doudna responds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162e</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6EYej_GRPjY/547162e</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6EYej_GRPjY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Taxonomy: refine rather than stabilize</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162d</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pt_WFq9fNxM/547162d</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pt_WFq9fNxM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Sustainable development: Manage chemicals and waste globally</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162c</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/HPTj976QL8I/547162c</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/HPTj976QL8I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Research foundations: Philanthropic risks can hit home runs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5bxXTgSLJYc/547162b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5bxXTgSLJYc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Solar energy: Switch it off on eclipse day</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EFj813LKLHY/547162a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EFj813LKLHY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Books in brief</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547161a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/c61KHRKazhs/547161a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Barbara Kiser reviews five of the week's best science picks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 161 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547161a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547161a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/c61KHRKazhs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: History: Science lessons from the Gulag</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547160a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/TuEizgHcvyQ/547160a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Asif Siddiqi examines a biography of a Soviet meteorologist who taught his daughter from prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 160 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547160a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547160a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/TuEizgHcvyQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Information technology: A digital genius at play</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547159a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/mUV9VQ2P9ts/547159a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Vint Cerf savours a life of Claude Shannon, information-theory pioneer and wildly inventive tinkerer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 159 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547159a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547159a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/mUV9VQ2P9ts&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Whales feast when hatcheries release salmon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/whales-feast-when-hatcheries-release-salmon</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/whales-feast-when-hatcheries-release-salmon</link>
	<description>Whales: “They’re 40 feet long and they’re feeding on fish that are the size of my finger.”</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 23:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071117_SM_whale_main_free.jpg?itok=Gpo4XHBH" length="37417" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The most distant star ever spotted is 9 billion light-years away</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/most-distant-star-ever-spotted-9-billion-light-years-away</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/most-distant-star-ever-spotted-9-billion-light-years-away</link>
	<description>A bright blue star sends its light from two-thirds of the way across the universe, thanks to a chance alignment with a galaxy cluster.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071117_LG_distant-star_main.jpg?itok=_4v0yFu9" length="29006" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: More notices appear for embattled Cornell food researcher</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50968</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/notices-appear-embattled-cornell-food-researcher/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Journals have posted two corrections alongside papers by Brian Wansink, a food researcher whose work has lately come under fire. One of the corrected papers was among the initial batch that raised eyebrows last year; after Wansink praised the productivity of one of his researchers, critics suggested four papers contained critical flaws. The questions about […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/notices-appear-embattled-cornell-food-researcher/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;More notices appear for embattled Cornell food researcher&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 16:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lost in translation: Authors blame a language error for wrong diagnosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50965</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/lost-translation-authors-blame-language-error-wrong-diagnosis/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A patient’s “unusual” brain cyst excited several researchers in China so much they published a paper about it in a major journal. Soon a reader identified a glaring mistake: the authors had described the cause of the cyst incorrectly.   A month after the paper appeared online in November 2016, the reader — a neurologist […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/lost-translation-authors-blame-language-error-wrong-diagnosis/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lost in translation: Authors blame a language error for wrong diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 13:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: The weather and the brain – using new methods to understand developmental disorders</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=459</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The latest article was written by our brilliant lab member Danyal Akarca. It describes some of his MPhil research which aims to explore transient brain networks in individuals with a particular type of genetic mutation. Dan finished his degree in Pre-Clinical Medicine before joining our lab and has since been fascinated by the intersection of genetic disorders and the dynamics of brain networks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain is a complex dynamic system. It can be very difficult to understand how specific differences within that system can be associated with the cognitive and behavioural difficulties that some children experience. This is because even if we group children together on the basis that they all have a particular developmental disorder, that group of children will likely have a heterogeneous aetiology. That is, even though they all fall into the same category, there may be a wide variety of different underlying brain causes. This makes these disorders notoriously difficult to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developmental disorders that have a known genetic cause can be very useful for understanding these brain-cognition relationships, because by definition they all have the same causal mechanism (i.e. the same gene is responsible for the difficulties that each child experiences). We have been studying a language disorder caused by a mutation to a gene called &lt;em&gt;ZDHHC9&lt;/em&gt;. These children have broader cognitive difficulties, and more specific difficulties with speech production, alongside a form of childhood epilepsy called rolandic epilepsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our lab, we have explored how brain structure is organised differently in &lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2016/06/08/a-single-gene-disorder-affects-brain-organisation/&quot;&gt;individuals with this mutation,&lt;/a&gt; relative to typically developing controls. Since then our attention has turned to applying new analysis methods to explore differences in dynamic brain function. We have done this by directly recording magnetic fields generated by the activity of neurons, through a device known as a magnetoencephalography (MEG) scanner. The scanner uses magnetic fields generated by the brain to infer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetoencephalography&quot;&gt;electrical activity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical way that MEG data is interpreted, is by comparing how electrical activity within the brain changes in response to a stimulus. These changes can take many forms, including how well synchronised different brain areas are, or the how size of the magnetic response differs across individuals. However, in our current work, we are trying to explore how the brain configures itself within different networks, in a dynamic fashion. This is especially interesting to us, because we think that the ZDHHC9 gene has an impact on the excitability of neurons in particular parts of the brain, specifically in those areas that are associated with language. These changes in network dynamics might be linked to the kinds of cognitive difficulties that these individuals have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used an analysis method called &lt;em&gt;“Group Level Exploratory Analysis of Networks” &lt;/em&gt;– or GLEAN for short – and has recently been developed at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2sJbg72&quot;&gt;Oxford centre for Human Brain Activity&lt;/a&gt;. The concept behind GLEAN is that the brain changes between different patterns of activation in a fashion that is probabilistic. This is much like the concept of the weather – just as the weather can change from day to day in some probabilistic way, so too may the brain change in its activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-509 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;509&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;480,345&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e/&quot; height=&quot;247&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247&quot; width=&quot;344&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis method not only allows us to observe what regions of the brain are active when the participants are in the MEG scanner. It also allows us to see the probabilistic way in which they can change between each other. For example, just as it is more likely to transition from rain one day to cloudiness the next day, relative to say rain to blistering sun, we find that brain activation patterns can be described in a very similar way over sub-second timescales. We can characterise those dynamic transitions in lots of different ways, such as how long you stay in a specific brain state or how long does it take to return to a state once you’ve transitioned away. (A more theoretical account of this can be found in another recent blog post in our Methods section – “&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2016/06/03/the-resting-brain-that-never-rests/&quot;&gt;The resting brain… that never rests&lt;/a&gt;”.) We have found that a number networks differ between individuals with the mutation and our control subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Picture1&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-529 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;529&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Picture1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;944,373&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/picture1-2/&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208&quot; width=&quot;526&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(These are two brain networks that show the most differences in activation – largely in the parietal and frontotemporal regions of the brain.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, these networks strongly overlap with areas of the brain that are known to express the gene (we found this out by using data from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brain-map.org/&quot;&gt;Allen Atlas&lt;/a&gt;). This is the first time that we know of that researchers have been able to link a particular gene, to differences dynamic electrical brain networks, to a particular pattern of cognitive difficulties. And we are really excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/459/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/459/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=459&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 11:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Adaptive reuse of buildings in the healthcare industry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9223</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/11/adaptive-reuse-of-buildings-in-the-healthcare-industry/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Before-WK-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abandoned buildings are a common and unfortunate sight in communities, emerging for myriad reasons ranging from progress, which compels establishments to relocate to better serve clients, to misfortune, which prompts businesses to cease operations at particular locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many overlook dilapidated buildings altogether . . . others see opportunities for, of all things, enhancing the depth and breadth of healthcare services in communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their idled states, these buildings often fall into disrepair, diminishing scenic beauty and even posing threats to health and safety as abandoned structures are vulnerable to criminal and environmental elements. While many overlook dilapidated buildings altogether, considering them to be well suited only for the wrecking ball, others see opportunities for, of all things, enhancing the depth and breadth of healthcare services in communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Willis-Knighton Health System and adaptive reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shreveport, Louisiana-based Willis-Knighton Health System has extensive adaptive reuse experience and credits the practice with facilitating expansion initiatives which have improved access to care in the community. The system decided to tap into the unrealized potential of abandoned buildings beginning in the 1970s as a means of acquiring space economically as it expanded its presence in the market. Its initial repurposing endeavors proved economical and effective, compelling subsequent pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, Willis-Knighton Health System has successfully accomplished over 20 adaptive reuse projects. Its most recently completed initiative involved repurposing the former Doctors’ Hospital of Shreveport, a 150,000 square foot building that ceased operations in 2010 and quickly became a prominent blight overlooking the heart of downtown Shreveport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building, reintroduced in 2017 as the WK Rehabilitation Institute, is virtually indistinguishable from brand new construction and features an entirely revised facade, all-new interior elements, and an enhanced layout which facilitates access. The building cost $26 million (acquisition plus renovations), a bargain price, especially when considering that equivalent new construction would total $44.5 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9226&quot; style=&quot;width: 2410px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9226 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1590&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/After-WK.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2400&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The WK Rehabilitation Institute, repurposed from Doctors’ Hospital. © Willis-Knighton Health System.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunities associated with adaptive reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential possessed by adaptive reuse to deliver significant financial savings unavailable through equivalent new construction projects is perhaps its most notable benefit. In fact, this attribute is cited as the primary motivation for its pursuit, and in each of Willis-Knighton Health System’s experiences, cost advantages over equivalent new construction scenarios were observed. This point certainly shouldn’t be lost on those serving in the healthcare industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical space required by physicians, nurses, administrators, and others to carry out their many duties often represents a significant expenditure, consuming financial resources which otherwise could be directed toward patient care. Economies achieved on this front permit more resources to be directed toward mission fulfillment activities and adaptive reuse offers a prudent method for realizing such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond financial advantages, adaptive reuse offers opportunities for healthcare entities to bolster community renewal initiatives by returning to service formerly inactive properties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond financial advantages, adaptive reuse offers opportunities for healthcare entities to bolster community renewal initiatives by returning to service formerly inactive properties. Further, the practice is environmentally friendly, as repurposing abandoned buildings conserves resources and averts demolition, reducing the burden on landfills which otherwise would have to accommodate the waste. Adaptive reuse also has the potential to bring highly-prized locations in communities back into consideration in circumstances where relocations or closures present optimally situated availabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, adaptive reuse offers a unique and mutually beneficial method for addressing the spatial expansion needs of healthcare institutions, providing those serving in hospitals, medical clinics, and other care providing facilities with an option to consider beyond traditional renovation and new construction pathways. The practice by its very nature coincides nicely with the community-minded, altruistic missions typically espoused by healthcare establishments, affording an exceptional strategic fit when proper circumstances present themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional insights on the practice of adaptive reuse, including descriptions of opportunities and obstacles, case presentations profiling several of Willis-Knighton Health System’s repurposing initiatives, and a detailed operational framework, consult the associated article featured in BMC Health Services Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/11/adaptive-reuse-of-buildings-in-the-healthcare-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Adaptive reuse of buildings in the healthcare industry&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Before-WK-1-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Sexual offending by women is surprisingly common, claims US study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26502</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/11/sexual-offending-by-women-is-surprisingly-common-claims-us-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_26631&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-535192499.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26631&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26631&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 650D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed on white background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1422464045&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Chris_Tefme&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/11/sexual-offending-by-women-is-surprisingly-common-claims-us-study/silhouette-of-woman-in-dress-with-arms-crossed/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;“Attention to female sexual perpetration serves important feminist goals,” the researchers said&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of US researchers led by Lara Stemple at the UCLA School of Law has analysed data from several large federal crime victimisation surveys and they say their findings show that sexual offences by women against male and female victims are surprisingly common. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178916301446?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Writing in &lt;em&gt;Aggression and Violent Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the researchers stress that they are in no way intending to minimise the human cost of sexual violence perpetrated by men. But they say their results are “sufficiently robust so as to compel a rethinking of long-held stereotypes about sexual victimisation and gender”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26502&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stemple’s team begin by pointing to data from the Center For Disease Control’s Survey of thousands of people for the “National Intimate Partner Violence and Sexual Violence”. In 2011, for example, this survey showed that equal numbers of men and women reported being forced into non-consensual sex (either raped themselves or forced to penetrate someone else). Extrapolated to the US as a whole, this would represent 1.9 million victims among each sex during the preceding 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are similar findings for sex of victim in the 2010 survey, the researchers said, and that year, the survey also included detail on the sex of offender. To illustrate the prevalence of female offending, the researchers highlighted the number of men who reported being forced by a woman to penetrate her. The survey estimated that nearly 4.5 million men in the US had at some time in their lives been forced to penetrate another person, and crucially, that in 79.2 per cent of cases the perpetrator forcing the sexual act was a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another survey the researchers looked at was the National Crime Victimisation Survey, pooling the data from 2010 to 2013. This showed that female perpetrators (without a male accomplice) were reported in 28 per cent of rape or sexual assault cases against men and 4.1 per cent of such cases against female victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from prisons collected by the Bureau of Justice Statistics is equally surprising. Among female prisoners who have been the victims of sexual offences during their incarceration, they far more often report the offender to be another female inmate than a male member of staff. Indeed, contrary to stereotypes, another survey found that women prison inmates were more than three times as likely to be sexually victimised by another women inmate as compared with male prisoners’ risk of sexual victimisation by another male prisoner (bi-sexual women were at highest risk). For boys and men who are incarcerated, the prison data also show that they are overwhelmingly more likely to be sexually victimised by female staff than male staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National surveys by the U.S. Census Bureau are also revealing. A 2012 study asked respondents whether they had ever forced someone to have sex against their will: of those who said they had, 43.6 per cent were female (compared with 56.4 per cent of men).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stemple’s team also considered data from college samples. Most recently, a 2014 study of 284 men and boys in college found that 43 reported having been sexually coerced, mostly unwanted sexual intercourse, with 95 per cent of the perpetrators reported as being female. An earlier survey obtained anecdotal descriptions of sexual violence from perpetrators. One woman described how she “locked the room door that we were in. I kissed and touched him. I removed his shirt and unzipped his pants. He asked me stop. I didn’t. Then I sat on top of him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the researchers say that the data challenge the one-dimensional stereotype of women as only passive and harmless. Facing up to the reality of the prevalence of female sex offences actually serves feminist goals, they argue, citing another scholar who wrote that to be fully recognised, women must be “heard in all possible forms, whether in compassion, in protest or in violence”. The results also challenge stereotypes about men, they added, such as that they have “an insatiable desire for sex”, and they challenge rape myths such as that it is impossible for “a big strong man to be raped by a woman” (which the majority of students endorsed as true in a recent survey).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it is only by recognising the reality of female sexual offending that the needs of those who offend can be properly addressed. “Female perpetration [of sexual aggression] is frequently intertwined with women’s past experience of their own victimisation”, the researchers said. For instance, evidence suggests that female offenders “have often experienced severe childhood sexual abuse themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the “culture of denial” about female sexual offending means that most female offenders are not convicted, and when they are, they receive lighter sentences, Stemple and her colleagues said. Male victims may feel pressure to interpret their victimisation experiences in a way consistent with masculine ideals, “such as the idea that men should relish any available opportunity for sex.” Meanwhile, “heterosexist” assumptions (that sexual violence is only ever perpetrated by men, usually against women) mean that lesbian and bisexual victims of female sexual aggression are “invisible to professionals”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also commonly assumed that female offenders nearly always co-offend with a male accomplice, the researchers noted, but while it is true that co-offending is more common among female offenders, data suggest they are still more likely to abuse alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We call for feminist approaches – expansively interpreted – to challenge these stereotypes, making room to consider women who are abusive, power seeking, and sexually aggressive, while taking into account the troubled background many such women possess,” the researchers concluded. “Those victimised by women are doubly harmed when we fail to treat their abuse as worthy of concern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178916301446?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Sexual victimization perpetrated by women: Federal data reveal surprising prevalence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26502/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26502/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26502&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 09:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Female astronomers of colour face daunting discrimination</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22291</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/aAX54wm-R-g/nature.2017.22291</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Two-fifths report feeling unsafe at work, and 18% have concerns about attending conferences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22291&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22291&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/aAX54wm-R-g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: World's largest hoard of carbon dates goes global</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22287</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/LkTbrmz3YUc/nature.2017.22287</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists hope pooled records could answer major archaeological questions and map human migration patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22287&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22287&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/LkTbrmz3YUc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Witness gravity’s quantum side in the lab</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547156a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/kyHm9hcE6k4/547156a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Physicists should rethink interference experiments to reveal whether or not general relativity follows classical theory, argue Chiara Marletto and Vlatko Vedral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 156 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547156a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547156a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/kyHm9hcE6k4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The fight against gonorrhea gets a potential new weapon: a vaccine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gonorrhea-std-meningitis-vaccine</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gonorrhea-std-meningitis-vaccine</link>
	<description>A vaccine used in New Zealand to curb meningitis also appeared to drop gonorrhea infections, results that hint at a way to make a gonorrhea vaccine.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071017_ls_gonorrhea_main.jpg?itok=NoQ1RAis" length="34967" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Just one night of poor sleep can boost Alzheimer’s proteins</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/just-one-night-poor-sleep-can-boost-alzheimers-beta-proteins</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/just-one-night-poor-sleep-can-boost-alzheimers-beta-proteins</link>
	<description>Deep sleep may prevent the buildup of Alzheimer’s proteins.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 20:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071117_TI_alzheimers_sleep_main_FREE.jpg?itok=dFs-AsgJ" length="18205" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Political Neuroscience: &quot;Growth Mindsets&quot; and Disability</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8936</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8936</link>
	<description>On Twitter, I learned that the British government is citing neuroscience studies as part of a new welfare initiative.



The &quot;Health and Work Conversation&quot; (HWC) is a newly-introduced procedure for welfare claimants receiving support because sickness or disability impairs their ability to work. The one hour &quot;conversation&quot; is mandatory in most cases and it seems intended to encourage people to seek whatever work they are able to do.

A Freedom of Information Act request has revealed documen</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lancet retracts (and replaces) paper a year after authors report error that changes “all numbers”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50957</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/lancet-retracts-replaces-paper-year-authors-report-error-changes-numbers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2016, researchers in Switzerland and Canada published a meta-analysis in The Lancet, exploring the optimal painkiller and dose for treating pain in knee and hip osteoarthritis. Soon after, the authors were informed of an error that would change “all numbers” in a paper that may influence clinical practice. The authors contacted The Lancet […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/lancet-retracts-replaces-paper-year-authors-report-error-changes-numbers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lancet retracts (and replaces) paper a year after authors report error that changes “all numbers”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: HIV Reservoirs: Does The Virus Hide in the Brain?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22605</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/10/hiv-reservoirs-does-the-virus-hide-in-the-brain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Treatment advances over the last several decades have dramatically extended the lifespan of patients with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). However, a continuing problem in HIV treatment is the ability of the virus to remain dormant in a small number of cells throughout the body, including some areas of the brain. Researchers at the University of Montreal in Canada recently discovered a way to locate and destroy hidden HIV viral particles, a finding that could eventually lead to a complete cure for the disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV currently affects an estimated 36.7 million people worldwide, and infects 2.1 million new individuals each year. HIV infection targets a group of immune cells called CD4+ T cells. These cells are responsible for recognizing and attacking harmful bacteria and viruses that enter the body. When a large proportion of these cells are destroyed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/05/08/hiv-medications-linked-to-increase-in-alzheimers-disease-protein/&quot;&gt;HIV&lt;/a&gt;, the body can no longer defend against infections and other diseases. This stage is called acquired immunodeficiency syndrome, or AIDS, and frequently results in premature death due to opportunistic infections and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present treatments for HIV include reverse transcriptase inhibitors and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/05/08/hiv-medications-linked-to-increase-in-alzheimers-disease-protein/&quot;&gt;protease inhibitors&lt;/a&gt;, among several others. These drugs work by targeting the enzymes that convert viral RNA into DNA and produce mature viral particles. These drugs are highly effective and have drastically increased the life expectancy of patients. However, a complete cure for HIV has remained elusive because of the ability of the virus to remain in so-called reservoirs in the body. If a patient in remission forgoes their medication, the virus can become re-activated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from several universities, led by Daniel Kauffman of the University of Montreal, recently discovered a way to identify and potentially destroy HIV reservoirs. Their findings are published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Cell Host and Microbe&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the researchers sought a new way to identify HIV-infected CD4+ T cells using a method called flow-FISH, which combines two techniques for identifying proteins and nucleotides in cells. Flow cytometry uses a machine to sort and identify cell subpopulations based on surface protein markers, but it is not sensitive or specific enough to identify HIV-infected cells. Fluorescence in situ hybridization, or FISH, uses fluorescent probes directed against specific nucleotide sequences to identify DNA or RNA in a cell with local and temporal specificity. Flow-FISH was used to detect the mRNA of two specific &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/09/08/does-hiv-make-the-brain-old-before-its-time/&quot;&gt;HIV genes&lt;/a&gt; in CD4+ T cells, &lt;em&gt;gag &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;pol&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this method, the researchers were able to detect virus-containing cells at concentrations as low as 0.5–1 per million CD4+ T cells. This assay was combined with polychromatic flow cytometry, which analyzes multiple cell surface markers simultaneously. Together, these techniques allowed the researchers to quantify and identify the characteristics of HIV-infected cells in patient blood samples. HIV-infected CD4+ T-cells showed an increase in markers of “&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2010/12/12/preventing-hiv-before-exposure/&quot;&gt;immune exhaustion&lt;/a&gt;” (PD-1, CTLA-4, and TIGIT), which occurs when T cells have been chronically activated and are no longer responsive. They also were able to estimate the size of the viral reservoir, which was on average 3.56 cells per million CD4+ T cells, but a wide variation was observed among patients on anti-viral therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next part of the study, two latency-reversal agents (LRA) were tested on cells from HIV-infected patients. LRAs are used in a “shock and kill” technique that activates dormant viral particles in the body, allowing them to be eradicated by antiretroviral agents. Bryostatin modulates protein kinase C, an enzyme involved in cell signaling pathways, and is currently being tested for use as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/04/01/new_anti_cancer_drug_for_aggressive_brain_tumors/&quot;&gt;anti-cancer&lt;/a&gt;, anti-HIV, and memory-enhancing agent. Ingenol is a plant-derived drug with several proposed mechanism of action that include protein kinase C activation, which leads to the activation of immune cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers determined that bryostatin and ingenol differed in their ability to activate two subpopulations of CD4+ T cells. Ingenol activated central memory cells, which persist for several years in patients, whereas bryostatin was not as effective against this T-cell subpopulation. This finding suggested that ingenol may be a more effective treatment for latent HIV. While both drugs were capable of killing the HIV virus &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, their effectiveness in the body remains unclear. The researchers suggest that their viral detection method will be useful for assessing the effectiveness of LRAs in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method of reactivating latent HIV provides hope for one day eradicating the virus, but it is not without the potential for side effects. Researchers at Johns Hopkins University recently tested the effect of viral reactivation by LRAs in monkeys with simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV), the correlate of HIV in monkeys. They found that the drug caused a harmful form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/05/28/lack-of-sleep-affects-performance-and-damages-brain-cells/&quot;&gt;brain inflammation&lt;/a&gt;. The researchers suspect that this side effects was caused by the existence of HIV reservoirs in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIV-infected monkeys were treated with a cocktail of antiretroviral agents (tenofovir, darunavir, ritonavir, and the integrase inhibitor L-870812). Following 400 days on this regimen, viral suppression was confirmed by measuring SIV in plasma. Then two of the monkeys were treated for ten days with the latency-reversing agents ingenol-B and vorinostat. Vorinostat is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/08/best-and-worst-of-neuroscience-and-neurology-october-2015/&quot;&gt;histone deacetylase&lt;/a&gt; inhibitor that works by changing the expression of genes involved in cell differentiation. The animals continued on the antiretroviral drug cocktail during the treatment with LRAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the treated monkeys remained healthy under this treatment regimen. However, the second monkey developed symptoms of brain inflammation, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/02/08/winter-depression-new-discoveries-in-treatment-of-seasonal-affective-disorder/&quot;&gt;lethargy&lt;/a&gt; and lack of appetite. Active SIV and markers of inflammation were detected in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), the fluid that surrounds the brain and spinal cord. After the animal was euthanized due to the illness, they removed the brain for examination. They were careful to first remove the monkey’s blood to ensure that the brain tissue wasn’t contaminated by infected blood cells. They found that SIV was present in a part of the brain called the occipital cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery that viral reactivation can cause brain inflammation, possibly by reactivating brain reservoirs of the virus, is a potential drawback for using LRAs to treat latent HIV in humans. Reassuringly, this side effect occurred in only one of the two animals, so these findings are still preliminary. Further, while there are innate differences between SIV and HIV, clinical trials of LRA in humans with HIV must be carried out with caution. Monitoring the CSF for evidence of viral reactivation in the brain should accompany LRA treatment to prevent such side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lugli E., Troiano L, Cossarizza A. (2009) Investigating T cells by polychromatic flow cytometry. Methods Mol Biol. 514:47-63. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1007/978-1-60327-527-9_5&quot;&gt;10.1007/978-1-60327-527-9_5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherry, J.E. and Kurachi M. (2015) Molecular and cellular insights into T cell exhaustion. Nature Reviews Immunology 15:486–499. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/nri3862&quot;&gt;10.1038/nri3862&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorenzo-Redondo R., Fryer H.R., Bedford T., Kim E.Y., Archer J., Kosakovsky Pond S.L., et al. (2016) Persistent HIV-1 replication maintains the tissue reservoir during therapy. Nature 530:51–56. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/nature16933&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;10.1038/nature16933&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gama L., Abreu C.M., Shirk E.N., Price S.L., Li M., Laird G.M. et al. (2017) Reactivation of simian immunodeficiency virus reservoirs in the brain of virally suppressed macaques. AIDS. Jan 2;31(1):5-14. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1097/QAD.0000000000001267&quot;&gt;10.1097/QAD.0000000000001267&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/typographyimages-3575871/&quot;&gt;typographyimages&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Sharing knowledge to uncover cancer cells’ secret disguises</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/sharing-knowledge-to-uncover-cancer-cells-secret-disguises</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/sharing-knowledge-to-uncover-cancer-cells-secret-disguises</link>
	<description>How we used epigenetics to map the switches that help uterine cancer cells hide and spread</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Why autistic people may be less susceptible to marketing tricks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26486</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/10/why-autistic-people-may-be-less-susceptible-to-marketing-tricks/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-466216200.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26497&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26497&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The woman buys a TV in shop&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1426078347&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;97&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A woman observing prices for a television in a store&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A woman observing prices for a television in a store&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466216200.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466216200.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466216200.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3000,2000&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/10/why-autistic-people-may-be-less-susceptible-to-marketing-tricks/a-woman-observing-prices-for-a-television-in-a-store/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-466216200.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know from past research that autistic people process the world differently at a perceptual level, including showing reduced sensitivity to context. One consequence is that they’re better than average at finding figures in complex shapes. But does this way of looking at the world also influence their higher-level decision-making? According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0956797617694867&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science, &lt;/i&gt;it does: William Skylark and his University of Cambridge colleagues George Farmer and Simon Baron-Cohen found that people with autism spectrum conditions (ASC) – as well as people in the general population with relatively high levels of autistic traits – make more “conventionally rational” decisions, which could influence everything from how they vote to what products they choose to buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26486&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team recruited 90 men and women who had been diagnosed with an ASC and 212 neurotypical controls and presented them with ten consecutive pairs of products, which differed in each case on two dimensions (for example, one USB stick (A) had relatively high capacity but low longevity, while the other (B) had low capacity but high longevity). Each pair was also accompanied by a third “decoy” product. In every case, the participants had to choose which product was “best”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants saw each product pair twice. On one occasion, it was accompanied by a decoy that was fractionally inferior compared with product A; on the other occasion, the decoy was fractionally inferior than product B. Earlier work using this kind of challenge has shown that while people rarely choose the decoy, it makes the product that is marginally better seem more attractive than the other option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While conventional accounts of rational choice dictate that a person’s preference be independent of the other options on offer, this often isn’t actually the case. “If one prefers salmon to steak, this should not change because frogs’ legs are added to the menu,” the researchers explained. However, the thinking of neurotypical people is swayed in exactly this way and what Skylark and his colleagues wanted to know is whether the choices of people with ASC are influenced in this way too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found that they were – but to a lesser extent than controls. The autistic participants made more consistent choices about which product was best, showing they were less influenced by the decoys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the team repeated the study with people drawn from the general population who scored either relatively high or relatively low on a measure of traits typically associated with autism, they found a similar, though less marked, difference between the two groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These findings suggest that people with autism might be less susceptible to having their choices biased by the way information is presented to them – for instance, by marketing tricks when choosing between consumer products,” says Farmer. Indeed, given that choice consistency is usually seen as rational, autistic people’s reduced sensitivity to context “would provide a new demonstration that autism is not in all respects a ‘disability’,” the researchers wrote in their paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is also work finding that in situations where someone isn’t sure about what decision to make, using context and new information about other options may be useful. (“Whereas conventional accounts of rational choice dictate choice consistency, emerging Bayesian frameworks construe preference reversals as an adaptive response to uncertainty about the value of an option,” the team explained.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there could be a price to pay for autistic people’s reduced sensitivity to contextual influence – and that “may be a reduction in the potentially adaptive updating of beliefs about optimum choice that comes from using local comparisons to inform decision-making,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617694867&quot;&gt;People With Autism Spectrum Conditions Make More Consistent Decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26486/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26486/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26486&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Are there foxes in Tasmania? Follow the poop</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50378</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/foxes-tasmania-follow-poop/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Stephen Sarre, based at the University of Canberra in Australia, has made a career out of collecting and analyzing poop. It’s a tough job, but someone’s got to do it. Part of his work is designed to answer a multi-million dollar question: Is Tasmania home to foxes, a pest that carries rabies and other diseases […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/foxes-tasmania-follow-poop/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Are there foxes in Tasmania? Follow the poop&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How a crop-destroying fungus mutated to infect wheat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-crop-destroying-fungus-mutated-infect-wheat</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-crop-destroying-fungus-mutated-infect-wheat</link>
	<description>Study details how wheat got a new pathogen called blast fungus.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070717_TI_wheat-fungus_main.jpg?itok=OuVdhiT9" length="39301" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Machine Learning to Predict Childhood PTSD</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9238</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/10/machine-learning-predict-childhood-ptsd/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/AI-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of children who are exposed to a trauma, between 10 and 40% will develop Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD). PTSD is a debilitating psychiatric condition that can have significant impact on a child’s functioning and, perhaps, even the development of their brain. There is also a growing literature indicating that PTSD may be prevented, if a child at risk (i.e. the 10-40%) is identified early enough. How can we know which child is at risk for PTSD – as early as possible after trauma exposure – so that this risk may be mitigated? What does the literature say about our ability to predict a child’s risk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A definitive account about the state of this literature was published a few years ago. Trickey and colleagues conducted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0272735811001875?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;meta-analysis of 64 studies on child PTSD risk&lt;/a&gt; published over the previous two decades, and found that the effect sizes for all but a handful of risk factors were very small: and not many more than a handful of risk variables (25) had even been studied, more than once. I have been studying risk for child PTSD since the beginning of the two-decade time span of this landmark meta-analysis, and I was not surprised by the discouraging results, reported. PTSD is a complex phenomenon. In all likelihood, its’ expression involves the complex interactions between a wide diversity of biopsychosocial processes, that engage over time – in specific ways – under specific conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been studying risk for child PTSD since the beginning of the two-decade time span of this landmark meta-analysis, and I was not surprised by the discouraging results, reported&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years before this meta-analysis was published, I became convinced that the data methods conventionally used for PTSD risk factor research could not approach the complexity of the subject under study. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0151174&quot;&gt;began to explore the application of new methods&lt;/a&gt; such as Machine Learning predictive classification, non-experimental causal discovery, and complex systems science. These methods were gaining tremendous traction in other fields for the very problems that seemed to plague research in my field. The study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;published today&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; entitled “Machine Learning Methods to Predict Child Posttraumatic Stress: A Proof of Concept Study” is an outcome of this effort, and reports the first ever application of Machine Learning to predict childhood PTSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; reports on a longitudinal study of children assessed in the wake of a trauma (hospitalization for an acute injury) to predict who would acquire PTSD from information available around the time of trauma. We assessed a wide variety of risk factors while the child was in the hospital including candidate genes, neurochemical and neurophysiologic responses, hospital treatment, qualities of the child’s family and early development, and parent’s stress and mental health. We then applied state-of-the-art Machine Learning methods to use all the risk information we collected, to build models of risk for PTSD, and test these models for their reliability and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9239&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9239&quot; height=&quot;188&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/artificial-intelligence-2228610_1920-300x188.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is Machine Learning? Details are found in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; but – broadly and briefly – Machine Learning is a computational approach designed to find patterns in data that will form reliable and accurate predictive models of specified events (e.g. the occurrence of PTSD in a traumatized child). The ‘machine’ will use specified algorithms to search through the space of possibilities contained in the data, to arrive at a predictive model. The reliability and accuracy of this predictive model is then tested with data the ‘machine’ has not yet seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used five different approaches to Machine Learning predictive classification and each of the yielded models showed strong predictive performance, certainly stronger than comparisons with conventional methods. We also integrated a feature selection method designed to find the variables that had &lt;em&gt;causal&lt;/em&gt; influence on PTSD. We understand that this claim for &lt;em&gt;causality&lt;/em&gt; will often arouse incredulity within the psychiatric research community. How can we make such a claim?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We understand that this claim for &lt;em&gt;causality&lt;/em&gt; will often arouse incredulity within the psychiatric research community. How can we make such a claim?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our causal discovery, feature selection methods are designed to find what is called the &lt;em&gt;Markov Boundary&lt;/em&gt; for a response variable (R) (e.g. PTSD). The Markov Boundary defines the set of variables that render every other variable set in the data independent of R. The Markov Boundary – in the majority of distributions – also possesses a &lt;u&gt;causal function&lt;/u&gt; as it includes the direct causes, direct effects and direct causes of the direct effects of R. When the response variable is a terminal event (i.e. no variables occur after R), then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmlr.org/papers/v11/aliferis10a.html&quot;&gt;the Markov Boundary is the set of direct causes of R&lt;/a&gt;. What are the implications of finding such a Markov Boundary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our methods have enabled the discovery of the Markov Boundary for the terminal response variable of PTSD. Therefore, we have discovered the set of direct causes of PTSD. Some of you may be tempted to search through our article to find the method we used to conduct the experiment that allowed such causal inference. Alas, none will be found, and that is the point. Should we have randomly assigned a child to a trauma condition? Of course, ethical considerations cannot allow such a study and, therefore, there is no ethically allowable search for causation using conventional methods in our field. And, therefore, there is no available knowledge of causation (outside of animal research) in our field. And this is a very big problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;our article&lt;/a&gt;, we include many references documenting the mathematical rigor of Markov Boundary induction, and the track record of Markov Boundary induction algorithms for detecting true causes, from data sets where true causes were previously known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did we find? We found a set of causal variables, measured around the time of trauma that predicted PTSD, three months later. In this set, were specific candidate genes that may point to the potential preventative use of specific medications targeted towards the biological processes encoded by these genes. Other identified causal variables were more directly remediable, such as the child’s level of acute pain and the parent’s level of acute distress. Interestingly, we also found that the child’s history of being breast fed as an infant, and whether the child attended religious services regularly, was protective of PTSD: indicating the important role of attachment, community, and spirituality for a child’s recovery after trauma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/10/machine-learning-predict-childhood-ptsd/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Machine Learning to Predict Childhood PTSD&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/AI-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Drinking sugary beverages in pregnancy linked to kids’ later weight gain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/drinking-sugary-beverages-pregnancy-linked-kids-later-weight-gain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/drinking-sugary-beverages-pregnancy-linked-kids-later-weight-gain</link>
	<description>Consuming sugary drinks while pregnant may mean kids are heavier when they reach elementary school age.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 04:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070617_AC_pregnant_main_free.jpg?itok=KDyYgVXz" length="21154" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: K2P2.1 (TREK-1)–activator complexes reveal a cryptic selectivity filter binding site</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22988</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jIjgCgt7v5c/nature22988</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Polymodal thermo- and mechanosensitive two-pore domain potassium (K2P) channels of the TREK subfamily generate ‘leak’ currents that regulate neuronal excitability, respond to lipids, temperature and mechanical stretch, and influence pain, temperature perception and anaesthetic responses. These dimeric voltage-gated ion channel (VGIC) superfamily members have a unique topology comprising two pore-forming regions per subunit. In contrast to other potassium channels, K2P channels use a selectivity filter ‘C-type’ gate as the principal gating site. Despite recent advances, poor pharmacological profiles of K2P channels limit mechanistic and biological studies. Here we describe a class of small-molecule TREK activators that directly stimulate the C-type gate by acting as molecular wedges that restrict interdomain interface movement behind the selectivity filter. Structures of K2P2.1 (also known as TREK-1) alone and with two selective K2P2.1 (TREK-1) and K2P10.1 (TREK-2) activators—an N-aryl-sulfonamide, ML335, and a thiophene-carboxamide, ML402—define a cryptic binding pocket unlike other ion channel small-molecule binding sites and, together with functional studies, identify a cation–π interaction that controls selectivity. Together, our data reveal a druggable K2P site that stabilizes the C-type gate ‘leak mode’ and provide direct evidence for K2P selectivity filter gating. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22988&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22988&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jIjgCgt7v5c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: The ‘Journal Grand Master,’ what drives online attention to studies; a song of replication</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50954</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/08/weekend-reads-journal-grand-master-drives-online-attention-studies-song-replication/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a story of unintended consequences and a broken relationship, and a retraction for a paper that had just about everything wrong with it. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Who is the ‘Journal Grand Master?’” An argument for using a journal ranking system based on sports rankings. (Robert Lehmann, Klaus […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/08/weekend-reads-journal-grand-master-drives-online-attention-studies-song-replication/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: The ‘Journal Grand Master,’ what drives online attention to studies; a song of replication&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 13:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Why Psychiatry Needs Neuroscience</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-81</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/V_n-EeFxXKM/scientificamericanmind0717-81</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 81 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-81&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-81&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel Barron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An influential subset of psychiatrists argue—absurdly—that neuroscience has little clinical relevance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/V_n-EeFxXKM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: How the Science of “Blue Lies” May Explain Trump's Support</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-77</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/1sD5vfmOUfQ/scientificamericanmind0717-77</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 77 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-77&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-77&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Jeremy Adam Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are a very particular form of deception that can build solidarity within groups&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/1sD5vfmOUfQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Does Living in Crowded Places Drive People Crazy?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-74</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/k76rC7jo45g/scientificamericanmind0717-74</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 74 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-74&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-74&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authors: Oliver Sng, Steven Neuberg, Michael Varnum &amp;amp; Douglas Kenrick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new theoretical tool called life history theory offers an answer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/k76rC7jo45g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: How to Prevent Suicide with an Opioid</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-70</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/aDXvWVsFJu8/scientificamericanmind0717-70</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 70 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-70&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-70&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anne Skomorowsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fascinating study suggests treating “psychache”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/aDXvWVsFJu8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Cross-Cultural Evidence for the Genetics of Homosexuality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-7</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/0qCH19Hv3fg/scientificamericanmind0717-7</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 7 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-7&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-7&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Debra W. Soh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico's third gender sheds light on the biological correlates of sexual orientation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/0qCH19Hv3fg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Lonely but Never Alone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-62</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/vUehlK0iG_w/scientificamericanmind0717-62</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 62 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-62&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-62&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anna von Hopffgarten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space travel: How does the brain react to the isolation encountered in outer space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/vUehlK0iG_w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Schizophrenia's Unyielding Mysteries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-50</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/1re-cswoq90/scientificamericanmind0717-50</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 50 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-50&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-50&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Balter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gene studies were supposed to reveal the disorder's roots. That didn't happen. Now scientists are broadening the search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/1re-cswoq90&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Listen between the Cries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-44</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/Zd_zosyqrOE/scientificamericanmind0717-44</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 44 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-44&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-44&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Janosch Deeg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers try to decipher the hidden messages in babies' wailing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/Zd_zosyqrOE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: How Gut Bacteria Tell Their Hosts What to Eat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-4</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/TZqVhGzrYe0/scientificamericanmind0717-4</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 4 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Knvul Sheikh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By suppressing or increasing cravings, microbes help the brain decide what foods the body “needs”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/TZqVhGzrYe0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Deciphering the Language of Love</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-35</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/0uuhTxBTmPA/scientificamericanmind0717-35</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 35 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-35&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-35&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Sue Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attachment science is helping couples master communication and connection—and getting through conflict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/0uuhTxBTmPA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Mind over Meal: Does Weight-Loss Surgery Rewire Gut-Brain Connections?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-27</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/CziKqLoebCk/scientificamericanmind0717-27</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 27 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-27&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-27&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Bret Stetka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New evidence hints that bariatric surgery changes the dialogue between bowel and brain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/CziKqLoebCk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Meditation's Calming Effects Pinpointed in the Brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-24</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/3HpgRtDXMuE/scientificamericanmind0717-24</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 24 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Diana Kwon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new mouse study reveals a set of neurons that may point to physiological roots for the benefits of breathing control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/3HpgRtDXMuE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Your Brain Remembers Languages You Think You Forgot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-22</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/TydQxo0mAgs/scientificamericanmind0717-22</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 22 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Jane C. Hu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kids adopted in a new country have an advantage in learning their native tongue as adults, even if they have not heard it since birth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/TydQxo0mAgs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Welcome to the New Scientific American Mind</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-2</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/SjNdIeb7H5w/scientificamericanmind0717-2</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 2 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-2&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-2&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/SjNdIeb7H5w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: The Genius of Pinheads: When Little Brains Rule</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-17</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/kdoQ5OqOzJk/scientificamericanmind0717-17</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 17 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-17&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-17&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Erik Vance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bigger brains are not always better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/kdoQ5OqOzJk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: This is Your Brain on Poverty</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-13</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/dezr_8BaN0A/scientificamericanmind0717-13</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 13 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-13&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-13&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Amanda Montañez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations highlight the surprising connections between income and brain structure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/dezr_8BaN0A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American Mind: Don't Forget: You, Too, Can Acquire a Super Memory</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-10</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~3/0EEqKQXxw4Q/scientificamericanmind0717-10</link>
	<description>&lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American Mind 28, 10 (2017).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-10&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamericanmind0717-10&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Catherine Caruso&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning a memorization technique used by elite memory athletes leads to widespread changes in brain wiring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamericanmind/rss/current/~4/0EEqKQXxw4Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamericanmind/rss/current">Scientific American Mind - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fossil tooth pushes back record of mysterious Neandertal relative</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-tooth-pushes-back-record-mysterious-neandertal-relative</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-tooth-pushes-back-record-mysterious-neandertal-relative</link>
	<description>A Denisovan child’s fossil tooth dates to at least 100,000 years ago, researchers say.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070717_BB_denisovan_main.jpg?itok=sXrbJxtc" length="17445" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Newfound particle relies on its charm(s)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newfound-particle-relies-its-charms</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newfound-particle-relies-its-charms</link>
	<description>First-of-its-kind subatomic particle is composed of two charm quarks and an up quark.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 16:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070617_ec_newparticle_free.jpg?itok=X2tbsaJp" length="15748" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Failed whistleblower suit is a reminder that public universities are hard to sue</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50946</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/07/failed-whistleblower-suit-reminder-public-universities-hard-sue/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Suing the government is difficult. And because public universities often function as an arm of state governments, that makes them hard to sue, too, a fact reiterated in a whistleblower case decided earlier this year. In January, Judge David Hale of the Western District of Kentucky dismissed a lawsuit filed by former employees of the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/07/failed-whistleblower-suit-reminder-public-universities-hard-sue/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Failed whistleblower suit is a reminder that public universities are hard to sue&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: China’s quantum satellite adds two new tricks to its repertoire</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-quantum-satellite-adds-two-new-tricks-repertoire</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/china-quantum-satellite-adds-two-new-tricks-repertoire</link>
	<description>Satellite performs quantum teleportation and securely transmits encryption keys.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070617_EC_quantum-satellite_main.jpg?itok=TmYH_jup" length="36184" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Using Citizen Science to Monitor Road-Kills</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9260</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/07/using-citizen-science-to-monitor-road-kills/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Zamenis_longissimus_Aesculapian_snake_user_cpratte_via-roadkill.at_-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worldwide many terrestrial vertebrate populations are declining due to several reasons. Among them are habitat loss, climate change, illegal hunting and roads. The influences of roads on animal biodiversity are manifold, ranging from various pollutions to the most direct impact of road-kill. Our new research article focuses on the effects of land-cover on road-killed amphibians and reptiles and the feasibility of a large scale citizen science approach to elucidate underlying patterns and interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizen science is the active participation of laymen/amateurs in scientific projects. Currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://theoryandpractice.citizenscienceassociation.org/articles/10.5334/cstp.96/&quot;&gt;a discussion is going on&lt;/a&gt; regarding the terminology in citizen science. What is ‘citizen science’, who is a ‘citizen’ and who is allowed to do ‘science’. However, the participation of amateurs in scientific projects has many benefits, including the collection of data on different objects covering a wide geographic area, and at the same time it raises awareness for a specific topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall goal of our citizen science project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://roadkill.at/en/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roadkill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to get an overview of numbers and patterns of road-killed vertebrates. In the last 3 years over 500 participants collected data of more than 5000 road-kills all over the world with a focus on Austria. The workload of the project is completely covered by volunteers (professional scientists and amateurs), ranging from website and app development to data collection, verification and publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9267&quot; style=&quot;width: 856px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9267&quot; height=&quot;843&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/European_green_toad_-user_JGZ_via_roadkill.at_.png&quot; width=&quot;846&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;European green toad killed on a road&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;User JGZ via roadkill.at&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2013 we regularly improved our method of data collection, published three peer reviewed articles, and did a lot of public relations in order to increase the number of project participants. Only then was it possible to cover the large and diverse geographic area of Austria and to increase data quantity. If you are interested in our work, please follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/project.roadkill&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ProjektRoadkill&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/projectroadkill/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of our study was to examine the applicability of open-access remote sensing data for a large-scale citizen science approach to describe spatial patterns of road-killed amphibians and reptiles on tertiary roads. Using our citizen science app &lt;em&gt;Roadkill&lt;/em&gt; we monitored road-kills of amphibians and reptiles along 97.5 km of tertiary roads covering agricultural, municipal and interurban roads as well as cycling paths in eastern Austria over two seasons. Surrounding landscape was assessed using open access land cover classes for the region (Coordination of Information on the Environment, CORINE). We also estimated the potential cost-efficiency of a large scale citizen science monitoring project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recorded 180 amphibian and 72 reptile road-kills comprising eight species mainly occurring on agricultural roads. We found a significant clustering of road-killed amphibians and reptiles, which is important information for authorities aiming to mitigate road-kills. Our analyses identified road-kills especially next to preferred habitats of green toads, common toads, and grass snakes. It was encouraging to see that land cover classes based on a rather coarse 500-m grid matched well with the most preferred habitats of the most abundant amphibian species in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9268&quot; style=&quot;width: 857px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9268&quot; height=&quot;844&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Lacerta_viridis_European_green_lizard_user_JGZ_via-_roadkill.at_.png&quot; width=&quot;847&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Remains of a road-killed European green lizard&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;User JGZ via roadkill.at&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We concluded that citizen science would be an appropriate method to monitor road-kills of amphibians and reptiles on a regular basis and on a larger scale when investigating the influence of land cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plans for the future are to (I) continue the long-term citizen observatory system for road-killed vertebrates in Austria including the presence-only data collection and additionally establish a monitoring approach in coordination with already existing European systems, (II) enhance awareness-raising for the topic of road-killed animals among the general public and (III) develop a monitoring system involving various stakeholders aiming to reduce the number of road-killed animals in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on the benefits of citizen science in collecting ecological data, read this blog from last year by Poppy Lakeman Fraser – &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2016/07/22/citizen-science-looking-glass/&quot;&gt;Citizen science: through the looking glass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-9265&quot; height=&quot;1836&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Heigl_Roadkill.jpg&quot; width=&quot;3264&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/07/using-citizen-science-to-monitor-road-kills/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Using Citizen Science to Monitor Road-Kills&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Zamenis_longissimus_Aesculapian_snake_user_cpratte_via-roadkill.at_-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Scientist Trains Minority STEM Students</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1102</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/07/science-exchange-scientist-trains-minority-stem-students/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We are proud of our own Dr. Gabriel Roybal-Jungemann, Senior Scientist and R&amp;amp;D Specialist at Science Exchange, who will be speaking this week at a career panel aimed at increasing STEM leaders of color. Promoting diversity in science is crucial to achieving Science Exchange’s mission of enabling breakthrough research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gabriel joined Science Exchange after 12+ years in biomedical research and teaching at minority-serving institutions. He is also an entrepreneur, having founded his first company in 2013 to help improve family health and address health disparities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a scientist of color, Gabriel will be speaking to minority STEM students about entrepreneurship and to encourage alternative careers and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the event below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Gabriel.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gabriel Roybal-Jungemann&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1103&quot; height=&quot;194&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Gabriel-300x194.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, a select cohort of underrepresented minority STEM students will begin their path to leadership. Science Exchange will be represented with the participation of Dr. Gabriel Roybal-Jungemann, Senior Scientist, Research and Development Specialist, as a Career Panel Speaker for the &lt;strong&gt;inaugural SACNAS Chapter Leadership Institute (CLI).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLI is led by &lt;a href=&quot;http://sacnas.org/&quot;&gt;Society for Advancement of Chicanos/Hispanics &amp;amp; Native Americans in Science (SACNAS)&lt;/a&gt; and funded by the Genentech Foundation. Dr. Roybal-Jungemann has been involved with SACNAS since 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The institute, held July 7 – 8 at San Jose City College, is two full days of small group exercises, keynote speakers, leadership development workshops, networking opportunities, and extensive community building among selected participants from colleges and universities across California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SACNAS Director of Programs, Mr. Rolando Madrid says the Genentech Foundation is the ideal partner to nurture a new generation of leaders. He notes, “We are proud to partner with the Genentech Foundation to launch our inaugural Chapter Leadership Institute. Genentech understands the importance of investing in our next generation of underrepresented minority scientists and is doing their part to ensure that the future is well developed and prepared to tackle the issues of the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants of the CLI are all part of the SACNAS chapter program, a national network of 115 student and professional chapters that work to strengthen community and peer support for minority scientists at the local and regional levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms. Tanya Beat, manager of the SACNAS Chapter Program, says, “The CLI will equip students with critical take-away tools including individual leadership plans, mentor-mentee relationships, and a rich network of peers and STEM leaders from California.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2009, SACNAS leadership initiatives have trained a cohort of 30 PhD-level scientists each year, making it the largest group of emerging STEM leaders of color in the country. With the introduction of CLI, SACNAS is expanding leadership training to the undergraduate and graduate student levels, nurturing leaders earlier in their educational and career trajectories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sacnas.org/cli-cohort/&quot;&gt;View the entire SACNAS Chapter Leadership Institute Cohort. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SACNAS &amp;amp; The Genentech Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SACNAS&lt;/strong&gt; is an inclusive organization dedicated to fostering the success of Chicanos/Hispanics and Native Americans, from college students to professionals, in attaining advanced degrees, careers, and positions of leadership in STEM. Considered the founder of the biotechnology industry, &lt;strong&gt;Genentech&lt;/strong&gt; is leader in the discovery, development, manufacturing, and commercialization of medicines that treat patients with serious or life-threatening medical conditions. &lt;strong&gt;The Genentech Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on three charitable giving goals: advancing scientific knowledge, enhancing health outcomes, and building strong communities to build real and lasting change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 13:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The retraction countdown: How quickly do journals pull papers?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50941</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/07/retraction-countdown-quickly-journals-pull-papers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;After Tina Wenz was found guilty of scientific misconduct, how long did it take for journals to retract the problematic papers?  The answer: Between three and nine months. In September 2016, the University of Cologne found that Wenz had committed scientific misconduct in six papers and requested they all be retracted. From that point on, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/07/retraction-countdown-quickly-journals-pull-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The retraction countdown: How quickly do journals pull papers?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Hermaphrodite wildflower has its own battle of the sexes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hermaphrodite-wildflower-has-its-own-battle-sexes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/hermaphrodite-wildflower-has-its-own-battle-sexes</link>
	<description>A new example of sexual conflict shows up in a plant with a troublesome pollinator.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/063017_SM_plant-sex-wars_main.jpg?itok=TpulFeSs" length="24898" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Juno will fly a mere 9,000 km above Jupiter’s Great Red Spot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-fly-mere-9000-km-above-jupiters-great-red-spot</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-fly-mere-9000-km-above-jupiters-great-red-spot</link>
	<description>Juno is about to get up close and personal with Jupiter’s Great Red Spot.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/070617_MT_juno-flyby_main.jpg?itok=oTHOJ-3d" length="21534" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Rural Cameroonian pre-schoolers just aced Mischel’s iconic Marshmallow Test</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26323</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/07/rural-cameroonian-pre-schoolers-just-aced-mischels-iconic-marshmallow-test/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_26469&quot; style=&quot;width: 1024px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-89409231.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26469&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26469&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cover\/Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Nikon SUPER COOLSCAN 4000 ED&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1980. Yaunde, Cameroon. Portrait of a children.  (Photo by Gianni Ferrari\/Cover\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1980. Yaunde, Cameroon. Portrait of a children.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;1980. Yaunde, Cameroon. Portrait of a children.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-89409231.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-89409231.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-89409231.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,691&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/07/rural-cameroonian-pre-schoolers-just-aced-mischels-iconic-marshmallow-test/1980-yaunde-cameroon-portrait-of-a-children/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-89409231.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;It’s the first time that this iconic test of children’s self-control has been used in a traditional non-Western culture&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walter Mischel’s Marshmallow Test of self-control is one of psychology’s iconic experimental set-ups. First conducted in the 1960s, Mischel told the kids he tested that if they managed to resist eating the marshmallow in front of them until he returned (usually about 15 minutes later), they would be rewarded with a second marshmallow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children varied greatly in their powers of restraint and those who performed better displayed some cute distraction strategies, such as singing to themselves and covering their eyes. Perhaps most important, those kids who performed well at the test tended to do well in later life too, in terms of their health, education and career success. Given the huge impact this research has had, it’s amazing that it’s never been exported to a non-Western setting. Until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cdev.12847/full&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Child Development&lt;/em&gt;, Bettina Lamm and her colleagues have compared the performance of 125 4-year-olds from urban middle-class Germany with the performance of dozens of 4-year-olds from the Nso farming families of rural Cameroon. The Cameroonian kids aced the test, performing much better than their German peers. What’s more, their success seemed to be tied to the traditional, strict, hierarchical culture in which they’d been raised. The results challenge Western assumptions about what constitutes an ideal parenting style, and they provide another powerful demonstration of the urgent need for psychology to conduct more research outside of its usual Western focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26323&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task faced by the German and Cameroonian children was very similar to the original version of the Marshmallow Test except the source of temptation for the German kids was either a lollipop or a chocolate bar (no one treat is equally liked in Germany so the researchers used whichever was the more desirable for each child), and for the Cameroonians it was a puff-puff, which is a kind of doughnut. On first seeing whichever treat was used, the children’s initial outward behavior in both cultures made it clear that they found it extremely tempting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children sat at a table on which either the lollipop, chocolate bar or puff-puff was placed within their reach. Before leaving the room, the researcher told them that they could eat the treat now, or if they waited until the researcher came back (which he or she did 10 minutes later), they would get the first treat plus a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly 70 per cent of the Cameroonian children succeeded in waiting for the researcher to return without eating the first treat, compared with fewer than 30 per cent of the German children. Furthermore, the emotions the children displayed and the strategies they used differed depending on their cultural background. Whereas the German children showed more frustration and used a lot of distraction techniques, such as turning away, talking and singing, the Cameroonians showed little emotion or activity, in fact eight of them fell asleep! Also several of the German kids who couldn’t wait actually left the room to go and look for the researcher, but only one Cameroonian kid did this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers believe the contrast in behavior between the children in the two cultures has to do with the very different social milieu and parenting styles they have experienced. The Cameroonian kids are raised in multi-generational family groups with many siblings and they are taught to contain their emotions, obey their elders and to recognise the importance of group solidarity and social responsibility. In contrast, and as in most rich Western countries, the German kids are mostly raised in small family groups and they are taught the importance of self-expression, individuality and freedom of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lamm and her team think this manifests in the way the kids from the two cultures handle the Marshmallow Test: the German kids sought to impose their will on the situation, such as by districting themselves or leaving the room to go look for the researcher. By contrast, the Cameroonian kids adopted what the researchers call “holistic self-regulation”, that is they seemed to be better able to control their own emotions from within, perhaps through all the practice they’d had in their upbringing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this is conjecture, of course. There are other ways to interpret the findings – for instance, we don’t know for sure that the Cameroonian kids really were as tempted by the treats as the Germans. Perhaps they found the whole set-up more intimidating and they were more subdued (though there was no evidence that they displayed more negative emotion). As the researchers admitted, “it remains unclear whether [the Cameroonian kids’ success] is the result of effective emotion regulation in this specific situation or whether emotional socialisation [their strict upbringing] produces a completely different experience of the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test their theory that children’s self-control develops differently across the cultures due to different social values and parenting styles, Lamm and her colleagues performed a follow up study using data they’d collected from a sub-set of the kids in both cultures when they were just 9-month-old babies. This involved videoing the babies and their mothers in a free play session and coding the mothers’ behavior. The mothers also completed questionnaires about the social values they most cherished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the researchers found that the Cameroonian mothers placed more value on conservative goals (loyalty, obedience, solidarity etc) and they were more directive in their play, creating a highly structured play situation and continually engaging their infants. The German mothers said they valued encouraging psychological autonomy (freedom of preference, individuality etc) and in their play they were less hands on, tending to let their babies take the lead and letting them have more unstructured breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, these distinctive parenting patterns correlated with the children’s Marshmallow test performance at age 4. Across groups, kids with mothers who particularly emphasized autononomy and freedom and allowed more unstructured play particularly struggled to resist the treat – this was mostly the German kids. In contrast, kids with mothers who particularly emphasized traditional hiercharchial goals and structured play tended to excel at showing self-restraint – this was mostly the Cameroonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are group-level correlations so causal effects of parenting and values have not been established (among other things, the genetic inheritance of self-control is an important confound). But one credible interpretation of the findings is that children’s self-control is shaped by the culture of their upbringing, and that there are different ways to find success in the Marshmallow test – the less effective “external” approach of the Western kids, which is based on exerting control over the environment, versus the more social, self-disciplined approach of the Cameroonian kids quite likely based on their having learnt greater control of their emotions in the service of obedience and group solidarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intriguingly, this picture clashes somewhat with popular Western findings and theory around parenting, which stated crudely have suggested that authoritative parenting (in which children are given boundaries but are also supported and encouraged to pursue their own interests and desires) is the ideal way to foster a conscientious child whereas authoritarian parenting (strict and limiting parenting that emphasises obedience, arguably similar in some ways to the Cameroonian approach) should be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fascinating possibility is the developmental consequences of different parenting styles is culture-dependent: for instance, perhaps a more authoritarian style is beneficial to children raised in rural Cameroon in large families with many generations under one roof and strict social hierarchies. If nothing else, this research is a reminder that we must study a broader range of humanity else we might find our most cherished theories are built on foundations of Western sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cdev.12847/full&quot;&gt;Waiting for the Second Treat: Developing Culture-Specific Modes of Self-Regulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: 1980. Portrait of children in Cameroon. (Photo by Gianni Ferrari/Cover/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26323/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26323/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26323&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 09:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC-series: June 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog?p=9220&amp;preview_id=9220</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/07/highlights-bmc-series-june-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology: publication of the first results-free peer review article &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-016-0167-7&quot;&gt;Results-free review&lt;/a&gt; is a new model of peer review aiming to reduce publication bias, and prevent impressive ends from justifying poor means. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/em&gt; first launched results-free review in December 2016, and the first article to have undergone the full results-free review process has been published and is featured below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0183-2&quot;&gt;Consumption of wine and glass size&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few studies have explored the psychology of what influences how much alcohol is consumed in a social setting, and this study focuses on what can be done to change drinking behaviors based solely on how the alcohol is presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study tested the effects changing the size of the wine glass had on the drinking rate, sip number, and sip duration of wine in young women. The same amount of wine was provided in either a small or large wine glass, and participates’ behavior was observed. Surprisingly, it was found that larger cup size resulted in women drinking alcohol much slower, and with shorter sip durations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the study, please read &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/12/results-free-review-impressions-from-the-first-published-article/&quot;&gt;a Q&amp;amp;A from the authors and editors&lt;/a&gt; discussing what the new peer-review process means for authors, reviewers, editors and readers. To learn more about how the size of a drinking glass can influence alcohol consumption the authors of this study have written a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/12/micro-drinking-behaviors-responsible-increased-wine-consumption-served-larger-glass/&quot;&gt;blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry:  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1369-0&quot;&gt;Euthanasia for psychiatric disorders or dementia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End of life decisions have become an increasingly common medical choice among terminally ill and suffering patients.  In Belgium, the right to die extends beyond just the terminally ill, and includes patients suffering from psychiatric disorders and dementia.  This study analyzes the anonymous databases of euthanasia cases reported to the Federal Control and Evaluation Committee Euthanasia from the implementation of the euthanasia law in Belgium in 2002 until the end of 2013, and found that the prevalence of euthanize has increased in this vulnerable population since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more in depth discussion on this topic, please read the&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/23/euthanasia-for-people-with-psychiatric-disorders-or-dementia/&quot;&gt; author blog&lt;/a&gt; on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Microbiology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmicrobiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12866-017-1044-0&quot;&gt;Gut microbial colonization and asthma development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;The authors of this study explored the effects of environmental exposure and asthma development in developing mice. In this study mice were kept in a controlled, germ-free environment at various stages of development to investigate the effect of early-life diverse microbial exposures on gut microbial colonization in an OVA-induced asthma model in BALB/c mice.  The researchers found that exposure to the non-germ free environment lead to the greatest diversity in intestinal flora in the mice, and mice with increased intestinal flora diversity had lower pathological scores of OVA-induced asthma.  The results also suggest that exposure in early life to a diversity of microbes may prevent airway inflammation in asthma by regulating the Th1/Th2 pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Public Health: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4422-5&quot;&gt;Physical activity in seniors with dogs &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;This study seeks to quantify if older adults can increase their daily activity by owning a pet dog. This longitudinal case-controlled study explores if owning a dog can lead to changes in exercise and behavior amount in elderly adults in the UK.  Researchers compared a dog-owning population to a non-dog owning population, of groups comprised of adults over the age of 65, and measured time spent walking, steps taken, and sedentary time. Results showed that owning a dog did lead to significant changes of behavior, specifically increased walking times, and increased step numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;For a more in depth analysis of this topic, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/06/16/the-influence-of-dog-ownership-on-sedentary-behavior-in-older-adults/&quot;&gt;BMC series blog&lt;/a&gt; on this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image of the month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-9262&quot; height=&quot;2574&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Figure_1_Escalona-et-al.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1989&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;A representative spectrum of morphology and feeding habits of true ladybirds (or ladybugs for our American readers). From Escalona et al. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-017-1002-3&quot;&gt;Molecular phylogeny reveals food plasticity in the evolution of true ladybird beetles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Nutrition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnutr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40795-017-0168-9&quot;&gt;High fructose corn syrup drinks and coronary heart disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;It is well known that drinking soda in excess can lead to severe health problems, namely obesity and diabetes.  This study explored the relationship between a diet with drinks containing high levels of high fructose corn syrup and likelihood to develop coronary heart disease in adults in the United States.  The researchers analyzed data from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) between the years 2003–2006, and discovered a significant correlation between intake of any combination of HFCS sweetened soft drinks, fruit drinks, and apple juice with CHD.  The correlation may be due to the high ratio of fructose to glucose in these highly sweetened beverages, and a possible mechanism of action would be an underlying inability to absorb fructose contributing to the intestinal in situ formation of pro-inflammatory enFruAGEs, which are eventually absorbed and induce inflammation of the coronary arteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;journal-header__title journal-header__title--medium&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Biotechnology&lt;/strong&gt;:  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcbiotechnol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12896-017-0374-1&quot;&gt;Monitoring 3D spheroids using beetle luciferase-expressing hepatocytes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Monitoring the health of &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; spheroids is difficult to assess, due to the physical nature of spheroids. In this methods article the authors have constructed a monitoring system in which the cytotoxicity in the same 3D spheroids was continuously and sensitively monitored over a long term using a non-destructive bioluminescence derived from Emerald Luc (ELuc), a green-emitting beetle luciferase from &lt;em class=&quot;EmphasisTypeItalic&quot;&gt;P. termitilluminans&lt;/em&gt;. This system can be applied to other cell models, such as human primary cells or stem cells, and is expected to serve as the preferred platform for simple and cost-effective long-term monitoring of cellular events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;ArticleTitle&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Neuroscience:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcneurosci.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12868-017-0369-9&quot;&gt;Toxic effects of iron oxide nanoparticles &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron oxide nanoparticles studies have been ongoing in several fields of medical research, most of which target the central nervous system.  These nanoparticles have a wide variety of uses, including to deliver medication, clarify MRI images, and target amyloid beta plaques.  The authors of this study performed a systematic review of the toxic effects of iron oxide nanoparticles, and the results suggest that depending on the type of nano-particles involved, their use can lead to iron accumulation, oxidative stress and protein aggregation in the neural cells.  Awareness of these results would be important for scientists performing future studies with iron oxide nanoparticles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/07/highlights-bmc-series-june-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC-series: June 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The &quot;Electrosensitive&quot; Brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8925</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8925</link>
	<description>A strange new paper reports &quot;abnormal&quot; brain activity in 10 patients with electrohypersensitivity (EHS) - a controversial condition allegedly triggered by electromagnetic fields from devices such as phones and power-lines.



But the methods used in this study were very odd.

According to the authors, Gunnar Heuser and Sylvia A. Heuser, the ten patients all suffered from symptoms such as
Headaches, impairment of cognitive function, tremors, weakness, and others. Multi-system complaints we</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 09:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Pin-drop test pops Greek amphitheater’s acoustic claims</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pin-drop-test-pops-greek-amphitheater-acoustic-claims</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pin-drop-test-pops-greek-amphitheater-acoustic-claims</link>
	<description>Analysis of an ancient Greek amphitheater’s ability to carry sounds reveals overblown tour guide claims.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 19:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070517_re_theater_free.jpg?itok=HJlAF8rh" length="55404" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Dive deep to discover unexpected connections</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dive-deep-discover-unexpected-connections</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dive-deep-discover-unexpected-connections</link>
	<description>Readers often praise Science News for its brevity. But some ideas need more space, writes acting editor in chief Elizabeth Quill.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 16:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
