<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: Dwarf planet Ceres may store underground brine that still gushes up today</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dwarf-planet-ceres-may-store-underground-brine-still-gushes-today</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dwarf-planet-ceres-may-store-underground-brine-still-gushes-today</link>
	<description>Waterlogged minerals and changing ice add to evidence that Ceres is geologically active.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 22:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031418_LG_ceres-water_feat.jpg?itok=WDjgquBF" length="36988" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Is Human Adult Neurogenesis Dead? And Does It Matter?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9406</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9406</link>
	<description>Does the human brain continue creating new neurons throughout adult life? The idea that neurogenesis exists in the adult human hippocampus has generated a huge amount of excitement and stimulated much research. It's been proposed that disruptions to neurogenesis could help to explain stress, depression, and other disorders.

But a new study, published in Nature, has just poured cold water on the whole idea. Researchers Shawn F. Sorrells and colleagues report that neurogenesis ends in humans so</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 20:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New Horizons’ next target has been dubbed Ultima Thule</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-horizons-next-target-has-been-dubbed-ultima-thule</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-horizons-next-target-has-been-dubbed-ultima-thule</link>
	<description>NASA has named New Horizons spacecraft’s next target Ultima Thule after the public suggested tens of thousands of monikers for the Kuiper Belt object.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031418_MD_ultima-thule_feat.jpg?itok=pQPAOvMi" length="19054" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Hospital admissions show the opioid crisis affects kids, too</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/hospital-admissions-kids-opioid-crisis</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/hospital-admissions-kids-opioid-crisis</link>
	<description>Opioid-related hospitalizations for children are up, a sad statistic that shows the opioid epidemic doesn’t just affect adults.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 17:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/blogposts/031318_ls_opioids_feat_free.jpg?itok=TrPzhYM-" length="24044" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Forget Pi Day. We should be celebrating Tau Day</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/forget-pi-day-we-should-be-celebrating-tau-day</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/forget-pi-day-we-should-be-celebrating-tau-day</link>
	<description>Pi Day may be fun, but it’s based on a flawed mathematical constant.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/blogposts/031418_ec_pi_feat_free.jpg?itok=auPU5njF" length="35156" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Cancer biologist retracts five papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62936</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/14/cancer-biologist-retracts-five-papers/</link>
	<description>A cancer researcher based at The Ohio State University has retracted five papers from one journal, citing concerns about figures. The notices for all five papers state the Journal of Biological Chemistry raised questions about some figures, and the authors were not able to supply raw data in all instances. Four of the notices say … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/14/cancer-biologist-retracts-five-papers/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Cancer biologist retracts five papers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Renowned physicist Stephen Hawking dies at 76</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physicist-stephen-hawking-dead-76</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/physicist-stephen-hawking-dead-76</link>
	<description>Beyond his research contributions, Stephen Hawking popularized black holes and the deep questions of the cosmos.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 14:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031418_ec_hawking-obit_feat.jpg?itok=BGsdPqeV" length="24814" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Handling Variability in Model Transformations and Generators</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-03-14:/2018/03/14/handling-variability-in-model-transformations-and-generators.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/03/14/handling-variability-in-model-transformations-and-generators.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The talk will be based mainly on Voelter et al's paper on &quot;Handling
Variability in Model Transformations and Generators&quot;. Marco will provide
an introduction to the topic and explain how it relates to his
research. At the end of the talk he will provide a brief introduction
to Rose et al's paper on &quot;A Feature Model for Model-to-Text
Transformation Languages&quot; and explain how it interlinks with the first
paper and his research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main paper by Voelter et al: Handling Variability in Model Transformations and Generators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software product line engineering aims to reduce development
time, effort, cost, and complexity by taking advantage of the
commonality within a portfolio of similar products. The effectiveness
of a software product line approach directly depends on how well
feature variability within the portfolio is implemented and managed
throughout the development lifecycle, from early analysis through
maintenance and evolution. Using DSLs and AO to implement product
lines can yield significant advantages, since the variability can be
implemented on a higher level of abstraction, in less detailed models.
This paper illustrates how variability can be implemented in
model-to-model transformations and code generators using
aspect-oriented techniques. These techniques are important ingredients
for the aspectoriented model-driven product line engineering approach
presented in [13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondary paper by Rose et al: A Feature Model for Model-to-Text Transformation Languages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model-to-text (M2T) transformation is an important model management
operation, as it is used to implement code and documentation
generation; model serialisation (enabling model interchange); and
model visualisation and exploration. Despite the creation of the MOF
Model-To-Text Transformation Language (MOFM2T) in 2008, many very
different M2T languages exist today. Because there is little
interoperability between M2T languages and rewriting an existing M2T
transformation in a new language is costly, developers face a
difficult choice when selecting a M2T language. In this paper, we use
domain analysis to identify a preliminary feature model for M2T
languages. We demonstrate the appropriateness of the feature model by
describing two different M2T languages, and discuss potential
applications for a tool-supported and model-driven approach to
describing the features of M2T languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 28/02/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 13:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Stem cell researchers investigated for misconduct recommended for roles at Italy’s NIH</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62898</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/14/stem-cell-researchers-investigated-for-misconduct-recommended-for-roles-at-italys-nih/</link>
	<description>Two stem cell scientists who left Harvard University in the aftermath of a messy misconduct investigation may have found new roles in Italy’s National Institute of Health. According to a document on the institute’s website, which we had translated, Piero Anversa and Annarosa Leri have been approved to start work at the Istituto Superiore di Sanità (ISS) … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/14/stem-cell-researchers-investigated-for-misconduct-recommended-for-roles-at-italys-nih/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Stem cell researchers investigated for misconduct recommended for roles at Italy’s NIH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: What role does branding play in the smoking experience?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10011</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/14/role-branding-play-smoking-experience/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/smoking-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-018-5200-8&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; recently published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, Melanie Wakefield &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; from the Cancer Council Victoria employed a within-subjects design to test their hypothesis that the presence of a premium brand name would enhance perceived smoking experience and result in higher purchase intent, compared to when that same cigarette was presented with the brand name masked. The study was carried out in 2015, approximately 2.5 years after the introduction of plain packaging in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a sample of 75 Australian smokers aged 18-39 years, the researchers asked participants to smoke (take four puffs of) two identical cigarettes (1) with the brand variant name (branded) and (2) without the brand variant name (masked), the order of which was randomized. Only premium brands/more expensive mainstream brands were chosen and participants were required to be familiar with one of the eligible brand variants in order to be selected for the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-10015 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/smoke-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;“Masked” cigarettes were presented to participants on a plain white, ceramic dish whereas “Branded” cigarettes were presented to participants in their premium/upper-mainstream branded pack. All packs displayed the same “Smoking causes blindness” health warning in circulation at the time of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants perceived that the branded cigarette tasted better and was less stale than the masked cigarette. Furthermore, fewer participants reported that they would be likely to purchase the masked cigarette compared to the branded cigarette.  The authors also found that expected enjoyment of the brand variant and objective enjoyment of the cigarette (assessed through the masked condition) both significantly predicted perceived enjoyment of the cigarette when the brand variant name was known. However, objective cigarette quality did not predict perceived quality when the brand variant name was known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the study indicate that, even in a plain packaging marketplace, branding can still influence smokers’ perceptions and that smokers may still associate particular brands with advertising even after the introduction of plain packaging. Countries which are considering the implementation of plain packaging should therefore also consider the effects of the remaining brand variant names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers caution that the high proportion of participants who were not considering quitting in the next 6 months may have influenced the study results, as it is possible that smokers with no desire to quit have more favorable expectations of cigarette brands. Furthermore, participants were only asked to take four puffs of each cigarette within a single testing session. Future studies which allow smokers to experience the full cigarette, in their own time and in their regular environment, may clarify findings and strengthen conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/14/role-branding-play-smoking-experience/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What role does branding play in the smoking experience?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/smoking-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Investigating the “STEM gender-equality paradox” – in fairer societies, fewer women enter science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33468</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/14/investigating-the-stem-gender-equality-paradox-in-fairer-societies-fewer-women-enter-science/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33477&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-14 08.41.46.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33477&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33477&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-14 08.41.46&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-14-08-41-461.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-14-08-41-461.png?w=845?w=278&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-14-08-41-461.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1710,1846&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/14/investigating-the-stem-gender-equality-paradox-in-fairer-societies-fewer-women-enter-science/screenshot-2018-03-14-08-41-46-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-14-08-41-461.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;The percentage of women with STEM degrees is lower in more gender-equal countries, as measured by the WEF &lt;a href=&quot;http://reports.weforum.org/global-gender-gap-report-2015/&quot;&gt;Gender Gap Index&lt;/a&gt;. Image from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797617741719&quot;&gt;Stoet &amp;amp; Geary, 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The representation of women in STEM fields (science, technology, engineering and maths) is increasing, albeit more slowly than many observers would like. But a focus on this issue has begun throwing up head-scratching anomalies, such as Finland, which has one of the larger gender gaps in STEM occupations, despite being one of the more gender equal societies, and boasting a higher science literacy rate in its girls than boys. Now a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797617741719&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/i&gt; has used an international dataset of almost half a million participants that confirms what they call the “STEM gender-equality paradox”: more gender-equal societies have fewer women taking STEM degrees. And the research goes much further, exploring the causes that are driving these counterintuitive findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33468&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gijsbert Stoet at Leeds Beckett University and David Geary at the University of Missouri analysed several large and often publicly available datasets, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://reports.weforum.org/global-gender-gap-report-2015/&quot;&gt;gender inequality measures&lt;/a&gt; taken by the World Economic Forum (WEF; based on metrics like women’s earnings, life expectancy and seats in parliament) and UNESCO data on STEM degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found the percentage of women STEM graduates is &lt;i&gt;higher &lt;/i&gt;for countries that have more gender inequality. For instance, countries like Tunisia, Albania and Turkey, which come out the poorest on the WEF gender equality measures, see women making up 35-40 per cent of STEM graduates, whereas in countries with more gender equality, like Switzerland and Norway, the figure is lower at around 20 per cent, similar to Finland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better understand the STEM gender-equality paradox, Stoet and Geary accessed results from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/education/pisa-2015-results-volume-i-9789264266490-en.htm&quot;&gt;2015 OECD educational survey&lt;/a&gt; of the science literacy and attitudes to science of 15 to 16-year-old students from 67 countries. Objectively, neither boys or girls were more scientifically literate – girls were better in 19 countries, boys in 22, with no difference in the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These survey results suggest it is not girls’ lack of scientific knowledge or negative attitudes toward science that holds them back. It’s possible, however, that girls might match or outperform boys in science lessons in some countries and still be making a rational choice to avoid STEM routes because they outperform boys &lt;i&gt;even more&lt;/i&gt; in other areas (it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savethechildren.org.uk/news/media-centre/press-releases/boys-falling-behind-at-school&quot;&gt;well&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/06/schools-colleges-failing-boys-masculinity&quot;&gt;documented&lt;/a&gt; that girls outperform boys at school on many topics, on average).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the OECD survey, Stoet and Geary calculated a personal ranking for each student of their relative ability across the three main areas of maths, science and reading. In all but two of the 67 nations, boys more than girls were personally stronger in science (80 per cent of boys were personally strongest in either maths or science; in contrast, half of girls were personally strongest in reading). Stoet and Geary found that boys tending to be personally stronger in science was most apparent in more gender-equal countries, the very countries where boys go on to pursue more STEM careers. This smooths some of the kinks in the STEM gender-equality paradox: in fairer societies, boys seem to be optimising their future by pursuing science-like activities, whereas girls have other options on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, questions remain. For instance, why should a motivated and academically talented teenage girl forego a science route because her reading slightly outperforms her other literacies? After all, reading and writing skills are also beneficial to scientists, from paper writing to fundraising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stoet and Geary tried to address this question by focusing on gender differences in motivation, in terms of interest, confidence and enjoyment. In 60 per cent of countries, boys showed more interest in science than girls (in various fields, from disease prevention to energy), and the gender-gap in scientific interest was greater in the most gender-equal countries; boys also expressed more confidence in their science abilities in 39 of 67 countries, especially the gender-equal ones. And even though girls reported enjoying scientific activities more than boys in two-thirds of the countries, boys’ enjoyment was higher in the more gender-equal countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are boys most enthusiastic, interested, and personally strongest at science in more gender-equal societies? The authors suggest that in highly stable countries with strong welfare systems, people can pursue their calling and unlock their personal potential, building their future around their genuine interests and personal strengths. This echoes the finding popularised in &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/youtube-nbzAynn80SU&quot;&gt;online lectures&lt;/a&gt; by psychologist Jordan Peterson that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20161011-do-men-and-women-really-have-different-personalities&quot;&gt;sex-related personality differences are higher in gender-equal societies&lt;/a&gt; – when societies’ social pressures are less tyrannical, individual tendencies can be expressed more freely.  In more repressive cultures, by contrast, young people are liable to prioritise pragmatism – food on the table – over self-actualisation, and as STEM jobs tend to be stable and well-paid, that would encourage more female representation. Consistent with this, Stoet and Geary used a United Nations life satisfaction measure as a proxy for cultural stability and found that more women took STEM degrees in countries where life satisfaction is lower – which tended to be in the unequal societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings suggest we need a nuanced approach to the sticky issue of gender and participation in science. Firstly, there is no question from this data that objectively, young women across the globe are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20180312-the-teen-coder-who-wants-to-change-the-world&quot;&gt;just as capable&lt;/a&gt; to tackle scientific subjects as are young men. And even after taking into account the gender differences in science attitudes and personal strengths, the researchers calculated that, in a society where women’s rational preferences led directly to their level of STEM participation, we should see women take 34 per cent of STEM degrees, while the actual global average is 28 per cent – so other factors unaddressed in this study are clearly leading women away from science roles. So the study doesn’t suggest that we sit on our laurels and validate the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does suggest, however, that we misunderstand the current level of STEM gender imbalance if we attribute it entirely to social injustice. A substantial cause of the current STEM gender mix may be the product of young men and women making considered, rational choices to leverage their strengths and passions in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0956797617741719&quot;&gt;The Gender-Equality Paradox in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 08:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OIST Japan - CNU - Eric De Schutter: Scientists Illuminate Mechanism at Play in Learning</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.oist.jp/groups/32420 at https://www.oist.jp</guid>
	<link>https://www.oist.jp/news-center/news/2018/3/13/scientists-illuminate-mechanism-play-learning</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/news/2018/3/13/scientists-illuminate-mechanism-play-learning&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://oist-prod-www.s3-ap-northeast-1.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/styles/news_teaser_image__600x200_/public/2018-03-12-schutter-banner.jpg?itok=fpvw9pzy&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/news/2018/3/13/scientists-illuminate-mechanism-play-learning&quot;&gt;Scientists Illuminate Mechanism at Play in Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;New research illuminates complex molecular network involved in learning.&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 01:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.oist.jp/taxonomy/term/424/feed">Computational Neuroscience Unit (Erik De Schutter)</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Cosmic dust may create Mars’ wispy clouds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cosmic-dust-may-create-mars-wispy-clouds</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cosmic-dust-may-create-mars-wispy-clouds</link>
	<description>Magnesium left by passing comets seeds the clouds of Mars, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 21:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031218_LG_martian-cloud_main.jpg?itok=vAWFPdH6" length="14491" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain matters the Podcast: Hey Brain Matters, I am a Neuroscience undergrad at ASU who is starting a podcast with fellow undergrads to talk about everything psychology and neuroscience. We are trying to focus on topics that deal with heuristics and delivering neuroscience as thought provoking and accessible to all audiences. Dr. B B Braden referred me to your site and I have gotten addicted listening to your episodes. I would be grateful if you could share some advice on how to start our on podcast. Thanks so much, Milo.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://brainpodcast.com/post/171836150949</guid>
	<link>http://brainpodcast.com/post/171836150949</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hey Milo - Thanks for listening. I’d be happy to give you some advice on how we got started. Shoot me an email at anthony@brainpodcast.com and I can hopefully provide some help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;-Anthony&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 18:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainpodcast.com/rss">Brain Matters the Podcast</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Brain waves may focus attention and keep information flowing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-waves-may-focus-attention-and-keep-information-flowing</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-waves-may-focus-attention-and-keep-information-flowing</link>
	<description>Not just by-products of busy nerve cells, brain waves may be key to how the brain operates.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030618_LS_brain-wave_feat.jpg?itok=uUq96KJL" length="24916" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Dino-bird had wings made for flapping, not just gliding</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/archaeopteryx-had-wings-made-flapping-not-just-gliding</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/archaeopteryx-had-wings-made-flapping-not-just-gliding</link>
	<description>Archaeopteryx fossils suggest the dino-birds were capable of flapping their wings in flight.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 16:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031218_CG_archaeopteryx_main.jpg?itok=I5cxDPZX" length="31480" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Altmetrics reveal insights into the impact of scientific knowledge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/altmetrics-reveal-insights-into-the-impact-of-scientific-knowledge</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/altmetrics-reveal-insights-into-the-impact-of-scientific-knowledge</link>
	<description>Want a higher h-index? Maybe you should be spending more time on Twitter</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 15:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journals retract 30 papers by engineer in South Korea</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62875</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/13/journals-retract-30-papers-by-engineer-in-south-korea/</link>
	<description>An engineer in South Korea has lost 30 papers, at least seven of which for duplication and plagiarism. He has also been fired from his university position. Soon-Gi Shin, whose affiliation was listed as Kangwon National University in Gangwon, is the sole author on the majority of the papers, published in four journals between 2000 … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/13/journals-retract-30-papers-by-engineer-in-south-korea/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journals retract 30 papers by engineer in South Korea&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The retraction process needs work. Is there a better way?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62853</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/13/the-retraction-process-needs-work-is-there-a-better-way/</link>
	<description>Retractions take too long, carry too much of a stigma, and often provide too little information about what went wrong. Many people agree there’s a problem, but often can’t concur on how to address it. In one attempt, a group of experts — including our co-founder Ivan Oransky — convened at Stanford University in December … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/13/the-retraction-process-needs-work-is-there-a-better-way/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;The retraction process needs work. Is there a better way?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: The dramatic increase in the diagnosis of ADHD has not been accompanied by a rise in clinically significant symptoms</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33460</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/13/dramatic-increase-in-diagnosis-of-adhd-not-accompanied-by-rise-in-clinically-significant-symptoms/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-687790406.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33490&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33490&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mischievous teen boy with dirty hand smiling close up portrait&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1495639005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0015625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mischievous teen boy with dirty hand smile&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;mischievous teen boy with dirty hand smile&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-687790406.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-687790406.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-687790406.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2313,1296&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/13/dramatic-increase-in-diagnosis-of-adhd-not-accompanied-by-rise-in-clinically-significant-symptoms/mischievous-teen-boy-with-dirty-hand-smile-2/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-687790406.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the globe, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder-adhd/&quot;&gt;ADHD&lt;/a&gt; prevalence is estimated around 5 per cent. It’s a figure that’s been rising for decades. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24796725&quot;&gt;Sweden saw&lt;/a&gt; ADHD diagnoses among 10-year olds increase more than sevenfold from 1990 to 2007. Similar spikes have been reported from other countries, too, including Taiwan and the US, suggesting this may be a universal phenomenon. In fact, looking at dispensed ADHD medication as a proxy measure of ADHD prevalence, studies from the UK show an even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4932306/&quot;&gt;steeper&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27145886&quot;&gt;increase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this mean that more people today really have ADHD than in the past? Not necessarily. For example, greater awareness by clinicians, teachers or parents could have simply captured more patients who had previously had been “under the radar”. Such a shift in awareness or diagnostic behaviour would inflate the rate of ADHD diagnoses without necessarily more people having&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;clinical ADHD. However, if this is not the true or full explanation, then perhaps ADHD symptoms really have become more frequent or severe over the years. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12882/full&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;The Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt; from Sweden with almost 20,000 participants has now provided a preliminary answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33460&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers, led by Mina Rydell at Karolinska Institutet, examined data from participants in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ki.se/en/meb/the-child-and-adolescent-twin-study-in-sweden-catss&quot;&gt;ongoing study&lt;/a&gt; of all twins in Sweden that started in 2004 and aims to study their physical and mental health, with various measures taken the year that the children turn nine years of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the researchers analysed A-TAC (Autism-Tics, ADHD and other Comorbidities Inventory) scores from 19,271 children from 9,673 families recorded between 2004 and 2014. The A-TAC is a telephone-based interview in which parents are quizzed about their kids’ behaviour and mental health, including sub-scales focused on attention deficits and hyperactivity. The questions are about symptoms with no mention of diagnostic categories and the wording has stayed the same over the years. A typical question is “Does he/she have difficulties keeping his/her hands and feet still or can he/she not stay seated?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers used the A-TAC scores to classify the proportion of children in different years with diagnostic-level ADHD or subthreshold ADHD or no ADHD. Important to keep in mind here is that instruments like the A-TAC are restricted to assessing the severity of certain symptoms and cannot be used to diagnose children with ADHD (only clinicians and mental health experts can diagnose someone). For example, if a child fell in the diagnostic-level ADHD category, it would mean that the severity of his or her ADHD symptoms would likely result in a diagnosis by a specialist, but this couldn’t be known for sure. The authors calculated the changes in these categories, as well as in mean A-TAC scores, over time by comparing results from the parent interviews conducted in 1995-1998, 1992-2002 and 2003-2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the 10-year study period, 2.1 per cent of all participants (n=406) showed diagnostic-level ADHD and 10.7 per cent (n=2,058) showed subthreshold level ADHD. Interestingly, there was no statistically significant increase in diagnostic-level ADHD prevalence over time, fluctuating around 2 per cent in most years. On the other hand, the prevalence of sub-threshold ADHD increased significantly from 2004 to 2014, when at 14.76 per cent it reached its peak. Mean ADHD scores and inattention/ hyperactivity-impulsivity sub-scale scores also showed a similar increase from 1994 to 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These symptom changes over time are probably not due to changes during the study in the status of the twin families who agreed to take part in the research and those who didn’t. The researchers accessed the National Patient Register and this showed that while participants in the twin study differed from non-participants in terms of having fewer ADHD diagnoses, this difference did not change over the years of the study, suggesting that it was unlikely to explain the results. Perhaps most important, the National Patient Register showed that prevalence of clinician-diagnosed ADHD had increased more than fivefold from 2004 to 2014, which is inconsistent with the fact that the twin study found diagnostic-level ADHD prevalence did not see a similar rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while the diagnosis rates of clinical ADHD increased during the period of the study, the findings from the twin study suggest that only milder forms of ADHD-related symptoms became more frequent across the population during the same years. This suggests that the number of people who have such severe ADHD symptoms that it merits a diagnosis has actually remained stable, and that other factors are more probably the driving force behind an increased ADHD prevalence. While speculative, these could be related to changes in awareness among parents, teachers or clinicians; societal or medical norms; or better access to healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several caveats that need to be kept in mind when interpreting these findings. For example, as mentioned, A-TAC relies on parents’ reports, which might not be the most adequate source of information. In fact, a diagnosis of ADHD requires symptom impairments in at least two different contexts, such as at school or at home. Because only twins were enrolled in CATSS, it is also not clear whether these results also apply to only children. A similar argument could be made about the age of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping its limitations in mind, this study highlights an important point by providing an alternative explanation for rising ADHD diagnoses. This demonstrates the effects that shifts in societal, political or medical opinion can have on the “prevalence” of an illness. Considering that more diagnoses are likely to go hand in hand with more (potentially unnecessary) medication, this study provides food for thought to clinical and political decision-makers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12882/full&quot;&gt;Has the attention deficit hyperactivity disorder phenotype become more common in children between 2004 and 2014? Trends over 10 years from a Swedish general population sample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written for &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Helge studied psychology and clinical neurosciences. Since 2014, he is a PhD student in medical neurosciences at Charité University Hospital in Berlin, Germany, with a focus on understanding the role of the immune system in major depression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 09:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OIST Japan - CNU - Eric De Schutter: Cells and Synapse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.oist.jp/groups/32423 at https://www.oist.jp</guid>
	<link>https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/cells-and-synapse</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/cells-and-synapse&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/s3/files/styles/news_teaser_image__600x200_/public/photos/2018-03-12-schutter-banner.jpg?itok=8jGNSZkg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-multimedia-credit field-type-text field-label-inline clearfix&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Credit: &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;multimedia-credit&quot;&gt;OIST Computational Neuroscience Unit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/cells-and-synapse&quot;&gt;Cells and Synapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-date-created field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;13 Mar 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 08:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.oist.jp/taxonomy/term/424/feed">Computational Neuroscience Unit (Erik De Schutter)</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OIST Japan - CNU - Eric De Schutter: Model of LTP and LTD</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.oist.jp/groups/32422 at https://www.oist.jp</guid>
	<link>https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/model-ltp-and-ltd</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/model-ltp-and-ltd&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/s3/files/styles/news_teaser_image__600x200_/public/photos/2018-03-12-schutter-graphical-abstract.jpg?itok=Ck-rogSe&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-multimedia-credit field-type-text field-label-inline clearfix&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Credit: &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;multimedia-credit&quot;&gt;OIST Computational Neuroscience Unit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/model-ltp-and-ltd&quot;&gt;Model of LTP and LTD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-date-created field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;13 Mar 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.oist.jp/taxonomy/term/424/feed">Computational Neuroscience Unit (Erik De Schutter)</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OIST Japan - CNU - Eric De Schutter: Eric De Schutter and Andrew Gallimore</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.oist.jp/groups/32421 at https://www.oist.jp</guid>
	<link>https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/eric-de-schutter-and-andrew-gallimore</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/eric-de-schutter-and-andrew-gallimore&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/s3/files/styles/news_teaser_image__600x200_/public/photos/2018-03-12-schutter-andrew-erik.jpg?itok=M0ugXhbp&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-title-field field-type-text field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oist.jp/news-center/photos/eric-de-schutter-and-andrew-gallimore&quot;&gt;Eric De Schutter and Andrew Gallimore &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-date-created field-type-date field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;13 Mar 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 08:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.oist.jp/taxonomy/term/424/feed">Computational Neuroscience Unit (Erik De Schutter)</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Over the brainbow: The science of sleep: Part I</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9:573b8312c2ea515a3fd6e6bb:5a818d13c830253b86604668</guid>
	<link>http://overthebrainbow.com/blog/2018/2/12/the-science-of-sleep</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This post is gonna be about a passion of mine. Something I can indulge in anytime, anywhere, for any amount of time. Something I would choose over diamonds and Michelin restaurants. I now realise the punchline of this joke would have been better if the title hasn’t already disclosed that it’s gonna be around sleeping. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sleep, as mysterious as it is necessary, still puzzles scientists -- and they have been researching it for decades (and people have been sleeping for thousands of years). What exactly happens when we sleep? Why do we do it? Can we stop sleeping at all? What happens then? Got you curious enough? Then read on and find out how close we are to answering all of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;

  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot;giphy.gif&quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a818d998165f5c700d26d8a/1518550578196/giphy.gif&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;245x160&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a818d998165f5c700d26d8a&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a818d998165f5c700d26d8a/1518550578196/giphy.gif?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.
Some theoretical background: the what’s and when’s of snoozing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has heard about REM sleep: either because of its connection to dreams or because of how important it is or just because you liked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xwtdhWltSIg&quot;&gt;“Losing My Religion”&lt;/a&gt;. But there is more to sleep: it also contains three non-REM stages with different characteristics and functions (and differing probabilities you will be grumpy when woken up during this stage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stage 1 sleep (Non-REM1)&lt;/em&gt; is the drowsy sleep phase when you drift between waking and sleeping. Your muscles are not fully inhibited yet and you can experience the “I’m falling”-sensation, a sudden muscle contraction which is called “myoclonic jerk” (some scientists have assumed it might stem from brains of our primate ancestors making us confuse muscle relaxation with falling from a tree&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uccs.edu/Documents/fcoolidg/Before%20Farming%202006%20Dream%20paper.pdf&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). Moreover, there is a change in your brain waves, synchronised electrical pulses resulting from tons of neurons communicating with each other (see Fig. 1 for a visualisation of all the possible brain waves). In a waking state your brain produces a lot of brain waves called beta and gamma. Both are rather jerky and high-frequency and are either connected to concentration (beta) or theorized to play a role in creating consciousness (gamma). In this first sleep stage instead of beta and gamma your brain starts showing slower and more synchronized alpha waves (associated with relaxation and peacefulness) and even more slower theta waves (associated with deep relaxation and daydreaming) -- keyword: slowing down. This stage lasts between 1 and 10 minutes.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK19956/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleep.org/articles/what-happens-during-sleep/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot; Fig 1. A short intro into what brain waves happen in your head. &quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a818fb8e4966bd4a45c76cb/1518550578199/Brain+Waves+Graph.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;506x409&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a818fb8e4966bd4a45c76cb&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a818fb8e4966bd4a45c76cb/1518550578199/Brain+Waves+Graph.jpg?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          
          
            &lt;p&gt;Fig 1. A short intro into what brain waves happen in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stage 2 sleep (Non-REM2):&lt;/em&gt; Here, your consciousness has drifted away. Heart rate and breathing slow down, temperature decreases, you prepare to enter the deep sleep and theta waves are still very prominent. This stage together with the previous one comprise what is known as “light sleep”. We spend most of our (around 45% of the night) snoozing time in this stage. Light sleep is the best phase to wake up in as you won’t feel groggy or disoriented but rather refreshed and ready to take on the day.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK19956/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleep.org/articles/what-happens-during-sleep/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stages 3+4 sleep (Non-REM 3 &amp;amp; 4):&lt;/em&gt; This is when things get serious: the deep sleep stage. It is also called slow-wave-sleep because -- you guessed it -- the brain waves slow down and become larger. Now delta waves, the slowest one your brain can produce, rule the party. You are unresponsive to any outside sounds, hard to wake up and your muscles are completely relaxed. This sleep stage is called restorative as your tissue gets repaired, energy gets restored, your kidneys clean your blood, you get the picture.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK19956/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sleep.org/articles/what-happens-during-sleep/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Waking up during a deep sleep phase leads to this state (a scientifically proven fact, no citation needed).&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot;giphy (2).gif&quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a83400cc83025ee6a17d9aa/1518551177749/giphy+%282%29.gif&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;500x311&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a83400cc83025ee6a17d9aa&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a83400cc83025ee6a17d9aa/1518551177749/giphy+%282%29.gif?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;REM sleep + sleep paralysis&lt;/em&gt;: The arguably most intriguing feature of sleep -- dreams -- mostly happen during this stage, being vivid and elaborate. The defining feature is the random and rapid side-to-side eye movements. The purpose of these movements is not completely clarified yet (what in neuroscience is, after all?), but theories include scanning of the scenes we see in our dreams&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/133/6/1737/356388&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/23295226_Human_Brain_Activity_Time-Locked_to_Rapid_Eye_Movements_during_REM_Sleep&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20478849&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and memory formation&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10771409&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/cercor/article/25/6/1565/300470&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/352/6287/812&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; (we’re gonna talk more about the sleep functions later). Your blood pressure and breathing rate rise to almost the waking level and your brain waves resemble waking state too -- there are even high-concentration beta-waves present!&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK19956/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Due to all this weird stuff REM sleep has earned the title of “Paradoxical Sleep”. A bit scary but worth knowing is that your muscles become completely paralyzed during this stage -- neurotransmitters called GABA and glycine prevent your muscles from receiving brain signals and protect you from acting out on your dreams and potentially hurting yourself&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22815493&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. So basically we’re just laying there completely paralysed while our eyes uncontrollably dart from side to side. Lovely. Scientists believe that when the transition from and to REM sleep doesn’t go smoothly it may lead to sleep paralysis -- a frightening state when you’re already aware but still can’t move your body&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16120108/&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. In this limbo between wakefulness and vivid dreams people often report seeing scary stuff which can be mostly categorized as either an incubus (you experience chest pressure and problems breathing which you might perceive to be caused by a demonic entity sitting on your chest), an intruder (you sense an unwanted presence of some fearful creature) or an out-of-body experiences&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10487786&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. This might explain a lot of reports of seeing paranormal activity&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/30035099?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; or being abducted by aliens&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/13546800244000058?journalCode=pcnp20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; (sorry, Agent Mulder!). Approximately 7,6% of the general population suffers from sleep paralysis, while the rate increases drastically for students, 28% of whom have reported experiencing it.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21571556&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During an average night, you would go through several complete sleep cycles (one cycle lasting ca. 90 minutes) with REM stages getting longer towards morning.&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot; A short overview of what is going on during the night. As you can see, slow wave sleep dominates the beginning of the night while REM sleep becomes more prominent in the second half of the sleeping period. &quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a83449d08522934089bfdc5/1518552232485/93c0b843-ba78-4721-bf67-c1eed9ec0a6e_zps826d43c3.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;669x392&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a83449d08522934089bfdc5&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a83449d08522934089bfdc5/1518552232485/93c0b843-ba78-4721-bf67-c1eed9ec0a6e_zps826d43c3.jpg?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          
          
            &lt;p&gt;A short overview of what is going on during the night. As you can see, slow wave sleep dominates the beginning of the night while REM sleep becomes more prominent in the second half of the sleeping period.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.
How does your brain fall asleep?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to pinpoint the exact moment of falling asleep. One moment you are still going through all the dumb stuff you did five years ago and another moment you’re already drifting away towards the second sleep stage. So what happens in your brain when you fall asleep?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a tiny thing deep in your brain called suprachiasmatic nucleus (SCN) which is the mastermind behind our 24-hour sleep-wake cycle. Directly from your eyes it receives information about how much light exposure you’re getting. It uses this information to reset your internal clock to correspond to the normal day-night cycle. In turn, the internal clock accordingly regulates multiple bodily functions, such as temperature, hormone release and, interestingly for us, sleep and wakefulness&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3026325/&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. Interestingly, even in a complete absence of light, our internal clock still functions in a roughly 24-hour rhythmus.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10381883&quot;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC61161/&quot;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; It has been found that it is due to a cyclical activity of certain genes (fittingly called “clock genes”)&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/9989497&quot;&gt;19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. These genes produce different levels of various &quot;clock proteins&quot; depending on the time of the day -- and these proteins then regulate your daily rhytmus (such as what your body tempreture is, how much melatonin is secreted, how alert you are etc etc).&lt;br /&gt;SCN is intricately connected to the -- prepare for another long name -- ventrolateral preoptic nucleus (VLPO)&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2701283/&quot;&gt;20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; -- a structure which is active during sleep&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature04284&quot;&gt;21&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. These connections are thought to activate VLPO and thus to promote the onset of sleep -- ‘cause when VLPO neurons are activated, they release inhibitory chemicals (called GABA and galanin) which, in turn, suppress our arousal system. So through a long chain of command a switch is turned and your arousal slowly goes to zero. 
VLPO neurons can also be activated by a chemical called adenosine. Adenosine builds up during the day after glycogen, the body’s principal store of energy, breaks down, and after enough of it has accumulated it starts to promote tiredness and nudge you towards a more restful state.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2948963/&quot;&gt;22&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17468046&quot;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; This is called a homeostatic regulation as the brain strives to balance out the tiredness that builds up with some rest.&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot; A short overview of the chain of command. From https://www.medscape.org/viewarticle/703161_2 &quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b1a3b9140b7effc32a0fc/1519065667064/703161-fig1.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;761x268&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a8b1a3b9140b7effc32a0fc&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b1a3b9140b7effc32a0fc/1519065667064/703161-fig1.jpg?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          
          
            &lt;p&gt;A short overview of the chain of command. From https://www.medscape.org/viewarticle/703161_2&lt;/p&gt;
          
          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;Another sleep related chemical is the one you will see as a supplement in a supermarket: melatonin. It is produced by the pineal gland and its production, as so many other things, is regulated by our circadian clock. When the sun goes down, SCN commands the pineal gland to start producing melatonin (whose levels are barely detectable during the day) which is then released into your bloodstream and induces sleep. Recently, scientists have been warning us against using smartphones, TVs and other kinds of light-emitting devices before bad as it is supposed to mess with our melatonin levels. The light from our electronic devices has a much higher concentration of blue light than the natural light does, and this treacherous blue light suppresses the melatonin production more than any other wavelength&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3047226/&quot;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/112/4/1232&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. This throws off the sleep-wake cycle and can lead to a poorer quantity and quality of sleep as the brain is confused about what time of the day it is right now. So do yourself a favor and read a book before sleep instead. Or do some mindfulness meditation. Or have sex. Anything without a blue light.&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot; Suppressed melatonin production due to the bright light exposure vs. high melatonin production when wearing goggles blocking out blue light (and obviously high melatonin production when only being subjected to the dim light).&amp;amp;nbsp; From https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/90/5/2755/2836826 &quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b1ef024a694d707160c90/1519066890558/kayumov-et-al-2005-light-and-melatonin.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;570x332&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a8b1ef024a694d707160c90&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b1ef024a694d707160c90/1519066890558/kayumov-et-al-2005-light-and-melatonin.jpg?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          
          
            &lt;p&gt;Suppressed melatonin production due to the bright light exposure vs. high melatonin production when wearing goggles blocking out blue light (and obviously high melatonin production when only being subjected to the dim light).  From https://academic.oup.com/jcem/article/90/5/2755/2836826&lt;/p&gt;
          
          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. 
Why do we sleep? Why is sleep important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a really good question. And unfortunately there is no definite answer. As William Dement, the founder of Stanford Sleep Research Center said, &quot;As far as I know, the only reason we need to sleep that is really, really solid is because we get sleepy.&quot;
So… Let’s see what we already know (besides this grain of wisdom).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Memory
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The romance between sleep and memory consolidation (that is, its stabilization) has long been suspected and numerous studies in the last decades, if not even centuries, have solidified it (but none have set the record completely straight).
There is a distinction between two memory types: declarative (fact-based information, “what”-memories) and procedural (“how”-memories, like a muscle memory of how to drive a bike or play a new song on a guitar). It would be very convenient to have a clear distinction like “slow wave sleep is responsible for this and REM is responsible for that”, but unfortunately the reality is a less clear-cut mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, sleep helps memory: people who sleep after learning something tend to remember this newly learnt stuff better than their counterparts who stayed awake after the learning session.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20046194&quot;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Learning word lists&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/1995-16226-001&quot;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18275549&quot;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;, complex finger moving skills&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(02)00746-8?_returnURL=http%3A%2F%2Flinkinghub.elsevier.com%2Fretrieve%2Fpii%2FS0896627302007468%3Fshowall%3Dtrue&quot;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12193650&quot;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; or even gaining insight into complex hidden rules&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/14737168&quot;&gt;31&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;: all that benefited from a sleeping session following the learning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow wave sleep (SWS), dominating the first part of the night, was theorized to help specifically with the consolidation of declarative memories&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/4326302&quot;&gt;32&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23968216&quot;&gt;33&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22732649&quot;&gt;34&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. The process behind the stabilisation of newly acquired memories is believed to be their reactivation in hippocampus, our memory center, during sleep. By “replaying” the memories their traces would become more stable and less likely to perish away&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/np/2011/203462/&quot;&gt;35&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960982213009299&quot;&gt;36&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. One study found that if you learned something while smelling rose odour and then were exposed to the same smell during your SWS sleep, then your hippocampal activity increased and your memories next day were stronger&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17347444&quot;&gt;37&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. So, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stronger hippocampal reactivation during SWS. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better memories. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;??? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profit!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot;reece.JPG&quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b24318165f58a19cea74b/1519068212185/reece.JPG&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;504x415&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a8b24318165f58a19cea74b&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8b24318165f58a19cea74b/1519068212185/reece.JPG?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;REM sleep, on the other hand, was associated with procedural memory whose consolidation does not depend on hippocampus (but rather on rehearsing the movement commands in parts of the brain concerned with muscle control, such as cerebellum, basal ganglia and motor cortex).&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23968216&quot;&gt;38&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10442025&quot;&gt;39&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0896627304005409&quot;&gt;40&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;
Not that much is known about the exact consolidation mechanisms of this kind of memory so we’re gonna keep this paragraph short. However, there are studies speaking against such a clear cut distinction (or if you wanna be scientific, against “dual-process hypothesis”). For instance, it was shown that SWS sleep can also help to consolidate memories for movements (=procedural)&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18337406&quot;&gt;41&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15184907&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;
, whereas REM sleep had some part in stabilizing memories about events and facts&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17400305&quot;&gt;43&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://watermark.silverchair.com/sleep-27-3-395.pdf?token=AQECAHi208BE49Ooan9kkhW_Ercy7Dm3ZL_9Cf3qfKAc485ysgAAAbAwggGsBgkqhkiG9w0BBwagggGdMIIBmQIBADCCAZIGCSqGSIb3DQEHATAeBglghkgBZQMEAS4wEQQM6am08nmTk8yny9UAAgEQgIIBY3v5phvWY_KoId23Zl55sNPz7Rh-6AN5PLnPhZcjJ7SsmymfridIkyD9xZPH2Yw0jxn2ELwrOPfNt7VU_8DqjsB7bquCWG05YiNHjElCbOANbJ4eFDYix-KRCtuNZM_tAKma7QUxmZza4q_EomFHRa0hdcbzU0k2Oem9aAPMnhvxBEf5dVlJSmpX5i043nbwSKXeOo62eh73ZPiXVEsbnsVDa_sDVQF59lkkeQIrgBuTDjoUTmC1-FhTQI5MSq06AS9Du3rqgPnTc3UEd-yIKSuF5sV2T7-k1eCLPu0k6gizuj4H7LqRRHRUieG9e5656yYrSyRpp_Z-CC5RqZl1zkmDTsEHEO92KQS2sP-85FNuk8_xweTyMdWQDgWi6e6INIQVgxHmzr_5g0AwhcBw98S7WwtUVQoZfoKO7Z7gCfqqIRGFlE6u02a62ziTDYKSgqchrchG4NOUHkA9Ob2JMqoCxfI&quot;&gt;44&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;
. A not so clear separation of responsibilities after all, it seems. This rather indicates that both stages are important for both types of memory (this theory is called “sequential hypothesis”, again, if you wanna be scientific): they complement each other rather than compete. It just so happens that one stage (SWS) might contribute more to one type of memory (declarative) and vice versa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course this is not the end of the story. There is -- surprise -- another theory trying to describe how memories are consolidated (oh boy, was it fun to learn for the exam on memory). It is called “synaptic homeostasis” and it basically says that when you’re awake and you acquire all the new memories and experiences, the connections between your brain cells (=synapses) get stronger (and even new ones are created) and that when you sleep the brain tries to downscale all this huge daytime increase to a reasonable level by removing the unnecessary synapses.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18204445&quot;&gt;45&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;
So you could almost say you sleep to forget….in order to lift signal over noise and to start a new day refreshed and ready to learn again. Unnecessary connections and random memories get removed, while the important ones get stronger by being replayed. A recent study has provided a direct visual proof for this hypothesis: using extremely high-resolution microscopy the researchers first identified size and shape of 6920 synapses and then have shown that after a few hours of sleep 80% of the synapses shrank by ca. 18%.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28154076&quot;&gt;46&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


  

  	
      
      
        
          
            
              &lt;img alt=&quot; &amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;Large synapses in an awake mouse vs. shrunken synapses of a mouse who indulged in some sleep (Image Credit: med.wisc.edu) &quot; class=&quot;thumb-image&quot; data-image=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8d6388652deac0dff25afd/1519215510830/mice-synapse.jpg&quot; data-image-dimensions=&quot;850x679&quot; data-image-focal-point=&quot;0.5,0.5&quot; data-image-id=&quot;5a8d6388652deac0dff25afd&quot; data-load=&quot;false&quot; data-type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/573b647d2fe131f40453f2f9/t/5a8d6388652deac0dff25afd/1519215510830/mice-synapse.jpg?format=1000w&quot; /&gt;
            
          

          
          
            &lt;p&gt;   Large synapses in an awake mouse vs. shrunken synapses of a mouse who indulged in some sleep (Image Credit: med.wisc.edu)&lt;/p&gt;
          
          

        
      
      
    

  


&lt;p&gt;Of course there is no one correct answer -- the truth is somewhere in the middle, all these theories explaining some part of what is really going on. But now you know that you should think twice before pulling an all-nighter before an exam -- stressing out with Red Bull won’t make you remember stuff better, but some hours of restful ZZZ’s just might. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another theoreticized function of sleep is doing a little housekeeping. While you are sleeping the brain puts on the janitor robe and takes off to clear out all the junk that has accumulated there during all your daytime thinking. In a series of mice studies, researchers have discovered a system that drains waste products from the brain during sleep.&lt;sup data-preserve-html-node=&quot;true&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/342/6156/373&quot;&gt;47&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; A brain equivalent of lymphatic system, a network of tiny channels flushing out waste by-products with cerebrospinal fluid, is responsible for that. Scientists called it a “glymphatic system” because, well, it functions like a lymphatic system but with the help of supportive brain cells: glial cells. See what they did there? When mice were asleep, the system went into overdrive (the awake flow was just 5% of the sleep flow!) and the brain cells even shrank in size to make the spaces around them easier to clean. The by-products that get flushed out include beta-amyloid protein, the criminal mind behind Alzheimer’s disease (it gets cleared out twice as fast during sleep as compared to wakefulness!), and other things associated with neurodegenerative disorders. So if you wanna to pull an all-nighter think about all these toxins that accumulate in your brain and hit the hay for a couple of hours instead. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So while it is still not completely clear why we spend a third of our lives sleeping we seem to have pretty good pointers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for part II which will include fascinating infos on dreams, what can go wrong with our sleep and some advice on optimal sleeping practice!&lt;/p&gt;



  &lt;form autocomplete=&quot;on&quot; class=&quot;newsletter-form&quot; data-form-id=&quot;5aa6cc950852298bbb3449ee&quot; method=&quot;POST&quot;&gt;

    &lt;header class=&quot;newsletter-form-header&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;newsletter-form-header-title&quot;&gt;Subscribe to get fresh neuroscience news!&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sign up and never miss hot neuroscience stuff!&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/header&gt;

    

      

        

        

          
            
              &lt;label class=&quot;newsletter-form-field-label title&quot; for=&quot;email-yui_3_17_2_1_1520878559422_35914-field&quot;&gt;Email Address&lt;/label&gt;
              &lt;input class=&quot;newsletter-form-field-element field-element&quot; id=&quot;email-yui_3_17_2_1_1520878559422_35914-field&quot; name=&quot;email&quot; type=&quot;text&quot; /&gt;
            
          

        

          

        

      

      
        &lt;button class=&quot;newsletter-form-button sqs-system-button sqs-editable-button-layout sqs-editable-button-style sqs-editable-button-shape&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Sign Up&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-form-spinner sqs-spin light large&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-form-button-label&quot;&gt;Sign Up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newsletter-form-button-icon&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
      

    

    
      
    

    Thank you!
    

  &lt;/form&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 18:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://overthebrainbow.com/?format=rss">Stuff about brains</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: We probably won’t hear from aliens. But by the time we do, they’ll be dead.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/drake-equation-alien-extraterrestrial-civilizations</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/drake-equation-alien-extraterrestrial-civilizations</link>
	<description>Astronomers build on the Drake Equation to probe the chance that humans will find existing aliens. The answer: Not likely.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030918_drake_equation_main.gif?itok=yHS_-foT" length="131188" type="image/gif"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Misconduct investigation reports are uneven at best. Here’s how to make them better.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62800</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/12/misconduct-investigation-reports-are-uneven-at-best-heres-how-to-make-them-better/</link>
	<description>Retraction Watch readers may have noticed that over the past year or so, we have been making an effort to obtain and publish reports about institutional investigations into misconduct. That’s led to posts such as one about a case at the University of Colorado, Denver, one about the case of Frank Sauer, formerly of the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/12/misconduct-investigation-reports-are-uneven-at-best-heres-how-to-make-them-better/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Misconduct investigation reports are uneven at best. Here’s how to make them better.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Ethics, authorship concerns sink homeopathy paper by researchers arrested last year</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62757</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/12/ethics-authorship-concerns-sink-homeopathy-paper-by-researchers-arrested-last-year/</link>
	<description>For a host of reasons, a journal has retracted a paper co-authored by a researcher who reportedly once faced charges of practicing medicine without proper qualifications. According to the retraction notice for “Psorinum Therapy in Treating Stomach, Gall Bladder, Pancreatic, and Liver Cancers: A Prospective Clinical Study,” published Dec. 8, 2010 in Evidence-Based Complementary and … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/12/ethics-authorship-concerns-sink-homeopathy-paper-by-researchers-arrested-last-year/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Ethics, authorship concerns sink homeopathy paper by researchers arrested last year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How biology breaks the ‘cerebral mystique’</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/the-biological-mind-alan-jasanoff</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/the-biological-mind-alan-jasanoff</link>
	<description>The Biological Mind rejects the idea of the brain as the lone organ that makes us who we are. Our body and environment also factor in, Alan Jasanoff says.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031718_reviews_biological-mind_main.jpg?itok=vLEi3vGX" length="27624" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Children with higher working memory are more inclined to finger count (and less able kids should be encouraged to do the same)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33432</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/12/children-with-higher-working-memory-are-more-inclined-to-finger-count-and-less-able-kids-should-be-encouraged-to-do-the-same/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-833912150.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33449&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33449&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young expressive redhead girl doing school homework at the end of the day. Horizontal waist up indoors shot with copy space. This is part of a \u00ab\u00a0Day in the life of a child\u00a0\u00bb serie and was taken in Montreal, Canada.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1501859401&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young expressive redhead girl doing school homework at home.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Young expressive redhead girl doing school homework at home.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-833912150.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-833912150.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-833912150.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/12/children-with-higher-working-memory-are-more-inclined-to-finger-count-and-less-able-kids-should-be-encouraged-to-do-the-same/young-expressive-redhead-girl-doing-school-homework-at-home/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-833912150.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finger counting by young kids has traditionally been frowned upon because it’s seen as babyish and a deterrent to using mental calculations. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20445911.2017.1396990&quot;&gt;a new Swiss study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognitive Psychology&lt;/em&gt; has found that six-year-olds who finger counted performed better at simple addition, especially if they used an efficient finger counting strategy. What’s more, it was the children with &lt;em&gt;higher&lt;/em&gt; working memory ability – who you would expect to have less need for using their fingers – who were more inclined to finger count, and to do so in an efficient way. “Our study advocates for the promotion of finger use in arithmetic tasks during the first years of schooling,” said the researchers Justine Dupont-Boime and Catherine Thevenot at the Universities of Geneva and Lausanne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33432&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The 84 child volunteers were recruited from six different Swiss schools where the policy is not to teach finger counting explicitly, but not to discourage it either (except for very simple additions where the sum is less than 10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers tested the children’s working memory using the backward digit span task, which involves hearing a string of numbers and repeating them back in reverse order. Children with higher working memory can accurately repeat back longer strings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also videoed the children discreetly while they performed, one child at a time, simple single-digit additions, some a bit trickier than others because they involved sums larger than 10 (some kids did the addition task before the memory tests, others afterwards). The researchers later coded the videos to see which kids counted on their fingers during the addition task, and which strategy they used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifty-two of the children finger counted, and there was a significant correlation between finger counting and better performance (for the easier and harder sums), and also between finger counting and higher working memory ability. The researchers think kids with poorer working memory struggle to discover finger counting for themselves, even though it would be advantageous if they used the right strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A problem for those kids with lower working memory ability who did finger count is that they tended to use a more laborious strategy that involves counting out both addends (i.e. numbers to be added) on their fingers, whereas the children with higher working memory ability favoured an efficient strategy that only involved using the fingers to count on from the first addend – for example, for 8+3, the child would only use three fingers to count on from eight. When the kids with lower working memory used the laborious finger strategy, they actually performed worse than if they used no fingers, especially for the harder sums. However, if they used the superior strategy, they did better at addition than those who didn’t use their fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Explicitly teaching lower achievers to use the [more efficient finger counting] strategy could be very beneficial for them,” the researchers said, adding that “… repeatedly using fingers to solve arithmetic problems should allow children to progressively abandon this strategy for more mental procedures and, thus, allow children to become more and more performant through practice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new findings build upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1467-7687.2008.00715.x/full&quot;&gt;a previous study&lt;/a&gt; that tested five-year-olds’ addition skills repeatedly over a three-year period and which found that finger counting correlated with superior performance up to, but not beyond, age 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20445911.2017.1396990&quot;&gt;High working memory capacity favours the use of finger counting in six-year-old children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/a&gt;) is Editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 09:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Depression among new mothers is finally getting some attention</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/postpartum-depression-scientific-research-mothers</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/postpartum-depression-scientific-research-mothers</link>
	<description>Scientists search new mothers’ minds for clues to postpartum depression.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 09:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031718_PPD_feat.jpg?itok=A21RE0H6" length="20401" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: A new plagiarism euphemism; how Photoshop abuse destroys science; bias against women authors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62765</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/10/weekend-reads-a-new-plagiarism-euphemism-how-photoshop-abuse-destroys-science-bias-against-women-authors/</link>
	<description>The week at Retraction Watch featured a look at what happens to authors when a journal is delisted, a reminder of how hard it is to figure out whether a paper has been retracted, and a survey on how common plagiarism is in economics. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: That wasn’t plagiarism, it was “unprofessional … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/10/weekend-reads-a-new-plagiarism-euphemism-how-photoshop-abuse-destroys-science-bias-against-women-authors/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A new plagiarism euphemism; how Photoshop abuse destroys science; bias against women authors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 15:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Superconductors may shed light on the black hole information paradox</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/superconductors-black-hole-paradox</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/superconductors-black-hole-paradox</link>
	<description>Materials that conduct electricity without resistance might mimic black hole physics.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 21:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030918_EC_superconducting_black-holes_main.jpg?itok=kj9K06nA" length="23129" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What we do and don’t know about how to prevent gun violence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/evidence-preventing-gun-violence-deaths-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/evidence-preventing-gun-violence-deaths-research</link>
	<description>Background checks work to prevent gun violence; concealed carry and stand-your-ground laws don’t. But lack of data makes it hard to make other links.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 20:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030718_RE_gun-violence_feat.jpg?itok=rjQC3UJg" length="14993" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: What Does Any Part of the Brain Do?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9395</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9395</link>
	<description>How can we know the function of a region of the brain? Have we been approaching the problem in the wrong way? An interesting new paper from German neuroscientists Sarah Genon and colleagues explores these questions.





According to Genon et al., neuroscientists have generally approached the brain from the standpoint of behavior. We ask: what is the neural basis of this behavioral or psychological function?
Traditionally, assigning functions to brain regions has mainly been based on conc</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 20:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Museum mummies sport world’s oldest tattoo drawings</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/museum-mummies-sport-worlds-oldest-tattoo-drawings</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/museum-mummies-sport-worlds-oldest-tattoo-drawings</link>
	<description>A wild bull and symbolic designs were imprinted on the bodies of two Egyptians at least 5,000 years ago.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 17:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030818_BB_tattoos_feat.jpg?itok=Snuv3bgZ" length="26620" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Child took wrong compound for over a year after “communication error”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62749</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/09/child-took-wrong-compound-for-over-a-year-after-communication-error/</link>
	<description>A journal is retracting a paper after it discovered researchers gave a child the wrong supplement for more than a year. Rhiannon Bugno, managing editor for Biological Psychiatry, told Retraction Watch the mix-up did not put the patient at risk. However, the mistake was enough for the journal’s editor, John Krystal, of Yale University, to … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/09/child-took-wrong-compound-for-over-a-year-after-communication-error/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Child took wrong compound for over a year after “communication error”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Discussing what matters when facts are not enough</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/discussing-what-matters-when-facts-are-not-enough</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/discussing-what-matters-when-facts-are-not-enough</link>
	<description>Editor in Chief Nancy Shute reflects on finding common ground with science and policy.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 15:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers muse about memory, magnetic monopoles and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-muse-about-memory-magnetic-monopoles-and-more</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-muse-about-memory-magnetic-monopoles-and-more</link>
	<description>Readers had questions about the physical trace of memory, magnetic monopoles, blowflies and more.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 15:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Bioethics article retracted for…ethics violation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62727</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/09/caught-our-notice-bioethics-article-retracted-for-ethics-violation/</link>
	<description>Title: Bioethics and Medical Education What Caught Our Attention: As we’ve said before, you can’t make this stuff up: An article on bioethics had its own ethical issues to deal with. It turns out, the authors had “substantial unreferenced overlap” with another article, that “overlap” including the article’s title. Here’s a side by side comparison … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/09/caught-our-notice-bioethics-article-retracted-for-ethics-violation/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Bioethics article retracted for…ethics violation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Psychologists have explored why we sometimes like listening to the same song on repeat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33446</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/09/psychologists-have-explored-why-we-sometimes-like-listening-to-the-same-song-on-repeat/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33447&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-667678356.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33447&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33447&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Candid shot in light nature.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1487851068&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;160&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Happy asian youth teenage using and listening music on cellphone with retro car.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Happy asian youth teenage using and listening music on cellphone with retro car.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-667678356.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-667678356.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-667678356.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/09/psychologists-have-explored-why-we-sometimes-like-listening-to-the-same-song-on-repeat/happy-asian-youth-teenage-using-and-listening-music-on-cellphone-with-retro-car/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-667678356.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Bittersweet songs were listened to more often than happy or relaxing songs, and provoked a deeper connection&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s that song. Again. The one they play over, and over, and over. It might be your roommate, child, or colleague. The year I shared a flat with my brother, it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1lCVmu3xN8&quot;&gt;Worst Comes To Worst&lt;/a&gt; thrice daily. What are the properties of the songs that drive some people to repeatedly listen to them over and over? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0305735617751050&quot;&gt;new article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Psychology of Music&lt;/i&gt; explores the tunes that just won’t quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33446&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Autumn of 2013, the research team led by Frederick Conrad of the University of Michigan asked 204 men and women, mostly in their 30s or younger, what song they were “listening to most often these days”. Participants mentioned mostly pop and rock songs, but also rap, country, jazz and reggae, with only 11 songs picked by more than one listener (the most frequently mentioned were &lt;i&gt;Get Lucky&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Royals&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Blurred Lines&lt;/i&gt;, all of which were hits in the year of the survey).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighty-six per cent of participants listened to their song at least once a week, and almost half did so daily. Sixty per cent said that they liked to re-listen to this song immediately, with many enjoying a third or even fourth go. Participants reported having high levels of connection with their named song, with higher connection associated with a tendency to close their eyes during listening to devote the fullest attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompted to describe their chosen song’s effect in their own words, the participants’ descriptions suggested the songs fell into three categories. Over two-thirds were happy, energetic songs – “Pumped up! Excited! Ready to dance, sing, and love!”. For these songs, beat and rhythm were important, and almost half of people who were stuck on a happy song also reported tapping their feet, clapping their hands or drumming on the furniture during listens. This is definitely the vibe that was driving my brother’s daily house party!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other categories were calm and relaxed (“It makes me feel at ease, calm, and helps me to put things into perspective”) and bittersweet (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/07/15/why-do-people-like-listening-to-sad-music-when-theyre-feeling-down/&quot;&gt;It makes me feel sad. But not the bad kind of sad, and I like singing with it&lt;/a&gt;”). Bittersweet songs were the most likely to produce deep connections, and were also associated with a greater ability to build a “mental model” of the song, as measured by how much of the song participants felt they could replay in their head. (This ability increased with frequency of all song listens, but more so for bittersweet ones.) Bittersweet songs were listened to many more times than the other song types – on average 790 times, vs. 515 for calm songs and 175 for happy songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeated listening to songs is a bit of a riddle, given previous research that tends to bear out the classic Wundt curve, which states that a pleasurable stimulus becomes more pleasurable with familiarity until reaching a ceiling and dropping off, as happens with songs on heavy radio rotation. But our listeners weren’t being assailed with the songs against their will (only six per cent of the songs were even on the radio during that time), they were deliberately seeking out and returning to them. For some idiosyncratic reason, a particular song speaks to this particular person, and that connection provides an incentive to listen deeply to the song, which can unlock further nuance in lyrical meaning or musical richness. And the emotional payoff is reliable, much as is a mood-regulating drug, and that reliable payoff can be more important than the hit of something novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not review your top listens on Spotify, iTunes or Winamp – this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/nils_frahm/said-and-done?in=nils_frahm/sets/spaces-8&quot;&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt; – and have a think about what they are giving you: a dose of energy to tackle the day, a tonic of restoring calm, or a companion to join you in walking through contradictory, complex feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0305735617751050&quot;&gt;Extreme re-listening: Songs people love . . . and continue to love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 09:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Pet ownership as a social determinant of health</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9982</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/09/pet-ownership-social-determinant-health/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/pet-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-018-5188-0&quot;&gt;study published today in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Megan Kiely Mueller (Tufts University Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine) and colleagues used data from the Health and Retirement Study (HRS), an ongoing biennial longitudinal cohort study of approximately 20,000 Americans aged 50 and older, to examine the relationship between multiple health outcomes and pet ownership. Their sample included 1,657 of the participants of the HRS. To assess the characteristics of pet ownership, participants were asked to report whether they currently owned a pet, types of pets (dog, cat, small mammal, bird, fish, reptile, or other), number of each type of pet, and number of years they have had pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants were also asked about their attachment to pets using the Pet Attachment Questionnaire which included the following items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do you consider your pet a friend?”, “Do you talk to your pet?”, “Would you say that owning a pet adds to your happiness?”, “Do you talk to others about your pet?”, “Do you often play with your pet?” and “Does your pet know how you feel about things?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall health was also measured, using a five point self-report rating from 1 = Excellent and 5 = Poor. In addition, participants were asked if they had ever experienced depression (yes/no) and if they had experienced depression within the last week (yes/no). Finally, frequency of mild, moderate, and vigorous physical activity was also measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs and cats were the most frequently reported pets owned and pet owners were more likely to own their own homes compared to non-pet owners in the sample studied. The authors also found that pet ownership was more common in older adulthood. Furthermore, over 80% of all pet owners reported that they considered their pet a friend, talked to their pet regularly, felt their pet added to their happiness, talked to others about their pet and played with their pet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9985&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9985 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/petman-300x225.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although more than 60% of dog owners regularly walked their dogs, which may be indicative of maintaining a physically active, healthy lifestyle, there was no significant difference between pet owners and non-owners on overall health status. However, pet ownership was a significant predictor of the likelihood of ever having experienced depression. This could indicate a relationship between pet ownership and depression, but, due to the cross-sectional nature of the study, it is impossible to determine the directionality of that relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the question arises: Do people become depressed because they have opted to include pets in their lives or do people who are depressed opt to acquire a pet as a way of treating their depression?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that the study found that current depression (in the last week) was not associated with pet ownership status, suggesting that the companionship of the pet may alleviate depressive symptoms or that the loss of a previous pet and subsequent loss of companionship may exacerbate depressive symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors conclude their study by pointing out that, although pet ownership may increase the potential for social interaction and support, more research is needed to explore potential health benefits and challenges unique to older adults. Furthermore, intervention and longitudinal studies that identify strategies for optimizing mutually-beneficial human-animal relationships across the life-course are also required to fully understand the implications of pet ownership on health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/09/pet-ownership-social-determinant-health/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pet ownership as a social determinant of health&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 09:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/pet-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The debate over how long our brains keep making new nerve cells heats up</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neurogenesis-neurons-brain-nerve-cells</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neurogenesis-neurons-brain-nerve-cells</link>
	<description>Adult humans don’t have newborn nerve cells in a memory-related part of the brain, a controversial paper suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 22:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030818_LS_neurogenesis_feat.jpg?itok=gWuuHYIs" length="42339" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Give double-layer graphene a twist and it superconducts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/give-double-layer-graphene-twist-and-it-superconducts</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/give-double-layer-graphene-twist-and-it-superconducts</link>
	<description>When graphene layers are twisted to a “magic angle,” the material superconducts.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 21:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030818_EC_superconductive-graphene_main.jpg?itok=kQ4BJIUm" length="50869" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Newer drugs make hepatitis C-positive kidneys safe for transplant</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newer-drugs-make-hepatitis-c-positive-kidneys-safe-transplant</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/newer-drugs-make-hepatitis-c-positive-kidneys-safe-transplant</link>
	<description>People without hepatitis C did not contract the disease after receiving successful transplants of infected kidneys along with newer antiviral drugs.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030718_AC_kidney-transplant_feat.jpg?itok=RXHY6sck" length="34289" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Oops: Elsevier journal retracts the wrong paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62653</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/08/oops-elsevier-journal-retracts-the-wrong-paper/</link>
	<description>When Saidur Rahman learned last month that his 2010 review paper about nanoparticles in refrigeration systems had been retracted, he was concerned—no one at the journal had told him it was going to be pulled. Rahman, a professor of engineering at Sunway University in Selangor, Malaysia, had recently corrected his 2010 review in Renewable and … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/08/oops-elsevier-journal-retracts-the-wrong-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Oops: Elsevier journal retracts the wrong paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 20:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Diamonds reveal sign of the deepest water known inside Earth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/diamonds-reveal-sign-deepest-water-known-inside-earth</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/diamonds-reveal-sign-deepest-water-known-inside-earth</link>
	<description>A rare form of ice crystal in the gems could have formed only at the crushing pressures found in the mantle.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 19:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030818_CG_diamonds-water_feat.jpg?itok=8iV27XX4" length="23643" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: On Twitter, the lure of fake news is stronger than the truth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/twitter-fake-news-truth</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/twitter-fake-news-truth</link>
	<description>An analysis of more than 4.5 million tweets discussing false and true stories reveals that in the Twittersphere, fake news gets more views.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030718_MT_fake-news_feat.jpg?itok=pPAGHzpN" length="46781" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Is plagiarism a problem in economics? Survey of editors says … yes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62521</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/08/is-plagiarism-a-problem-in-economics-survey-of-editors-says-yes/</link>
	<description>In 2004, a survey of editors of economic journals found 3 out of 10 had seen at least one case of plagiarism within the past year. More than a decade later, has the problem gotten better? Or worse? Gary Hoover at the University of Oklahoma, who co-authored the 2004 paper, decided to revisit the issue … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/08/is-plagiarism-a-problem-in-economics-survey-of-editors-says-yes/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Is plagiarism a problem in economics? Survey of editors says … yes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Learning sparse codes and predictive context with compartmentalised inputs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-03-08:/2018/03/08/learning-sparse-codes-and-predictive-context-with-compartmentalised-inputs.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/03/08/learning-sparse-codes-and-predictive-context-with-compartmentalised-inputs.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;There has been renewed interest in dendrites in computational neuroscience. The
corresponding concept in artificial neural networks is that of
compartmentalised inputs: integrating different pathways in distinct locations
within each unit, with potentially different learning rules. Here we show how a
single layer of neurons with multiple compartments can learn sparse codes and
their predictive context using a local unsupervised rule, and how this could be
used as a building block for cognitive architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 09/03/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 13:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, pulsars burst onto the scene</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-pulsars-burst-scene</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-pulsars-burst-scene</link>
	<description>Thousands of pulsars have been discovered since the announcement of their detection 50 years ago.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/021418_EC_pulsar_feat.jpg?itok=pNT4LExX" length="13012" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Jabe Wilson on the future of AI and scholarly publishing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/jabe-wilson-on-the-future-of-ai-and-scholarly-publishing</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/jabe-wilson-on-the-future-of-ai-and-scholarly-publishing</link>
	<description>R&amp;amp;D Magazine features Elsevier’s Consulting Director for Text and Data Analytics</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 10:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Best-selling introductory psychology books give a misleading view of intelligence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33429</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/08/best-selling-introductory-psychology-books-give-a-misleading-view-of-intelligence/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33434&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-08 08.55.05.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33434&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33434&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-08 08.55.05&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-08-55-05.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-08-55-05.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-08-55-05.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2400,1646&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/08/best-selling-introductory-psychology-books-give-a-misleading-view-of-intelligence/screenshot-2018-03-08-08-55-05/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-08-55-05.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;12 different logical fallacies (used to dismiss intelligence research) appeared in at least one of the introductory psychology textbooks. Table from &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-07714-001&quot;&gt;Warne et al 2018&lt;/a&gt; [fallacies originally documented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/11861-001&quot;&gt;Gottfredson 2009&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A researcher in human intelligence at Utah Valley University has analysed the 29 best-selling introductory psychology textbooks in the US – some written by among the most eminent psychologists alive – and concluded that they present a highly misleading view of the science of intelligence (see full list of books below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uvu.edu/profpages/profiles/show/user_id/10984&quot;&gt;Russell T Warne&lt;/a&gt; and his co-authors found that three-quarters of the books contain inaccuracies; that the books give disproportionate coverage to unsupported theories, such as Gardner’s “multiple intelligencies”; and nearly 80 per cent contain logical fallacies in their discussions of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-07714-001&quot;&gt;Reporting their findings in an open-access article in &lt;em&gt;Archives of Scientific Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Warne and his colleagues say that altogether the widely used books contained “43 inaccurate statements, 129 questionably accurate statements and 51 logical fallacies” and therefore “members of the public [are] likely to learn some inaccurate information about intelligence in their psychology courses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33429&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of topic coverage, over 93 per cent of the books covered &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_multiple_intelligences&quot;&gt;Gardner’s multiple intelligences&lt;/a&gt; and over 89 per cent covered &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triarchic_theory_of_intelligence&quot;&gt;Sternberg’s triarchic theory of intelligence&lt;/a&gt; (both of which challenge the idea of there being a unitary “intelligence” per se), even though neither of these theories are mainstream or well-supported by evidence, according to Warne. In contrast, fewer than a quarter of the books covered the most strongly supported contemporary, hierarchical theories, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-stratum_theory&quot;&gt;Carroll’s three-statrum model&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cattell–Horn–Carroll_theory&quot;&gt;CHC theory&lt;/a&gt; each of which posits the influence of a general intelligence on other cognitive abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To identify factual inaccuracies, Warne’s team used as a benchmark &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0160-2896(97)90011-8&quot;&gt;a consensus statement on intelligence&lt;/a&gt; research published in 1997 by Linda Gottfredson et al, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.51.2.77&quot;&gt;a 1996 APA report on the state of the field&lt;/a&gt;. Although no longer cutting edge, Warne chose these references because they reflect consensus in the field and because they are old enough for the information in them to have filtered through to non-specialist textbook authors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common inaccuracy (appearing in nearly half the books) was that intelligence tests are biased against particular groups or individuals. This contradicts the 1997 consensus statement which tackles this issue and concludes that “intelligence tests are not culturally biased”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-22&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-08 09.05.47.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33435&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33435&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-08 09.05.47&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-09-05-47.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-09-05-47.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-09-05-47.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2792,1764&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/08/best-selling-introductory-psychology-books-give-a-misleading-view-of-intelligence/screenshot-2018-03-08-09-05-47/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-08-09-05-47.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;The 29 best-selling textbooks that were subject to scrutiny for their coverage of intelligence. From &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-07714-001&quot;&gt;Warne et al, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other common inaccuracies included promotion of the idea that it is not possible to measure intelligence in a meaningful way (in fact, Warne and his colleagues point out that “it is actually easier to measure intelligence than many other psychological constructs”), and claims that intelligence is only relevant in academic settings (in fact, intelligence correlates with many non-academic life outcomes, from life expectancy to risk of dying in a car accident, and is among the strongest predictors of career success).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the logical fallacies in the books is what’s known as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_Genetic_Diversity:_Lewontin's_Fallacy&quot;&gt;Lewontin’s fallacy&lt;/a&gt;” – this idea, advanced in six of the books, states that because humans share about 99 per cent of the same genes, that genes cannot therefore have a role in the differences between individuals or groups. In fact, “slight differences in genotypes among organisms can result in major phenotype differences”, according to Warne and his team. Twelve other fallacies appeared in the books – see full list above – such as giving less scrutiny to politically correct ideas or claiming that intelligence doesn’t exist because it is a collection of abilities (suggesting the textbook authors had failed to understand the principle of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G_factor_(psychometrics)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;g&lt;/em&gt; or “general intelligence”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of questionable accuracy (i.e. errors not covered by the consensus statements), Warne highlights issues around the discussion of the taboo topic of race and IQ; textbook authors overplaying the role of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/10/19/reverse-stereotype-threat-women-play-chess-better-than-expected-against-men/&quot;&gt;stereotype threat&lt;/a&gt;“, and authors having a tendency to overestimate environmental influences on intelligence (the books largely neglected the work of scholars who study the genetic influences on intelligence, such as the British researchers Ian Deary and Robert Plomin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warne and his team admit there is an element of subjectivity in their analysis of the textbooks. However, they tried to mitigate this by using the two consensus publications from the 1990s as a reference point, by being as lenient as possible in their judgments of the books, and by being explicit in the how they went about their analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new analysis helps explain why the public and lay journalists often express a scepticism toward intelligence and intelligence testing that is at odds with expert opinion (perhaps best captured by the hackneyed claim that “intelligence tests only measure your ability to take intelligence tests”). Over a million students take introductory psych courses every year in the USA alone (a majority of whom are taking the course as part of a different degree subject), and judging by the content of most popular introductory psych textbooks in America, it seems likely these students are getting a highly distorted view of the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious issue for our domestic readers is that it’s not clear if the same inaccuracies and bias toward intelligence research also appear in British and European introductory textbooks. In fact this is a recurring shortcoming in &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/category/textbooks/&quot;&gt;our coverage of investigations into psychology textbooks&lt;/a&gt; – there simply doesn’t seem to be the same scrutiny of psychology textbooks here as there is in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Improving the public’s understanding about intelligence starts in psychology’s own backyard with improving the content of undergraduate courses and textbooks,” Warne and his colleagues conclude. And for anyone who would like to know more about intelligence, they recommend &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligence-That-Matters-Stuart-Ritchie/dp/1444791877/&quot;&gt;Intelligence: All That Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Research Digest &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/01/31/was-that-new-science-paper-hyped-and-over-interpreted-because-we-liked-its-message/&quot;&gt;guest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/09/12/its-now-possible-in-theory-to-predict-life-success-from-a-genetic-test-at-birth/&quot;&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/08/20/why-do-more-intelligent-people-live-longer/&quot;&gt;Stuart&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/08/08/how-do-you-prove-that-reading-boosts-iq/&quot;&gt;Ritchie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Intelligence-Very-Short-Introduction-Introductions/dp/0192893211&quot;&gt;Intelligence: A Very Short Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Ian Deary – these books are “not only accurate, but they also have a breezy writing style that makes them easily digestible”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-07714-001&quot;&gt;What do undergraduates learn about human intelligence? An analysis of introductory psychology textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 09:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Danielle Stodilka and the Matilda effect</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9952</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/08/danielle-stodilka-matilda-effect/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/IMG_0490-e1519165910764-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the speakers at the United Nations for International Women and Girls in Science day was Danielle Stodilka, a materials and data scientist from Canada who is a senior fellow with the Canadian International Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danielle received a PhD in Materials Science and Engineering from the University of Florida in the early 1990s, at a time where very few women were involved in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to statistics presented at the UN meeting, biology has perhaps the highest percentage of women representation among the STEM fields, with engineering containing the least, at around 11% and shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In my country, the recruitment and retention of women in engineering was still overcoming the impact of the Montreal Massacre in 1989”, she says, “I enrolled in engineering in the early 90’s to pay respect to the young women who lost their lives, while at the same time knowing they could have mentored me”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s most remarkable about Danielle’s story is how closely it aligns with so many stories reiterated by female speakers during the conference; while pursuing a master’s degree as one of the few, if not only, women in her field, Danielle’s scientific work was appropriated by males in her research group without giving her credit. This behavior was overlooked at the institution, where all of the superiors were male and there was very much an “old boys club” atmosphere in the laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danielle references this to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/285482?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&quot;&gt;the Matilda effect&lt;/a&gt;”, where the contributions of women in science are overlooked, citing an article that discusses the phenomenon in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some women have sued institutions for this unethical behavior, others have protested within the departments, all to varying degrees of success, but ultimately this behavior is still seen today. The fact that this is going on should be a high level of concern for all STEM institutions and industries, and should be on the radar for all funding institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Danielle’s story is not a negative one, but very much a positive one, as she met this situation with resilience and perseverance. She told another story that perhaps many of our readers can relate to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she was a small child in preschool, the boys and girls were given separate toys: the girls were given dolls, and the boys were given building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; style=&quot;width: 251px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;251&quot; src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a5/Children_marbles.jpg/575px-Children_marbles.jpg&quot; width=&quot;241&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Tup Wanders Source: https://www.flickr.com/photos/tupwanders/83092660/&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, she decided to leave the dolls for a little while and join the boys so that she could play with the blocks as well. At that point, a young boy told her she had no right to do so, since she was a girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I in no way advocate violence,” she says with wry grin, but it did lead to a bit of a tussle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danielle went on to receive accolades for her work, and entered the field of Materials Science and Engineering in the early 1990s at a time when very few had been involved in the field. She went on to pursue a PhD in America on a post-graduate fellowship, when she found a female mentor in Florida in a field of her interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding a science mentor is perhaps the greatest challenge facing women in STEM today, because there are so few women to begin with, it can be hard to find someone who can provide advice for navigating a particularly competitive and demanding field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danielle strongly encourages all women and girls to join the field of science, particularly that of engineering. She says this would be an excellent strategy to avoid the Matilda effect because she believes if more women are physically present and involved in decision making processes, science will become a more female-friendly workplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She went on to state that having more women involved in the STEM fields will benefit all of humanity, because they can offer new perspectives, not only for safety, efficiency, and aesthetics but also in new research discoveries and our understanding of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/08/danielle-stodilka-matilda-effect/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Danielle Stodilka and the Matilda effect&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 09:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/IMG_0490-e1519165910764-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Some meteorites contain superconducting bits</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/some-meteorites-contain-superconducting-bits</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/some-meteorites-contain-superconducting-bits</link>
	<description>Scientists find materials that conduct electricity without resistance in two meteorites.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 22:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030718_EC_medeorite_main.jpg?itok=MU5cM9yb" length="44757" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 4 surprising things we just learned about Jupiter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-polar-cyclones-planet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-polar-cyclones-planet</link>
	<description>Polar cyclones, surprisingly deep atmosphere and a fluid mass spinning as a rigid body are among the latest discoveries at Jupiter.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030618_CC_jupiter_main.jpg?itok=nkkjE_gH" length="58014" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Data in biofuel paper “had either been grossly misinterpreted or fabricated”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62502</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/07/data-in-biofuel-paper-had-either-been-grossly-misinterpreted-or-fabricated/</link>
	<description>A biology journal has retracted a 2011 paper after the University of California, Los Angeles determined that the data in three figures “cannot be supported.” In February, the journal Applied and Environmental Microbiology retracted the paper, which explores efforts to engineer bacteria to convert plant biomass into biofuel. Claudia Modlin, assistant director of UCLA’s Office … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/07/data-in-biofuel-paper-had-either-been-grossly-misinterpreted-or-fabricated/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Data in biofuel paper “had either been grossly misinterpreted or fabricated”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: This scientist has made a career of confronting failures</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/this-scientist-has-made-a-career-of-confronting-failures</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/this-scientist-has-made-a-career-of-confronting-failures</link>
	<description>As an environmental researcher, Dr. Dawn Fox of Guyana finds ways to turn “trash into treasure” – literally and figuratively</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This baby bird fossil gives a rare look at ancient avian development</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/baby-bird-fossil-gives-rare-look-ancient-avian-development</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/baby-bird-fossil-gives-rare-look-ancient-avian-development</link>
	<description>A 127-million-year-old fossil of a baby bird suggests diversity in how a group of extinct birds grew.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030618_CG_baby-bird_feat.jpg?itok=KNbFrzJ2" length="56339" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Want to tell if a paper has been retracted? Good luck</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62497</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/07/want-to-tell-if-a-paper-has-been-retracted-good-luck/</link>
	<description>Nowadays, there are many ways to access a paper — on the publisher’s website, on MEDLINE, PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and other outlets. So when the publisher retracts a paper, do these outlets consistently mark it as such? And if they don’t, what’s the impact? Researchers Caitlin Bakker and Amy Riegelman at the University of Minnesota … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/07/want-to-tell-if-a-paper-has-been-retracted-good-luck/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Want to tell if a paper has been retracted? Good luck&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 13:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Humans don’t get enough sleep. Just ask other primates.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-primates-sleep-evolution</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-primates-sleep-evolution</link>
	<description>Short, REM-heavy sleep bouts separate humans from other primates, scientists find. Sleeping on the ground may have a lot to do with it.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030618_bb_primate-sleep_feat_free.jpg?itok=pYfjZj0X" length="57072" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: First systematic study of people who can give themselves goose-bumps at will</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33422</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/07/first-systematic-study-of-people-who-can-give-themselves-goose-bumps-at-will/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of us, goose-bumps are something that happens outside of our conscious control, either when we’re cold or afraid, or because we’ve been moved by music or poignant art. However, it seems there are a few individuals with a kind of psychophysiological super-power – they can give themselves goose-bumps at will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a new study, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://peerj.com/preprints/26594/&quot;&gt;they’ve released as a pre-print at &lt;em&gt;PeerJ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a team led by James Heathers at Northeastern University, Boston, created &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/voluntarygoosebumps&quot;&gt;a Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; with descriptions of “voluntary piloerection”, to use the technical term,  and invited anyone with this ability to complete a comprehensive questionnaire. Thirty-two voluntary goose-bumpers took part. Though the results are preliminary, this is a landmark study considering that voluntary piloerection has not previously been subject to systematic investigation, and that the scientific record contains just three prior case studies over a period of more than a century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33422&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average age of the individuals who answered the survey was 32 and there were many consistencies in their descriptions of their goose-bump ability, closely matching the few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physiology.org/doi/abs/10.1152/ajplegacy.1902.7.4.369?journalCode=ajplegacy&quot;&gt;obscure accounts&lt;/a&gt; in the existing medical literature. Nearly three quarters said that the voluntary sensation or action began on the back of their head or neck; many described a shiver or tingle down the spine; and ninety per cent said the sensation manifested on their arms, among other body areas. The participants overwhelmingly described their ability as a voluntary act, akin to deciding to move, as opposed to using their imagination or memories to cause the goose-bumps. They saw it as a normal, harmless activity and many were surprised to learn that others cannot do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I tighten a muscle behind my ears … and the goosebumps appear on my back and then travel to my arms”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think about goose-bumps, they start to appear, I shudder/shiver, and there they are”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I simple [sic] think of doing it. I don’t need to have a [sic] emotion involved, in fact I can do it now without feeling any emotion whatsoever”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I flex a ‘muscle’ in my brain. Sometimes I have to concentrate a little if I’ve been doing it a while”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the participants said that they noticed their ability in adolescence or early adulthood; two said they only realised they had the ability after reading the description on Facebook (leading the researchers to doubt that the ability arises via conditioning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the participants didn’t use emotions to produce their goose-bumps, triggering the sensation was associated with subsequent emotional experience, especially absorption and wonder (similar to involuntary goose-bumps). In fact, nearly three quarters of them said they deliberately triggered goose-bumps while engaged in aesthetic activities, such as listening to music or dancing, and also activities like sex and study, as if to accentuate or facilitate these experiences. Half of them also used their ability to prolong involuntary goose-bumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An obvious criticism of the study is that the participants’ accounts must be taken on trust – the researchers didn’t invite these individuals to the lab to study the phenomenon with their own eyes (or if they have, these results aren’t available yet). However, given the consistency of the accounts, Heathers and his colleagues doubt that the participants are fabricating, and they added: “It is unlikely any participant had prior cues or expectations regarding how their ability might be expected to work due its rarity”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the survey, the participants also completed a personality and emotion questionnaire and the most striking result was that they scored much higher than average on the trait of Openness, and they experienced the state of absorption more often than normal. The personality finding isn’t surprising given that prior research has found that more open individuals are more prone to involuntary goose-bumps; openness is also associated with self-experimentation, which may be one way that the goose-bumpers discovered or developed their skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we still have no idea about the prevalence of the voluntary goose-bump ability because the researchers don’t know how many people viewed their online advertisements for the survey. We do know that they screened 682 first-year psychology students, and none of them had the ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s going to be exciting to see what more can be discovered about this little known phenomenon, especially how other physiological systems such as heart rate are involved, and how it affects emotional experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead author James Heathers, perhaps best known for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2018/02/meet-data-thugs-out-expose-shoddy-and-questionable-research&quot;&gt;data sleuthing activities&lt;/a&gt;, said (on Twitter): “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jamesheathers/status/969330864164392960&quot;&gt;This is the strangest thing I’ve ever gotten to study, and I love it&lt;/a&gt;“. Can he do it? “No,” he said, adding: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jamesheathers/status/969336047682367488&quot;&gt;Do you know how many hours I’ve spent staring at my damn arms or hands, trying to focus ‘energy’ at the back of my head?? I feel ridiculous and I absolutely cannot do it&lt;/a&gt;.” Check Heathers’ twitter feed &lt;span class=&quot;username u-dir&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;ProfileCardMini-screennameLink u-linkComplex js-nav u-dir&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jamesheathers&quot;&gt;@jamesheathers&lt;/a&gt; for more discussion and information. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://peerj.com/preprints/26594/&quot;&gt;The voluntary control of piloerection&lt;/a&gt; [this study is a pre-print and has not yet been subjected to peer review]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 09:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Yourbrainhealth: The emerging field of psychobiotics (Part 3)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5317</guid>
	<link>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/emerging-field-psychobiotics-part-3/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-5318 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Screen-Shot-2018-03-05-at-9.41.23-am-1024x652.png&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today in Part 3 of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/category/gut-brain-axis/&quot;&gt;series on the gut-brain axis&lt;/a&gt;, Drs Amy Reichelt and Sarah McKay discuss mind-altering microbes and the emerging field of psychobiotics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome is a key node in the gut-brain axis. Scientists are only just uncovering how microbes in the gut influence physical, brain and even mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2004, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15133062&quot;&gt;pivotal study&lt;/a&gt; found &lt;a href=&quot;https://irp.nih.gov/catalyst/v19i4/germ-free-mice&quot;&gt;“germ-free”&lt;/a&gt; mice that lacked a gut microbiome had exaggerated emotional responses to stressful events compared to normal mice. Intriguingly, more pronounced emotional reactions were &lt;em&gt;reversed&lt;/em&gt; when the gut microbiome was restored using probiotics. Findings such as this have lead to an explosion of interest in the use of probiotics for treating myriad illnesses including depression and anxiety in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is the difference between probiotics and psychobiotics?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abc.net.au/health/thepulse/stories/2013/04/10/3733630.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Probiotics&lt;/a&gt; are living microrganisms such as bacteria or yeast, which when taken in large enough quantities, help improve and maintain the health of your gastrointestinal tract. The most frequently used &lt;em&gt;pro&lt;/em&gt;biotic bacteria are from &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus&lt;/em&gt; families. Also included in the class of probiotics are &lt;em&gt;pre&lt;/em&gt;biotics, which ‘feed’ or ‘fertilise’ resident beneficial gut bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5102282/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychobiotics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are a class of probiotics, which, when ingested, confer brain or mental health benefits through interactions with gut bacteria and the gut-brain axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychobiotic research examines rodent behaviour to measure changes in motivation, anxiety, and depression following treatment. For example, in 2015, a study published in &lt;em&gt;Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt; reported probiotic supplements &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26408987&quot;&gt;improved resilience&lt;/a&gt; in rats following stressful experiences. Dosing stressed rats  with &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus helveticus&lt;/em&gt; lowered anxiety and depression-like behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gut feelings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal studies have paved the way for studies testing the ability of probiotics versus placebo controls to improve mood in people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17151594&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; double-blind randomised controlled trial&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;em&gt;European Journal of Clinical Nutrition&lt;/em&gt; in 2007, 132 people consumed either a milk drink containing &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus casei Shirota&lt;/em&gt; or a milk-based placebo for three weeks. All volunteers completed mood and cognitive tests at baseline and every 10 days during the trial. When the baseline measures of those consumed the two types of drink were compared, no significant differences were found with any measure of mood or cognition. However, for a subset of volunteers who reported&lt;em&gt; low&lt;/em&gt; moods beginning the trial, the probiotic drink improved their mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other studies have reported supplements containing a variety of probiotic strains, including &lt;em&gt;Lactobacillus helveticus&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Bifidobacterium longum&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20974015&quot;&gt;reduce self-reported negative moods&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25862297&quot;&gt;emotional reactions to sad experiences&lt;/a&gt;. Probiotic treatments also lower the body’s response to stressful situations which can be measured through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yourhormones.info/hormones/cortisol/&quot;&gt;cortisol&lt;/a&gt; levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These studies suggest that probiotics have the potential to improve mood and help control responses to stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Can probiotics make you smarter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of their potential to alter brain function, research has examined whether psychobiotics improve memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probiotic supplements enhance the ability of mice to solve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23454729&quot;&gt;memory tasks&lt;/a&gt;. This improvement was linked to increased neuroplasticity-boosting brain chemicals such as brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) in the hippocampus – a key brain area for forming memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress can increase forgetfulness, and stressed-out rats treated with probiotics were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26408987&quot;&gt;better at remembering objects&lt;/a&gt; than stressed rats that received placebos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also know that junk food diets can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29251841&quot;&gt;detrimental to brain function&lt;/a&gt; and impair memory. A recent study showed that a probiotic cocktail &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/mp201738&quot;&gt;restored memory&lt;/a&gt; in rats that typically ate junk foods. Oddly, the probiotic treatment &lt;em&gt;decreased&lt;/em&gt; memory performance in rats that usually ate a &lt;em&gt;healthy&lt;/em&gt; diet. Such unexpected results show that manipulating the microbiome may not always be beneficial in a healthy population and have the potential to disrupt healthy brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the advocates (and advertisements) tout probiotics as the silver bullet for almost every illness you can think of, rightly so, there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2016/01/21/probiotics-shaky-science/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plenty of scepticism&lt;/a&gt; in the neuroscientific and medical communities surrounding the use of psychobiotics as therapy for mood disorders. There is some concern that psychobiotics may be used a replacement for evidence-based treatments (including talking therapies), or as a reason to postpone seeking help from a mental health professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmicrobiol201775&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nature Microbiology&lt;/a&gt; in 2017, immunologists Jotham Suez and Eran Elinav state&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“While some studies have suggested mechanistic insights into how probiotic bacteria may mediate beneficial effects, these were mostly done in cell culture and animal models. As such, insufficient evidence supports the efficacy of the current probiotics approach (one bacterial mix is beneficial to all conditions) in most indications, while their human health benefits remain controversial.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suez and Elinav acknowledge out the huge potential for gut microbiome interventions as shown by faecal microbiome transplantation (FMT) for infections such as &lt;i&gt;Clostridium difficile,&lt;/i&gt; but caution against the “one strain fits all” therapeutic approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US NIH National Centre for Complementary and Integrative Health state&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“…preliminary evidence that some probiotics are helpful in preventing diarrhoeaa caused by infections and antibiotics and in improving symptoms of irritable bowel syndrome, but more needs to be learned.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, we still don’t know which probiotics are helpful and which are not. We also don’t know how much of the probiotic people would have to take, or who would most likely benefit from taking probiotics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5102282/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; 2016 Trends in Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt; review of psychobiotics concludes with the following rather long list of outstanding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl:dr “Plenty we don’t yet know”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p52&quot;&gt;What are the dose-response functions associated with psychobiotics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p53&quot;&gt;What are the contributions of gut hormones in the mechanisms of action of prebiotics versus probiotics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p54&quot;&gt;How do prebiotics and probiotics differ in terms of their impact on microbiome structure and relative abundance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p55&quot;&gt;Are there undetected psychophysiological costs alongside the observed benefits of psychobiotics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p56&quot;&gt;Does the brain adapt to long-term psychobiotic ingestion?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p57&quot;&gt;How do bacteria-derived blood metabolites affect the central nervous system, and how do psychobiotics modulate this relationship?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p58&quot;&gt;What is the time-course for the emergence of various psychobiotic effects, and how long do they last?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p59&quot;&gt;Are there ceiling effects on psychobiotic benefits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p60&quot;&gt;What are the functional implications of altered excitation–inhibition balance (due to alterations in GABA and glutamate concentrations) in specific brain regions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p61&quot;&gt;Why do some strains of probiotic or prebiotic show effects while others do not, and are these linked to dosage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p62&quot;&gt;Do neurotransmitters produced by gut bacteria modulate synaptic transmission in the proximal neurons of the enteric nervous system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p63&quot;&gt;What is the direction of causality between systemic and central changes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;__p64&quot;&gt;How do factors such as diet, genotype, sex, and age moderate the effects of psychobiotics?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/emerging-field-psychobiotics-part-3/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The emerging field of psychobiotics (Part 3)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/">Your Brain Health</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These petunias launch seeds that spin 1,660 times a second</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/petunias-seeds-launch-plants</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/petunias-seeds-launch-plants</link>
	<description>One species of petunia spreads its seeds explosively, giving them a rotation of 1,660 times per second.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030618_DG_ballistic-petunia_main.jpg?itok=QI2Be-mp" length="29313" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: When bogs burn, the environment takes a hit</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bogs-peatlands-fire-climate-change</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bogs-peatlands-fire-climate-change</link>
	<description>Bogs and other peatlands around the world store outsized amounts of carbon. Climate change and agriculture are putting them at risk.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/031718_LH_bogs_feat.jpg?itok=4TGd4lbF" length="42431" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: No retraction for “likely fraudulent” study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62278</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/06/caught-our-notice-no-retraction-for-likely-fraudulent-study/</link>
	<description>Title: Homocysteine as a predictive factor for hip fracture in elderly women with Parkinson’s disease What Caught Our Attention:  In a letter to the editor, researchers led by Mark Bolland recently outlined the many reasons why a study by Yoshihiro Sato and colleagues in The American Journal of Medicine was “unreliable,” including evidence that the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/06/caught-our-notice-no-retraction-for-likely-fraudulent-study/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: No retraction for “likely fraudulent” study&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 (misguided) excuses for skipping the flu vaccine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-misguided-excuses-for-skipping-the-flu-vaccine</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-misguided-excuses-for-skipping-the-flu-vaccine</link>
	<description>An Elsevier medical editor explains why people should get vaccinated for personal and public health reasons</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Open science: data from largest meta-analysis of antidepressants available</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-data-from-largest-meta-analysis-of-antidepressants-available</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-data-from-largest-meta-analysis-of-antidepressants-available</link>
	<description>Authors of a major study in The Lancet have made their dataset freely available on Mendeley Data</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: When a journal is delisted, authors pay a price</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62413</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/06/when-a-journal-is-delisted-authors-pay-a-price/</link>
	<description>Shocked, confused, disappointed — these are the reactions of authors who recently published in a cancer journal that was delisted by a company that indexes journals. Recently, Clarivate Analytics announced it would discontinue indexing Oncotarget after the first few issues of 2018 — as a result, the journal would not receive a current impact factor. The company … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/06/when-a-journal-is-delisted-authors-pay-a-price/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;When a journal is delisted, authors pay a price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In a pack hunt, it’s every goatfish for itself</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pack-hunt-its-every-goatfish-itself</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pack-hunt-its-every-goatfish-itself</link>
	<description>Pack hunting among goatfish is really about self-interest.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030518_SM_goatfish_feat.jpg?itok=2SqQVjKU" length="48917" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Against expectations, people with more egalitarian political views were more open to the idea that intelligence is fixed</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33415</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/06/against-expectations-people-with-more-egalitarian-political-views-were-more-open-to-the-idea-that-intelligence-is-fixed/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_33420&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-03-06 at 10.03.41.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33420&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33420&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screen Shot 2018-03-06 at 10.03.41&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-06-at-10-03-41.png?w=845?w=645&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-06-at-10-03-41.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-06-at-10-03-41.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;645,517&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/06/against-expectations-people-with-more-egalitarian-political-views-were-more-open-to-the-idea-that-intelligence-is-fixed/screen-shot-2018-03-06-at-10-03-41/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screen-shot-2018-03-06-at-10-03-41.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;People lower on “social dominance orientation” were more influenced by the argument that intelligence is a fixed trait (from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12238/full&quot;&gt;Hoyt et al 2018&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growth mindset – believing your capabilities can grow over time – can help us set self-improvement goals, consider mistakes as a step towards mastery, and remain upbeat when facing tribulation. Psychologists are excited by the ways we can help develop such mindsets, particularly towards creativity and intelligence, but some studies have found the impact &lt;a href=&quot;http://%2520https//osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/tsdwy&quot;&gt;less impressive&lt;/a&gt; than earlier research had suggested. Now researchers are hungry to understand the individual characteristics that might prevent these interventions making an impact on some people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12238/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;in the &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has investigated one possible candidate – political ideology, specifically a perspective known as “social dominance orientation”. If you are invested in preserving the status quo, perhaps that encourages you to see social relations as inevitable, as “just the way things are” – an essentialist, fixed view of the world that seems to carry over to how you view human capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33415&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crystal Hoyt at the University of Richmond and her colleagues asked 300 online participants to rate their agreement with statements about social dominance like “some groups of people are simply inferior to other groups.” Participants then read either an article about intelligence that promoted a growth mindset, or an article arguing for the opposite (both articles used text and graphs to suggest that intelligence was either highly influenced or entirely uninfluenced by the circumstances of our lives, respectively). Finally participants rated their agreement with fixed mindset items like “you can learn new things, but you can’t really change your basic intelligence”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, participants higher in social dominance orientation had a somewhat more fixed intelligence mindset. Their views also barely budged after reading either the growth or fixed-mindset article. In contrast, and against the researchers’ expectations, the low-dominance participants were particularly influenced by the article that argued for intelligence as a fixed quality (after reading it, they expressed a fixed mindset, as high as the high-dominance participants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps people who are low in social dominance beliefs are more open to scientific argument, and the fixed article was the one that presented them with a new take. In any case, the evidence suggests they are not the ones with most to gain from growth interventions, as was expected, but instead they are at greater risk of sliding towards a fixed argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a positive note, rather than suggesting that high-dominance people might be an especially hard nut for these mindset interventions to crack, the findings create a case for giving it a go – these people are no more resistant than anyone else, and may have further to go, and hence more to gain. All in all, this new research shows that individual differences are worth considering if we want to change mindset, but we’re still in early days of understanding how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12238/abstract?campaign=wolearlyview&quot;&gt;Social dominance orientation moderates the effectiveness of mindset messages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 10:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Family Practice:  highlights of 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9996</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/06/bmc-family-practice-highlights-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/feat-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0611-7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussing success in support for patient self-management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the rising prevalence of long-term health conditions, self-management by patients is seen as crucial to making health care service more effective.  Support for self-management (SSM) by healthcare professionals is an important contributor to patient well-being.  Evaluations of SSM tend to focus on just one or two outcomes and so do not reveal a complete picture of the quality of service provided to patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Successful self-management depends on many factors, many of which cannot be influenced by a health professional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this lack from the provider perspective, Owens &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; conducted individual interviews and group discussions with health professionals who worked with patients with diabetes and/or Parkinson’s Disease.  Participants were asked to discuss what they viewed as successful SSM and what factors helped or hindered this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The descriptions of success were complex and included elements that inter-related and sometimes contradicted each other.  The three main groups of elements of success were related to patient health and quality of life, patient self-management capacity, and provider-patient relationships and communication.  Many of these elements were specific to certain contexts or patients, highlighting the difficulty in developing generic measures of success in SSM.  One challenge that was highlighted was that successful self-management depends on many factors, many of which cannot be influenced by a health professional; meanwhile, outcomes which providers can influence may not be those most important to patients.  Additionally, the definition of “realistic” goals is both individual and subjective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussions of success in SSM in this paper indicate the need for careful consideration of measures of success that take into account the complexity of judgment and many ways to measure quality in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-016-0578-9&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are Self-Rating Scales an Effective Tool in Primary Care for Depressed Patients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9999 alignright&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/checklist-300x200.jpg&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;In Sweden, patients with depression are often treated in primary care. The recommended guidelines for this population suggest that general practitioners regularly administer self-rating scales as a means to monitor depressive symptoms. However, the most commonly used, Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS-S), is specifically designed for a psychiatric setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent multicenter randomized controlled study conducted by Wikberg &lt;em&gt;et al.,&lt;/em&gt; sought to address the utility of self-rating scales. The trial assessed the use of pharmacological treatment such as sedatives and antidepressants, patient’s quality of life, psychological wellbeing, sick leave, frequency of care visits, and the severity of depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For three months, general practitioners across 22 primary health care centers either administered a self-rating scale monthly along with their usual course of care or proceeded to treat patients as usual.  This study found that participants in both groups had significant improvements in quality of life, depressive symptoms and psychological wellbeing between the start of the study and the three-month follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the study, there were also increases in the percentage of antidepressant use by the three-month mark. At the six-month follow-up, 69% of patients in the intervention group were still on anti-depressants, as compared to 59% of controls.  By the one-year mark, over 50% of patients were still using anti-depressants, with 59% in the intervention and 58% in the control groups.  Additionally, the control group visited psychology health professionals more often than the intervention group, while the intervention group visited primary care centers more than the controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikberg&lt;em&gt; et al.&lt;/em&gt; concluded that while the self-rating scale lead to increases in continued use of anti-depressants, the other variables measured in the study were not significantly impacted by the scales. Furthermore, it is their belief that self-rating scales ma&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot;&gt;y be best left to the discretion of the general practitioner and the needs of their patient.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0634-0&quot;&gt;How health care providers’ burnout and empathy affect patient outcomes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure (BP) is increasingly prevalent in most populations.  Diagnosis, treatment, and monitoring of high BP regularly take place in primary care settings.  Outcomes are often poor due to a number of factors associated with how primary health care providers manage and interact with patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;They found that patients had significantly lower blood pressure when in the care of a doctor or nurse with low burnout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yuguero &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; investigated how primary care providers’ characteristics, specifically empathy and burnout, affected BP control and management in their patients.  Physician burnout is a measure of emotional exhaustion, depersonalization towards patients, and feelings of competence and success.  They found that patients had significantly lower BP when in the care of a doctor or nurse with low burnout.  They also found a significant association between low burnout and high empathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous studies have shown high empathy to improve immediate patient outcomes.  This suggests that the improved BP control seen in patients of health care professionals with lower burnout and higher empathy may result from a better physician-patient relationship and better adherence to treatment recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings of this study support recommendations to promote skills that improve empathy and reduce burnout among health care providers, particularly in primary care, to benefit both providers and patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0642-0&quot;&gt;Management of Polypharmacy in Primary Care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot; wp-image-9998 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/pills-300x251.png&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.5;&quot; width=&quot;243&quot; /&gt;Polypharmacy refers to the use of multiple medications by an individual patient over their course of treatment. Increasing rates of multi-morbidity and chronic illness, the use of disease-specific evidence-based guidelines, and the lack of guidelines for multi-morbidity, have led to increases in polypharmacy.  This phenomenon is positively associated with disease management and quality of life, but is also associated with increased risk for drug interactions and side-effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that polypharmacy is most advantageous for patients, researchers have identified high-risk groups and provided suggestions for primary care physicians.  Researchers found those at highest risk were adults 65 and older, due to higher incidence of multi-morbidity with age, as well as patients in residential health care facilities. Outside of this group, primary care physicians have looked for patients at risk based on the number of medications they were taking.  While the number of medications prescribed to patients with risk of polypharmacy varies, it was recommended that patients taking ten or more medications should be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an insightful debate article, Molokhia and Majeed suggest that once physicians are aware of what factors are associated with polypharmacy, electronic medical records can be a useful tool to easily filter through patients.  They also suggested improving patient-physician communication regarding risk and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, regularly checking in with patients to ensure that treatment are followed as directed and frequently assessing whether each drug is still necessary can allow physicians to proactively manage polypharmacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/06/bmc-family-practice-highlights-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;BMC Family Practice&lt;/i&gt;:  highlights of 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/feat-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Google moves toward quantum supremacy with 72-qubit computer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/google-moves-toward-quantum-supremacy-72-qubit-computer</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/google-moves-toward-quantum-supremacy-72-qubit-computer</link>
	<description>Google’s 72-qubit quantum chip may eventually perform a task beyond the ability of traditional computers.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 22:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030518_EC_google-quantum-computer_main.jpg?itok=GHdtvq-B" length="17108" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Pollution regulations help Chesapeake Bay seagrass rebound</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollution-regulations-help-chesapeake-bay-seagrass-rebound</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollution-regulations-help-chesapeake-bay-seagrass-rebound</link>
	<description>Regulations that have reduced nitrogen runoff into the Chesapeake Bay are driving the recovery of underwater vegetation.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030218_lh_seagrass_feat.jpg?itok=DcFhWOVr" length="46965" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: By 2100, damaged corals may let waves twice as tall as today’s reach coasts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2100-damaged-corals-waves-twice-tall-todays-reach-coasts</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/2100-damaged-corals-waves-twice-tall-todays-reach-coasts</link>
	<description>Structurally complex coral reefs can defend coasts against waves, even as sea levels rise.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 18:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030218_cg_coralreef_stat_feat.jpg?itok=BiDYYBNd" length="22587" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Probe into Carlo Croce reached “defensible and reasonable” decisions, says external review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62397</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/05/probe-into-carlo-croce-reached-defensible-and-reasonable-decisions-says-external-review/</link>
	<description>An independent analysis of how The Ohio State University reviewed allegations of misconduct against a high-profile cancer researcher has found that the institution “complied with applicable law and with relevant institutional policies and reached reasoned and supportable conclusions.” The review follows numerous allegations of research misconduct against Carlo Croce, described in a March 8 story … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/05/probe-into-carlo-croce-reached-defensible-and-reasonable-decisions-says-external-review/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Probe into Carlo Croce reached “defensible and reasonable” decisions, says external review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 16:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Dietary Intake of Omega Fatty Acids and Brain Health</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23569</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/03/05/dietary-intake-of-omega-fatty-acids-and-brain-health/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Omega fatty acids are well known to be important for the normal functioning of our body. These fatty acids are essential for the formation of the cell membrane. They play a critical role in brain health. In addition, they are crucial for fertility, visual acuity, and optimal cardiovascular health. Omega-3 fatty acids also have an anti-inflammatory effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DHA is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/16/nurturing-the-brain-part-7-omega-3-fatty-acids/&quot;&gt;omega-3 fatty acid&lt;/a&gt;. Omega fatty acids belong to a group called polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA). There are several kinds of omega-3 fatty acids, but for humans, three of them are considered to be essential. These are alpha-linolenic acid (ALA), eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALA is a short-chain fatty acid that cannot be made by our body and thus regarded as essential. EPA and DHA are classified as long-chain fatty acids. Our body can produce them in small quantities and a very inefficient manner. This is why one’s diet should provide enough of the essential and semi-essential omega-3 fatty acids. ALA is the only fatty acid which is present in plant-based food products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although EPA and DHA, both of which are particularly essential for brain health, can be produced in the body from ALA, the conversion process is not very efficient. It is believed that only ~15% of dietary ALA can be converted to EPA or DHA. ALA is present in canola oil, flaxseed oil, and in some other plant oils in sufficient quantities, whereas DHA and ALA are mainly present in seafood (various varieties of fish) and found in small amounts in other animal or poultry products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has shown that although fish are rich in omega fatty acids, they are not able to produce DHA or EPA. In fact, they get omega-3 fatty acids by ingesting phytoplankton. Phytoplankton, in turn, get DHA and EPA by eating microalgae that are able to produce these fatty acids. These findings draw attention to two important facts: the importance of fish and animal products in our diet for optimal cognitive health and the importance of preserving the fragile environmental balance where everything is interconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omega-3 fatty acids are essential for the formation of phospholipids that are in turn required for cellular membranes. DHA is particularly critical for brain health, as demonstrated by its high content in the brain. Furthermore, since DHA helps to reduce the inflammatory responses, it may have a neuroprotective action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of studies regarding the optimal intake of omega-3 and omega-6 fatty acids and their optimal ratio in one’s diet. However, the recommendations in this regard remain inconclusive. Rather than focusing on the total amount of omega fatty acids or the ratio of various fatty acids, one should focus on the overall dietary intake of EPA and DHA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although EPA and DHA have been accepted to be essential for wellbeing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/09/11/happy-retirement-5-ways-to-prolong-the-golden-years/&quot;&gt;healthy aging&lt;/a&gt;, and slowing down or preventing neurodegeneration, their levels are rarely assessed in clinical conditions. There is no standardized, universally accepted range, but the most widely accepted normal level is ~3–4% of all plasma phospholipids (for EPA and DHA combined).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plasma or serum fatty acid values are not very accurate, as they may change according to the content of recent meals. For this reason, many researchers recommend checking the content of EPA and DHA inthe red blood cell membranes, as this can give the approximate average of the last 120 days. At present, for European and American populations, 3–5% of EPA and DHA in erythrocyte membranes is considered in the normal range. In the Japanese population for example, where consumption of seafood is much higher, these numbers may be much higher too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are the dietary recommendations for Omega-3s?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, for a healthy brain, it is recommended to consume 1.6 g of omega-3s daily for males, and 1.1 g daily for females. As mentioned earlier, specific attention should be paid to the content of DHA and EPA in food items. Flaxseed oil, chia seeds, and walnuts are all rich in ALA. However, DHA and EPA are mainly present in fish, seafood, and poultry. Considering that only a small amount of ALA can be converted to DHA or EPA, it puts vegans at risk of developing a deficiency in these omega acids and thus raises the risk of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/04/24/surprising-role-of-prions-in-neurodegenerative-diseases/&quot;&gt;neurodegenerative disorders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter the deficit of DHA in plant-based products, many manufacturers have started to fortify soy beverages, juices, and milk products with DHA. Dietary supplements are another way of obtaining sufficient amounts of DHA. However, as most &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/03/05/dietary-intake-of-omega-fatty-acids-and-brain-health/&quot;&gt;dietary supplements&lt;/a&gt; are based on fish oil or krill oil, if a person is strictly vegetarian, they can take algal oil-based supplements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) 2011-12 indicates that most of the population in the US are obtaining enough dietary omega-3 fatty acids. However, the majority of omega fatty acids are coming from a plant-based diet, meaning that American food is rich in ALA but deficient in EPA and DHA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diagnosing the omega-3 deficiency is not an easy task, as there is no lower cut-off value. Researchers don’t currently know at which level an omega fatty acid insufficiency may start causing problems. Things get complicated further by individual differences. Present scientific data are insufficient to know at what level there is a risk of neural deficits, visual impairment, or alterations in immune responses. However, some people may develop specific dermatological signs in the omega-3 deficiency, like scaling of the skin or unexplained dermatitis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classical omega-3 deficiency is rare in the US, but considering the importance of DHA and EPA for healthy aging and cognitive capacity, one may suppose that strict vegans, vegetarians, or those who don’t eat fish may be at higher risk when compared to those that do eat fish without supplementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyall, S. C. (2015). Long-chain omega-3 fatty acids and the brain: a review of the independent and shared effects of EPA, DPA and DHA. &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2015.00052&quot;&gt;10.3389/fnagi.2015.00052&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McNamara, R. K. (2010). DHA Deficiency and Prefrontal Cortex Neuropathology in Recurrent Affective Disorders. &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Nutrition&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;140&lt;/em&gt;(4), 864–868. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3945/jn.109.113233&quot;&gt;10.3945/jn.109.113233&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office of Dietary Supplements – Omega-3 Fatty Acids. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/Omega3FattyAcids-HealthProfessional/&quot;&gt;https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/Omega3FattyAcids-HealthProfessional/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weiser, M. J., Butt, C. M., &amp;amp; Mohajeri, M. H. (2016). Docosahexaenoic Acid and Cognition throughout the Lifespan. &lt;em&gt;Nutrients&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(2). doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3390/nu8020099&quot;&gt;10.3390/nu8020099&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/pixel2013-2364555/&quot;&gt;pixel2013&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Retraction count for Italian researcher swells to 15 as five papers fall</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62308</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/05/retraction-count-for-italian-researcher-swells-to-16-as-five-papers-fall/</link>
	<description>A researcher who is facing a criminal investigation in Italy for research misconduct has seen five more papers retracted, for a total of 16 15. Molecular and Cellular Biology has retracted four papers published between 1987 to 2001 by Alfredo Fusco, a cancer researcher in Italy; the Journal of Virology retracted one 1985 paper. Fusco was … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/05/retraction-count-for-italian-researcher-swells-to-16-as-five-papers-fall/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Retraction count for Italian researcher swells to 15 as five papers fall&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Massive stellar flare may have fried Earth’s nearest exoplanet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/proxima-centauri-flare-may-have-fried-earths-nearest-exoplanet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/proxima-centauri-flare-may-have-fried-earths-nearest-exoplanet</link>
	<description>A massive flare made Proxima Centauri 1,000 times brighter in 10 seconds, dimming hopes that its planet may be habitable.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030118_LG_proxima-centauri-flare_feat.jpg?itok=CgYZ9efN" length="23732" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Unveil the mist of pain: Frontiers in pain research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9988</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/unveil-the-mist-of-pain-frontiers-in-pain-research/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/nerve-cell-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontiers in pain research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One important direction of pain research is to classify neurons that are involved in the pain transduction pathway. With further functional identification and neural circuit tracing, the neural network of pain can be ultimately decoded. This strategy not only applies to pain research, but also to other fields in neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Breakthroughs are very likely to be made first on the dorsal root ganglion (DRG) neurons, due to their advantages of easy operation.” says Prof. Xu Zhang. The DRG neurons possess nearly ten thousand genes, regardless of the size or function of the neuron. Of them over 2000 genes are differentially expressed by 5 folds or more. Combining neural circuit tracing by viral tools, functional test by electrophysiology and behavioral test, the whole picture of DRG neurons can be revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Breakthroughs are very likely to be made first on the dorsal root ganglion (DRG) neurons, due to their advantages of easy operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Xu Zhang&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next few years, the neuroscience community will ‘decompose the nervous system at a higher level’. The community is working together towards this goal, presenting us with a clearer view of the nervous system. Our current work is to set up a normal reference model at this level. Only by using this normal reference can we unravel abnormality in animal models or with transgenic techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about Dr. Zhang’s work on somatosensory neuron type, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/cr2015149&quot;&gt;check out this paper.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Data-Driven Research in Studying Pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The era of big data is coming, for sure,” says Dr. Zhang. As a pioneer of using big data strategy to study pain, his research benefited tremendously from the new strategy and technology. The gene profiling of DRG is like a dictionary, providing unprecedented depth of understanding and larger picture of pain study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From life science to pain research, multidisciplinary coordination is always needed to explore gene networks within a cell. Big data approaches like large-scale sequencing, computation and data statistics are becoming more and more essential, and will make basic research more objective and accurate. The Chinese government has been forethoughtful and gave strong financial support for the project of Mapping Brain Functional Connections, proposed by a small group of neuroscientists a few years ago and the achievements are now for all to see. This proves the power of big data in neuroscience and is a great start to a promising future of better understanding the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the current practice of big-data driven research is still at its preliminary stage in China. Databases supported by advanced technology and professional management are in great need for further development of China’s big-data driven research. “Particularly, I hope China can play a role in international data resource network to facilitate data sharing worldwide, thus make scientific progress more efficient.” Dr. Zhang adds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Big data-driven research requires technical and policy support for data management. Springer Nature pioneered in supporting scientists to share data in smooth and in order. Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.springernature.com/gp/authors/research-data-policy&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about data policy and data support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Basic and Clinical Researches Are Combined in Pain Research? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Basic research has greatly advanced our understanding of pain. Patients with chronic pain require much more attention and more professional treatment,” Dr. Zhang points out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long lasting pain may lead to alterations in brain structure which are not the direct outcome from diseases like periphery nerve injury, inflammation or cancer but rather subsequent effects of these diseases. Brain structure alterations would cause encephalopathy, resulting in a range of problems such as mania, depression, sleep disorders, learning and memory disorders and personality defects. From a clinical or medical perspective, it has been more and more accepted that “pain is a brain disease”, rather than “a local symptom” as it was previously recognized .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy of pain treatment shall be influenced by the constant advancing of people’s knowledge. In light of that, an utmost important thing to do is to provide patients with better disease diagnosis and treatment, especially timely treatment of pain to avoid its progression into a chronic status. In China, joint efforts are being made by the government, hospitals and academic societies. Medical treatment combination, which is promoted by National Health and Family Planning Commission of the People’s Republic of China and coordinated by the China-Japan Friendship Hospital and joined by hundreds of hospitals, is the channel to benefit the public with the latest research outcomes and translational applications in the pain field. The goal is to build a comprehensive pain management and treatment system, so that the “pain clinics” can be as widespread as dental clinics, thus benefitting the pain patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Xu Zhang, an Academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, from Institute of Neuroscience, CAS, is mainly interesting in the molecular and cellular mechanisms underlying pain and cognitive disorders. His lab used gene profiling strategy to identify pain modulators and underlying mechanisms, thus uncovered new regulators of pain transmission and new molecular pathways providing potential targets for clinic analgesia and drug discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/unveil-the-mist-of-pain-frontiers-in-pain-research/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unveil the mist of pain: Frontiers in pain research&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/nerve-cell-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: The human brain atlas: present and future</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9991</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/the-human-brain-atlas-present-and-future/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/Brain-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study of human brain atlas can be dated back to the early of the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. At the initial stage, researchers made endless efforts to map the brain and anatomically partition it into areas based on cytoarchitectonic information. The recent human Brainnetome Atlas is a novel type of atlas that, unlike the ordinary ones, provides connectivity-based parcellation, with a specific focus on brain connectivity architecture. The unprecedented connectivity-based thought fills the gap in old-fashioned brain mapping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only by constantly improving the fineness and accuracy of brain atlas, can we make good use of it to identify biomarkers for mental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the journey of Brainnetome Atlas is far from over. There are still much more to do before we can finally apply it for therapies like transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) and deep brain stimulation (DBS). What is more, only by constantly improving the fineness and accuracy of brain atlas, can we make good use of it to identify biomarkers for mental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this respect, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) – the technology that existed before the atlas – has been in a dilemma for a long time. Although having been available for more than three decades and still rapidly developing, MRI has not been adopted for clinical diagnosis criteria for brain disorders, particularly mental disorders. This could be due to limited disease data and poor accuracy of brain atlases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harnessing the brain atlas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put the atlas into use, we propose three important directions for future studies on the human Brainnetome Atlas. The first one is about identifying the biomarkers for early diagnosis, prognosis, and therapeutic efficacy evaluation in different mental disorders based on more sophisticated atlases. The second direction is to confirm the matching of different areas in the atlas to functional circuits of cognition such as emotion and memory and to generate brain functional atlases at different scales. Another direction involves the use of the language- or cognition-related brain atlas in computational modeling in brain-inspired artificial intelligence (AI) studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is tremendous amount of research that can be done on the link between brain atlas and the above-mentioned brain-inspired AI computing, which will be a research hotspot in the future. Although AI is a touted concept nowadays, challenges are everywhere including limited options of techniques for AI computation. Revealing how human brain processes information may largely facilitate the development of AI computation. For instance, it has been found that, when the human brain is processing information, the high-order interactions between neurons are characterized by the second-order interactions. It is important to uncover the false mask of the so-called high order. That will largely simplify AI computation and systemic structure design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next plan is to establish nonhuman primate brain atlases at three different levels. First, we will create a similar macroscopic atlas of macaque monkey brain as that of the human brain by parcellating its brain into different areas based on macrostructural features. Based on the macroscopic atlas, we will apply classical neural tract tracing technique and the new viral tracing methods to further create the connectivity atlas at the level of the neuronal populations (or different types of neurons). This is a major issue of importance to be addressed in the next 5 to 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the fineness, it is far superior to the purely MRI-dependent method. To delineate a microscopic atlas is our ultimate goal, although hardly achievable, as currently there is no better technique available in this field other than the electron microscopy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The establishment of nonhuman primate brain atlas using invasive tracing techniques, which are inapplicable in human beings, would advance our understanding of the atlas of human brain. In addition, comparing nonhuman primate and human atlases at the macroscale may provide some hints on the similarity and difference between the two species during evolution at the brain functional connectivity level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/the-human-brain-atlas-present-and-future/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The human brain atlas: present and future&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 11:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/Brain-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Understanding and preventing copycat suicides</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10001</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/understanding-and-preventing-copycat-suicides/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/Suicide-Blog-pic-1-e1520245604790-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I probably first heard the word copycat in the playground. Its childlike nature belies the now sinister connotations of this word. Research into the phenomenon of copycat suicide is important if we are to understand and prevent it, but we remain far from grasping the chain of cognitive processes and other influences involved. This blog describes a study we recently published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1560-3&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and what it reveals about the influence of another’s suicide on someone’s own attitudes to suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence of suicide in the media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 the broadcast of the controversial Netflix series &lt;em&gt;13 Reasons Why &lt;/em&gt;generated a media storm, provoking debate over the extent to which young people might be influenced by the suicides of other people, fictionalized or otherwise. The graphic depiction of the teenage protagonist’s death, its portrayal as inevitable, and the apparent glamorization of the aftermath of her death were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iasp.info/pdf/2017_iasp_statement_13_reasons_why.pdf&quot;&gt;criticized&lt;/a&gt; by those concerned about the powerful messages conveyed. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.suicideresearch.info/news-1/commentonthenetflixseries13reasonswhy&quot;&gt;Suicide researchers pointed out&lt;/a&gt; the potential triggering effects of the irresponsible reporting or portrayal of suicide and self-harm, as advised against in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.samaritans.org/media-centre/media-guidelines-reporting-suicide&quot;&gt;media guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;These media guidelines are based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3315075/&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; that young people may be susceptible to imitating the suicidal behavior of celebrities or others known to them where those deaths are glorified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These media guidelines are based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3315075/&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; that young people may be susceptible to imitating the suicidal behavior of celebrities or others known to them where those deaths are glorified. &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/2646773?redirect=true&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt; of internet searches in the 19 days after the series aired revealed that use of the search term ‘suicide’ rose by almost 20%. A number of cases of suicide reported in the press subsequently bore similarities to the death portrayed on screen, and were highly suggestive of a direct imitative effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attitudes to suicide after the suicide of a friend or relative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young people are also at increased risk of suicide attempt after the suicide or suicide attempt of a peer, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4461080/&quot;&gt;evidenced by large-scale US studies&lt;/a&gt;. This copycat behavior is thought to be explained by social learning, and has also been termed imitative suicide, suicide contagion, or suicide diffusion. Whilst the majority of research on this topic has been conducted in the US, including attempts to understand &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4472458/&quot;&gt;the underlying cognitions&lt;/a&gt; associated with this behavior, until now relatively little work has been done in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently published a British study investigating attitudes to suicide after the suicide of a friend or relative, published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1560-3&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This work provides valuable insights into whether or not a close contact’s suicide can trigger suicidal thoughts. To our knowledge, this is the published study with the largest sample size that explores qualitatively the attitudes of people bereaved by suicide towards suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the published study with the largest sample size that explores qualitatively the attitudes of people bereaved by suicide towards suicide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our online survey in 2010 we sampled young adults living across Britain who had lost a friend or relative to suicide. Using an anonymous internet-based survey we established the circumstances of the death and then asked: &lt;em&gt;“To what extent has their death made you fear that you may die in a similar way?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall we had free text responses from 429 people, and our team of researchers analyzed these responses using the approach of &lt;a href=&quot;http://eprints.uwe.ac.uk/11735/2/thematic_analysis_revised...&quot;&gt;thematic analysis&lt;/a&gt;. We were concerned to see that a minority (26%) of respondents who had given detailed responses to this question felt that following their own experience of suicide loss they now thought of suicide as a more tangible option for them. Their responses conveyed that many now felt inured to any previous fear of suicide, to the extent that it had been normalized for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give one example, a young man whose brother had died by suicide some years before commented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If anything, it made it easier for me to consider and attempt suicide. If he had not done it, I probably would have not considered it in my lowest moments&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly a young woman whose uncle had died by suicide reflected her relief that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Knowing that if things get to be too difficult there’s a way out.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study provides evidence to support the idea of a suicide suggestion effect in a sub-group of people exposed to a peer or relative’s suicide. This represents one possible explanation for the increased risk of &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/article-abstract/2609649?redirect=true&quot;&gt;suicide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/6/1/e009948&quot;&gt;suicide attempt&lt;/a&gt; after the suicide of a friend or relative. However, there is also a positive message from this work; namely, that the majority of those responding to the survey described great aversion to the idea of attempting suicide themselves, largely because of their awareness of the negative impact on other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is important for health professionals, bereavement counselors, and the general public in raising awareness of the increased risk of imitative suicide in a sub-set of people who lose a close contact to suicide. As a psychiatrist myself, I have resolved to ask my patients about their experiences of suicide in more careful detail, exploring their attitudes sensitively, and whether they might have been influenced by the suicidal behavior of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that this study will prompt further research work in schools, colleges, psychiatric units and social networks, to understand how attitudes to suicide might differ before and after a peer’s suicide. Improving our understanding of the phenomenon of copycat suicide offers us opportunities to intervene and prevent further suicides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acknowledgements: The authors of the study would like to thank the Medical Research Council for funding this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/05/understanding-and-preventing-copycat-suicides/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Understanding and preventing copycat suicides&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 10:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/03/Suicide-Blog-pic-1-e1520245604790-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Belief in brain myths and child development myths continues even among those who’ve studied psychology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33387</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/belief-in-brain-myths-and-child-development-myths-continues-even-among-those-whove-studied-psychology/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-532465705.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33407&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33407&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Left and right side of the brain, logic and creativity, vector&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;BlueLela&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Left and right side of the brain, logic and creativity, vector&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Left and right side of the brain, logic and creativity, vector&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-532465705.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-532465705.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-532465705.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1945,1542&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/belief-in-brain-myths-and-child-development-myths-continues-even-among-those-whove-studied-psychology/left-and-right-side-of-the-brain-logic-and-creativity-vector/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-532465705.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite countless myth-busting articles online, dedicated bloggers like &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/&quot;&gt;Neuroskeptic&lt;/a&gt;, and the publication of a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Great-Myths-Brain-Psychology/dp/1118312716&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; described by Ben Goldacre as “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Great_Myths_of_the_Brain.html&quot;&gt;a masterful catalogue of neurobollocks&lt;/a&gt;” (disclaimer: I wrote it), and another in the same series &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Great-Myths-Child-Development-Psychology/dp/1118521234&quot;&gt;addressing child development myths&lt;/a&gt;, public surveys continue to show stubborn, widespread belief in many brain myths and psychology myths, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/20/oh-dear-even-people-with-neuroscience-training-believe-an-awful-lot-of-brain-myths/&quot;&gt;even among people with neuroscience training&lt;/a&gt;. Now the latest survey of the public via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scirp.org/journal/PaperInformation.aspx?PaperID=82576&quot;&gt;published open-access in &lt;em&gt;Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, suggests that little has changed. Belief in many brain and child developmental myths remains rife, even among those who’ve taken psychology courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33387&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prolific psychology researcher and author &lt;a href=&quot;http://adrianfurnham.com&quot;&gt;Adrian Furnham&lt;/a&gt; sourced 56 brain myths from my 2014 book &lt;em&gt;Great Myths of the Brain&lt;/em&gt; and 49 child development myths from the 2015 book &lt;em&gt;Great Myths of Child Development&lt;/em&gt; by Stephen Hupp and Jeremy Jewell. Furnham presented the myths to 220 online participants (aged 19 to 66) and they rated them on a five-point scale from definitely false, probably false to probably true or definitely true, and also including “don’t know”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Great-Myths-Brain-Psychology/dp/1118312716&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-05 10.02.12&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-33405 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33405&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-05 10.02.12&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-02-12.png?w=674&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-02-12.png?w=199&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-02-12.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;674,1018&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/belief-in-brain-myths-and-child-development-myths-continues-even-among-those-whove-studied-psychology/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-02-12/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-02-12.png?w=99&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;99&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Belief in the most infamous brain myths, such as the idea &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-10-brain-myth-explained-in-60-seconds/&quot;&gt;we only use 10 per cent of our brains&lt;/a&gt; or that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-myths/201206/why-the-left-brain-right-brain-myth-will-probably-never-die&quot;&gt;some people are left-brained, others right-brained&lt;/a&gt;“, remains rife, according to this survey (over 40 per cent and 36 per cent of participants said probably or definitely true, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were four brain myths that over 40 per cent of the participants thought were definitely true: that the brain is very well designed; that after head injury, people can forget who they are and not recognise others, but be normal in every other way; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20141118-how-many-senses-do-you-have&quot;&gt;that we have five senses&lt;/a&gt;; and that our brain cells are joined together forming a huge net of nerves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Great-Myths-Child-Development-Psychology/dp/1118521234&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-05 10.01.56&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-33406 alignright&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33406&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-03-05 10.01.56&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-01-56.png?w=642&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-01-56.png?w=195&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-01-56.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;642,990&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/belief-in-brain-myths-and-child-development-myths-continues-even-among-those-whove-studied-psychology/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-01-56/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/screenshot-2018-03-05-10-01-56.png?w=97&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;97&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there were two child development myths that more than 30 per cent of participants thought were definitely true: that all boys have one Y chromosome and all girls do not; and that a woman who is already pregnant can’t get pregnant again. Other strongly endorsed child development myths included the idea that sugar makes kids hyperactive and that dyslexia’s defining feature is letter reversal (65 per cent and 66 per cent believed probably or definitely true, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no evidence that participants’ age, gender or educational background (including specific experience with psychology) made any difference to their endorsement in myths. However, those who rated their own common sense higher endorsed fewer myths, and there was a modest correlation between being more religious and/or more right-wing and endorsing fewer myths (Furnham has no explanation for these “surprising” correlations).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furnham notes that participants were generally disinclined to answer “don’t know” – on average less than a fifth chose this option. “It could be that people were too embarrassed to admit they did not know when indeed the evidence shows quite clearly that they did not,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study has a few issues, such as the lack of detailed information on the participants’ psychology background or their geographical location. There were no “brain facts” interspersed with the myths. Also, Furnham reproduced the wording of the myths verbatim from the books, even though many aren’t that easily understood without the accompany explanatory text from the books (some are also open to different interpretations without contextual explanation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, Furnham says his findings reveal once more “the ‘shocking truth’ about the widespread acceptance of myths” and he warns that they are “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/12/10-ways-brain-myths-harming-us/&quot;&gt;potentially harmful and socially divisive&lt;/a&gt;“. He adds: “The question of how to combat these myths and ensure that people are better informed about various areas of psychology remains largely unanswered.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scirp.org/journal/PaperInformation.aspx?PaperID=82576&quot;&gt;Myths and Misconceptions in Developmental and Neuro-Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Great_Myths_of_the_Brain.html&quot;&gt;Great Myths of the Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 10:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Randomised controlled studies find tea enhances divergent creativity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33400</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/randomised-controlled-studies-find-tea-enhances-divergent-creativity/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-670040428.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33403&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33403&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of a man's head with cup. Mental health relative brochure or report design template. Scientific medical designs. Connected lines with dots. Grunge concrete texture&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of a man's head with cup.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Silhouette of a man’s head with cup.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-670040428.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-670040428.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-670040428.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2148,1396&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/05/randomised-controlled-studies-find-tea-enhances-divergent-creativity/silhouette-of-a-mans-head-with-cup/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-670040428.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950329317303051&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;i&gt;Food Quality and Preference&lt;/i&gt; suggests that tea-drinking benefits divergent thinking, a key element of creativity that’s associated with generating ideas or identifying patterns. The researchers from Peking University greeted their initial 50 student participants with a cup of either hot water or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lipton&quot;&gt;black Lipton tea&lt;/a&gt;, before asking them to use children’s building blocks to make the most attractive design they could. Independent raters, blind to the study purpose and condition, rated the tea-drinkers designs as more creative, in terms of factors like aesthetic appeal, innovativeness and grandness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second study, 40 more participants proposed names for a ramen noodle shop, and judges considered the names produced by tea-drinkers to be more innovative (but no more playful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tea drinking has already been tied to enhanced convergent thinking – coming up with the single correct answer to a problem – but the researchers claim theirs is the first study to find a relationship with more open, explorative thinking. The reasons for the effect aren’t clear: no significant improvement in arousal or positive mood was observed in the tea drinkers, nor did the participants prepare tea themselves, a ritual that some have speculated could help shift mindset. It’s possible that the effect is simply due to relaxation – so why not sit back and enjoy a brew with your next brainstorm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950329317303051&quot;&gt;Drinking tea improves the performance of divergent creativity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 09:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In the future, an AI may diagnose eye problems</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-ai-may-diagnose-eye-problems</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-ai-may-diagnose-eye-problems</link>
	<description>Artificial intelligence could help diagnose blinding eye diseases and other illnesses, speeding up medical care in areas where specialists might be scarce.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/022718_MT_AI-disease-diagnosis_feat.jpg?itok=k-W9PnjU" length="30771" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: 20th anniversary of a fraud; uses and misuses of doubt; how common is scooping?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62318</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/03/weekend-reads-20th-anniversary-of-a-fraud-uses-and-misuses-of-doubt-how-common-is-scooping/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support it?  The week at Retraction Watch featured the story of how two highly cited papers turned out to be wrong; a big prize for a researcher who has been dogged by … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/03/weekend-reads-20th-anniversary-of-a-fraud-uses-and-misuses-of-doubt-how-common-is-scooping/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: 20th anniversary of a fraud; uses and misuses of doubt; how common is scooping?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Critter-finding mission to Antarctica’s Larsen C iceberg scrapped</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctica-larsen-c-iceberg-mission-scrapped</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/antarctica-larsen-c-iceberg-mission-scrapped</link>
	<description>Thick sea ice ended a rapid-response mission to study seafloor that lay beneath Larsen C iceberg.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/blogposts/030218_CG_larsen-c_main.jpg?itok=qoeKhm9b" length="34289" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Scientific Salami Slicing: 33 Papers from 1 Study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9387</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9387</link>
	<description>&quot;Salami slicing&quot; refers to the practice of breaking scientific studies down into small chunks and publishing each part as a seperate paper.



Given that scientists are judged in large part by the number of peer-reviewed papers they produce, it's easy to understand the temptation to engage in salami publication. It's officialy discouraged, but it's still very common to see researchers writing perhaps 3 or 4 papers based on a single project that could, realistically, have been one big paper.</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 11:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Penguin supercolony discovered in Antarctica</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/penguin-supercolony-discovered-antarctica</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/penguin-supercolony-discovered-antarctica</link>
	<description>Scientists have found a penguin supercolony living on tiny, remote Antarctic islands.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/blogposts/030318_KD_penguin_main.jpg?itok=lM_05VMe" length="27581" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Knotted structures called skyrmions seem to mimic ball lightning</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/knotted-structures-called-skyrmions-seem-mimic-ball-lightning</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/knotted-structures-called-skyrmions-seem-mimic-ball-lightning</link>
	<description>Skyrmions in a quantum state of matter have something surprising in common with ball lightning — linked magnetic fields.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030118_EC_new-skyrmion_main.jpg?itok=HI0jHiEe" length="27327" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Loner gas clouds could be a new kind of stellar system</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/loner-gas-clouds-could-be-new-kind-stellar-system</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/loner-gas-clouds-could-be-new-kind-stellar-system</link>
	<description>Weird loner clumps of gas that have wandered for 1 billion years may have been stripped from a trio of larger galaxies.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 16:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/022818_LG_loner-gas-cloud_main.jpg?itok=Mvud4wzw" length="28742" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A “GROSS CASE OF PLAGIARISM:” How did one Elsevier journal plagiarize another?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62294</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/02/a-gross-case-of-plagiarism-how-did-one-elsevier-journal-plagiarize-another/</link>
	<description>When Nicholas Peppas, chair of engineering at the University of Texas at Austin, discovered one of his papers had been plagiarized, he decided to “go public!” On February 27, Peppas tweeted about a “gross case of plagiarism:” He alleged a 2013 review published in Saudi Pharmaceutical Journal had directly copied sections of his 2011 review … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/02/a-gross-case-of-plagiarism-how-did-one-elsevier-journal-plagiarize-another/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A “GROSS CASE OF PLAGIARISM:” How did one Elsevier journal plagiarize another?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 16:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How a vaporized Earth might have cooked up the moon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-moon-formation-space-doughnut</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-moon-formation-space-doughnut</link>
	<description>A high-speed collision turned the early Earth into a hot, gooey space doughnut, and the moon formed within this synestia, a new simulation suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 15:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/022818_HT_moon-formation_main.jpg?itok=TSIa9jW9" length="15485" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Ethical shades of gray:” 90% of researchers in new health field admit to questionable practices</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=62274</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/02/ethical-shades-of-gray-90-of-researchers-in-new-health-field-admit-to-questionable-practices/</link>
	<description>It’s always interesting to know how many researchers in any given field engage in so-called questionable research practices that don’t rise to the level of out-and-out fraud: honorary authorship, citing articles they don’t read, choosing reference lists that would please editors or reviewers, for instance. And when the researchers work in a field with potential … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/03/02/ethical-shades-of-gray-90-of-researchers-in-new-health-field-admit-to-questionable-practices/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;“Ethical shades of gray:” 90% of researchers in new health field admit to questionable practices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 12:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Extreme cold is no match for a new battery</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-cold-no-match-new-battery</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-cold-no-match-new-battery</link>
	<description>A rechargeable battery that works at –70° C could be used in some of the coldest places on Earth or other planets.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030118_MT_cold-battery_feat.jpg?itok=83OLpdDL" length="40133" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Transforming chemistry research to solve tomorrow’s challenges</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transforming-chemistry-research-to-solve-tomorrows-challenges</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transforming-chemistry-research-to-solve-tomorrows-challenges</link>
	<description>Chemistry research is changing rapidly; a professor at the Russian Academy of Sciences explains how his colleagues are seizing opportunities</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 10:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Male and female bosses share the same “classically masculine” personality traits</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33385</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/02/male-and-female-bosses-share-the-same-classically-masculine-personality-traits/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-505412656.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33391&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33391&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait Of Multi-Cultural Business Team In Office&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1444580245&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;monkeybusinessimages&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;59&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait Of Multi-Cultural Business Team In Office&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Portrait Of Multi-Cultural Business Team In Office&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-505412656.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-505412656.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-505412656.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/02/male-and-female-bosses-share-the-same-classically-masculine-personality-traits/portrait-of-multi-cultural-business-team-in-office/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/gettyimages-505412656.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have seen the recent viral &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aMcjxSThD54&quot;&gt;TV interview&lt;/a&gt; in which the Canadian psychologist Jordan Peterson claimed that an important part of the reason there are fewer women than men in leadership positions is to do with personality differences between the sexes. Specifically, he said that women on average score lower than men on traits, such as assertiveness, that are known to be associated with reaching senior roles, and higher on others that work against promotion, especially agreeableness and emotional sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these observations are largely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20161011-do-men-and-women-really-have-different-personalities&quot;&gt;backed by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0021-9010.87.4.765&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt;, what’s far less clear – because the question simply hasn’t been studied much before – is whether women who reach senior management tend to share the traits of men in these positions, or if instead female bosses have a contrasting personality profile, indicative of an alternative, “feminine” route to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are pertinent questions for any one who would like more gender diversity in leadership roles because the findings could point to clues for how to ease the promotion path for women. For a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879118300228&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vocational Behaviour,&lt;/em&gt; a team led by Bart Wille at the University of Antwerp has investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33385&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers accessed comprehensive personality tests taken by nearly 600 top-level executives (including 143 female bosses) and over 52,000 non-executives (including 17,643 women) from diverse industries in Belgium and other European countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men and women in non-leadership roles differed in their personality traits in ways consistent with the existing literature – for instance, women scored higher than men on characteristics associated with being more agreeable, such as being cooperative and people-oriented, while scoring lower on emotional stability and aspects of extraversion. In contrast, the personalities of male and female bosses were far more similar, with many sex-linked differences absent altogether or greatly attenuated (although the women still scored higher on aspects of agreeableness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“…[M]en and women in executive positions demonstrate a similar pattern of classically masculine personality traits,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was reinforced by the within-sex personality comparisons between bosses and non-bosses. Whereas the personality of female managers contrasted sharply with the traits of non-managerial women, male bosses were not so different in their traits from non-managerial men. “Women tend to be lower on traits that lead individuals to pursue and be selected for leadership roles,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this would appear to support the Peterson view: because there are more men with the traits associated with striving for and obtaining leadership than there are women, it could be argued this helps explain the paucity of women in management roles. In turn, helping women develop more stereotypically masculine traits of the kind displayed by the male and female managers in this study, could be one way to enable more women to become bosses. Again, this matches the Peterson perspective – in his Channel 4 interview, he talked about how he has coached women to be more assertive to help them gain promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one problem with this solution is that existing evidence suggests that women often face a &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/10/04/female-bosses-judged-more-harshly-than-male-counterparts-for-being-insensitive-disrespectful/&quot;&gt;backlash&lt;/a&gt; when they display stereotypically masculine traits. Wille and his team mention this issue and they say that “organisations must strive to counter these biases”. Another criticism is that this approach is arguably all about changing women to excel in existing male-dominated hierarchies, rather than changing workplace cultures to make them fairer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, if there were a cultural change, then people with different personality profiles, including more stereotypically feminine traits, might more often reach leadership roles, which would then favour more women. Peterson acknowledged the potential benefits of such a shift in his Channel 4 interview: “It could be the case that if companies modified their behaviour and became more feminine then they would be more successful”, he said, although he added that “there is no evidence for it”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However you choose to interpret the new findings, they help answer a question that many have long speculated about. They suggest that even after several decades with an increasing female presence in the workplace, it remains the case that the same stereotypically masculine traits predict the attainment of senior roles among men and women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many issues remain unanswered and the study had various limitations. For instance, we don’t know if the women with a profile of higher extraversion and lower emotional instability were more likely to become bosses because they harboured more leadership ambitions, or because they had what it takes to overcome the barriers to the top. Also, the study relied on participants rating their own personalities, and it was conducted within a particular culture so the findings may not generalise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This study found that male and female C-level executives represent similar populations with a common profile of characteristic agentic, strategic personality traits,” the researchers concluded. “Ongoing research and practice should acknowledge that gender similarity, not difference, characterises leader personality and potential.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879118300228&quot;&gt;Personality characteristics of male and female executives: Distinct pathways to success?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 09:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Early land plants led to the rise of mud</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/early-land-plants-led-rise-mud</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/early-land-plants-led-rise-mud</link>
	<description>New research suggests early land plants called bryophytes, which include modern mosses, helped shape Earth’s surface by creating clay-rich river deposits.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 21:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/03/main/articles/030118_CG_mudplants_feat.jpg?itok=DuQXqbqh" length="464336" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: It’s official: Termites are just cockroaches with a fancy social life</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/its-official-termites-are-just-cockroaches</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/its-official-termites-are-just-cockroaches</link>
	<description>On their latest master list of arthropods, U.S. entomologists have finally declared termites to be a kind of cockroach.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/02/main/articles/022318_SM_termites_main.jpg?itok=htv-ww33" length="25352" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Musical universals: people can identify lullabies and dance songs from other cultures</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33375</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/01/musical-universals-people-can-identify-lullabies-and-dance-songs-from-other-cultures/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-149147996.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-33376&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;33376&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Music instruments icon set in globe world map background. Vector file available.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;cienpies&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Music instruments in world map&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Music instruments in world map&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-149147996.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-149147996.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-149147996.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2176,1378&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/03/01/musical-universals-people-can-identify-lullabies-and-dance-songs-from-other-cultures/music-instruments-in-world-map/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/02/gettyimages-149147996.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter where they live, people interpret certain kinds of vocalisations, even from animals, as conveying a particular emotion – as “angry”, for instance, or “soothing”. It’s tempting to think that there might be similar cross-cultural universals in the ways that we use music – that a song used to calm an infant in Melanesia, say, should bear striking similarities to a song created for the same purpose by a culture in the Arctic Circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s tempting if you’re a cognitive scientist – though not if you’re an ethnomusicologist (who studies music from different cultures), according to a survey of the opinions of academics reported in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/current-biology/abstract/S0960-9822(17)31675-5&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt;, published in &lt;i&gt;Current Biology&lt;/i&gt;. “Historically, the idea that there might be universals in music from many cultures has been met with considerable scepticism, especially among music scholars,” note the authors of the study, led by Samuel Mehr at Harvard University, which then goes on to explore whether they do exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33375&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team recruited 750 online participants from 60 countries. They listened to a random sample of 36 excerpts of songs taken from the &lt;i&gt;Natural History of Song&lt;/i&gt; discography, which includes vocal music from 86 predominantly small-scale societies – such as love songs from the Fulani society of pastoralists from Western Africa, lullabies from Igluik Inuit hunger-gatherers from the Arctic Circle, and dance songs by a society of horticulturalists from Melanesia. “The broad range of cultures and languages…combined with the many countries of origin of the participants makes it likely that participants were both unfamiliar with the music they heard and unable to understand the lyrics,” the researchers note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These particular songs were chosen because each represented one of four specific social functions: “for dancing”, “to soothe a baby”, “to heal illness” and “to express love for another person”. The participants’ task was to indicate, on six-point scales, the degree to which they believed each song was used for each of those four reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The listeners were fairly accurate at judging which songs were intended “for dancing” or “to soothe a baby”. They were less competent at recognising healing songs: while they were generally of the opinion that these songs were not “for dancing”, they found it hard to judge whether they were for healing or for soothing a baby. The participants were least accurate at spotting “love songs”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second experiment, the researchers explored which features of the various songs the listeners might have been using to make their judgements. Using 500 participants from India and 500 from the US, they found that dance songs were rated as having higher melodic complexity, a faster tempo and a steadier beat, for example, relative to the three other song types. Lullabies, meanwhile, were rated as having lower melodic complexity, lower rhythmic complexity, a slower tempo and a less steady beat than the other three types. It seems likely then that these are culturally universal characteristics shared by music that serves these functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we can’t be entirely sure this is the case. As the researchers note, all the participants in these experiments had access to the internet, so while in theory there was no reason to think that a listener from India would have been familiar with lullabies from the Arctic, they might have been. More likely, they may already have heard various songs with different uses from different cultures, and this experience, rather than cultural universals in the use of music, might have influenced the participants’ conclusions. “A stronger test of universality would require testing the inferences of people living in isolated societies with minimal access to the music of other cultures,” the researchers note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, overall, “these findings are consistent with the existence of universal form-function links in human song,” the researchers argue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(17)31675-5&quot;&gt;Form and Function in Human Song&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Research suggests link between suicidal ideation and low blood pressure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9976</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/01/research-suggests-link-suicidal-ideation-low-blood-pressure/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/AdobeStock_139538849-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most studies on blood pressure (BP) have focused on high BP, whereas studies on low BP are rare. Unlike hypertension, constitutional low BP is not considered to be related to serious illness or death, and it is widely accepted that ‘the lower the BP, the better’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was not difficult to find people who complain, ‘I’m dizzy because my blood pressure is low’ or ‘I feel down because of my low blood pressure’. This raised our suspicions about the common perception that low blood pressure is not really a problem, and thus marked the beginning of our research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using data from the 2010-2013 Korea National Health and Nutrition survey, we compared 10,708 people with either normal or low blood pressure. Suicidal ideation was identified by asking one of two questions: “Have you ever felt inclined to commit suicide over the last year?” (2010-2012) and “Have you ever considered suicide seriously over the last year?” (2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results showed that among people with normal blood pressure, the proportion of those with suicidal ideation was 10.8%. This proportion increased for people with lower blood pressures: those with systolic blood pressure (SBP) &amp;lt;100 mmHg the proportion was 12.5%; those with SBP &amp;lt;95 mmHg, 13.7%; and those with SBP &amp;lt;90 mmHg, 16.6%. In other words the lower the blood pressure, the higher the percentage of people with suicidal thought. Observing the distribution of low blood pressure among those with suicidal thought and those without, we came to the following assumption: Low blood pressure may explain a higher risk of suicidal thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Observing the distribution of low blood pressure among those with suicidal thought and those without, we came to the following assumption: Low blood pressure may explain a higher risk of suicidal thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then analyzed the risk of suicidal ideation present in people with low blood pressure after controlling for potential confounding variables such as gender, age, BMI and underlying diseases. As a result, people with a systolic blood pressure lower than 100 mmHg were shown to have more than 25% higher odds of suicide ideation than those with normal blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also found that increasing the strictness of the criteria for low BP led to a more pronounced tendency towards suicidal ideation. That is, the odds of suicidal ideation for the low blood pressure group with a cut-off value of SBP&amp;lt; 95 mmHg and SBP &amp;lt;90 mmHg was 43% and 74% higher, respectively, than that of the normal pressure group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to looking at low blood pressure, we also investigated the risk of suicidal thought at high blood pressure. However, there were no statistically significant differences between the risk of suicidal ideation among the higher blood pressure groups (pre-hypertensive and hypertensive) and that of the normotensive group. Therefore, low blood pressure may pose its own different health issues in comparison to high blood pressure. Our study hereby challenges the perception that, in terms of mental health, lower blood pressure is always better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, this study is a cross-sectional study and cannot verify the causal relationship between low blood pressure and suicidal ideation. The study’s use of self-reported survey data may have introduced information and recall bias. As only levels of systolic blood pressure were used to define low blood pressure, future studies are needed to explore the relationship between suicidal ideation and diastolic blood pressure. Further research is also needed into the possible biological mechanisms that may explain the association between blood pressure and suicidal ideation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is the first to investigate the association between low BP and suicidal ideation, which is an indicator of a negative psychiatric state, and thus underscores the need to re-evaluate the health implications of low BP. This may also call for careful monitoring of the mental health conditions of those with low BP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/03/01/research-suggests-link-suicidal-ideation-low-blood-pressure/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Research suggests link between suicidal ideation and low blood pressure&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/02/AdobeStock_139538849-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
