<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: A cheesy story: How media coverage creates opportunities for researchers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/a-cheesy-story-how-media-coverage-creates-opportunities-for-researchers</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/a-cheesy-story-how-media-coverage-creates-opportunities-for-researchers</link>
	<description>What makes a study hit the headlines, and how do you measure the impact when it does?</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 08:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: New research reveals the long-term toll of keeping secrets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29878</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/13/new-research-reveals-the-long-term-toll-of-keeping-secrets/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29877&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-639794440.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29877&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29877&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Thoughtful woman in the park&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1485440995&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Martin Dimitrov&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0015625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Unhappy girl sitting at bench&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Unhappy girl sitting at bench&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-639794440.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-639794440.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-639794440.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/unhappy-girl-sitting-at-bench/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-639794440.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;It is mind-wandering about our secrets that most seems to take a toll, rather than the job of concealing them&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secrets burden minds. To understand how, researchers have previously focused on the act of concealment during one-off social interactions, showing that keeping a secret is draining and can increase anxiety. But what about the longer-term toll? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-20428-001&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Attitudes and Social Cognition &lt;/i&gt;describes ten studies on the impact of secrecy day-on-day, showing how the burden of a secret peppers our waking life with reminders and periods of brooding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29878&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Columbia University team – Michael Slepian, Jinseok Chun, and Malia Mason – first developed and validated a secrets survey with two thousand participants. From this they identified 38 classes of secrets covering a range of contexts from theft and drug use to sexual orientation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the new survey with 600 more participants (for most of the paper, participants were recruited from an online portal and tended to be in their thirties), the researchers found that 96 per cent of them currently had a secret of some kind, most commonly romantic thoughts about someone outside their relationship, sexual behaviour, or emotional infidelity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also asked participants to consider the past month and report how often they were in a situation where they had to conceal their secret, and how often their mind wandered to the secret when there was no need for concealment. Mind-wandering was twice as common as episodes involving concealment, and crucially, it was how often participants caught themselves thinking about the secret – but not how often they had to actively conceal it – that was associated with the impact of the secret on their lives, as measured by their ratings of how much “this secret made my life and well-being worse”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This apparently adverse effect of thinking about our secrets was replicated in a survey of tourists canvassed in New York. These findings suggest that active concealment – the primary focus of most secrecy research, and tightly wound into its scientific definition – may not be the defining characteristic of secrecy, and that it may rather be the repeated reflections upon hidden information that enact a greater psychological toll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this research hasn’t shown a causal link between secret-related mind-wandering and wellbeing because the results are correlational (it would be hard to test this experimentally because it would be unethical to insert troubling life secrets into people’s lives). It seems likely that the association is at least partly caused by some toxic secrets both springing into mind more readily and having their own directly harmful influence on a person’s life. However, further analysis showed that higher secret-related mind-wandering still correlated with lower wellbeing regardless of the importance of a secret or the deviancy of the information it contained – suggesting repetitive thoughts about any kind of secret can take a toll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about secrets that are more obviously troubling to conceal (such as hiding an affair or trauma from a loved one) – might the act of concealment itself take a greater toll in these situations? To check this, the researchers focused in further studies on weightier secrets that the participants felt guilty for keeping from their partner. Yet participants still described mind-wandering about the secret more often than having to conceal it (one longitudinal study estimated mind wandering to be 2.5 times more frequent than concealment). And again, more frequent mind-wandering was associated with lower wellbeing, both in terms of diminished life satisfaction and relationship quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If these results are accurate and mind-wandering about secrets really does chip away at our wellbeing, what is the psychological process? It’s psychologically harmful to ruminate on negative thoughts or memories, and recalling a secret often involves accessing such content, so perhaps the same process is at play? It seems not. Slepian’s team asked 186 more participants to either recall a negative life event known to their partner or a secret they kept from them. Participants considered the negative life event more unpleasant than did those in the secret group, but it was the latter group who reported feeling less satisfied with life in that moment, suggesting that this wellbeing drop wasn’t simply a matter of bad feeling. Rather, the secrecy-related dissatisfaction was associated with a self-reported sense of weakened authenticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often feel forced to keep a secret because we fear the cost of revealing it. But this research suggests that the secret is already costing you, even when you’re not actively concealing it, through a steady drip of reminders that makes you resent your own obstruction of a well-lived life. That doesn’t mean that it’s straightforward to put aside the deception. But if you can find a way, it may change how you experience life: not just through the big release, but a freer mental space, day on day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-20428-001&quot;&gt;The experience of secrecy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29878/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29878/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29878&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 07:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: UK gender-equality scheme spreads across the world</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549143a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/m8APM3_pdOY/549143a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The United States is set to trial a version that will also cover race and disability, while other countries have already embraced the voluntary rating system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 143 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549143a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549143a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/m8APM3_pdOY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Like sea stars, ancient echinoderms nibbled with tiny tube feet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-stars-ancient-echinoderms-nibbled-tiny-tube-feet</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sea-stars-ancient-echinoderms-nibbled-tiny-tube-feet</link>
	<description>An ancient echinoderm fossil preserves evidence of tube feet like those found on today’s sea stars.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 23:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/091217_LH_tube-feet_main_FREE.jpg?itok=i3F4JFCl" length="31985" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How hurricanes and other devastating disasters spur scientific research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/hurricanes-disasters-scientific-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/hurricanes-disasters-scientific-research</link>
	<description>Hurricanes such as Harvey, Irma and others have been devastating, even deadly, yet they drive our desire for scientific discovery.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 21:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/091217_AY_hurricane_main.jpg?itok=Yni2552H" length="28158" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Copenhagen revokes degree of controversial neuroscientist Milena Penkowa</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51765</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/copenhagen-revokes-degree-controversial-neuroscientist-milena-penkowa/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Copenhagen has stripped Milena Penkowa of her doctoral degree, after determining she had covered up problems with her research. According to a release issued today by the university, Penkowa falsified documents to allay suspicions that she had not performed some animal experiments as she’d reported. This development is the latest in a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/copenhagen-revokes-degree-controversial-neuroscientist-milena-penkowa/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Copenhagen revokes degree of controversial neuroscientist Milena Penkowa&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 19:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: To Sign or Not to Sign: A Slice of Transparency in Peer Review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7721</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/veLAChjX0Ow/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/09/slice-of-pie-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp_orcid_field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://orcid.org/0000-0001-7318-5892&quot; rel=&quot;author&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;0000-0001-7318-5892&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists depend on the proper evaluation of research that creates the foundation for future work, and the public expects curated scientific content to be trustworthy. All forms of peer review, whether for ethical, technical and sound science criteria or for additional novelty, significance and perceived impact help ensure rigor in scientific research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, however, community and public skepticism regarding the quality, trustworthiness and authenticity of the review process, from the initial stage of evaluation before reviewer assignment to the final editorial decision. Making peer review more transparent, at any stage, has the potential to revitalize the process and restore trust in the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efforts to increase transparency in peer review should address challenges that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2016/09/how-review-paper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Training and mentoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://violentmetaphors.com/2013/12/13/how-to-become-good-at-peer-review-a-guide-for-young-scientists/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;how to review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/higher-education-network/blog/2013/sep/27/peer-review-10-tips-research-paper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;see ten tips here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable publisher &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/research/openscience/index.cfm?pg=home&amp;amp;section=monitor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open science and transparency policies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A process that is static in time and in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002506&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;number of people that participate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insights made during the review process often go &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/occams-corner/2015/sep/07/peer-review-preprints-speed-science-journals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;uncaptured or remain hidden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reshaping Peer Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is already happening as the scientific community develops variations on themes of open and transparent, and as publishers provide more peer review offerings that range from community participation to open but anonymous, to fully open and signed reviews. While not yet functioning at scale, experiments incorporating more transparent ways to discuss and assess papers over the entire lifecycle of the research are inching their way into practice. This way, the publication of an article isn’t the single defining event in its life; it is just one chapter of its story. Many of the arguments in favor of increased transparency in peer review also hold true in the discussion of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/occams-corner/2015/sep/07/peer-review-preprints-speed-science-journals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;benefits of preprint submissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. According to researchers working with neuroimaging, as stated in their &lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/article?id=10.1371/journal.pbio.1002506&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Community Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, “preprints allow the wider community to give feedback to the authors about the manuscript and potentially improve it, which is beneficial for both the authors as well as the journal the paper will be submitted to. For example, the present paper received useful comments from three individuals in addition to the appointed peer reviewers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Question of Signing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At PLOS, we’ve looked at one slice of transparency in peer review—signed reviews made available exclusively to the authors. In a research project that used a survey mechanism to collect experiences and opinions, our Publishing Operations team underwent an assessment of reviews from 2013-2016 in three of the PLOS journals (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our reviewer community is particularly engaged, and that’s what makes working at PLOS on this issue so exciting. Together we will be able to create solutions, both incremental and substantial, that bring constructive feedback to authors and transparency to the review process.” Helen Atkins, PLOS Director of Publishing Operations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of what we learned is that reviewers who were not in the habit of signing reviews simply had never been asked, or were not sure of the benefits. But it’s not as easy as just educating in these areas. These scientists also indicated that not signing allows them to be more honest and safe from retribution. We also discovered that signing can improve reviewer accountability and constructiveness, and help authors learn of a reviewer’s area of expertise. Authors who favored receiving signed reviews valued having this additional information as it provides potential for more open communication, moving research forward. The full results of this project, presented by Elizabeth Seiver, PLOS Researcher and Helen Atkins are part of the Editorial and Peer-Review Process Innovations Session on Tuesday, September 12 during the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peerreviewcongress.org/program-information&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;International Congress on Peer Review and Scientific Publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple but Substantive Practices &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; article “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0147913&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peer Review Quality and Transparency of the Peer-Review Process in Open Access and Subscription Journals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,” the focus is a general aspect of transparency in peer review—how academic journals (and/or publishers) present their peer-review process to the public. According to the authors of this study, a transparent peer review system “conveys to readers and potential contributors how the peer review is implemented and how articles are selected for publication.” The researchers found that “author’s ratings of peer-review transparency predicted their assessment of the quality of peer-review at that journal.”  Even small changes in practices and on publisher websites can help in this area. In addition, guidelines from the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Committee on Publication Ethics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://publicationethics.org/files/Principles_of_Transparency_and_Best_Practice_in_Scholarly_Publishing.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Principles of Transparency and Best Practice in Scholarly Publishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,” stating that all journal content apart from editorial material should be subject to peer review from outside experts must be met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning from Early Career Researchers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many ECRs do not get appropriate training on how to prepare or review manuscripts. Improved transparency in peer review would not only satisfy mid-to senior-level scientists, but in providing some form of open dialogue or open accountability it enables these scientists to lead by example and provide mentorship to the next generation of reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young and upcoming scientists have plenty of ideas when it comes to improving transparency in peer review. At PLOS, we received over 150 essays on how to revamp peer review from Early Career Researchers applying for our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/ecr-travel-awards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ECR Travel Award Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. These creative young scientists described what they consider to be characteristics of the optimal peer review process and how they might build this process either from scratch or using aspects of existing practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their ideas, edited for brevity, include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite reviewers to publish reviews of the article (should they wish to reveal their identity) as an accompanying commentary, for no additional fee. If reviewers know they could gain an additional publication for their efforts, this would motivate them to review more articles and respond in a constructive and timely fashion. Victoria Leong; orcid.org/0000-0003-0666-9445&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Provide] incentives for reviewing that encourages kind, open but fair responses; we would also be affecting a positive change in the culture of science; which will advance the science itself. Rebecca Gelding; orcid.org/0000-0003-4883-8075&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews should be open, archived and after publication, reviewers should be revealed. This aims to ensure two aspects of quality control: reviewers take more seriously their job since it will be public with their name tag on it; and reviewing records can be used when considering career development. Juan Rocha; orcid.org/0000-0003-2322-5459&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review record should also be one of the criteria judging and advancing a researcher’s professional development. Knowing that a reviewer’s identify would be revealed later and shared among peers, a reviewer would have more incentive to avoid giving low-quality comments. Xiao-Peng Song; orcid.org/0000-0002-5514-0321&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A transparent, open review process may promote accountability among reviewers. A peer reviewer whose dated comments are published as supplementary material with the article has a greater incentive to conduct a thorough and timely review of the manuscript. These same published comments could also be accessed by other researchers who are struggling to address similar issues in their own studies. Sericea Stallings-Smith; orcid.org/0000-0002-4876-9965&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slices of the Transparency Pie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solutions that will help peer review achieve its scholarly ideal are not untenable; the challenge lies in that they must satisfy a diverse researcher and stakeholder community. While some improvements are easier to implement than others, even small slices that expedite and enrich the process of assessment in fundamentally new ways contribute to advancing science and discovery for the broader scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishers have an opportunity to improve both speed and efficiencies: to improve review forms that may be cumbersome or insufficient to provide thoughtful and constructive feedback to authors and to provide training for reviewers and editors that mitigate potential bias. Additional possibilities include direct or facilitated mentoring of early career researchers to improve their understanding of the principles of peer review and how it is practiced within the scientific community. Imagine the impact of a global editorial and reviewer contributor community, appropriately trained, recognized and incentivized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more insights on peer review listen to the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOScast episodes&lt;/a&gt; and read the following posts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The PLOS Blogs Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLOScasts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of the history of peer review, how it’s changed over time, and the increased demand for transparency with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/04/18/the-history-of-scientific-publishing-an-interview-with-aileen-fyfe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aileen Fyfe of University of St. Andrews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lively discussion on the future of scientific collaboration and publishing, including transparency in peer review, with former PLOS Advocacy Director &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2015/10/19/introducing-ploscast-a-podcast-on-on-science-academia-and-the-future-of-scholarship/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cameron Neylon, currently at Curtin University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how Knowledge Lab applies informatics and systems modeling to understand relationships between researchers, reviewers and the review process with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2017/01/24/science-of-peer-review-an-interview-with-eamon-duede-part-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eamon Duende of the University of Chicago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas on how to stay up to date on all the scientific literature and the potential of preprints in paving the way for a more transparent peer review process with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/2016/10/24/the-power-of-preprints-an-interview-with-james-fraser/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Fraser of University of California, San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLOS BLOGS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PLOS Collections (Staff blog)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/report-plos-igem-realtime-peer-review-jamboree/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Report – PLOS iGEM Realtime Peer Review Jamboree&lt;/a&gt;. 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PLOS Paleo (PLOS Community blog)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/paleocomm/2017/09/10/peer-review-week-2017-peer-review-from-a-volunteer-editors-perspective/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peer Review from a Volunteer Editor’s Perspective&lt;/a&gt;. 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absolutely Maybe (Indie blog)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/absolutely-maybe/2017/09/11/good-enough-editors-statistics-grant-peer-review-prc8-day-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Good Enough? Editors, Statistics &amp;amp; Grant Peer Review: PRC8 Day 2&lt;/a&gt;. 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Science Blogs (Indie blog)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/onscienceblogs/2017/09/09/pubmed-and-its-post-publication-peer-review-tool-pubmed-commons/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed Commons and Post Publication Peer Review&lt;/a&gt;. 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PLOS Biologue (Staff blog)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/biologue/2013/08/08/what-does-peer-review-mean-when-applied-to-computer-code/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What does peer review mean when applied to computer code?&lt;/a&gt;  2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image Credit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Etsy; FuzzyButtFarm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/veLAChjX0Ow&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 15:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Bone researcher is up to 17 retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51732</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/bone-researcher-17-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A bone researcher has lost three more papers for scientific misconduct. The new retractions bring Yoshihiro Sato’s total to 17 and put him on our Leaderboard. According to the retraction notices, Sato asked the Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry to retract three of his papers “due to scientific misconduct.” In the letter, Sato—who is corresponding […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/bone-researcher-17-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bone researcher is up to 17 retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In these bot hookups, the machines meld their minds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-bot-hookups-machines-meld-their-minds</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-bot-hookups-machines-meld-their-minds</link>
	<description>A new type of robot can team up with its fellows to form a single-minded machine.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090817_MT_conglomerate-bot_main.jpg?itok=ukhYZ_cX" length="21056" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Should Research Funding Be Distributed Equally Among Scientists?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9103</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9103</link>
	<description>Instead of making scientists compete for grants based on project proposals, research funding could simply be divided equally among all 'qualified' researchers, according to a new paper.



Authors Krist Vaesen and Joel Katzav argue that such an 'egalitarian' distribution of funds would still leave each grant holder with enough money to support their work and pay for students and junior researchers. But I'm not sure I agree with their logic.



Vaesen and Katzav start by outlining the pro</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 13:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Fertility docs said their study didn’t need ethics review. An investigation said they were wrong.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51720</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/fertility-docs-said-study-didnt-need-ethics-review-investigation-said-wrong/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal is retracting a paper on the relative merits of one fertility procedure compared to another because the study never received ethical review or approval. In the paper, “Intracytoplasmic morphologically selected sperm injection versus conventional intracytoplasmic sperm injection: a randomized controlled trial,” originally published Aug. 27, 2015 in Reproductive Biology and Endocrinology, the authors […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/12/fertility-docs-said-study-didnt-need-ethics-review-investigation-said-wrong/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fertility docs said their study didn’t need ethics review. An investigation said they were wrong.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: The Martian had a lot of problems. Anemia probably wasn’t one of them.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9499</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/12/the-martian-had-a-lot-of-problems-anemia-probably-wasnt-one-of-them/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Astronaut_working_on_Mars-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spaceflight poses various risks to the human body as it is displaced from the Earth’s life-supporting environment to the less benign conditions encountered in space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These conditions include radiation; confinement in small, enclosed spaces with associated physical and psychological stressors; disrupted circadian rhythms; and, of course, microgravity. They take a toll on the human body, affecting vision, the musculoskeletal system, and the immune system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists at NASA are researching the risks associated with short and long duration space missions, such as spending more than six months on the ISS or – the next giant leap – a mission to Mars. A recent discovery by a team at NASA Johnson Space center suggests that one of these risks may not be as much of a problem as previously assumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Space flight anemia – the reduction of circulating red blood cells (RBCs) during time spent in space – is a generally accepted phenomenon. However, the majority of the studies examining changes to concentrations of red blood cells during spaceflight have been limited to evaluations of short-duration missions after astronauts had returned to earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The few evaluations made while astronauts were still in space have been conducted during short-duration flights, before the astronauts’ bodies had fully adapted to microgravity. Their findings may not accurately reflect what happens to red blood cells during long-duration flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmchematol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12878-017-0083-y&quot;&gt;study published this month&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmchematol.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Hematology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, a team of researchers used living, whole blood samples collected from astronauts aboard the International Space Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Richard Simpson, associate professor at The University of Arizona and the University of Houston, a co-author of the study explained: “This unique sample allowed us to track hematological parameters – such as concentrations of red blood cells (RBCs), hemoglobin or hematocrit – in astronauts on board the International Space Station &lt;em&gt;during&lt;/em&gt; flight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first study to show that RBC concentrations and hematocrit remain at higher levels even after astronauts’ bodies have adapted to microgravity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The samples were collected from 31 astronauts (six women and 25 men) who spent up to six months on the ISS. Blood was drawn at various time points before, during and after the astronauts’ time in space: at 180 and 45 days before they flew to the ISS, during their first two weeks in space, and approximately three and six months into the mission. The samples were sent to Earth within 48 hours of collection for analysis either in Houston or at Star City, Russia. Post-flight samples were collected three to eight hours after landing and 30 days after the mission had ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that during space flight, concentrations of RBCs, platelets and the oxygen-carrying protein hemoglobin were higher compared to pre-flight levels. Hematocrit (the ratio of RBCs to the total volume of blood) also increased during space flight. While previous studies had shown this to be the case during the first few days of flight, this is the first study to show that RBC concentrations and hematocrit remain at higher levels even after astronauts’ bodies have adapted to microgravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the changes observed in the in-flight blood samples were to be expected due to the 48-hour processing delay between sample collection and analysis (delays affect the concentration of various components of collected blood samples), but the changes in hematocrit during spaceflight were striking, according to the researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hematocrit had increased by 12.2%, 12.2% and 10.0% at early, mid, and late time points during space flight compared to pre-flight levels. However, only a 4.7% increase in hematocrit was observed in reference samples taken on earth from non-astronauts after the 48-hour processing delay. This suggests that the increases observed in the ISS samples are partly due to a true in-flight increase in RBC count. After the astronauts examined in this study returned to Earth, all blood parameters returned to pre-flight levels within 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings have to be interpreted within the context of the effects that microgravity has on body fluids, according to the study. For example, without the constant gravitational force that is present on Earth, fluids shift towards the head, resulting in a “puffy” face and a reduced leg volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Simpson said: “Although the data does not indicate that significant anemia is present, it must be interpreted in the context of crew plasma volume during flight. Overall plasma volume has been shown to be reduced during spaceflight, but this has not been assessed during long-duration missions. In order to fully interpret the changes to RBC, hematocrit and other parameters observed in this study, further research into plasma volume during long space missions is needed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/12/the-martian-had-a-lot-of-problems-anemia-probably-wasnt-one-of-them/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Martian had a lot of problems. Anemia probably wasn’t one of them.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 11:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Astronaut_working_on_Mars-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: HardwareX journal reveals the equipment behind the science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hardwarex-journal-reveals-the-equipment-behind-the-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/hardwarex-journal-reveals-the-equipment-behind-the-science</link>
	<description>Open-access platform opens opportunities for researchers by making designs reproducible and crediting the creators</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 10:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Mentally well voice-hearers have a heightened ability to detect real speech</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/12/mentally-well-voice-hearers-have-a-heightened-ability-to-detect-real-speech/</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/12/mentally-well-voice-hearers-have-a-heightened-ability-to-detect-real-speech/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29870&quot; style=&quot;width: 1400px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-12 09.49.55.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29870&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29870&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-12 09.49.55&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-12-09-49-55.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-12-09-49-55.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-12-09-49-55.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1400,538&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/screenshot-2017-09-12-09-49-55/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-12-09-49-55.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(A) Averaged brain activity in response to intelligible speech in control participants and (B) in non-clinical voice hearers; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/doi/10.1093/brain/awx206/4085330/Distinct-processing-of-ambiguous-speech-in-people&quot;&gt;Alderson-Day et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hallucinating voices isn’t always distressing. While the experience is commonly associated with schizophrenia, some people – an estimated 5 to 15 per cent of the general population – hear voices that aren’t real without finding it upsetting or debilitating  (they may even welcome it) and in the absence of any of the other symptoms of psychosis, such as delusions or confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/doi/10.1093/brain/awx206/4085330/Distinct-processing-of-ambiguous-speech-in-people&quot;&gt;new open-access research published in &lt;em&gt;Brain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has revealed a perceptual advantage for this group of people: they can detect hard-to-comprehend speech sounds more quickly and easily than people who have never hallucinated a voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29871&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study, led by Ben Alderson-Day at the University of Durham, involved twelve “non-clinical voice hearers” and 17 controls (matched for age, sex, handedness, education, and National Adult Reading Test scores) who do not hear voices. While their brains were scanned using fMRI, the volunteers listened to a series of so-called “sine-wave” speech recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These recordings of spoken sentences – such as “The clown had a funny face” – were acoustically altered so that they were either totally unintelligible, or potentially intelligible. Initially, many people report that potentially intelligible sine-wave speech sounds like “aliens” or birdsong. But with training, it’s possible to recognise and understand the distorted words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first part of the study, the volunteers had no idea that it was about speech perception. They were asked simply to press a button every time they heard a distinctive target sound. It was only after 20 minutes that they were asked if they’d noticed any words or sentences among the recordings they’d just listened to, and if so, to indicate when they had first noticed them and whether they had been able to understand any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine out of 12 voice-hearers (75 per cent) said they’d realised words were contained in the sounds, compared with eight (47 per cent) of the non voice-hearers, and the voice-hearers noticed the words earlier, on average. Seven of the voice-hearers and five of the controls said they could understand the words, and five in each group could accurately recall some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this first 20-minute run, the volunteers were trained in how to listen for words in sine-wave speech. Then the trial was repeated, and, afterwards they were again queried about what they’d heard. For both groups, the training helped, but this time, the voice-hearers’ performance was no better than the controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other work on people in the early stages of psychosis has found that they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26460044&quot;&gt;better at identifying objects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;in an ambiguous visual scene than healthy controls, &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; they are primed about what to look for. Prior expectation seems to give them a superior ability – compared with controls – to spot genuine signals in noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, being explicitly primed to listen for speech didn’t benefit the voice-hearers any more than the controls, so something different seems to be going on compared with the detection of visual patterns in psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fMRI scans showed that, like the controls, the voice-hearers’ brains responded differently to potentially intelligible versus unintelligible sine-wave-speech. This suggests that voice-hearers aren’t biased to hear speech in any sound, but only when there is the possibility of a meaningful signal being present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scans also revealed a key difference between the brain activity of the voice-hearers and the controls. In both, the potentially intelligible recordings engaged the brain network typically active in normal voice processing, but the voice-hearers showed stronger responses to this kind of speech in two regions: the dorsal anterior cingulate cortex and the superior frontal gyrus (responses that were not seen when the recording was unintelligible).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This suggests an enhanced involvement of attention and sensorimotor processes, selectively when speech was potentially intelligible,” the research team writes. “This suggests that the fundamental mechanisms underlying hallucination involve – and may develop from – ordinary perceptual processes, illustrating the continuity of mundane and unusual experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has implications for understanding the significant number of people who hallucinate voices but do not need psychiatric care. It also feeds in to the idea that, within the general population, there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11702510&quot;&gt;continuum of experiences normally associated – in their extremes – with psychosis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/brain/article/doi/10.1093/brain/awx206/4085330/Distinct-processing-of-ambiguous-speech-in-people&quot;&gt;Distinct processing of ambiguous speech in people with non-clinical auditory verbal hallucinations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29871/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29871/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29871&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 08:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Wallaby milk acts as a placenta for babies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22587</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CsK42NW_9mE/nature.2017.22587</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Gene-expression analysis suggests that marsupial placentas take two different forms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22587&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22587&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CsK42NW_9mE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Jordan seeks to become an oasis of water-saving technology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549142a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/iAqBnbM1c24/549142a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;As strains on the desert nation’s supply increase, scientists collaborate on projects to keep water flowing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549142a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549142a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/iAqBnbM1c24&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Faculty promotion must assess reproducibility</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549133a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/jfMzE0Z78So/549133a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Research institutions should explicitly seek job candidates who can be frankly self-critical of their work, says Jeffrey Flier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 133 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549133a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549133a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/jfMzE0Z78So&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Giraffes could have evolved long necks to keep cool</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549132a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Rhbdm382JNY/549132a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Another explanation offered for one of animal kingdom’s most distinctive features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 132 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549132a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549132a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Rhbdm382JNY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The sun’s strongest flare in 11 years might help explain a solar paradox</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-solar-flares-paradox</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-solar-flares-paradox</link>
	<description>The sun tends to release its biggest flares at the ends of solar cycles — and we might finally be able to test why.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/091117_lg_solarflares_feat_free.jpg?itok=5mszEDyq" length="17544" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Final flyby puts Cassini on a collision course with Saturn</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/titan-flyby-cassini-saturn-collision</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/titan-flyby-cassini-saturn-collision</link>
	<description>A “last kiss goodbye” with Saturn’s largest moon sent the Cassini spacecraft on its final trajectory into the planet’s atmosphere.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 20:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/091117_LG_cassini_ticker_main.jpg?itok=nwDbVNlW" length="7942" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Releases Latest Version of its Enterprise Dynamic Report Tool</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1127</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/09/science-exchange-releases-latest-version-of-its-enterprise-dynamic-report-tool/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Latest release gives enterprise clients access to real-time data to improve reporting &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;and decision-making for outsourced R&amp;amp;D investments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/dynamic-report-tool-blog-post-e1505137229947.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dynamic Report Tool&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-1128&quot; height=&quot;161&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/dynamic-report-tool-blog-post-300x171.png&quot; width=&quot;283&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, Sept. 11, 2017 –&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Demonstrating the company’s commitment to support its clients’ growth plans by optimizing data aggregation and business intelligence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D), recently released the latest version of its enterprise dynamic report tool. The tool enables Science Exchange’s enterprise clients, including some of the world’s top pharma and biotech companies, to perform real-time tracking of key performance indicators (KPIs) related to their outsourced R&amp;amp;D investments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“The Science Exchange enterprise dynamic report gives me the ability to tease out diverse suppliers and export spend data. Our procurement management team has been thrilled with the report,” said Greg Smith, Associate Director, Indirect R&amp;amp;D Procurement, Teva Pharmaceuticals Industries, Ltd.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;This latest enterprise dynamic report update allows enterprise clients like &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Teva Pharmaceuticals Industries, Ltd., &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Track spend, budget performance, and outsourcing efficiency in real time;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Gain visibility into service provider performance metrics; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Better assess efficiency of outsourced R&amp;amp;D programs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“With this dynamic reporting tool, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;our enterprise clients are able to gain a whole new understanding of category-specific purchasing behaviors within their organizations. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;R&amp;amp;D and procurement leaders can receive and proactively analyze – in real time – data and business intelligence that can help them quickly assess the performance and impact of their outsourced R&amp;amp;D programs,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “Science Exchange helps our clients make data-driven business decisions, while at the same time giving researchers quick and secure access to more than 2,500 scientific service providers – allowing researchers to focus on innovation and discovery.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about enterprise partnerships with Science Exchange, and request a demo of our private marketplaces for outsourced R&amp;amp;D:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Trans — From the Moment of Birth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22591</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/11/trans-from-the-moment-of-birth/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The moment I was born, the doctor looked at my nether regions, saw a penis, and announced to my parents, “It’s a boy”. Along with that announcement came a long list of expectations about how a boy’s life should unfold in rural Nebraska in the 1940s and ’50s. No ambiguity. No nuance. Boys will be boys—or else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/06/21/time-for-a-change-gender-reassignment/&quot;&gt;Gender&lt;/a&gt; reveal parties are a hot trend among today’s expectant parents.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At about twenty weeks of gestation, an ultrasound is completed, and family and friends are called together for “the reveal,” a celebration of the newly identified biologic sex of the child. Sometimes a baby-carriage-piñata filled with candy is struck until the candy, wrapped in either pink or blue, comes rolling out—along with all the expectations about gender roles that will be established even prior to birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it could be confusing to guests, I think those parties might better be called “sex reveal parties,” but I understand that guests might come with a different set of expectations. You see, what is being revealed isn’t gender at all but the biological sex of the child. Sex and gender are not the same, although they are often confused and the terms used interchangeably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans have a natural tendency to categorize, sometimes out of respect, sometimes based on stereotypes. At birth, infants are assigned a sex by a third party. It’s a binary choice based on their external genitalia or, in some cases, by chromosomes. Sex is binary: boy or girl. Gender is more of a psychological and societal concept. Gender is not binary; it may not even be linear. Enter the world of the transgender. (A discussion of intersex children who may have incomplete physical characteristics is beyond the scope of this article.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transgender individuals are those who identify with a gender that differs from the biological sex they were assigned at birth. They are born biologically male or female but express their gender in ways more consistent with the opposite sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it may seem like we have a wave of newly identified transgender people, the percent of trans people remains consistent at about 0.3%, and rather than a change in incidence, we are likely experiencing more visibility. While interviewing me, MJ Schwader said that he first came out as a lesbian at age nineteen and only many years later came out as a transgender man. He said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something wasn’t right; even without language around it, I knew from a very early age that I wasn’t going to be able to stay there. When I came to a realization that I was trans, there was this complete peace inside.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether speaking of sexual orientation or gender orientation, many people live in a kind of purgatory of sexual confusion until they acquire the words to describe their individual identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another layer of confusion is added when considering “drag,” that is practiced by people of all sexual orientations and gender identities. The term “drag” is used when someone wears clothing that is more conventionally worn by a person of the opposite sex, especially when a man wears women’s clothes. Drag is a performance; it does not refer to people who wish to assume a gender different from their assigned sex. Transgender women want to dress as women because they are women, transgender men are men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One morning I heard a television pundit who opposes transgender rights say that if men can gain an advantage by saying they are women, many will do so. He was wrong on so many levels. In our patriarchal society, most would agree that not many advantages accrue to women over men. He also implied that all a man had to do was put on a dress and a wig and suddenly he is transformed into a woman. His statement ignores the complexities and pain of a trans person’s decision to transition to a different gender. Some trans people work hard to leave no doubt as to the gender they believe they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a conflict exists between one’s biological sex and the gender with which one identifies, it creates gender dysphoria, a clinically significant form of distress. A report titled “Suicide Attempts among Transgender and Gender Non-Conforming Adults” states that over 40% of trans men and women have attempted suicide, with the prevalence being highest among the young, economically disadvantaged, less educated, and ethnic minorities.&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until a recent change in the &lt;em&gt;Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of the American Psychiatric Association&lt;/em&gt;, this condition was labeled “gender dysphoria disorder.” Although trans men and women experience dysphoria (anxiety, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/08/new-target-in-brain-for-treating-depression-the-bmp-pathway/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, and suicidal thoughts) at a higher rate than the general population, it is no longer considered a “disorder.” For many, their psychiatric symptoms disappear or markedly diminish once they have decided to transition to the gender with which they identify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would anyone, then, choose to assume a gender different from the biological sex with which they were born? Many studies on the causes of transsexuality have been widely discredited, particularly psychological studies. A recent review of literature on the causes of gender identity concluded that a fixed, biologic basis exists for gender identity and that the best clinical outcomes are associated with hormone therapy and surgical sexual transition.&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One classic way for scientists to test whether a trait is influenced by genetics is twin studies. Identical twins have the same chromosomes; fraternal twins are raised in the same environment but share only half their genes. Several studies have shown that among twins, both identical twins are transgender more often than both fraternal twins. Studies of the brain structure have also shown that the brains of transgender males or females are more similar to the brains of the sex with which these people identify than the brains of the sex they were assigned at birth.&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transgender identity is complex. It is not binary; it may not be linear. It is also most certainly not a capricious choice made to seek a particular advantage. It may also be more fluid than once thought. Sex and gender are most likely a matrix of identities without one precise set of causes. The most promising choices for understanding transsexualism is in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/06/11/epigenetics-and-its-major-influence-on-life/&quot;&gt;epigenomics&lt;/a&gt;, a study that combines the effects of the environment on genetic expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than one in four trans people has faced a bias-driven assault, and rates are higher for trans women and trans people of color.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Although more than half of Americans oppose laws requiring transgender people to use bathrooms that correspond to their birth sex, the current political environment is a very difficult one for transgender men and women. “Bathroom bills” have become the focal point of anti-LGBT measures across the country. In most cases, bathroom bills have been proposed by politicians up for re-election. The bills are being used to energize these politicians’ conservative base now that the issue of same-sex marriage has been resolved, and the arguments that they are using are the same that were used against same-sex marriage—for example, to protect children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump, indebted to conservative Christians, has reversed his pre-election position and has rescinded &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/06/04/making-the-president-disappear-the-inattentional-barack-obama-blindness-illusion/&quot;&gt;President Obama&lt;/a&gt;’s rule that trans people must be allowed to use the bathroom consistent with the sex with which they identify. In an administration that so easily dismisses science, the evidence that transsexualism is biologically determined will have little impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great deal to learn about transsexualism. For example, we know that the earlier hormonal treatment is given, the more apparent the physical transformation will be, but what are the long-term consequences of putting children on hormones with irreversible effects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we can be certain of is this: issues of sexual orientation and gender identification are complex and will not be resolved at a gender reveal party during the twentieth week of gestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Sirois M. (2017) A Word of Caution on Gender Reveal Parties.&lt;em&gt; HuffPost&lt;/em&gt;. Available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/a-word-of-caution-on-gender-reveal-parties_us_57a8f834e4b08f5371f1d001&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Olson L. (2017) Finally Out: Letting Go of Living Straight with Loren Olson, MD. &lt;em&gt;OMTimes Radio&lt;/em&gt;. Available &lt;a href=&quot;http://omtimes.com/iom/2017/02/finally-letting-go-living-straight-loren-olson-md/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Haas A, Rodgers P, Herman J. (2017) Suicide Attempts Among Transgender and Gender Non-Conforming Adults – Williams Institute. &lt;em&gt;Williams Institute&lt;/em&gt;. Available &lt;a href=&quot;https://williamsinstitute.law.ucla.edu/research/suicide-attempts-among-transgender-and-gender-non-conforming-adults/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Saraswat A, Weinland J, Shafer J. (2015) Evidence Supporting the Biologic Nature of Gender Identity, &lt;em&gt;Endocrine Practice&lt;/em&gt;, 21(2), 199-204. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.4158/EP14351.RA&quot;&gt;10.4158/EP14351.RA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Wu K. Between the (Gender) Lines: the Science of Transgender Identity – Science in the News. &lt;em&gt;Harvard University – The Graduate School of Arts and Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. 2017. Available &lt;a href=&quot;http://sitn.hms.harvard.edu/flash/2016/gender-lines-science-transgender-identity&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. (2017) Anti-Violence.&lt;em&gt; National Center for Transgender Equality&lt;/em&gt;. Available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transequality.org/issues/anti-violence&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/congerdesign-509903/&quot;&gt;congerdesign&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Rowdy Roddy Pilferer: Wrestling journal takes down plagiarized paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51729</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/11/rowdy-roddy-pilferer-wrestling-journal-takes-plagiarized-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal devoted to wrestling science — we’re not sure if it’s the only one — has given the old reverse frankensteiner to a 2016 article whose authors stole much of their text from a conference presentation one of them had reviewed for the meeting. The article, “The Role of Goal Setting, Collectivism, and Task Orientation […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/11/rowdy-roddy-pilferer-wrestling-journal-takes-plagiarized-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Rowdy Roddy Pilferer: Wrestling journal takes down plagiarized paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Authors withdraw study, citing “accidentally duplicated” images</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51716</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/11/authors-withdraw-study-citing-accidentally-duplicated-images/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers in Australia have withdrawn a 2006 paper in The Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC), citing image duplication. In the withdrawal notice, published July 14, 2017, the authors claim that the “errors do not impact the underlying scientific findings of the article.” Although the notice does not mention an investigation, a comment on PubPeer on March […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/11/authors-withdraw-study-citing-accidentally-duplicated-images/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors withdraw study, citing “accidentally duplicated” images&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Children as young as four believe in karma – good things happen to those who do good</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29776</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/11/children-as-young-as-four-believe-in-karma-good-things-happen-to-those-who-do-good/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-516294624-2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29866&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29866&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5DS&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Young hispanic boy with long hair leaning his chin on his arms on a wooden fence in a summer park looking away thinking&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1458396872&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;wundervisuals&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Little hispanic boy leaning on a rustic wooden fence thinking&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Little hispanic boy leaning on a rustic wooden fence thinking&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-516294624-2.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-516294624-2.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-516294624-2.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/11/children-as-young-as-four-believe-in-karma-good-things-happen-to-those-who-do-good/little-hispanic-boy-leaning-on-a-rustic-wooden-fence-thinking/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-516294624-2.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the most scientifically trained among us have &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2012/11/22/the-unscientific-thinking-that-forever-lingers-in-the-minds-of-physics-professors/&quot;&gt;an instinct for mystical thinking&lt;/a&gt; – seeing purpose in nature, for example, or reading meaning in random coincidences. Psychologists think this is to do with the way our minds work at a fundamental level. We have evolved to be highly attuned to concepts relevant to our social lives, things like intentions and fairness. And we just can’t switch off this way of thinking, even when we’re contemplating the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other things, this may explain the intuitive appeal of the Buddhist and Hindu notion of karmic justice – the idea, essentially, that you get what you deserve in life; that the cosmos rewards those who do good (variations of this idea are also spread by other religions). Indeed, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12442/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Developmental Science&lt;/em&gt;, psychologists at Yale University have shown that children in the US as young as four are inclined to believe in, and actively seek, karmic justice, regardless of whether they come from a religious family or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We conclude that, beginning early in development, children expect that life events are not purely random occurrences, but instead that they happen for an intended reason, such as rewarding people for their good behaviour,” said the study authors Konika Banerjee and Paul Bloom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29776&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experiment, 20 children aged four to six, tested alone, were told that if a completely random coin shake landed the right way up they would get a super cool glow-in-the-dark water wiggle toy. Then they were given some stickers to say thanks for taking part. Before the coin was shaken, they were told about two other kids doing the same challenge, one of whom gave his stickers away to needy children because he thought this would increase his chances of winning the toy; the other child threw her stickers in the bin because she thought this would increase her winning chances. Each participant was asked which child they thought was correct, and then they were given the chance to copy their actions (there was a donation box and a bin in the testing room).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the participating children expressed a belief in the karmic strategy (giving stickers away to needy children would boost their own chances of winning the toy), certainly much more than they believed in the rubbish bin strategy. Moreover, of the 45 per cent of the kids who tried out a strategy for themselves, nearly all of them tried the karmic strategy (only one child tried the rubbish bin strategy). This bias for believing in karma was true regardless of whether the children were from a religious family or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second experiment, 40 more children (aged five to six) were shown cartoon vignettes about other children trying to achieve something (e.g. a girl trying to find her lost puppy), and who used different strategies to boost their chances, either involving karmic bargaining (e.g. being friendly to a new girl at school), or a non-karmic strategy (e.g. making her hair shorter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each vignette, two different fictional characters gave their opposing verdicts on the  likely effectiveness of the karmic strategy. For instance one character said that being friendly to a new girl would help find the puppy because if you do something nice, it helps something nice happen to you. The other character was sceptical – yes, it is nice to do something kind for someone else but that doesn’t help make some unrelated good thing happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participating children were asked which character they thought was right and they far more often endorsed the character who was in favour of the effectiveness of the karmic strategy. A further control condition showed this wasn’t simply because of a generic bias for causal explanations (where any one thing is said to cause another), but was specifically for karma-related causal strategies where doing something nice increases the odds of an unrelated favourable outcome occurring for oneself. Again, the children’s belief in karma was unrelated to whether they came from a religious background or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final experimental with four- to six-year-old kids clarified things a little further, showing that young children tend to have a rather “diffuse” notion of karma – that is, they think the odds of something nice happening to them is increased not only by their doing something nice themselves, but also by someone else doing good in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banerjee and Bloom think young children’s belief in cosmic karma is probably an extension of their early belief in social karma – the generally accurate notion that if you do someone a favour, they are likely to reciprocate in due course. In other words, it’s another example of the way that we “overextend inferences and expectations from the social domain to the non-social domain” (similar to how we so readily attribute meaning and purpose to the inanimate world, such as thinking that trees make oxygen so that animals can breathe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers added: “Taken together, our findings support the view that notions of karma may be so cross-culturally successful because they capitalise on certain more generally social-cognitive propensities and heuristics for navigating our social relationships that are present and active early in development.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/desc.12442/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;You get what you give: children’s karmic bargaining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29776/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29776/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29776&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 11:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Science can’t forecast love</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-cant-forecast-love</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-cant-forecast-love</link>
	<description>Scientists’ forecast for romantic matches is unpredictable.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090717_BB_love-connection_main_FREE.jpg?itok=Sh7r_Qcz" length="24831" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Results-Free Peer-Review: Improving Transparency in Review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9495</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/11/results-free-peer-review-improving-transparency-in-review/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about Results-free review &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/about/results-free-peer-review-for-authors&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/11/results-free-peer-review-improving-transparency-in-review/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Results-Free Peer-Review: Improving Transparency in Review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Global fingerprints of sea-level rise revealed by satellites</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22588</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ok3FwPsDx-g/nature.2017.22588</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Geological processes send more meltwater from glaciers and ice sheets to Earth's mid-latitudes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22588&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22588&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ok3FwPsDx-g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The Olympics of research into scientific publishing is happening now. Follow along here.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51758</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/10/olympics-research-scientific-publishing-happening-now-follow-along/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;CHICAGO — As many Retraction Watch readers may know, the Peer Review Congress happens every four years — much like the Olympics. For three days here on the shores of Lake Michigan, researchers will present findings on subjects from bias to data sharing to misconduct. Our Ivan Oransky is there, and will be tweeting, so […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/10/olympics-research-scientific-publishing-happening-now-follow-along/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Olympics of research into scientific publishing is happening now. Follow along here.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 14:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Follow Me: Astrocytes in Spinal Cord Repair</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22766</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/09/follow-me-astrocytes-in-spinal-cord-repair/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;You are standing in the middle of King’s Cross with a postcode in your hands, your feet trodden on by the busy crowd. So much has changed since you were last here 20 years ago, and every way you go seems to meet frowning faces set in their own path. By a lucky coincidence, somebody recognizes you and shakes your hand—they are going the same way. What are the odds! “Thank you”, you mutter, “you are a star”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Through thistles and thorns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/09/spinal-cord-injury-and-wearable-robotics/&quot;&gt;Spinal cord injury&lt;/a&gt; (SCI) leaves patients isolated from their own bodies with devastating life-long consequences. The limited nature of adult human spinal cord repair is frustrating but understandable from a developmental point of view. If fasciculis gracilis, a tract of the spinal cord responsible for lower limb sensations that relays touch from the foot, gets traumatically disrupted, the dorsal root ganglion (DRG) cell axon would not only have to cross over the site of injury, but also find the correct path all the way up—up to 50 cm in a tall individual. Even if that tremendous task is accomplished, there still remains the challenge of finding the correct second order neuron of the nucleus gracilis that, in turn, connects to the third order thalamic neuron transmitting signals to the part of the somatosensory cortex representing that foot. Not something that can be easily done without help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the way to connectivity restoration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been noted that: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The three main aims of [axon regeneration] research are: to initiate and maintain axonal growth and elongation; to direct regenerating axons to reconnect with their target neurons; and to reconstitute original circuitry (or the equivalent), which will ultimately lead to functional restoration. Although many interventions have now been reported to promote functional recovery after experimental SCI, none has fulfilled all three of these aims. In fact, only the first aim has been extensively studied and convincingly demonstrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, even though the possibility of axon regrowth in the adult mammalian nervous system has been shown, the evidence supporting &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/02/05/a-virtual-brain-the-benefits-of-brain-modelling/&quot;&gt;neuronal connectivity&lt;/a&gt; restoration is rarely convincing. Without careful guidance, aberrant axonal regrowth is a serious obstacle to functional regeneration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, long-distance regeneration of axons is not the only mechanism through which normal spinal cord function can be restored. Injury is known to induce plasticity by several mechanisms including unmasking inactive spared pathways, compensatory collateral sprouting from the intact pathways, or an increase in receptor number due to denervation hypersensitivity.. For example, Hofstetter et al. commented that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excessive local sprouting in our present study might have facilitated the formation of [novel corticospinal tract] pathways, although we could not detect a correlation between the amount of local sprouting and motor recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst researchers are trying to find a way to artificially guide axons to their correct targets and induce &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/02/how-does-meditation-make-you-smarter/&quot;&gt;plasticity&lt;/a&gt;, there is a cell type that routinely orchestrates these processes. Astrocytes express a range of axon-attractive and repulsive molecules that are crucial for proper development and adult nervous system plastic reorganisation. They provide a physical adherent substrate for growing neurons, secrete extracellular neuro-attractants like vimentin and repellents like chondroitin sulphate proteoglycans (CSPGs) and semaphorins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A scar or a star?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurocentric paradigm considered astrocytes to be a barrier to healing after the SCI for almost a century despite the lack of evidence that purely neuron-based therapies are sufficient for full regeneration. However, if the derogatory-dubbed astrocytic scar is removed or prevented from forming in the SCI context, not only do axons fail to spontaneously regrow through the lesion, they also become unable to regrow upon delivery of stimulating growth factors that promote growth in the presence of astrocytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anderson et al. show that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/02/03/the-many-emerging-roles-of-astrocytes/&quot;&gt;astrocytes&lt;/a&gt; are not responsible for the bulk of the inhibitory CSPG production after the SCI lesion, as hypothesized previously, but instead provide crucial axon-supporting molecules. The injury environment primes reactive astrocytes to re-express developmental synaptogenic molecules such as thrombospondin-1 that result in protective neuroplasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not all are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite these recent discoveries, skepticism towards astrocyte-based therapies prevails. To exacerbate this view, several studies that used &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/08/28/the-gut-brain-connection-and-enterochromaffin-cells/&quot;&gt;neural stem cell&lt;/a&gt; (NSC) transplantation in an attempt to repair spinal cord damage observed neuropathic pain development that correlates with the astrocytic differentiation of NSCs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it is becoming clear that the astrocytic population is far from homogeneous. Subsets of astrocytes with different permissive and restrictive qualities towards the growth of specific types of axons are found within different regions of the spinal cord that guide region-specific development of sensory and motor axonal tracts. Not surprisingly, certain astrocytic types are more selective towards regeneration and plasticity of specific types of neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies at al. have discovered that astrocytes pre-differentiated from embryonic glial-restricted precursors (GRPs) (GRP-derived astrocytes or GDAs) are capable of promoting axonal regrowth alongside functional recovery and prevention of axotomized neuron atrophy upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/06/28/neuronal-transplantation-may-restore-brain-functionality/&quot;&gt;transplantation&lt;/a&gt; in rodents with SCI, where this method supersedes transplantation of undifferentiated neural precursors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the method of astrocytic differentiation of precursor cells plays a crucial role in determining their regenerative capacity. If bone morphogenic protein-4 (BMP4) is used in GDA astrogenesis, the resulting population creates a strongly supportive environment upon transplantation. In contrast, the same GRPs treated with ciliary neurotrophic factor (CNTF) have poor locomotor regenerative properties, but induce active calcitonin-gene-related peptide (CGRP)-positive nociceptive c-fiber sprouting that is associated with allodynia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This raises the possibility that the inflammatory environment of the injured spinal cord promotes differentiation of endogenous and transplanted astrocytes into the subtype that is not optimal for rubrospinal or dorsal column tract axon restoration, but, in turn, may be selectively supportive to pain-conducting c-fibers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to transplantation strategies, modification of endogenous astrocyte function can be employed. For example, oral administration of denosomin results in functional recovery in mice after SCI through increases in astrocyte proliferation, survival, and vimentin secretion that promotes locomotor raphespinal axon outgrowth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning from the experts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is noteworthy that astrocytic subtypes that promote recovery appear to physically realign local astrocytic processes in a linear fashion. Authors speculate that this linear organization provides more straightforward routes for regenerating axons to follow. Another exciting and unexplored possibility is that these astrocytes help to restore the endogenous astrocytic network function that gets disrupted by the injury, whilst beneficial &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/03/rna-storage-in-neurons-contributes-to-brain-plasticity/&quot;&gt;neuroplasticity&lt;/a&gt; is its natural corollary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping back from the exclusively neurocentric view of SCI may allow for unexpected advances in functional restoration. Ultimately, the bulk of research on the intricacies of axonal guidance and plastic synapse rearrangement is an attempt at recapitulation of normal astrocytic functions. When offered a helping hand, take it, and see where it leads you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bradbury EJ, McMahon SB. Spinal cord repair strategies: why do they work? Nat Rev Neurosci. 2006;7(8):644–53. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nrn1964&quot;&gt;10.1038/nrn1964&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pernet V, Schwab ME. Lost in the jungle: New hurdles for optic nerve axon regeneration. Vol. 37, Trends in Neurosciences. 2014. p. 381–7. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2014.05.002&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.tins.2014.05.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith GM, Falone AE, Frank E. Sensory axon regeneration: Rebuilding functional connections in the spinal cord. Vol. 35, Trends in Neurosciences. 2012. p. 156–63. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2011.10.006&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.tins.2011.10.006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weidner N, Tuszynski MH. Spontaneous plasticity in the injured spinal cord — Implications for repair strategies. Mol Psychiatry. 2002;(7):9–11. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/sj.mp.4001983&quot;&gt;10.1038/sj.mp.4001983&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hofstetter CP, Holmström N a V, Lilja J a, Schweinhardt P, Hao J, Spenger C, et al. Allodynia limits the usefulness of intraspinal neural stem cell grafts; directed differentiation improves outcome. Nat Neurosci. 2005;8(3):346–53. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nn1405&quot;&gt;10.1038/nn1405&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen NJ, Barres BA. Signaling between glia and neurons: Focus on synaptic plasticity. Vol. 15, Current Opinion in Neurobiology. 2005. p. 542–8. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2005.08.006&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.conb.2005.08.006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeman MR. Sculpting the nervous system: Glial control of neuronal development. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2006;16(1):119–25. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2005.12.004&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.conb.2005.12.004&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fallon JR. Preferential outgrowth of central nervous system neurites on astrocytes and Schwann cells as compared with nonglial cells in vitro. J Cell Biol. 1985;100(1):198–207. PMID: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/3880751&quot;&gt;3880751&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shigyo M, Tohda C. Extracellular vimentin is a novel axonal growth facilitator for functional recovery in spinal cord-injured mice. Sci Rep. 2016;6(February):28293. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/srep28293&quot;&gt;10.1038/srep28293&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang H, Katagiri Y, McCann TE, Unsworth E, Goldsmith P, Yu Z-X, et al. Chondroitin-4-sulfation negatively regulates axonal guidance and growth. J Cell Sci. 2008;121(18):3083–91. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.032649&quot;&gt;10.1242/jcs.032649&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Molofsky A V, Kelley KW, Tsai H-H, Redmond SA, Chang SM, Madireddy L, et al. Astrocyte-encoded positional cues maintain sensorimotor circuit integrity. Nature. 2014;509(7499):189–94. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nature13161&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature13161&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chu T, Zhou H, Li F, Wang T, Lu L, Feng S. Astrocyte transplantation for spinal cord injury: Current status and perspective. Vol. 107, Brain Research Bulletin. 2014. p. 18–30. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainresbull.2014.05.003&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.brainresbull.2014.05.003&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anderson MA, Burda JE, Ren Y, Ao Y, O’Shea TM, Kawaguchi R, et al. Astrocyte scar formation aids central nervous system axon regeneration. Nature. 2016;0(1):1–20. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/nature17623&quot;&gt;10.1038/nature17623&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tyzack GE, Sitnikov S, Barson D, Adams-Carr KL, Lau NK, Kwok JC, et al. Astrocyte response to motor neuron injury promotes structural synaptic plasticity via STAT3-regulated TSP-1 expression. Nat Commun. 2014;5:4294. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms5294&quot;&gt;10.1038/ncomms5294&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macias MY, Syring MB, Pizzi MA, Crowe MJ, Alexanian AR, Kurpad SN. Pain with no gain: Allodynia following neural stem cell transplantation in spinal cord injury. Exp Neurol. 2006;201(2):335–48. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2006.04.035&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.expneurol.2006.04.035&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies JE, Huang C, Proschel C, Noble M, Mayer-Proschel M, Davies SJA. Astrocytes derived from glial-restricted precursors promote spinal cord repair. J Biol. 2006;5(3):7. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1186/jbiol35&quot;&gt;10.1186/jbiol35&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davies JE, Pröschel C, Zhang N, Noble M, Mayer-Pröschel M, Davies SJA. Transplanted astrocytes derived from BMP- or CNTF-treated glial-restricted precursors have opposite effects on recovery and allodynia after spinal cord injury. J Biol. 2008;7(7):24. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1186/jbiol85&quot;&gt;10.1186/jbiol85&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teshigawara K, Kuboyama T, Shigyo M, Nagata A, Sugimoto K, Matsuya Y, et al. A novel compound, denosomin, ameliorates spinal cord injury via axonal growth associated with astrocyte-secreted vimentin. Br J Pharmacol. 2013;168(4):903–19. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-5381.2012.02211.x&quot;&gt;10.1111/j.1476-5381.2012.02211.x&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/StockSnap-894430/&quot;&gt;StockSnap&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Suicide after misconduct; taxonomic vandalism; a disastrous Nature editorial</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51753</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/09/weekend-reads-suicide-misconduct-taxonomic-vandalism-disastrous-nature-editorial/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured a battle over psychologists and torture, a case of misconduct at Harvard, allegations of bribery, and a lawsuit against the New York Times. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A researcher committed scientific misconduct, under great pressure and while taking inappropriate medications, was found guilty, and agreed to a ban […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/09/weekend-reads-suicide-misconduct-taxonomic-vandalism-disastrous-nature-editorial/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Suicide after misconduct; taxonomic vandalism; a disastrous Nature editorial&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 13:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Deadly Mexico earthquake had unusual cause</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22586</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6BQ5ZlKluNg/nature.2017.22586</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;US Geological Survey says tremor was within the Cocos Plate, not at the plate boundary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22586&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22586&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6BQ5ZlKluNg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Carlo Croce, Ohio State researcher facing misconduct allegations, suing New York Times for defamation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51737</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/carlo-croce-ohio-state-researcher-facing-misconduct-allegations-suing-new-york-times-defamation/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Carlo Croce, a cancer researcher at The Ohio State University who has faced numerous allegations of research misconduct, has filed a lawsuit against the New York Times, claiming the newspaper defamed him in a March 8 story. Croce filed the civil suit May 10, in the US District Court for the Southern District of Ohio, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/carlo-croce-ohio-state-researcher-facing-misconduct-allegations-suing-new-york-times-defamation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, Ohio State researcher facing misconduct allegations, suing New York Times for defamation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 22:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sugars in breast milk may fight harmful bacteria directly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/sugars-breast-milk-may-fight-harmful-bacteria-directly</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/sugars-breast-milk-may-fight-harmful-bacteria-directly</link>
	<description>A small study finds that the sugars present in some women’s breast milk may fight potentially harmful bacteria.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090817_LS_growth-curve_breastmilk_main_FREE.jpg?itok=yQnaM7F-" length="22435" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Author who previously claimed plagiarism was a mistake earns new erratum</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51703</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/author-previously-claimed-plagiarism-mistake-earns-new-erratum/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A biotechnology journal has corrected a 2006 paper after discovering duplication and plagiarism. This offense is the second we know of for the corresponding author, Uttam Chand Banerjee, in the same journal, Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology. Last year, Banerjee—who works at National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) in Mohali, Punjab, India—had a 14-year-old review […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/author-previously-claimed-plagiarism-mistake-earns-new-erratum/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author who previously claimed plagiarism was a mistake earns new erratum&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 15:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Air pollution takes a toll on solar energy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/air-pollution-takes-toll-solar-energy</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/air-pollution-takes-toll-solar-energy</link>
	<description>Dust and other tiny air pollutants can reduce solar energy output by as much as 25 percent in parts of the world.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080717_LH_air-pollution_main_free.jpg?itok=uQ2BYTVe" length="23416" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Behind the Image: bad day for a bumblebee</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9381</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/behind-image-bad-day-bumblebee/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Overall-3rd-place-Connections-by-Roberto-García-Roa-140x110.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9424&quot; height=&quot;3505&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;5258&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your profession?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a researcher at the Ethology unit, University of Valencia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What type of research are you involved in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research line combines experimental and phylogenetic approaches and encompasses both ecological and evolutionary studies focused on investigating those traits employed by animals to engage in social and sexual interactions and their role in lineages diversification and species adaptations. Specifically, I am currently investigating at the University of Valencia (at Pau Carazo´s Lab) the mechanisms inherent to sexual conflict and the ecological factors that modulate this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you become interested in this area of research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been interested in the process and mechanism underlying animal ecology and evolution and thus, my way has moved forward progressively, building this interesting framework of study in which I am involved in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you become interested in photography?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life cannot be understood without animals and hence, the best way to “capture” them and wear them always with you is with photography. They will be with you in photography forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where and how was this photo taken? Why were you there at the time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture was taken while I was walking with my dog in Valencia. I often observe snails, grasshoppers, lizards, and that time I could see that special interaction among three animals. I went to my house to take the camera and took several photos of what was happening in this interesting interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you explain a bit more about the image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In field work, you often see, with luck and effort, spiders hunting or even eating their prey. However, this case was special because a third protagonist appeared in the scene. This small fly was parasitizing the bee while it was being eaten by the spider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about this scene particularly interested you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, this scene reflects life from 3 different perspectives and show how complex are animal interactions. It shows mimicry with the crab spider, it shows the dangers underlying pollination for bees, it shows three different positions on the trophic web (predators, prey and parasites) and finally, the image highlights how connected are many animals in a dynamic in which the loss of some of them in a hypothetical region could trigger crucial consequences for other species in that region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/behind-image-bad-day-bumblebee/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Behind the Image: bad day for a bumblebee&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 12:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Overall-3rd-place-Connections-by-Roberto-García-Roa-125x125.jpeg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “We would now catch” this conflict of interest: Hindawi journal retracts two papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51656</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/now-catch-conflict-interest-hindawi-journal-retracts-two-papers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A computer science journal has retracted two papers, after discovering “a conflict of interest between the handling editor and one of the authors.” Matt Hodgkinson, head of research integrity at Hindawi Limited, which publishes the journal Scientific World Journal, told us that the conflict of interest stemmed from the fact that Zheng Xu, an author […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/08/now-catch-conflict-interest-hindawi-journal-retracts-two-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“We would now catch” this conflict of interest: Hindawi journal retracts two papers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Debates on whether science is broken don’t fit in tweets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/debates-whether-science-broken-dont-fit-tweets</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/debates-whether-science-broken-dont-fit-tweets</link>
	<description>Amid debates over whether science is broken, many experts are proposing repairs.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090417_to_pavalues_free.jpg?itok=-0BiMlvg" length="56686" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Can technology help global suicide prevention?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9484</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/can-technology-help-global-suicide-prevention/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/National-Suicide-Prevention-Jared-Keener-Flickr-CC-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization estimates that over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs398/en/&quot;&gt;800,000 people die by suicide each year&lt;/a&gt; – that is one person every 40 seconds! But for every suicide, there are many more people who attempt suicide, and many individuals who are impacted by the suicide of a loved one. Suicide is not restricted by age, gender, nationality or income; it occurs throughout the lifespan and in 2015, was the second leading cause of death among 15–29-year-olds. A prior suicide attempt is the single most important risk factor for suicide in the general population, and whilst people with mental health conditions are at higher risk of suicide, many suicides occur spontaneously in response to life events or crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suicide is a serious public health concern and is preventable. In 2014, the World Health Organization published “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/mental_health/suicide-prevention/world_report_2014/en/&quot;&gt;Preventing suicide: a global imperative&lt;/a&gt;”, it’s first global report to increase awareness of suicide and suicide attempts, and to make suicide prevention a global public health priority. Suicide is a complex issue and therefore effective suicide prevention efforts require multiple constituents. One critical component to suicide prevention is the early identification of those in need, to ensure that they receive appropriate care and support; this is where the social support provided by communities and loved ones can be so vital to a vulnerable individual seeking mental health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to appropriate mental health care, when and where it is needed, is vital for the prevention of suicide. In some countries mental health care may be harder to access due to geographical or financial restraints. However, even in countries where access to care is ready available many who experience suicidal ideation do not seek help. A number of barriers may prevent those experiencing suicidal ideation from seeking treatment; suicide and mental illness are still heavily stigmatized in many communities, and some groups of the general population are less likely to seek help than others, including young people and men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9486&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9486&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/Dropbox-Johan-Larsson-Flickt-CC-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Johan Larsson, Flickr, CC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing global reliance on technology allows for opportunities to improve mental health care provision; the potential for those who cannot, or choose not to, access traditional ‘face-to-face’ healthcare to be reached by digital methods is possible. To date, this has taken many forms – from doctor-patient consultations via video calling, to the development of sophisticated online and mobile telephone applications. Research examining the effectiveness of digital or eHealth interventions for both preventative treatment and follow-up care is rapidly expanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A  systematic review and meta-analysis, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://monash.edu/research/explore/en/persons/katrina-witt%289a5e2239-c431-43cb-aa45-cb74096b4056%29.html&quot;&gt;Katrina Witt&lt;/a&gt; and colleagues from Monash University, Australia, examined the effectiveness of digital interventions for the self-management of suicidal ideation or self-harm. The researchers analyzed data from 14 published studies including a total of 3,356 participants. Most of the studies included evaluated online interventions, but two examined mobile phone applications that were designed for people suffering from depression/suicidal-ideation to self-manage their symptoms. The researchers found that despite limitations with many of the published studies design, there is some evidence that digital interventions may be associated with reductions in suicidal ideation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another systematic review and meta-analysis, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.unsw.edu.au/people/mr-mark-deady&quot;&gt;Mark Deady&lt;/a&gt; and colleagues from the University of New South Wales and the Black Dog Institute (Australia), &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1473-1&quot;&gt;recently published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, evaluated the effectiveness of eHealth interventions for the prevention of depression and anxiety. The researchers analyzed data from 10 published randomized controlled trials, including a total of 4,522 participants. The studies included evaluated online and mobile phone applications, but also other intervention methods such as those using email and/or text messaging to provide support. The review suggests that a range of eHealth intervention programs produce small, but positive, effects on symptom reduction for anxiety and depression in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both of these reviews the intervention programs were developed by psychologists/psychiatrists using aspects of cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), and were found to be beneficial compared with control conditions. However, it should be emphasized that in all studies there is lack of long-term follow up data, and it is therefore unclear whether these interventions may translate to reduced suicide attempts, depression and anxiety in the longer term. The small numbers of studies in both reviews indicate the continuing need to rigorously evaluate the effectiveness of eHealth interventions; despite the ever increase number of digital programs and apps available that are designed to improve and promote mental wellbeing, a clear distinction needs to be made between those designed with a basis in evidence based medicine, such as the studies analyzed here, and those that are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eHealth and digital interventions have the potential to reach more people with fewer resources than face-to face care, and may be useful in breaking down some of the current barriers that prevent those in need from accessing mental health care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9488 size-full aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;141&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/2017_wspd_banner_english.png&quot; width=&quot;701&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find out more about suicide prevention please see &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry’s&lt;/em&gt; dedicated section ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/sections/causes-treatment-and-prevention-of-suicide&quot;&gt;Causes, treatment and prevention of suicide&lt;/a&gt;‘.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/08/can-technology-help-global-suicide-prevention/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Can technology help global suicide prevention?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 09:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/National-Suicide-Prevention-Jared-Keener-Flickr-CC-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Learning more about yourself could help you better understand others</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29764</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29767&quot; style=&quot;width: 1624px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-501651483.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29767&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29767&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A woman is looking into the mirror asking herself \&amp;quot;Who am I?\&amp;quot;. In her face there is a big question mark to bring ones consciousness into question. Vector illustration.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;PeterHermesFurian&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mirror Who Am I Woman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Mirror Who Am I Woman&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845?w=264&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1624,1846&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/mirror-who-am-i-woman-3/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-5016514832.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;The intervention used in this research was based on the Internal Family Systems model that sees an individual’s personality as made up of different sub-personalities&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariannecezza.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Marianne Cezza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As social creatures, accurately recognising and understanding the mental states of others (their intentions, knowledge, beliefs, etc.) is crucial to our social bonds and interactions. In fact, in today’s multi-cultural world and strongly divided political climate, this skill – known as Theory of Mind – is perhaps more important than ever. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s41465-017-0023-6&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cognitive Enhancement&lt;/i&gt; proposes that an effective way to develop our Theory of Mind lies in learning to better understand ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29764&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anne Böckler and colleagues, based at the Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences in Leipzig, recruited 141 participants to take part in a three-month long contemplative training course that teaches people to take the perspective of the different aspects of their own personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before they started, the participants completed a test of their Theory of Mind: they watched short video clips of people describing autobiographical events, then answered a questionnaire about the storyteller’s intentions, thoughts and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the participants were taught to identify and label six ‘inner parts’ or sub-personalities within themselves, for example ‘the caring part’, ‘the inner happy child’, ‘the vulnerable part’. They could modify or add to this list at any time during the training course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course itself consisted of two key components that the participants practised daily for thirty minutes, and at a two-hour guided weekly training sessions. The first component was an ‘observing-thoughts’ meditation, in which participants observed their thoughts objectively,  de-identified from them (i.e. observed them in a detached way), then classified the thoughts into categories of me/other, past/future or positive/negative. The second component was a perspective-taking exercise which participants conducted in pairs, alternating between the role of speaker and listener. The speaker recounted an event from their day from the perspective of one of their randomly selected inner parts. Aware of the speaker’s various inner parts, the listener had to guess which one was talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These perspective-taking exercises and the concept of ‘inner parts’ are based on the Internal Family Systems (IFS) model; an approach used in psychotherapy. The model sees an individual’s personality as made up of different sub-personalities, each with its own set of behaviours, cognitions and affects.  The current study is part of a larger research project which draws from the model’s principles, successfully implemented in a therapeutic setting (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23950186&quot;&gt;with rheumatoid arthritis patients&lt;/a&gt;), and applies them to a non-clinical, healthy, adult population with the aim of improving mental well-being and social intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, the participants in the current study identified 11 inner parts to their personalities, of which 44 per cent were labelled by independent judges as negative traits and 56 per cent were positive traits. The researchers organised the participants’ different personality parts into related trait types according to the IFS model, the most common being: Protectors (12 per cent), Managers and Pleasure Parts (both 11 per cent), Inner Critics (9 per cent), and Vulnerable Parts (8 per cent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing the training course the participants re-took the same Theory of Mind test that they’d taken at the start of the study. Improvement in Theory of Mind was correlated with the number of different inner personality parts identified – the more facets the participants were able to recognise within themselves, the better they seemed to become at understanding others. This is reflected in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2gDnXvv&quot;&gt;neuroimaging&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2wCOd20&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt;, where the processes of perspective-taking of the self and others utilise shared neural mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the correlation between number of parts of self identified and improvement in Theory of Mind was even stronger in those who identified more negative parts. The researchers propose that this supports the theory that people are naturally resistant to looking for negative aspects of their personality, therefore those who do are thought to be working more profoundly to better understand themselves. In addition to the result of a better understanding of the mental states of others, this deeper work also improves psychological wellbeing, as it is widely acknowledged in clinical psychology that accepting negative emotions is beneficial to mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of identifying the different aspects of our personalities is to understand that through them one can view a single situation through a handful of different outlooks; we learn to see the self as multifaceted and can detach and de-identify from one sole personal perspective. Consequently, we’ll also be more open to the different points of view of others, and less likely to assume that a person’s perspective remains consistent across different life situations. It’s likely this increased interpersonal understanding will in turn encourage greater respect and compassion for others, facilitate communication and reduce the ostracism and stigmatisation of groups with alternative outlooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems a little soul searching is required to better understand the people around us. Why not have a go at reflecting on your own psyche, and see what you can recognise in others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s41465-017-0023-6&quot;&gt;Know Thy Selves: Learning to Understand Oneself Increases the Ability to Understand Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-29769&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29769&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=380&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=112&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;380,508&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/08/learning-more-about-yourself-could-help-you-better-understand-others/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/383662_290702477618241_1756317123_n.jpg?w=112&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;112&quot; /&gt;Written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://mariannecezza.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Marianne Cezza&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@maricezza&quot;&gt;@maricezza&lt;/a&gt;) for the BPS Research Digest&lt;/strong&gt;. Marianne studied psychology at the University of York, where she was editor of the psychology department’s magazine. She now works as a freelance writer and blogger specialising in psychology, neuroscience and mental well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29764/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29764/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29764&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: Tip for new PIs : always do administrative work at the last minute, or later</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1446</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/tip-for-new-pis-always-do-administrative-work-at-the-last-minute-or-later/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This is a tip that has taken me years to really grasp, and I still haven't fully internalized it. I don't like to work at the last minute. If I have something to do and I don't do it, then it stays in the back of my mind until I do it. So, especially if it's some boring task like administrative work, I like to get rid of it as soon as possible. That's a mistake. I'm speaking of my experience in France, so maybe it doesn't apply so much elsewhere. The reason it's a mistake is that what you are required to do changes all the time, so the latest you do it, the least work you will have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every new politician seems to want to add a new layer of bureaucracy, independently of their political origin, so the amount of administrative work you are required to do as a scientist keeps growing, and it doesn't seem to converge. But setting up new rules and reglementations in a complex bureaucratic monster is not easy, so the monster often outputs nonsensical forms and requirements. One example in France is the evaluation of labs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hceres.fr/&quot;&gt;HCERES&lt;/a&gt;), whose role is unclear and changing. The amount of redundancy and the absurdity of some requirements is abysmal. For example, you are required to fill a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SWOT_analysis&quot;&gt;SWOT diagram&lt;/a&gt;, to select and list 20 % of all your « outputs », but also to list each one of them in another form, etc. Because many of the requirements are vague and nonsensical, any organization that deals with them will take some time to converge to a clear set of rules issued to the labs. I have written my evaluation document about 4 times because of the changing instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another recent example is the new evaluation system set up by INSERM (national medical research institution). Someone there (external consulting company ?) apparently decided that having an online CV with fields to fill instead of uploading a text would be more convenient. So for example you have to insert, one by one in web forms, the list of all journals for which you have reviewed in your entire career, and how many papers you have reviewed for each of them. You need to insert the list of all students you have supervised in you entire carrier, with names and exact dates, etc, all one by one in separate fields. Imagine that for senior PIs. Guess what : one week before deadline, the requirement of filling that CV was lifted for most scientists because of many complaints (a bit too late for most of them, including me). About a quarter of them still have to, but the message says that the format of the CV will change next year since it was not good, so all the work will basically be for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here is my conclusion and tip : bureaucracy is nonsense and don't assume otherwise ; just set yourself some time on the deadline to do the required work, whatever it might become at that time (and it might disappear).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 07:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: South Korean researchers lobby government to lift human-embryo restrictions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22585</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0-4Doaca2_M/nature.2017.22585</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Regulations are deterring research that could lead to disease treatments, say scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 141 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22585&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22585&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0-4Doaca2_M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Readers respond to Nature’s Editorial on historical monuments</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22584</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y7b_MW2XJgQ/nature.2017.22584</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22584&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22584&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y7b_MW2XJgQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Geneticists pan paper that claims to predict a person's face from their DNA</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22580</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/DLKxNScNA_s/nature.2017.22580</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Reviewers and a co-author of a paper by genomics entrepreneur Craig Venter claim that it misrepresents the risks of public access to genome data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 139 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22580&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22580&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/DLKxNScNA_s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Pluto’s pits, ridges and famous plain get official names</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/pluto-pits-ridges-plain-get-official-names</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/pluto-pits-ridges-plain-get-official-names</link>
	<description>From Adlivun to Voyager, the International Astronomical Union officially names 14 surface features on the dwarf planet.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 22:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090717_LG_pluto_main.jpg?itok=t4WOyklp" length="14216" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: When a fungus invades the lungs, immune cells can tell it to self-destruct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-fungus-invades-lungs-immune-cells-can-tell-it-self-destruct</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/when-fungus-invades-lungs-immune-cells-can-tell-it-self-destruct</link>
	<description>Immune system resists fungal infection by directing spores to their death.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 21:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090717_lh_fungus_feat_free.jpg?itok=TMoelDma" length="22952" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Brain chemical lost in Parkinson’s may contribute to its own demise</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-chemical-lost-parkinsons-may-contribute-its-own-demise</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-chemical-lost-parkinsons-may-contribute-its-own-demise</link>
	<description>A dangerous form of the chemical messenger dopamine causes cellular mayhem in the very nerve cells that make it.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090717_ls_parkinsons_feat_free.jpg?itok=Rd2Lqge1" length="67654" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Why bats crash into windows</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/why-bats-crash-windows</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/why-bats-crash-windows</link>
	<description>Smooth, vertical surfaces may be blind spots for bats and cause some animals to face-plant, study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090617_ht_batwallticker_main.jpg?itok=eUsVS54F" length="29226" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: UCSF, VA investigations find “clear evidence” of misconduct in cancer papers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51707</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/ucsf-va-investigations-find-clear-evidence-misconduct-cancer-papers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the University of California, San Francisco and the San Francisco Veterans Administration Medical Center teamed up to write a letter. Addressed to the editorial office at the American Association of Cancer Research (AACR), the letter, parts of which have been published in a retraction notice, contained information concerning two papers on genetic […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/ucsf-va-investigations-find-clear-evidence-misconduct-cancer-papers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;UCSF, VA investigations find “clear evidence” of misconduct in cancer papers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 15:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Woolly rhinos may have grown strange extra ribs before going extinct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/woolly-rhinos-extra-ribs-extinct</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/woolly-rhinos-extra-ribs-extinct</link>
	<description>Ribs attached to neck bones could have signaled trouble for woolly rhinos, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090117_SM_woolly-rhinos_main.jpg?itok=7X3o_Ltz" length="43185" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: The Dos and Don’ts of PhD supervision</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=544</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/09/07/the-dos-and-donts-of-phd-supervision/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Myself and Sue Fletcher-Watson (you know, the fabulously clever one…) have been putting our minds to a series of blog posts, attempting to help the fledgling academic get to grips with some of their new professional duties.  This week it is a real classic – how to supervise a PhD student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;download&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-547 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;547&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;download&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192?w=341&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;341,148&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/09/07/the-dos-and-donts-of-phd-supervision/download/&quot; height=&quot;192&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/download.png?w=443&amp;amp;h=192&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a good supervisor is not easy, and tricky relationships between students and supervisors are all too common (you may have direct experience yourself). Understanding and mutually agreeing upon the role of the student and the supervisor is a crucial starting point. Establishing these expectations is an important early step and will make navigating the PhD easier for all concerned. With a shared idea of where you are both starting from, and where you want to get to, together you can chart the path forward.  Hopefully these DOs and DON’Ts will help you get off on the right foot as a PhD supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing your intellectual contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO challenge their thinking…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good PhD supervisor should question their student’s decision making – some part of your supervision meetings should be viva-like. Why are you doing this? How does this method answer this question? What do these data mean? Make sure your student understands what you’re doing and why – be explicit that you expect them to defend their interpretation of the literature / research plans NOT adhere to yours. It is important that they don’t feel that this is a test, with just one right answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When questioning your student, strike a balance between exploring alternatives, and making forward progress. Probing assumptions is important but don’t become a pedant; you need to recognise when is the time to question the fundamentals, and when is the time to move the debate on to the next decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T make decisions for them…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help students determine the next decision to be made (“&lt;em&gt;now that we have selected our measures we need to consider what analysis framework we will use&lt;/em&gt;”) and also the parameters that constrain this decision… but remember that it is not your place to make the decisions for them. Flagging the consequences of the various choices is an excellent way to bring your experience to bear, without eclipsing the student. You may wish to highlight budget constraints, discuss the likely recruitment rate, or consider the consequences of a chosen data type in terms of analysis time and required skills. Help them see how each decision feeds back. Sue recently worked with a student to move from research question, to methods, to power calculation, to ideal sample size, and then – finding that the project budget was inadequate to support the sample target – back to RQ again. It’s tough for a student to have to re-visit earlier decisions but important to consider all the relevant factors before committing to data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who’s in charge?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO give them project management responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Sue and Duncan run fortnightly lab group meetings with all their students and this is highly recommended as a way to check in and ensure no student gets left hanging. But don’t make the mistake of becoming your student’s project manager. Whether you prefer frequent informal check-ins or more formal supervisions that are spaced apart, your student should be in charge of monitoring actual progress against plans, and recording decisions. For formal meetings, they can provide an agenda, attachments and minutes, assigning action points to you and other supervisors, and chasing these if needed. They should monitor the budget, and develop excellent version control and data management skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This achieves a number of different goals simultaneously. First, it gives your student a chance to learn the generic project management skills which will be essential if they continue in an academic career, and useful if they leave academia too. Second, it helps to reinforce the sense that this is &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; project, since power and responsibility go hand in hand. Finally, it means that your role in the project is as an intellectual contributor, shaping and challenging the research, rather than wasting your skills and time on bureaucratic tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T make them a lackey to serve your professional goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate students are not cheap research assistants. They are highly talented early career researchers with independent funding (in the majority of cases) that has been awarded to them on merit. They have chosen to place their graduate research project in your lab. They are not there to conduct &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; research or write &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; papers. In any case, attempting this approach is self-defeating. Students soon realise that they are being taken advantage of, especially when they chat with friends in other labs. When students become unhappy and the trust in their supervisor breaks down, the whole process can become ineffective for everyone concerned. As the supervisor you are there to help and guide their project… not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be really challenging when graduate projects are embedded within a larger funded project. How do you balance the commitment you’ve made to the funder alongside the need for students to have sufficient ownership? Firstly, think carefully about whether your project really lends itself to a graduate student. Highly specified and rigid projects need great research assistants rather than graduate students. Secondly, build in sufficient scope for individual projects and analyses, for example by collecting flexible data types (e.g. parent-child play samples) which invite novel analyses, and make sure that students are aware of any constraints before they start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are they here to learn?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO provide opportunities to learn skills which extend beyond the project goals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A successful graduate project is not just measured in terms of thesis or papers, but in the professional skills acquired and whether these help them launch a career in whichever direction they choose. This will mean allowing your students to learn skills necessary for their research, but also giving them broader opportunities: formal training courses, giving and hearing talks, visiting other labs or attending conferences. This is all to be encouraged, though be careful that it happens alongside research progress, rather than as a displacement activity. Towards the end of the PhD, as the student prepares to fly the nest, these activities can be an important way of building the connections that are necessary to be part of a scientific community and make the next step in their career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T expect them to achieve technical marvels without support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All too often supervisors see exciting new analyses in papers or in talks and want to bring those skills to their lab. But remember, if you cannot teach the students to do something, then who will? Duncan still &lt;em&gt;tries&lt;/em&gt; to get his hands dirty with the code (and is humoured in this effort by his lab members), but often manages to underestimate how difficult some technical steps can be. Meanwhile, Sue is coming to terms with the fact that she will never fully understand R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you recommend new technical analyses, or development of innovative stimuli, then make sure you fully understand what you are asking of your student – allow sufficient time for this and provide appropriate support. When thinking of co-supervisors, don’t always go for the bigwig you are trying to cosy up to… often a more junior member of staff whose technical skills are up-to-date would be far more useful to your student. Also try and create a lab culture with good peer support. Just as ‘&lt;em&gt;it takes a village to raise a child’&lt;/em&gt;, so “&lt;em&gt;it takes a lab to supervise a PhD student&lt;/em&gt;”. Proper peer support mechanisms, shared problem solving and an open lab culture are important ingredients for giving students the proper support they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being reasonable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO set clear expectations             &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one of any PhD should be to create a project timeline.  Sue normally recommends a detailed 6-month plan alongside a sketched 3-year plan, both of which should be updated about quarterly. For a study which is broken down into a series of short experiments, a different model might be better. Whatever planning system you adopt, you should work with your student to set realistic deadlines for specific tasks, assuming a full time 9-5 working day and no more, and adhere to these. Model best practice by providing timely feedback at an appropriate level of detail – remember, you can give too much as well as too little feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think carefully about what sort of outputs to ask for – make them reasonable and appropriate to the task. You might want propose a lengthy piece of writing in the first six months, to demonstrate that your student has grasped the literature and can pull it together coherently to make a case for their chosen research.  But, depending on the project, it might also be a good idea to get them to contrast some differing theoretical models in a mini-presentation to your lab, create a table summarising key methodological details and findings from previous work, or publish a web page to prioritise community engagement with the project topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T forget their mental health and work-life balance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhD students might have recently moved from another country or city – they may be tackling cultural differences at work and socially. Simultaneous life changes often happen at the same time as a PhD – meeting a life partner, marriage, children. Your students might be living in rented and shared accommodation, with all the stresses that can bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your students go home at a reasonable hour.  If you must work outside office hours be clear you don’t expect the same from them. Remind them to take a holiday – especially if they have had a period of working hard (e.g. meeting a deadline, collecting data at weekends). Ensure that information about the University support services are available prominently in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to take into account their personal lives when you are discussing project progress. Being honest about your own personal situation (without over-sharing) creates an environment where it is OK to talk about stuff happening outside the office. Looking after your students’ mental health doesn’t mean being soft, or turning a blind eye to missed deadlines or poor quality work – it means being proactive and taking action when you can see things aren’t going well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about the research??&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are planning another blog in the future about MSc and undergrad supervision which might address some other questions more closely tied to the research itself – how to design an encapsulated, realistic but also worthwhile piece of research, and how to structure this over time. But the success (or otherwise) of a PhD hangs on a lot more than just having a great idea and delivering it on time. We hope this post will help readers to reflect on their personal management style and think about how that impacts their students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, be humble. Be supportive. Be a good supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/544/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/544/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=544&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 14:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Did the author of a now-retracted article bribe a critic to silence him?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51449</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/author-now-retracted-article-bribe-critic-silence/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Authors react in a variety of ways to criticism of their work. Some stonewall, some grit their teeth but make corrections, and others thank their critics. But what about bribery? After an economist alerted a journal and government agency to potential problems with a 2015 paper, he says the first author tried to bribe him […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/07/author-now-retracted-article-bribe-critic-silence/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Did the author of a now-retracted article bribe a critic to silence him?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 12:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Guiding addiction treatment from the front lines</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/guiding-addiction-treatment-from-the-front-lines</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/guiding-addiction-treatment-from-the-front-lines</link>
	<description>Elsevier’s Dr. Leslie Dye on recognizing addiction — and using technology to get health professionals the information they need at the point of care</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 11:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, West Germany embraced nuclear power</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-west-germany-embraced-nuclear-power</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-west-germany-embraced-nuclear-power</link>
	<description>In 1967, Germany gave nuclear power a try. Today, the country is trading nukes for renewables.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/080417_50yaGermany_free.jpg?itok=frf4-UYb" length="21059" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Elsevier supports TOP Guidelines in ongoing efforts to ensure research quality and transparency</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-supports-top-guidelines-in-ongoing-efforts-to-ensure-research-quality-and-transparency</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-supports-top-guidelines-in-ongoing-efforts-to-ensure-research-quality-and-transparency</link>
	<description>Elsevier’s new journal data guidelines promote the exchange and integrity of scientific research</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 09:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC-series: August 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9490</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/07/highlights-bmc-series-august-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Family Practice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0650-0&quot;&gt;Managing diagnostic uncertainty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic uncertainty is one of the biggest predictors of diagnostic error. When coming across diagnostic uncertainty, physicians can respond in multiple ways including cognitive, emotional and ethical reactions. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcfampract.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12875-017-0650-0&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Family Practice &lt;/em&gt;determined how primary care physicians deal with diagnostic uncertainty in cognitive, emotional, and ethical domains. These responses included behaviors such as reaching out to supportive colleagues, seeking out further training, anxiety due to diagnostic uncertainty, and whether or not to disclose diagnostic uncertainty to patients. Diagnostic uncertainty can have implications for the doctor, patient, and healthcare system in general and the authors further discuss how doctors can better manage their responses to diagnostic uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Psychiatry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;Mobile applications for suicidal ideation self-management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of online and mobile telephone applications (‘apps’) have been increasingly used to treat psychological disorders, especially for populations that have limited resources and are remotely located. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1458-0&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, Witt and colleagues searched the exhisting literature to determine the effectivenss of apps for the self-management of suicidal ideation and self-harm. The use of apps offers some promise for reducing suicidal ideation although there did not seem to be any beneficial impact on suicide attempts or self-harm. Furthermore, the adherence to these programs was poor. The authors discuss the limitations and variability of the existing literature and argue for more well designed studies to determine whether the use of apps for suicidal ideation and self-harm can be productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Physiology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcphysiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12899-017-0033-8&quot;&gt;Androgen receptors in developing heart cells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Androgens have been shown to be involved in the sex differences in cardiovascular diseases. Androgen receptors in cardiac muscle cells called myocytes could help explain this association. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcphysiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12899-017-0033-8&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Physiology&lt;/em&gt;, the authors examined the expression of androgen receptors on cardiac myocytes while also looking at alpha and beta myosin heavy chain genes and atrial natriuretic peptide genes. The authors looked at the hearts of male and female mice prenatally and early postnatally.  Androgen receptors were found in cardiac myocytes during heart development prenatally and during heart maturation postnatally.  Androgen receptors were found primarily in the cardiac myocytes nuclei compared to surrounding cells and were found more in atria compared to ventricles postnatally. These findings indicate that androgen receptors are involved in heart development pre- and post-natally but interestingly the lack of sex difference suggests that sex differences in cardiovascular diseases may not be related to the developing heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image(s) of the month:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0138-8&quot;&gt;The winners of the 2017 &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Image competition 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the fifth year &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; held its astounding image competition.  Ecologists from all over the world submitted their photographs to showcase their research. The &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology &lt;/em&gt;editorial board, along with special guest judge Chris Darimont, had the pleasure to vote on the photographs based on the image and the story behind it. This year’s winning image was by Ana Carolina Lima who took a picture of giant South American turtles (&lt;em&gt;Podocatemias expansa&lt;/em&gt;) which was admired for its “…rare, multi-layered perspective from above”.  In contrast to the lively image of the winner, the first runner-up photograph entitled “Two Towers” pictures the stark Antarctic landscape.  Winners were selected for each section of &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; including a special Editor’s pick. Meanwhile 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; place went to the image below, entitled ‘Connections’. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-017-0138-8&quot;&gt;Read the announcement editorial&lt;/a&gt; to see all the winners, along with a number of excellent highly commended entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9424&quot; style=&quot;width: 5268px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9424&quot; height=&quot;3505&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;5258&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Second runner-up&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Roberto García-Roa &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Psychology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0198-8&quot;&gt;Methods for word learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several techniques to learn new words which can include recall, reproduction, and restudy. These techniques have been shown to be beneficial when learning written words. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40359-017-0198-8&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology&lt;/em&gt; by Krishnan and colleagues, which went through &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychology’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychology.biomedcentral.com/about/results-free-peer-review-for-authors&quot;&gt;Results-free Review&lt;/a&gt; process, aimed to determine the effects of three different word learning techniques when participants are taught words that are presented to them verbally instead of in written form. Participants went through a task in which they learned pseudowords presented verbally and learned these words through a cued recall, reproduction, and restudy method of learning. It was hypothesized that cued recall practice would lead to better retention in the long term.  In contrast to the hypothesis, cued recall training did not provide better retention of newly learned words in the long term compared to the forms of learning new words. This suggests that how people learn words presented verbally differs from how they learn written words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC Geriatrics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-017-0578-1&quot;&gt;Changes in physical activity in older people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than 10% of the population in the UK over 75 years of age reach the recommended amount of physical activity. Unfortunately, this information is primarily collected through subjective questionnaires thereby risking accuracy. In a study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-017-0578-1&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Geriatrics&lt;/em&gt; the authors surveyed a population of almost 600 community dwelling people over the age of 65. Various questionnaires were used to assess health, subjective norms, coping planning and social support, anxiety, and depression.  Subjects were then fitted with an accelerometer on their waist to measure physical activity. The lack of a satisfactory social network, older age, lower self-reported physical functioning and diabetes all independently predicted lower objectively measured physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/07/highlights-bmc-series-august-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC-series: August 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 09:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: How short-term increases in testosterone change men’s thinking style</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29735</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/07/how-short-term-increases-in-testosterone-change-mens-thinking-style/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29753&quot; style=&quot;width: 1522px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-91016858.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29753&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29753&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;MaryLB&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Retro profile of a man with gears in brain II&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845?w=791&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845?w=232&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1522,1970&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/07/how-short-term-increases-in-testosterone-change-mens-thinking-style/retro-profile-of-a-man-with-gears-in-brain-ii/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-91016858.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Competitive situations or the presence of attractive potential mates can lead to the short-term testosterone increases that were the focus of the new research&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hot-headed “macho man”, who acts first and thinks later, has long been popular in movies.  Now there’s psychological evidence to support it. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617709592&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/i&gt; finds that a short-term rise in testosterone – as might occur when in the presence of an attractive potential mate, or during competition – shifts the way men think, encouraging them to rely on quick, intuitive, and generally less accurate, judgements, rather than engaging in careful, more deliberate thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29735&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the biggest investigation of the effects of testosterone on human behaviour to date, a team from Caltech, the University of Pennsylvania, Western University and the ZRT Laboratory in Oregon, recruited 243 men, mostly college students. The men rubbed a gel that they were told either contained testosterone or was a placebo over their shoulders, upper arms and chest. Four-and-a-half hours later – enough time for their testosterone levels to peak – they embarked on a series of tests (saliva samples taken from the men through the study confirmed that testosterone levels were indeed higher in the group that applied the gel that contained testosterone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most critical test, in terms of the study aims, was the three-item Cognitive Reflection Test, which evaluates a person’s ability to override quick and intuitive, but likely incorrect, judgements through deliberate, careful thought. The volunteers were told that they’d be paid $1 for each correct answer, with a bonus of $2 for three correct answers, and they could take as long as they liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example from the test: &lt;i&gt;A bat and a ball cost $1.10 in total. The bat costs $1.00 more than the ball. How much does the ball cost? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier work has found that, when presented with this question, most people go with their first thought, and answer, incorrectly, 10 cents – even though it is straightforward to check the answer, which would show that 10 cents is wrong. With a little deliberation, it’s not too difficult for most people to work out the right answer*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that the men who’d received testosterone performed significantly worse on this test. Overall, they came up with 20 per cent fewer correct answers than the men who’d received the placebo. What’s more, when volunteers who’d received testosterone gave correct answers, they tended to do this more slowly than the volunteers who’d got the placebo. While the team didn’t measure individual volunteers’ testosterone levels, based on previous work on the dose used (100 mg of topical 1 per cent testosterone), they were probably at around the level that young men experience during real-world competition, the researchers say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tasks also included an arithmetic test, and those who’d got the testosterone did as well as the others. The researchers take this to show that it was the men’s ability to reflect on their first impulses that was affected by the testosterone dose, rather than their level of engagement in the study, their motivation or their arithmetic skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our results demonstrate a clear and robust causal effect of testosterone on human cognition and decision making,” the researchers write. “The influence of testosterone on the Cognitive Reflection Test, alongside its lack of effect on the arithmetic control task, suggests that testosterone decreases … the probability of engaging in slow and effortful cognitive processes but keeps the capacity to perform them intact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context will determine whether this is bad news or not. Rapid intuitive responses could be beneficial for increasing the chance of having sex or succeeding at a physical challenge, the researchers observe. But they could be detrimental in the workplace – or an exam room. Is this an argument, then, for gender separation in classrooms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volunteers were all male, so the study tells us nothing about the effects of testosterone on thinking in women (who also produce the hormone, but at lower levels). And the study doesn’t identify what might mediate the greater reliance on intuitive decision-making with raised testosterone – over-confidence, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Male testosterone levels gradually fall with age, and some older men use testosterone ‘replacement’ gels, often at the dose used in this study, or inject the hormone. “Western society has been experiencing an exogenous testosterone ‘shock’ over the past decade from a rapidly growing testosterone-replacement-therapy industry,” the researchers write, in a final note. “The possibility that this widely prescribed treatment has unknown deleterious influences on specific aspects of decision making should be investigated further and taken into account by users, physicians and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More work is now needed to explore the effects of testosterone supplements in older men (whose levels are lower to start with), as well as to better understand how testosterone levels fluctuate naturally in day to day life – and so the likely effects on cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0956797617709592&quot;&gt;Single-Dose Testosterone Administration Impairs Cognitive Reflection in Men&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*The bat costs $1.05 and the ball costs 5 cents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29735/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29735/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29735&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 09:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Bats slam into buildings because they can't 'see' them</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22583</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3_5ZonPOZ40/nature.2017.22583</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Smooth, vertical structures such as steel and glass buildings appear invisible to bats' echolocation system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22583&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22583&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3_5ZonPOZ40&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Pollen hitches a ride on bees in all the right spots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollen-hitches-ride-bees-all-right-spots</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/pollen-hitches-ride-bees-all-right-spots</link>
	<description>Flower reproduction depends on the pollen that collects in hard-to-reach spots on bees, a new study shows.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090517_mt_bees_feat_free.jpg?itok=qGBd2Okr" length="39191" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers were curious about rogue planets, exomoons and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-were-curious-about-rogue-planets-exomoons-and-more</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-were-curious-about-rogue-planets-exomoons-and-more</link>
	<description>Readers had questions about rogue planets, human arrival in Australia, and exomoons.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 17:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Learning is a ubiquitous, mysterious phenomenon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/learning-ubiquitous-mysterious-phenomenon</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/learning-ubiquitous-mysterious-phenomenon</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill talks about the science of learning and how our brains process new knowledge.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 17:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Predatory journals: Not just a problem in developing world countries, says new Nature paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51688</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/predatory-journals-not-just-developing-world-countries-says-new-nature-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;“Common wisdom,” according to the authors of a new piece in Nature, “assumes that the hazard of predatory publishing is restricted mainly to the developing world.” But the authors of the new paper, led by David Moher of the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, found that more than half — 57% — of the 2,000 articles […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/predatory-journals-not-just-developing-world-countries-says-new-nature-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Predatory journals: Not just a problem in developing world countries, says new Nature paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Machines are getting schooled on fairness</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/machines-are-getting-schooled-fairness</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/machines-are-getting-schooled-fairness</link>
	<description>Machine-learning programs are introducing biases that may harm job seekers, loan applicants and more.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/091617_learning-machine_feat.jpg?itok=16cdJuis" length="17664" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: One In Four US Children Exposed To Weapon Violence: Helping Kids Cope with Trauma</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22663</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/06/one-in-four-children-exposed-to-weapon-violence-helping-kids-cope-with-trauma/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An important study published in &lt;em&gt;Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; indicated that over 17.5 million (or 1 in 4) school-aged children in the United States have been exposed to weapon violence in their lifetime, as either witnesses or victims. The results also suggest that more than 2 million (1 in 33) children have been directly assaulted with lethal weapons, including guns and knives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data was collected as part of the National Survey of Children’s Exposure to Violence. The sample (N = 4114) was a nationally represented survey conducted in 2011 of children (51% boys, 56.7% Caucasian, 18.8% Latino, 15.1% Black, and 9.4 Another Non-Latino Race) between the ages of two and seventeen years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the authors, children’s exposure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/02/19/human-aggression-and-violence-a-necessary-evil/&quot;&gt;violence&lt;/a&gt; is a primary national healthcare crisis, even greater than pediatric diabetes or cancer. The American Academy of Pediatrics&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; suggests an even higher concern, stating that gun violence is the second leading cause of death for children in the United States. Data from the National Center for Health Statistics&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; supports these concerns, indicating that firearms are in the top 10 leading causes of injury deaths for children as young as 1 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brady Campaign&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; also reports staggering statistics, including a daily average of 40 children and teens being shot and surviving, American children being killed by gun violence 11 times more often than children in other high-income countries, and the incidence of over 160 school shootings since the Sandy Hook mass shooting in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical, psychological, and economic cost of these statistics are profound, but frequently neglected or unknown. It is estimated that homicide- and assault-related injuries cost the US $16 million annually.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Being a victim, a victim of multiple incidents (poly-victim), or even a witness of violence results in significant levels of symptoms of trauma, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/08/new-target-in-brain-for-treating-depression-the-bmp-pathway/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, anxiety, anger, and aggression in youth.&lt;sup&gt;1,5&lt;/sup&gt; The authors report that children exposed to lethal weapon violence, such as a knife or gun crime, were significantly more likely to report these symptoms than children who had not been exposed to such weapon violence, even after taking into consideration and removing the variables of physical abuse, sexual abuse, and neglect that are also associated with trauma symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that research indicates that witnessing violence is also a significant risk factor, and is often more frightening to children.&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Moreover, high lethality risk weapon violence is a greater contributing factor to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/24/how-does-post-traumatic-stress-disorder-change-the-brain/&quot;&gt;trauma symptoms&lt;/a&gt;, even more than that of multiple victimization incidents.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence, prevalence, and research indicate that weapon violence is frighteningly high in the United States, and a substantial number of children may be at risk for significant &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/03/18/the-trauma-inflicted-by-child-sex-predators/&quot;&gt;mental health issues&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, program development and implementation focused on intervention and prevention related to the consequences of weapon violence are sparse and often unavailable to communities who need it most. It is imperative that we focus our resources on what is being defined by experts as a “national youth crisis” in delivering cost-effective, immediate, and community-based mental health programs to children exposed to weapon violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it may take years to diminish the prevalence of weapon violence in the US, simple therapeutic tools may be the first step for immediate intervention. One such resource is a new book, &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go? Helping Children Cope With A Traumatic Death&lt;/em&gt; that can serve as an excellent first step in the journey of healing. &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go? &lt;/em&gt;is a children’s picture book for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;therapeutic coping&lt;/a&gt; that is to be read by an adult to a young child (3–8 years) who has witnessed or survived a traumatic death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the book is to facilitate the child’s processing and coping with the fear, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/07/03/coping-with-grief-and-loss-the-five-stages/&quot;&gt;loss&lt;/a&gt;, and confusion associated with the trauma in developmentally appropriate and safe ways. Thorough guides for adults and child-based interventions are provided at the beginning and end of the book. The book is versatile and can be utilized for incidents of gun violence, other-weapon violence, terrorist attacks, car accidents, and plane crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents, teachers, pediatricians, ER doctors, counselors, and social workers in schools, shelters, community clinics, and hospitals, who are the first to observe socio-emotional and physical symptoms in children, can use &lt;em&gt;Where Did My Friend Go?&lt;/em&gt; as a first step assessment and intervention tool. The professionals on the front lines working with affected children need to be proactive in asking children about their exposure to weapon violence, and this book can serve as a helpful resource in the process. The play-based interventions at the end of the book are also an effective guide for parents and professionals on how to explore, shift, and reassure young children’s trauma, anxiety, and loss to more adaptive functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mental health professionals need to begin to develop and deliver intervention and prevention programs in schools, clinics, and shelters for the staggering number of children and teenagers exposed to lethal weapon violence. Teachers and healthcare professionals can play a critical role in identifying victims of violence and making appropriate referrals. Establishing and implementing standardized screenings for exposure to lethal weapon violence for children and teenagers as part of a general well-visit exam at the pediatrician’s, as well as in all schools, Head Starts, ERs, and shelters may further allow us to intervene at the early stages of symptom presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we well know, violence begets violence. Early intervention is prevention, and if one in four American children are being directly exposed to weapon violence, we need to step in now to break the intergenerational cycle of violence and the emerging mental health crisis related to trauma and weapon violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitchell, K., Hamby S., Turner, H., Shattuck, A., and Jones, M. (2015). Weapons involvement in the victimization of children. Pediatrics, &lt;em&gt;136&lt;/em&gt; (1), 10-17. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2014-3966&quot;&gt;10.1542/peds.2014-3966&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Pediatrics (2013). Retrieved from http://bit.ly/2wxZSiY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Center for Health Statistics, National Vital Statistics System. 10 Leading causes of injury deaths by age group highlighting violent-related injury deaths. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/injury/wisqars/pdf/10LCID_Violence_Related_Injury_Deaths_2010-a.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brady Campaign. Retrieved from http://bit.ly/1Rhqfts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner, H.A., Shattuck, A., Hamby S, and Finkelhor, D. (2013). Community disorder, victimization exposure, and mental health in a national sample of youth. Journal of Health and Social Behavior, &lt;em&gt;54&lt;/em&gt; (2), 258-275. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1177/0022146513479384&quot;&gt;10.1177/0022146513479384&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamby S., Finkelhor D., and Turner H. (2013). Perpetrator and victim gender patterns for 21 forms of youth victimization in the National Survey of Children’s Exposure to Violence. Violence and Victims, &lt;em&gt;28 &lt;/em&gt;(6), 915–939. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00067&quot;&gt;10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00067&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/kellepics-4893063/&quot;&gt;kellepics&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 15:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Data fabrication by ex-Harvard researcher takes down paper on Huntington’s disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51671</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/data-fabrication-ex-harvard-researcher-takes-paper-huntingtons-disease/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A researcher at Harvard Medical School and Massachusetts General Hospital is retracting a paper due to “inappropriate manipulation and fabrication of data” by the first author. According to the retraction notice, published Aug. 22, corresponding author Marian DiFiglia is retracting the paper because the alleged misconduct by the first author, Antonio Valencia: led to an […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/06/data-fabrication-ex-harvard-researcher-takes-paper-huntingtons-disease/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Data fabrication by ex-Harvard researcher takes down paper on Huntington’s disease&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The results from a slew of experiments are in: Dark matter remains elusive</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/results-slew-experiments-are-dark-matter-remains-elusive</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/results-slew-experiments-are-dark-matter-remains-elusive</link>
	<description>Scientists continue the search for particles that make up the universe’s missing matter.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090517_ec_darkmatter.jpg?itok=X17l8w2I" length="48403" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Rising temperatures threaten heat-tolerant aardvarks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-temperatures-threaten-heat-tolerant-aardvarks</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rising-temperatures-threaten-heat-tolerant-aardvarks</link>
	<description>Aardvarks may get a roundabout hit from climate change — less food.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/080217_SM_notebook_aardvark_main.jpg?itok=VTMz4FZw" length="35837" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Researchers asked these British mothers which personality traits they would most wish for their babies – extraversion came out on top</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29622</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-587877026.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29725&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29725&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 6D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A happy mother kisses her baby's feet while she is lying down. The baby is looking up at her wearing a white baby grow.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1470912399&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SolStock&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Affectionate Mother&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Affectionate Mother&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/affectionate-mother/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-587877026.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambitious and self-disciplined or affable and fun-loving? If you could choose the personality profile for your children, what would you prioritise? Researchers at Goldsmiths, University of London, put this question to 142 British mothers with a baby aged 0 to 12 months. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865&quot;&gt;Reporting their findings in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Rachel Latham and Sophie von Stumm say there was a clear preference among the mothers for most of all wanting their infants to grow up to be extraverted, especially friendly and cheerful, more so than conscientious or intelligent, even though these latter attributes are more likely to contribute to a healthy, successful life. To the researchers’ knowledge this is the first time mothers’ wishes for their children’s personalities has been studied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29622&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latham and von Stumm told the mothers (average age 33) the six personality facets that make up each of the Big Five personality traits (Extraversion, Conscientiousness, Neuroticism, Agreeableness, Openness to Experience). For each trait, the mothers were asked to say which facet they would most like their child to have. See the results below, showing how often each facet was chosen as the most preferred for each trait:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29698&quot; style=&quot;width: 2800px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-06 11.01.48.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29698&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29698&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-09-06 11.01.48&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2800,2380&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/06/most-mothers-hope-their-babies-will-become-extroverts-more-than-smart-or-self-disciplined/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/screenshot-2017-09-06-11-01-48.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865#f0005&quot;&gt;Latham and von Stumm, 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, the mothers were asked to place their chosen five facets (one from each trait) in order of most to least important for their child to have, and to also place intelligence in its appropriate place in this list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than half the mothers chose a facet of Extraversion as the most important overall, followed by 20 per cent choosing a facet of Agreeableness, such as being moral or trustworthy, as most important. An Openness facet was chosen as most important by just under 10 per cent of mothers, with intelligence or a facet of Conscientiousness, such as achievement-striving, not far behind at 9 to 10 per cent. Mothers’ choices didn’t vary with the sex of their child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latham and von Stumm point out that the high priority that mothers placed on Extraversion and the relatively low priority given to Conscientiousness and Intelligence contrasts sharply with the research literature on which traits are most important to positive and negative life outcomes. For instance, people who are more intelligent and Conscientious tend to live longer, healthier lives and do better in their careers and relationships. By contrast, although Extraversion correlates with being happier, it is also associated with negative outcomes such as drink and drug problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the research doesn’t speak to why mothers prioritised the traits that they did. “It is possible that mothers’ preference for extraversion is the result of a cohort effect, whereby the current zeitgeist, rather than the mothers themselves, values and encourages extraversion,” Latham and von Stumm speculated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see follow-up research on this question – for instance, how might mothers’ wishes for their children vary cross-culturally. And what about fathers’ wishes? The researchers speculated that perhaps fathers would place a higher value on traits that promote achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study contains an odd anomaly. Four of the five Big Five personality traits were presented in such a way that having more of any of the related facets would be an obviously welcome thing – such as being more friendly (a facet of Extraversion), having more imagination (Openness), being more self-disciplined (Conscientious). However, in terms of a person’s emotionality, the researchers presented the relevant trait as a negative: as Neuroticism rather than as Emotional Stability, its positive polar opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s little wonder then than zero mothers chose a facet of Neuroticism (such as self-consciousness or vulnerability) as the facet they would most like their child to have. Of course, if this trait had been framed as Emotional Stability (with positive facets, such as relaxed and not easily embarrassed), it’s possible many mothers would have placed a high priority on this trait. In fact, past research has shown that when young adults around the world are asked how they would most like to change their personality, most of them say that increasing their Emotional Stability (or reducing Neuroticism) is the change they would most like to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last, related point. Introverts may notice that the facets of Extraversion were all worded in a way biased in favour of the extroverted end of this personality dimension. It’s easy to imagine the results would have been different with some word changes to make the introverted end of this trait more appealing, such as listing “is content to spend time alone” and “happy to take it easy” as facets of Introversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917304865#f0005&quot;&gt;Mothers want extraversion over conscientiousness or intelligence for their children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and his next book &lt;em&gt;Personology &lt;/em&gt;(due 2019) is on the science of personality change. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29622/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29622/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29622&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 10:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Researchers riled by lack of detail in Brexit science plans</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22566</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/t8OBuN9VUV8/nature.2017.22566</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;UK government document fails to extinguish concerns over funding and migration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 140 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22566&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22566&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/t8OBuN9VUV8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Massive genetic study shows how humans are evolving</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22565</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3dfBJ2GQjic/nature.2017.22565</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Analysis of 215,000 people's DNA suggests variants that shorten life are being selected against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22565&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22565&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3dfBJ2GQjic&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Bacterial 'aphrodisiac' sends single-celled organism into mating frenzy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22549</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/B20mXw3oXG4/nature.2017.22549</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers surprised to observe bacterial protein triggering a switch from asexual to sexual behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22549&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/B20mXw3oXG4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Germany must go back to its low-carbon future</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549026a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rYn5vpowqhU/549026a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Once a world leader in renewables, the nation will miss all of its environmental goals unless the next government realigns its energy policies, warns Claudia Kemfert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 26 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549026a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549026a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rYn5vpowqhU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Stop this waste of people, animals and money</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549023a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yJ5FdgsqOlg/549023a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Predatory journals have shoddy reporting and include papers from wealthy nations, find David Moher, Larissa Shamseer, Kelly Cobey and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549023a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549023a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yJ5FdgsqOlg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The secret to Germany’s scientific excellence</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549018a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4KXb-leqrWI/549018a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;With a national election this month, Germany proves that foresight and stability can power research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 18 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549018a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549018a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4KXb-leqrWI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: North Korea's nuclear test, cash for Italy's scientists and Zika-vaccine pause</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549010a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EWKXArtPEHY/549010a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 1–7 September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 10 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549010a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549010a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EWKXArtPEHY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Illegitimate journals scam even senior scientists</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549007a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/unYzndNfZxs/549007a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Kelly Cobey has seen a litany of researchers preyed on by predatory journals — and has ideas on how to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 7 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549007a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549007a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/unYzndNfZxs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Merkel deserves another term as German chancellor</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549005a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/aTDw5ucWOQ4/549005a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The former physicist shows a welcome immunity to the mood of anti-science resentment that has infected some democracies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 5 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/549005a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549005a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/aTDw5ucWOQ4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Palmitoylation-dependent activation of MC1R prevents melanomagenesis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23887</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tf2Nw-2YK28/nature23887</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The melanocortin-1 receptor (MC1R), a G-protein-coupled receptor, has a crucial role in human and mouse pigmentation. Activation of MC1R in melanocytes by α-melanocyte-stimulating hormone (α-MSH) stimulates cAMP signalling and melanin production and enhances DNA repair after ultraviolet irradiation. Individuals carrying MC1R variants, especially those associated with red hair colour, fair skin and poor tanning ability (denoted as RHC variants), are associated with higher risk of melanoma. However, how MC1R activity is modulated by ultraviolet irradiation, why individuals with red hair are more prone to developing melanoma, and whether the activity of RHC variants might be restored for therapeutic benefit are unknown. Here we demonstrate a potential MC1R-targeted intervention strategy in mice to rescue loss-of-function MC1R in MC1R RHC variants for therapeutic benefit by activating MC1R protein palmitoylation. MC1R palmitoylation, primarily mediated by the protein-acyl transferase ZDHHC13, is essential for activating MC1R signalling, which triggers increased pigmentation, ultraviolet-B-induced G1-like cell cycle arrest and control of senescence and melanomagenesis in vitro and in vivo. Using C57BL/6J-Mc1re/eJ mice, in which endogenous MC1R is prematurely terminated, expressing Mc1r RHC variants, we show that pharmacological activation of palmitoylation rescues the defects of Mc1r RHC variants and prevents melanomagenesis. The results highlight a central role for MC1R palmitoylation in pigmentation and protection against melanoma. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23887&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23887&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tf2Nw-2YK28&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: m6A modulates haematopoietic stem and progenitor cell specification</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23883</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/p9FyrIb-Coo/nature23883</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 N6-methyladenosine (m6A) has been identified as the most abundant modification on eukaryote messenger RNA (mRNA). Although the rapid development of high-throughput sequencing technologies has enabled insight into the biological functions of m6A modification, the function of m6A during vertebrate embryogenesis remains poorly understood. Here we show that m6A determines cell fate during the endothelial-to-haematopoietic transition (EHT) to specify the earliest haematopoietic stem/progenitor cells (HSPCs) during zebrafish embryogenesis. m6A-specific methylated RNA immunoprecipitation combined with high-throughput sequencing (MeRIP–seq) and m6A individual-nucleotide-resolution cross-linking and immunoprecipitation with sequencing (miCLIP–seq) analyses reveal conserved features on zebrafish m6A methylome and preferential distribution of m6A peaks near the stop codon with a consensus RRACH motif. In mettl3-deficient embryos, levels of m6A are significantly decreased and emergence of HSPCs is blocked. Mechanistically, we identify that the delayed YTHDF2-mediated mRNA decay of the arterial endothelial genes notch1a and rhoca contributes to this deleterious effect. The continuous activation of Notch signalling in arterial endothelial cells of mettl3-deficient embryos blocks EHT, thereby repressing the generation of the earliest HSPCs. Furthermore, knockdown of Mettl3 in mice confers a similar phenotype. Collectively, our findings demonstrate the critical function of m6A modification in the fate determination of HSPCs during vertebrate embryogenesis. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23883&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23883&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/p9FyrIb-Coo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Polycomb-like proteins link the PRC2 complex to CpG islands</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23881</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/E7Eowlfqbuo/nature23881</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The Polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2) mainly mediates transcriptional repression and has essential roles in various biological processes including the maintenance of cell identity and proper differentiation. Polycomb-like (PCL) proteins, such as PHF1, MTF2 and PHF19, are PRC2-associated factors that form sub-complexes with PRC2 core components, and have been proposed to modulate the enzymatic activity of PRC2 or the recruitment of PRC2 to specific genomic loci. Mammalian PRC2-binding sites are enriched in CG content, which correlates with CpG islands that display a low level of DNA methylation. However, the mechanism of PRC2 recruitment to CpG islands is not fully understood. Here we solve the crystal structures of the N-terminal domains of PHF1 and MTF2 with bound CpG-containing DNAs in the presence of H3K36me3-containing histone peptides. We show that the extended homologous regions of both proteins fold into a winged-helix structure, which specifically binds to the unmethylated CpG motif but in a completely different manner from the canonical winged-helix DNA recognition motif. We also show that the PCL extended homologous domains are required for efficient recruitment of PRC2 to CpG island-containing promoters in mouse embryonic stem cells. Our research provides the first, to our knowledge, direct evidence to demonstrate that PCL proteins are crucial for PRC2 recruitment to CpG islands, and further clarifies the roles of these proteins in transcriptional regulation in vivo. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23881&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23881&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/E7Eowlfqbuo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Competing memories of mitogen and p53 signalling control cell-cycle entry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23880</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/qSQ5T4rhHu8/nature23880</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Regulation of cell proliferation is necessary for immune responses, tissue repair, and upkeep of organ function to maintain human health. When proliferating cells complete mitosis, a fraction of newly born daughter cells immediately enter the next cell cycle, while the remaining cells in the same population exit to a transient or persistent quiescent state. Whether this choice between two cell-cycle pathways is due to natural variability in mitogen signalling or other underlying causes is unknown. Here we show that human cells make this fundamental cell-cycle entry or exit decision based on competing memories of variable mitogen and stress signals. Rather than erasing their signalling history at cell-cycle checkpoints before mitosis, mother cells transmit DNA damage-induced p53 protein and mitogen-induced cyclin D1 (CCND1) mRNA to newly born daughter cells. After mitosis, the transferred CCND1 mRNA and p53 protein induce variable expression of cyclin D1 and the CDK inhibitor p21 that almost exclusively determines cell-cycle commitment in daughter cells. We find that stoichiometric inhibition of cyclin D1–CDK4 activity by p21 controls the retinoblastoma (Rb) and E2F transcription program in an ultrasensitive manner. Thus, daughter cells control the proliferation–quiescence decision by converting the memories of variable mitogen and stress signals into a competition between cyclin D1 and p21 expression. We propose a cell-cycle control principle based on natural variation, memory and competition that maximizes the health of growing cell populations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23880&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23880&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/qSQ5T4rhHu8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: The neuropeptide neuromedin U stimulates innate lymphoid cells and type 2 inflammation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23676</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jYZx1HglNDQ/nature23676</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The type 2 cytokines interleukin (IL)-4, IL-5, IL-9 and IL-13 have important roles in stimulating innate and adaptive immune responses that are required for resistance to helminth infection, promotion of allergic inflammation, metabolic homeostasis and tissue repair. Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) produce type 2 cytokines, and although advances have been made in understanding the cytokine milieu that promotes ILC2 responses, how ILC2 responses are regulated by other stimuli remains poorly understood. Here we demonstrate that ILC2s in the mouse gastrointestinal tract co-localize with cholinergic neurons that express the neuropeptide neuromedin U (NMU). In contrast to other haematopoietic cells, ILC2s selectively express the NMU receptor 1 (NMUR1). In vitro stimulation of ILC2s with NMU induced rapid cell activation, proliferation, and secretion of the type 2 cytokines IL-5, IL-9 and IL-13 that was dependent on cell-intrinsic expression of NMUR1 and Gαq protein. In vivo administration of NMU triggered potent type 2 cytokine responses characterized by ILC2 activation, proliferation and eosinophil recruitment that was associated with accelerated expulsion of the gastrointestinal nematode Nippostrongylus brasiliensis or induction of lung inflammation. Conversely, worm burden was higher in Nmur1−/− mice than in control mice. Furthermore, use of gene-deficient mice and adoptive cell transfer experiments revealed that ILC2s were necessary and sufficient to mount NMU-elicited type 2 cytokine responses. Together, these data indicate that the NMU–NMUR1 neuronal signalling circuit provides a selective mechanism through which the enteric nervous system and innate immune system integrate to promote rapid type 2 cytokine responses that can induce anti-microbial, inflammatory and tissue-protective type 2 responses at mucosal sites. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23676&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jYZx1HglNDQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Structural basis of MsbA-mediated lipopolysaccharide transport</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23649</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ix3bppkVzaw/nature23649</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in the outer membrane of Gram-negative bacteria is critical for the assembly of their cell envelopes. LPS synthesized in the cytoplasmic leaflet of the inner membrane is flipped to the periplasmic leaflet by MsbA, an ATP-binding cassette transporter. Despite substantial efforts, the structural mechanisms underlying MsbA-driven LPS flipping remain elusive. Here we use single-particle cryo-electron microscopy to elucidate the structures of lipid-nanodisc-embedded MsbA in three functional states. The 4.2 Å-resolution structure of the transmembrane domains of nucleotide-free MsbA reveals that LPS binds deep inside MsbA at the height of the periplasmic leaflet, establishing extensive hydrophilic and hydrophobic interactions with MsbA. Two sub-nanometre-resolution structures of MsbA with ADP-vanadate and ADP reveal an unprecedented closed and an inward-facing conformation, respectively. Our study uncovers the structural basis for LPS recognition, delineates the conformational transitions of MsbA to flip LPS, and paves the way for structural characterization of other lipid flippases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23649&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23649&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ix3bppkVzaw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cell signalling: Red alert about lipid's role in skin cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23550</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/XumbpYRZtp0/nature23550</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Some versions of the MC1R protein are associated with red hair and an increased risk of developing a skin cancer called melanoma. It emerges that a lipid that binds MC1R might provide a target to reduce this risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23550&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23550&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/XumbpYRZtp0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cell biology: The persistence of memory</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23549</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/LfkPrIp7lZ8/nature23549</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Live imaging reveals that whether or not a daughter cell proliferates is influenced by two molecular factors inherited from its mother, providing insight into how the behaviour of a newly born cell can be predetermined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23549&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23549&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/LfkPrIp7lZ8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Leukaemia: Vitamin C regulates stem cells and cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23548</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/E44QHoPFeZA/nature23548</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It emerges that high levels of vitamin C in blood-forming stem cells influence the number and function of the cells and affect the development of leukaemia, through binding to a tumour-suppressor protein, Tet2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23548&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23548&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/E44QHoPFeZA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Neuronal regulation of type 2 innate lymphoid cells via neuromedin U</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23469</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/15555gY4WQY/nature23469</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Group 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) regulate inflammation, tissue repair and metabolic homeostasis, and are activated by host-derived cytokines and alarmins. Discrete subsets of immune cells integrate nervous system cues, but it remains unclear whether neuron-derived signals control ILC2s. Here we show that neuromedin U (NMU) in mice is a fast and potent regulator of type 2 innate immunity in the context of a functional neuron–ILC2 unit. We found that ILC2s selectively express neuromedin U receptor 1 (Nmur1), and mucosal neurons express NMU. Cell-autonomous activation of ILC2s with NMU resulted in immediate and strong NMUR1-dependent production of innate inflammatory and tissue repair cytokines. NMU controls ILC2s downstream of extracellular signal-regulated kinase and calcium-influx-dependent activation of both calcineurin and nuclear factor of activated T cells (NFAT). NMU treatment in vivo resulted in immediate protective type 2 responses. Accordingly, ILC2-autonomous ablation of Nmur1 led to impaired type 2 responses and poor control of worm infection. Notably, mucosal neurons were found adjacent to ILC2s, and these neurons directly sensed worm products and alarmins to induce NMU and to control innate type 2 cytokines. Our work reveals that neuron–ILC2 cell units confer immediate tissue protection through coordinated neuroimmune sensory responses. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23469&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23469&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/15555gY4WQY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A right-handed signalling pathway drives heart looping in vertebrates</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23454</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/MAMKqUtNmzA/nature23454</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Most animals show external bilateral symmetry, which hinders the observation of multiple internal left–right (L/R) asymmetries that are fundamental to organ packaging and function. In vertebrates, left identity is mediated by the left-specific Nodal–Pitx2 axis that is repressed on the right-hand side by the epithelial–mesenchymal transition (EMT) inducer Snail1 (refs 3, 4). Despite some existing evidence, it remains unclear whether an equivalent instructive pathway provides right-hand-specific information to the embryo. Here we show that, in zebrafish, BMP mediates the L/R asymmetric activation of another EMT inducer, Prrx1a, in the lateral plate mesoderm with higher levels on the right. Prrx1a drives L/R differential cell movements towards the midline, leading to a leftward displacement of the cardiac posterior pole through an actomyosin-dependent mechanism. Downregulation of Prrx1a prevents heart looping and leads to mesocardia. Two parallel and mutually repressed pathways, respectively driven by Nodal and BMP on the left and right lateral plate mesoderm, converge on the asymmetric activation of the transcription factors Pitx2 and Prrx1, which integrate left and right information to govern heart morphogenesis. This mechanism is conserved in the chicken embryo, and in the mouse SNAIL1 acts in a similar manner to Prrx1a in zebrafish and PRRX1 in the chick. Thus, a differential L/R EMT produces asymmetric cell movements and forces, more prominent from the right, that drive heart laterality in vertebrates. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 86 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23454&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/MAMKqUtNmzA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Molecular biology: Rhino gives voice to silent chromatin</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549038a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4LARF4WF7jQ/549038a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Flies use master lists of DNA sequences from transposons to identify and silence these virus-like, genomic parasites. How the lists themselves escape the fate of their transposon targets has now been solved.  See Letter    p.54&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 549 38 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/549038a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/549038a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4LARF4WF7jQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Zika could one day help combat deadly brain cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-could-one-day-help-combat-deadly-brain-cancer</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/zika-could-one-day-help-combat-deadly-brain-cancer</link>
	<description>The Zika virus targets cells that cause glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer, studies in human cells and mice show.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/articles/090117_LH-zika-cancer_main.jpg?itok=yqJS_SaS" length="33930" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Authors retract Science paper after investigation reveals manipulated images</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51680</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/authors-retract-science-paper-investigation-reveals-manipulated-images/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at a prominent Japanese university have retracted a 2015 paper in Science, after an investigation uncovered image falsification and fabrication. Last September, the University of Tokyo began an investigation of seven papers from the lab of cell biologist Yoshinori Watanabe after receiving anonymous allegations. In May 2017, the university determined that five papers contained falsified […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/authors-retract-science-paper-investigation-reveals-manipulated-images/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors retract Science paper after investigation reveals manipulated images&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Amid legal battle, psych journal issuing caution about torture paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51666</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/amid-legal-battle-psych-journal-issuing-caution-torture-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A psychology journal plans to issue an editor’s note about a controversial paper exploring what the author called “the biggest scandal to hit” the American Psychological Association (APA) in years. The note cautions readers that the subject of the paper, published in the SAGE journal Teaching of Psychology, is part of a pending lawsuit, and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/amid-legal-battle-psych-journal-issuing-caution-torture-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Amid legal battle, psych journal issuing caution about torture paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 15:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Learning takes brain acrobatics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-flexibility-learning</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-flexibility-learning</link>
	<description>Brains that learn best seem able to reconfigure themselves on the fly, a new line of research suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/091617_learning-brain_feat.jpg?itok=QDyTZTbF" length="28055" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Data and efficiency in science and medicine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/data-and-efficiency-in-science-and-medicine</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/data-and-efficiency-in-science-and-medicine</link>
	<description>September's theme explores how professionals are using smart technology to make data-driven decisions</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 13:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Scientifically misleading errors” prompt authors to withdraw paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51621</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/scientifically-misleading-errors-prompt-authors-withdraw-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A group of authors have withdrawn a paper after revealing a litany of issues to the journal that published it. Among those issues were “scientifically misleading errors,” “insufficient” validation, and a disagreement between the researchers on whether it should have been published at all. “Optimal DNA structure of reverse-hairpin beacons for label-free and positive surface […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/09/05/scientifically-misleading-errors-prompt-authors-withdraw-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Scientifically misleading errors” prompt authors to withdraw paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Teaching methods go from lab to classroom</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teaching-methods-go-lab-classroom</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/teaching-methods-go-lab-classroom</link>
	<description>Cognitive researchers are finding ways to help young students to hold on to all the knowledge and skills they need to succeed in school.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/091617_learning-classroom_feat.jpg?itok=j8NmKwZ3" length="31556" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: People may have lived in Brazil more than 20,000 years ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/stone-age-people-brazil-20000-years-ago</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/stone-age-people-brazil-20000-years-ago</link>
	<description>Stone Age humans left behind clues of their presence at a remote Brazilian rock shelter.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/09/main/blogposts/090117_BB_south-america_main.jpg?itok=XZOPdqMB" length="38977" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Increase the meaningfulness of your work by considering how it helps others</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=29538</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/05/increase-the-meaningfulness-of-your-work-by-considering-how-it-helps-others/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_29613&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-638601948.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-29613&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;29613&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark IV&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Mid adult African American businesswoman and mid adult Caucasian businessman discuss project strategy. The woman is gesturing while talking with business partner.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1484587546&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Steve Debenport&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;80&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;320&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Diverse male and female business partners discuss strategy&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Diverse male and female business partners discuss strategy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/09/05/increase-the-meaningfulness-of-your-work-by-considering-how-it-helps-others/diverse-male-and-female-business-partners-discuss-strategy/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/09/gettyimages-638601948.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;You will be happier and more productive in your work if you find it meaningful&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we find our work meaningful and worthwhile, we are more likely to enjoy it, to be more productive, and feel committed to our employers and satisfied with our jobs. For obvious reasons, then, work psychologists have been trying to find out what factors contribute to people finding more meaning in their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top of the list is what they call “task significance”, which in plain English means believing that the work you do is of benefit to others. However, to date, most of the evidence for the importance of task significance has been correlational – workers who see how their work is beneficial to others are more likely to find it meaningful, but that doesn’t mean that task significance is causing the feelings of meaningfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Blake Allan at Purdue University has provided some of the first longitudinal evidence that seeing our work as benefiting others really does lead to an increase in our finding it meaningful. “These results are important both for the wellbeing of individual workers and as a potential avenue to increase productivity,” he concludes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300702&quot;&gt;in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Vocational Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-29538&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blake contacted thousands of alumni of a university in Midwestern USA and asked them to complete a survey about their job, and then to complete it again three and six months later. Over 600 of them were in work and completed the survey at all three time points: just over half were female; they ranged in age from 22 to 82; and they were in a range of jobs, the most commonly cited titles being director, engineer, manager, teacher, professor and admin assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each survey point, the participants rated their agreement with four statements about the “task significance” of their work, such as “My job provides opportunities to substantially improve the welfare of others,” and “A lot of others can be positively affected by how well my job gets done”. They also rated their agreement with six statements about how meaningful they find their work to be, such as: “The work I do on this job is very important to me”; “My job activities are personally meaningful to me”; and “The work I do on this job is worthwhile”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater belief in task significance at an earlier time point tended to be followed by increasing ratings of work meaningfulness three months’ later, and this was true regardless of previous meaningfulness levels, and whatever the participants’ age, gender or social class. The reverse was not true: finding work to be more meaningful at an earlier time point wasn’t associated with seeing it as more beneficial to others at later survey points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new data complement another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28493738&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; by the same researcher in which he experimentally manipulated participants to experience greater task significance (for instance by having them complete a task that they were told would benefit of others versus being told it would benefit themselves). He found that those told it would benefit others found the work more meaningful as compared with those doing it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, Blake said it seems that “perceiving one’s work as improving the welfare of others leads to the perception that it is personally meaningful, important and valuable.” He added that employers might therefore be able to help workers to find their work more meaningful by helping them make contact with the people who benefit from their work, by increasing the influence of their work on others, or “creating a prosocial climate in the workplace”. Also, he suggests we can help ourselves find our work more meaningful, for example by setting aside time each week to help others in our work, or writing about times we’ve helped others through our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weakness of the new study is that the sample was predominantly made up of White people of higher social class. Although social class didn’t moderate the longitudinal link between task significance and finding work meaningful in the current data this may be because there wasn’t a wide enough range of social class in the sample. “Therefore, future studies should replicate the current findings and re-test social class as a moderator with more representative sample,” Blake said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0001879117300702&quot;&gt;Task significance and meaningful work: A longitudinal study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29538/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/29538/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=29538&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 08:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Hold the phone! Cell phone use while pregnant not linked to child neurodevelopment problems</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9481</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/05/hold-the-phone-cell-phone-use-while-pregnant-not-linked-to-child-neurodevelopment-problems/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/pexels-photo-261628-140x110.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cell phone use and exposure to weak radio frequency electromagnetic fields (EMF-RF) has been a public health concern for several years. Specific concerns on whether using your cell phone while pregnant can harm your fetus are mainly due to their extensive use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the widespread uncertainty among the public that EMF-RFs from cell phones might harm the developing brain of the fetus, the evidence from animal experiments and from previous epidemiological studies with mothers and children are inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find answers, we studied the association between maternal cell phone use during pregnancy and child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years. We included around 45,000 mothers and their children from all over Norway who are participants of a large birth cohort study, the Norwegian Mother and Child Study (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fhi.no/en/studies/moba&quot;&gt;MoBa study&lt;/a&gt;). This is the largest study worldwide that follows families from pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The child’s neurodevelopment was assessed by questionnaires answered by the parents. These are frequently used questionnaires in epidemiological studies, with questions like: “When you ask you child to point at his/her eyes, nose, hair, etc. does he/she point correctly on at least seven parts of the body?” and “Can your child catch a large ball with both hands?”. In addition, we used language development as an outcome because in previous studies we found this parameter to be sensitive to exposure to neurotoxicants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found no evidence of a harmful effect of the mother using her cell phone during pregnancy on her child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found no evidence of a harmful effect of the mother using her cell phone during pregnancy on her child’s neurodevelopment at 3 and 5 years. Further to this, we even found that the more the mother was using her cell phone during pregnancy the better language and motor skills her child had at 3 years of age. We observed no associations when the child was 5 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160412016307383?via%3Dihub&quot;&gt;in another study&lt;/a&gt; that included mothers and children from five birth cohorts, including MoBa, the authors found that cell phone use during pregnancy was related to a higher risk for the child to have hyperactivity/inattention problems at 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personality, parenting style and other factors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, high cell phone use for the Norwegian women was related to a lower risk of emotional problems at 5 years. As in our study, the interpretation of such results is unclear. Mainly due to the small RF-EMF exposure that reached the fetus when the mother is using the phone while pregnant and due to other unmeasured factors that can “mask” the findings, such as maternal depression or anxiety, parenting style and maternal personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assumed that extrovert women would talk more (using their cell phones more) and this can help their child to advance their communication skills. The “International Personality Item Pool” questionnaire assessed the mother’s extrovert personality. Even after taking into account maternal extroversion, cell phone use in pregnancy was not found to be harmful for the child’s neurodevelopment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that a social and family background that is beneficial for the child’s language and motor skills development, rather than parental cell phone use in itself, might cause the observed effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A changing world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still large gaps of knowledge on the effects of EMF-RF exposure to human health. By the time our study was conducted cell phone use was widespread. During the recruitment period (2001 – 2009), cell phone use increased from 68% to 99%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cell-phone technology has changed tremendously since 2009, with the major milestone of smart phone use. Smart phones and other smart devices have completely changed the way we use cell phones, including frequency of use, type of use and starting age of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though we cannot be absolutely sure if we could observe the same results if the study was conducted now and had included the widespread use of smart phones, the physical exposure to EMF-RF has not changed that much and we believe that our results also have validity for the present situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/09/05/hold-the-phone-cell-phone-use-while-pregnant-not-linked-to-child-neurodevelopment-problems/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hold the phone! Cell phone use while pregnant not linked to child neurodevelopment problems&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 08:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/09/pexels-photo-261628-125x125.jpeg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
