<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: A lot of life on planet Earth is awful and incredible</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lot-life-planet-earth-awful-and-incredible</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lot-life-planet-earth-awful-and-incredible</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses how the natural world feeds our sense of wonder.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 15:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers fascinated by critters’ strange biology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-fascinated-critters-strange-biology</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-fascinated-critters-strange-biology</link>
	<description>Readers responded to fish lips, monkey brains, sunless tanner and more.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 15:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Elsevier retracts entire issue after mistakenly publishing it online</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51371</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/09/elsevier-retracts-entire-issue-mistakenly-publishing-online/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Publishing giant Elsevier has retracted an entire issue of one of its journals because the contents — abstracts from a conference about child neurology — were never supposed to make it online. We discovered the retraction after realizing that every aspect of the issue in Brain &amp;amp; Development had been retracted, including the cover, editorial […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/09/elsevier-retracts-entire-issue-mistakenly-publishing-online/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Elsevier retracts entire issue after mistakenly publishing it online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ticks are here to stay. But scientists are finding ways to outsmart them</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ticks-here-stay-scientists-finding-ways-outsmart-bloodsuckers</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ticks-here-stay-scientists-finding-ways-outsmart-bloodsuckers</link>
	<description>Researchers acknowledge that there’s no getting rid of ticks, so they are developing ways to make them less dangerous.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081917_tick_main.jpg?itok=IJmewCql" length="19685" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Fearing “stigmatization,” patient’s father seeks retraction of paper on rare genetic mutation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51366</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/09/fearing-stigmatization-patients-father-seeks-retraction-paper-rare-genetic-mutation/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The father of a boy with a rare genetic mutation has accused a scientist of exploiting his child by proclaiming the defect a “genetic syndrome” and naming it after herself. At an impasse with scientists investigating, publicizing, and interpreting his son’s condition, the father seems willing to use any leverage he can muster to remove […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/09/fearing-stigmatization-patients-father-seeks-retraction-paper-rare-genetic-mutation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fearing “stigmatization,” patient’s father seeks retraction of paper on rare genetic mutation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fossil find suggests this ancient reptile lurked on land, not in the water</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-find-suggests-ancient-reptile-lurked-land-not-water</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fossil-find-suggests-ancient-reptile-lurked-land-not-water</link>
	<description>An exquisitely preserved fossil shows that an ancient armored reptile called Eusaurosphargis dalsassoi wasn’t aquatic, as scientists had suspected.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081917_notebook_rethink_main.jpg?itok=FDhTbH6s" length="48704" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: The secret to a long life could be the right job (at least for ants)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9391</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/09/the-secret-to-a-long-life-is-down-to-your-job-for-ants/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Giehr-Figure2-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sociality favours the adjustment to ecological niches and facilitates the spread of a species. Group living is therefore widespread, from insects to mammals, but differs in the degree of cooperation and altruism. In subsocial species (e.g. giant water bugs, several spiders or fish), the parents stay with their offspring for some time until the latter start to reproduce independently. In cooperatively breeding birds (e.g. Southern Ground-Hornbill) or mammals (e.g. mongooses), sociality reaches a higher level with older siblings or other group members helping to raise offspring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highest form of social cooperation is eusociality, which is rare in mammals (only naked-mole rats), but abundant in two insect orders: Hymenoptera (e.g. bees, wasps, ants) and Blattodea (termites). The intense cooperation between individuals in these species might be the cause of the evolutionary and ecological success of eusocial insects, which can make up to 75% of a habitat’s animal biomass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The organisation of eusocial insect colonies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, colonies of eusocial Hymenoptera consist of overlapping generations of related, female individuals, whereas males are often only produced seasonally for mating. Most females, the “workers”, refrain from reproduction or are completely sterile. They care for other colony members and the brood, supply them with food, and maintain or defend the nest. In many species these tasks are distributed by age: the younger workers conduct work within the nest, while the older ones take over the risky tasks outside the nest. The reproductive queens do not participate in such non-reproductive tasks but are responsible for the production of new offspring. They often differ from the workers in body size and morphology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9393&quot; style=&quot;width: 4618px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9393&quot; height=&quot;3052&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Giehr-Figure1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4608&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;A winged virgin queen and a wingless mated queen of the ant &lt;em&gt;Cardiocondyla obscurior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Julia Giehr&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fitness of insect societies mainly depends on the efficiency of interactions between reproductives and helpers, as the reproductive task is not exchangeable in many species. This makes ants a suitable model organism to study the interrelations between individual and group characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unpredictable social or environmental changes, like, e.g., destruction of the nest, might afford adaptions regarding the task allocations. Ants of our study species &lt;em&gt;Cardiocondyla obscurior&lt;/em&gt; found new nests via budding, which means that a few individuals – e.g. workers, together with brood and queen(s) – leave the maternal nest to initiate a new colony. In this case, workers might have to react flexibly to new conditions and possibly have to switch from outer to inner nest tasks and vice versa. Although studies in bees and ants have confirmed a flexible task allocation, its effect on the performance and survival of individuals has rarely been studied. In our study we wanted to test whether a forced task shift has an effect on colony growth and fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our experimental set-up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our study, we created new colonies that consisted of only young (freshly eclosed) or only old (12 weeks old) workers, together with either a single young or old queen. This setup forced a part of the young workers to leave the nest precociously to forage, while several old workers had to revert from foraging to brood care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then examined the effect of queen and worker age on colony growth and task performance by estimating the number of produced brood and offspring and its quality (weight) during a complete colony lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9395&quot; style=&quot;width: 4618px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9395&quot; height=&quot;3052&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Giehr-Figure3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;4608&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Mated &lt;em&gt;Cardiocondyla obscurior&lt;/em&gt; queen (left) together with brood items and one worker (right)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Julia Giehr&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our experiment showed that colonies perform much better when queens and workers are of similar age. Task performance of a worker did not mainly depend on its chronological age but on group composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, lifespan appears to be a very plastic trait in ants and is strongly affected by colony demography. The event of colony founding seems to reset the age of the workers and indicates that chronological and physiological age are not necessarily linked. Twelve-week old workers that were exposed to the condition of a newly founded nest with a new queen and without brood outlived workers that eclosed in the same situation by several weeks. A similar effect of social environment was also observed in queens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why observe ageing in ants?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging and senescence are ubiquitous phenomena throughout multicellular life and have fascinated humanity for centuries. Although many studies have focussed on the mechanisms underlying aging, its proximate and ultimate causes are still not completely understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ant &lt;em&gt;Cardiocondyla obscurior&lt;/em&gt; provides an ideal model organism for ageing in social insects&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;It appears that the lifespan of workers is more affected by colony stage and demography than by chronological age and that workers do not suffer strongly from an age-related decline of performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, queens of this species not only outlive their conspecific sterile nestmates (workers) by weeks, despite sharing the same genome, but in contrast to other animals they also do not suffer from reduced survival after an increased investment in reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative senescence and the effects on physiological age still raise many questions. This is why our team at the University of Regensburg, together with colleagues in a DFG-funded research unit (“Sociality and the reversal of the fecundity-longevity trade-off,” FOR 2281), focuses on reproduction and ageing in social insect queens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/09/the-secret-to-a-long-life-is-down-to-your-job-for-ants/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The secret to a long life could be the right job (at least for ants)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 10:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Giehr-Figure2-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Researchers are studying psychopathic chimps to better understand the human variety</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28322</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/09/researchers-are-studying-psychopathic-chimps-to-better-understand-the-human-variety/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-584864828.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28332&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28332&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Shouting a Angry Chimpanzee. The chimpanzee (Pan troglodytes) shouts in rain forest, giving signs to the relatives. Uganda. Africa&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1228911661&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Shouting a Angry Chimpanzee. The chimpanzee (Pan troglodytes) shouts in rain forest, giving signs to the relatives.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Shouting a Angry Chimpanzee. The chimpanzee (Pan troglodytes) shouts in rain forest, giving signs to the relatives.&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-584864828.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-584864828.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-584864828.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2123,1412&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/09/researchers-are-studying-psychopathic-chimps-to-better-understand-the-human-variety/shouting-a-angry-chimpanzee-the-chimpanzee-pan-troglodytes-shouts-in-rain-forest-giving-signs-to-the-relatives/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-584864828.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the drivers of a psychopathic personality (marked by callousness, disinhibition and superficial charm), it’s worth looking at our closest relatives. Some chimps, like some people, score highly on scales designed to evaluate psychopathic tendencies. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnins.2017.00407/full&quot;&gt;new work&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Neuroscience &lt;/i&gt;reveals a potentially important genetic contributor to psychopathic traits&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;in chimps, which could lead to a better understanding of the traits in people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28322&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team led by Robert Latzman at Georgia State University studied 164 chimpanzees housed at the Yerkes National Primate Research Center in Atlanta, Georgia and the National Center for Chimpanzee Care at the University of Texas. Each chimpanzee was rated by typically two to three colony staff members, who knew the individual animals, on the “CHMP-Tri scales” (a kind of chimp personality questionnaire that assesses their boldness, meanness and disinhibition – the three traits that form the so-called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19583890&quot;&gt;triarchic model” of psychopathy&lt;/a&gt;). They also sequenced the AVPR1A regions of the chimps’ genomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latzman and his team decided to home in on this gene because it codes for a receptor for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasopressin&quot;&gt;vasopressin&lt;/a&gt;, a neuropeptide known to play a role in complex social behaviours in humans and other animals, and so, in theory, relates to psychopathy. Vasopressin levels have been found to correlate with a history of aggression in people with various personality disorders. And polymorphisms (variations) in a region of the AVPR1A gene have been associated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12119/full&quot;&gt;variability in a number of traits relevant for psychopathy&lt;/a&gt;, including increased novelty-seeking and decreased avoidance of harm in people, and also to personality in chimps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team also considered each chimp’s gender (as there are sex differences in the vasopressin system) and also, given extensive work finding that genes can interact with early life experience to influence behaviour, whether each animal had been reared by its own mother (119 had been) or, because of maternal neglect, or illness or injury, the chimp had been reared, for its own wellbeing, from a very early age by people (59 fell into this category).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For chimps reared by their own mothers, whether they had a common polymorphism in a key region of AVPR1A was correlated with their score on disinhibition. Variations in the AVPR1A gene also correlated with scores for boldness, and the animals’ total psychopathy scores. But for chimps reared by people, there was no relationship between their AVPR1A genotype and their CHMP-Tri scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the team didn’t directly measure vasopressin levels, the results are consistent with the idea that genetically determined levels of vasopressin contribute to psychopathic tendencies, and  “provide additional compelling evidence that psychopathic tendencies are rooted in basic, evolutionarily-meaningful dispositions,” the team writes. The results also, of course, show an important role for the environmental factor of rearing experience (perhaps roughly equivalent to parenting or foster care experiences for children).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to know more about the interaction between early care-giver experiences and the heritability of psychopathy. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://latzmanlab.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Latzman-et-al-in-press-Etiology-of-Triarchic-Psychopathy-Dimensions-in-Chimpanzees.pdf&quot;&gt;another paper &lt;/a&gt;published this year by some of the authors of the current research and others, nursery-reared chimps scored significantly higher on the measure of disinhibition than those reared by their own mothers, though there was no relationship between rearing environment and either boldness or meanness. Might the higher disinhibition scores among the nursery-reared animals overwhelm, then, any effect of variations in AVPR1A (thus explaining why the gene was unrelated to psychopathic traits in nursery-reared chimps in the current research)? Or is something else going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US National Institutes of Health has scaled back some studies involving chimpanzees. But Latzman and his colleagues argue that ethically sound and scientifically justifiable studies could (alongside studies of people) provide valuable insights into biological and behavioural processes relevant not just to psychopathy but to psychological illness more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnins.2017.00407/full?utm_source=F-AAE&amp;amp;utm_medium=EMLF&amp;amp;utm_campaign=MRK_337964_55_Neuros_20170725_arts_A&quot;&gt;Triarchic Psychopathy Dimensions in Chimpanzees (Pan troglodytes): Investigating Associations with Genetic Variation in the Vasopressin Receptor 1A Gene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28322/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28322/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28322&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 08:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Thousands across India march in support of science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22439</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/2hY8QOSoUZs/nature.2017.22439</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by global demonstrations, protesters demand respect for research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22439&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22439&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/2hY8QOSoUZs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Citizen scientists chase total solar eclipse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22415</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/0D18F4sWW9A/nature.2017.22415</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Non-scientists are being recruited to collect data on everything from the Sun’s outer atmosphere to animal behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 147 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22415&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22415&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/0D18F4sWW9A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Shake up conferences</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548153a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/E4r-k7TZ8pI/548153a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Emojis, smartphone technologies and revamped guidelines would boost transparency at scientific meetings, say Shai D. Silberberg and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548153a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548153a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/E4r-k7TZ8pI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Mysteries of Sun’s corona on view during upcoming eclipse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548146a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/yriqBjkwNes/548146a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;From ground, sky and space, researchers are ready to test latest technologies on the Great American Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 146 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548146a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548146a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/yriqBjkwNes&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Telescope protest, GM salmon and a giant 'dead zone'</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548140a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/FYAbQ1uEczE/548140a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 4–10 August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 140 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548140a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548140a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/FYAbQ1uEczE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Female Brains Are More Active?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9026</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9026</link>
	<description>Another day, another over-hyped sex differences neuroscience study. The headlines this time around are especially cringeworthy:
Study Finds Women’s Brains Are Far More Active Than Men’s

Women Are Using A LOT More Of Their Brains Than Men. Surprise, surprise 😏

Women really DO overthink things! Scans reveal they have ‘more active brains than men’


The paper in question was published in the Journal of Alzheimer's Disease and it comes from a group led by Dr. Daniel Amen. Amen is a contro</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 19:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A look at Rwanda’s genocide helps explain why ordinary people kill their neighbors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rwanda-genocide-psychology-murder</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/rwanda-genocide-psychology-murder</link>
	<description>New research on the 1994 Rwanda genocide overturns assumptions about why people participate in genocide. A sense of duty, not blind obedience, drives many perpetrators.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 19:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081917_genocide_main.jpg?itok=io1pcO7l" length="43689" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Neutrino experiment may hint at why matter rules the universe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrino-experiment-may-hint-why-matter-rules-universe</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrino-experiment-may-hint-why-matter-rules-universe</link>
	<description>T2K experiment hints at an explanation for what happened to antimatter.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080817_ec_neutrino-antineutrino_free.jpg?itok=XL1jpT7x" length="34963" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “Right to be forgotten” takes down BMJ’s 15-year-old film review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51354</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/08/right-forgotten-takes-bmjs-15-year-old-film-review/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A subject in a documentary film about the psychology of religious ideation has pushed the BMJ to take down its review of the film, based on a complaint citing a European internet privacy rule. On July 3, BMJ posted a retraction notice for an article that barely said anything: This article has been retracted by […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/08/right-forgotten-takes-bmjs-15-year-old-film-review/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“Right to be forgotten” takes down BMJ’s 15-year-old film review&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These record-breaking tube worms can survive for centuries</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-record-breaking-tube-worms-can-survive-centuries</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-record-breaking-tube-worms-can-survive-centuries</link>
	<description>Deep-sea tube worms can live decades longer than their shallow-water counterparts.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/072417_MT_tubeworm_main.jpg?itok=W8Z_8Lwu" length="51070" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Third retraction for former rising star found guilty of misconduct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51349</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/08/third-retraction-former-rising-star-found-guilty-misconduct/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A once-prominent researcher in the field of infectious disease — who was found guilty of misconduct last year— has had a third paper retracted, a 2006 article in PNAS. Last year, the University of Dundee in Scotland found that Robert Ryan had committed research misconduct, which included misrepresenting clinical data and duplicating images in a […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/08/third-retraction-former-rising-star-found-guilty-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Third retraction for former rising star found guilty of misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How spiders mastered spin control</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-spiders-mastered-spin-control</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-spiders-mastered-spin-control</link>
	<description>Scientists reveal a new twist on the unusual properties of spider silk.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/072517_EC_spider-silk_main.jpg?itok=1UVGr0xe" length="17086" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Punishment vs. Negative Reinforcement + 9 More Pairs of Psych Terms You’re Getting Confused</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28108</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/08/punishment-vs-negative-reinforcement-9-more-pairs-of-psych-terms-youre-getting-confused/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-3137853.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28316&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28316&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;10th December 1953:  A puzzled looking young man scratching his head.  (Photo by Chaloner Woods\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A Puzzled Scratch&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;A Puzzled Scratch&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-3137853.jpg?w=845?w=725&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-3137853.jpg?w=845?w=212&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-3137853.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;725,1024&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/08/punishment-vs-negative-reinforcement-9-more-pairs-of-psych-terms-youre-getting-confused/a-puzzled-scratch/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-3137853.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of pairs of terms in psychology that sound as if they refer to the same thing, and can therefore be used interchangeably, when in fact they refer to different concepts that are distinct in important ways. As Emory University professor Scott Lilienfeld and his colleagues point out in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/feduc.2017.00037/full&quot;&gt;their new open-access paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Education&lt;/em&gt;, even experienced psychologists and science communicators sometimes confuse these pairs of terms, which inevitably impedes their understanding of the underlying concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their new paper outlines 50 “frequently confused term pairs in psychology” from across different fields of psychology and related subjects. “Our list … should hopefully be a modest contribution toward enhancing psychological literacy and critical thinking in psychology more broadly,” they write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below we’ve highlighted 10 of the pairs of psychology terms that Lilienfeld and his co-authors believe you might be getting confused (check &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/feduc.2017.00037/full&quot;&gt;the full paper&lt;/a&gt; for the other 40):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28108&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Negative Reinforcement” versus “Punishment”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A few years ago &lt;em&gt;ABC news&lt;/em&gt; reported “&lt;a href=&quot;http://abcnews.go.com/International/story?id=80629&quot;&gt;British Soccer Players Get Negative Reinforcement&lt;/a&gt;“. The story was about the players who’d played badly being made to drive around in an old, uncool car. But this wasn’t negative reinforcement, it was a punishment: an unpleasant experience intended to deter future bad play. Negative reinforcement, by contrast, is a reward in the form of the removal of a previously unpleasant stimulus or experience, thus increasing the likelihood of the behaviour that preceded it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Envy” versus “Jealousy”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A lot of us use these terms interchangeably not realising that envy is specifically about the dynamics between two people whereas jealousy involves three or more. A leading researcher in this area is psychologist Richard Smith. He &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/joy-and-pain/201401/what-is-the-difference-between-envy-and-jealousy&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;Psychology Today&lt;/em&gt;: “Envy occurs when we lack a desired attribute enjoyed by another” whereas “Jealousy occurs when something we already possess (usually a special relationship) is threatened by a third person”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Antisocial” versus “Asocial”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Both sound very similar if we’re not paying attention. The clue of course is that the prefix “anti” means against, where as the prefix “a” means without. In psychology, anti-social is often used in the context of antisocial personality disorder, which describes a person who behaves against others, engaging “in reckless, irresponsible, and at times illegal behaviours” (to quote Lilenfeld et al). By contrast, an asocial person is “shy or disinterested in interpersonal contact”. Lilienfeld and his coauthors give the example of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/09/01/introvert-myths_n_3569058.html&quot;&gt;a Huffington Post article&lt;/a&gt; that conflated this distinction, stating: “the idea that introverts are antisocial or don’t want the company of others is completely false”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Obsession” versus “Compulsion”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Easy to confuse, but in terms of Obsessive Compulsive Disorder, obsessions are anxiety-generating repetitive thoughts, urges or images (e.g. “I feel dirty”, “I’ve been contaminated”), whereas compulsions are the behaviours or mental acts that the person performs to try to reduce their anxiety (e.g. hand washing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Psychopathy” vs. “Sociopathy”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You might have heard an unpleasant character described as a sociopath and wondered if that’s the same or different from a psychopath. At least in the context of clinical and forensic psychology, Lilienfeld et al explain that a psychopathic personality is defined by a specific mix of features including superficial charm and callousness. Sociopathy on the other hand is not a formal or technical term, and it’s used to mean different things by different people, for example as a synonym for psychopath or to describe someone with a long history of criminal behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Serial killer” versus “Mass murderer”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While we’re on the subject of criminal characters, Lilienfeld et al also highlight an important distinction in forensic psychology between types of murderer: Serial killers (e.g. Peter Sutcliffe AKA the Yorkshire Ripper) kill “multiple people in a string of incidents that are separated by ‘cooling off’ periods,” while mass murderers (e.g. Thomas Hamilton, the perpetrator of the mass shooting at a Dunblane school) massacre “a large number of people in a single incident”. For completeness, Lilienfeld’s team add that spree killers form another group: like serial killers, they kill multiple people in separate incidents, but unlike serial killers their “homicidal episodes are not separated by clear-cut cooling-off periods”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Mediator” versus “Moderator”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
From types of killer to statistical nuance. As Lilienfeld at al explain, “A mediator is a variable, C, that intervenes between two correlated variables A and B, and that accounts at least in part … or entirely … for their statistical association.” Mediators speak to the why of an association. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2011/01/20/how-michael-jacksons-heal-the-world-really-could-help-heal-the-world/&quot;&gt;a 2011 study&lt;/a&gt; found that listening to prosocial songs like Michael Jackson’s Heal the World was associated with lower aggression and that this seemed to be partly mediated by the effect of the song on listeners’ mood rather than on their thoughts. A moderator, by contrast, “is a variable, C, that statistically affects the direction, magnitude, or both, of the relation between variables A and B”. Lilienfeld et al give the example of the association between negative life events and severity of illness, which is stronger for uncontrollable events (e.g. death of a spouse) than more controllable ones (e.g. divorce). “Moderators tend to address ‘when’, ‘for whom’, and ‘under which’ questions,” Lilienfeld explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Prevalence” versus “Incidence”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What proportion of the population have a mental health diagnosis? The answer would tell you the prevalence of mental health problems. How many people are newly diagnosed with mental health problems in a given year (or other time period)? The answer to that question would tell you the incidence. “More technically,” explain Lilienfeld et al, “prevalence equals incidence multiplied by duration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Coma” versus “Persistent Vegetative State”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Lilienfeld’s team place this one in their miscellaneous category. Coma and persistent vegetative state (PVS) are closely related, they explain, “but should be distinguished”. I covered misconceptions about these states and other disorders of consciousness at length &lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=fBPyBQAAQBAJ&amp;amp;q=coma#v=snippet&amp;amp;q=coma&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;in my 2014 book &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://books.google.co.uk/books?id=fBPyBQAAQBAJ&amp;amp;q=coma#v=snippet&amp;amp;q=coma&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;Great Myths of the Brain&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;While coma and PVS are both&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;caused by brain damage and are associated with a lack of conscious awareness, there are important differences in the two states: Coma patients’ brains show no sign of a sleep wake cycle because of damage to the reticular system; in contrast PVS patients’ brains have an intact reticular system and show signs of a sleep wake cycle. Indeed, a PVS patient will usually have their eyes open during the wake part of the cycle (which can be confusing for loved ones and give false hope) and their eyes closed during the sleep phase. Also, coma patients are totally unresponsive whereas PVS patients often move and make sounds, and they may respond to noises and momentarily track moving targets with their eyes. Coma patients who survive but don’t wake up may progress to a PVS. If it is believed that a PVS patient has some rudimentary awareness, their diagnosis is changed to “minimally conscious state”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Relapse” versus “Recurrence”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To grasp the distinction between relapse and recurrence, it helps also to realise the difference between “remission” from a psychological disorder (a full improvement that has lasted at least four months after treatment) and “recovery” (full improvement that’s lasted more than a year). According to Lilienfeld and his colleagues, relapse is when a condition returns after the start of remission but before recovery. Recurrence, by contrast, is when the condition returns after recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to check the &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/feduc.2017.00037/full&quot;&gt;full paper&lt;/a&gt; for 40 more psychological term pairs that you might be getting confused. Also well worth reading, two years ago Lilienfeld and co produced &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01100/full&quot;&gt;a complementary paper&lt;/a&gt; listing 50 widely used psychological and psychiatric terms that should probably be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/feduc.2017.00037/full&quot;&gt;50 Differences That Make a Difference: A Compendium of Frequently Confused Term Pairs in Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28108/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28108/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28108&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 09:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 20 more science songs for your lab playlist</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/20-more-science-songs-for-your-lab-playlist</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/20-more-science-songs-for-your-lab-playlist</link>
	<description>“Music has no effect on research work,” said Einstein – but then he didn’t have the benefit our lab-friendly soundtrack …</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 08:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Insomnia linked to premature birth in study of 3 million mothers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22419</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/R-AczCpTfAA/nature.2017.22419</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Women with sleep disorders were about twice as likely to deliver babies more than six weeks early.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 145 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22419&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22419&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/R-AczCpTfAA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Home-grown scientists step up to save Africa’s primates</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548144a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/rH9L8BQJFaA/548144a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific network aims to train a generation of African leaders in primate research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 144 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548144a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548144a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/rH9L8BQJFaA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Commit to talks on patient data and public health</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548137a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/arZbUcM9qo0/548137a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Gene-edited embryos are exciting, but the truly urgent conversations concern genomic medicine, says Vivienne Parry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 137 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548137a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548137a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/arZbUcM9qo0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PLOS Neuroscience Community: The challenge to define cortex (By Ashley Juavinett)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19411</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/xtNlrUv1N_E/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/7030838119_f617dfcd3c_z-150x150.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our fragmentary and rapidly evolving understanding is reminiscent of the situation faced by cartographers of the earth’s surface many centuries ago, when maps were replete with uncertainties and divergent portrayals of most of the planet’s surface.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– David Van Essen, 2003&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love talking about cortex. It’s bumpy, it’s got layers, and it’s probably the brain structure that makes us the very verbal, skilled primates that we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also love all of the different areas of cortex—there’s one for face recognition, another for motion detection, and many for decision-making. Often, labs stake claims on their cortical area of interest, diving deep into how that particular patch gets its job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how well can we really divvy up that important sheet of tissue that makes us human? Can we confidently say we’ve left one area, and moved into the next? And how well can we translate these borders to smaller animal models, such as mice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiny brains with big aspirations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mice are super important to neuroscientists. Sure, they’re quite small and not exactly the most brilliant animals, but we’ve been able to engineer them to mark specific cell types, express glowing proteins, and more. As a result of this powerful murine toolbox, mice have gained a lot of attention from scientists who want to understand circuits and cell types in the brain. In particular, the &lt;em&gt;visual cortex&lt;/em&gt; of the mouse has been the site of a lot of discussion, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/news/neuroscience-through-the-eyes-of-a-mouse-1.13901&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;with many researchers&lt;/a&gt; hoping that we could use our extensive knowledge about the coarse organization of the primate visual system to ask detailed questions in the mouse brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we want to use powerful genetic and recording tools in mice, we first need to understand how their cortex is organized. So, many neuroscientists have been working to combine textbook knowledge about primate brain organization with novel techniques designed for the tiny mouse brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few landmark papers showing that mice have multiple visual areas like primates, the field immediately grabbed its two-photon microscopes and optical fibers and got to work. But as it turns out, mouse visual cortex isn’t &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; arranged like primate cortex, and many mouse researchers are left wondering if they have indeed isolated a meaningful cortical “area,” or a dubious patch of cortex. This challenge to disentangle the mouse brain has unearthed several fundamental questions about defining cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An age-old problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for the new generation of mouse vision researchers, many before us have given careful thought to how we should consider the cortex. Primate researchers are quite familiar with the problem of defining cortical areas as well as the difficulties that arise when comparing across species. Multiple cortical partitioning schemes exist for macaque visual cortex and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S089662730700774X&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mapping these areas onto humans&lt;/a&gt; is quite contentious. In primates, there are 10-12 areas with clear organization, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainmap.wustl.edu/resources/VisChapter.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;there is anatomical and functional evidence for more than 40 distinct visual areas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/Cortex_Jungle.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-19413&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/Cortex_Jungle-249x300.png&quot; width=&quot;249&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;In an elegant book chapter on the topic, cortical map guru &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainvis.wustl.edu/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Van Essen&lt;/a&gt; lays out four ways to divide primate visual cortex: architecture, connectivity, retinotopy (an ordered map of the visual world), and functional specialization. Still, when we compare maps from these types of data they’re often conflicting, even in the relatively large primate brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usefully, Van Essen also defines three frequent problems encountered when defining a cortical area. First, there may be subtle (or imprecise) boundaries between areas, and therefore ground truth is not easily defined. Second, areas may be internally heterogeneous, either because they have repetitive structures, asymmetric organization, or gradients of function. Last, areas may differ between individual animals. Even in primates, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/6740964&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;primary visual cortex&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/2449473&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the middle temporal area&lt;/a&gt; can vary two-fold or more in size between monkeys. And while anatomical boundaries are often used to locate these areas in primates, these landmarks are quite variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The current state of cortex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;In the past year or so, multiple studies have been released that are challenging our current conceptions of mouse and human cortex. &lt;a href=&quot;https://elifesciences.org/articles/18372&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Research from the Allen Brain Institute&lt;/a&gt; suggests that mice have even more visual areas than we previously thought—something on the order of &lt;em&gt;sixteen&lt;/em&gt;. As in primates, many of these areas don’t clearly receive input from primary visual cortex, and some of them have really weak and/or partial maps of the visual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the research on human cortex is also getting a bit complicated. Using an enormous dataset from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanconnectomeproject.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Human Connectome Project&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v536/n7615/full/nature18933.html?foxtrotcallback=true&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Van Essen and his team identified 97 new cortical areas&lt;/a&gt;. That’s more than double the number of areas previously reported. They were able to do this by using multiple sources of information about organization, such as the thickness of cortex, or the activity in a given area during resting state. Like all good big data papers, they used machine learning to train a classifier to determine area boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these projects represent a new wave of approaches to integrate many types of data in order to accurately draw cortex area borders. Ultimately—as Van Essen himself once proposed—we may need to settle on probabilistic boundaries: area #1 &lt;em&gt;likely &lt;/em&gt;ends here, and area #2 is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;likely &lt;/em&gt;next door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as it turns out, dividing up the cortex isn’t as simple as separating yellow and red M&amp;amp;Ms. However, with multiple types of anatomical and functional information across species, we’re hopefully moving towards a common framework for the widely-adored cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glasser, M.F., Coalson, T.S., Robinson, E.C., Hacker, C.D., Harwell, J., Yacoub, E., Ugurbil, K., Andersson, J., Beckmann, C.F., Jenkinson, M., Smith, S.M., Van Essen, D.C. (2016). A multi-modal parcellation of human cerebral cortex. &lt;em&gt;Nature. &lt;/em&gt;536: 171-178. doi:10.1038/nature18933&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maunsell, J.H., Van Essen, D.C. (1987). Topographic organization of the middle temporal visual area in the macaque monkey: representational biases and the relationship to callosal connections and myeloarchitectonic boundaries. &lt;em&gt;J Comp Neuro&lt;/em&gt;. 266(4): 535-55. doi: 10.1002/cne.902660407&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Essen, D.C., Newsome, M.T, Maunsell, J.H. (1984). The visual field representation in striate cortex of the macaque monkey: asymmetries, anisotropies, and individual variability. &lt;em&gt;Vision Res&lt;/em&gt;. 24(5): 429-48.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van Essen DC: Organization of Visual Areas in Macaque and Human Cerebral Cortex.&lt;strong&gt; I&lt;/strong&gt;n Visual Neurosciences (L. Chalupa and J Werner, eds.). 2004.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhuang, J., Ng, L., Williams, D., Valley, M., Li, Y., Garrett, M., Waters, J. (2016). An extended map of mouse cortex. &lt;em&gt;eLife&lt;/em&gt;. 6. doi: 10.7554/eLife.18372&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit https://www.flickr.com/photos/38703275@N06&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/London_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-19412&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/08/London_2-150x150.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ashley Juavinett&lt;/strong&gt; is a neurosciences postdoctoral fellow at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, a lover of cortex, and a writer of both prose and music. Her exploits be followed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/analog_ashley&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@analog_ashley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/xtNlrUv1N_E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 22:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro">PLOS Neuroscience Community</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Nostalgic Voyager documentary relives first exploration of the solar system</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nostalgic-voyager-documentary-relives-first-exploration-solar-system</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/nostalgic-voyager-documentary-relives-first-exploration-solar-system</link>
	<description>A new TV documentary is a tender tribute to Voyagers 1 and 2, which launched 40 years ago and were the first spacecraft to visit the outer solar system.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 19:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081917_reviews_main.jpg?itok=P8mdDNa_" length="14752" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: To combat cholera in Yemen, one scientist goes back to basics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-cholera-yemen-one-scientist-goes-back-basics</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-cholera-yemen-one-scientist-goes-back-basics</link>
	<description>As the cholera epidemic rages on in war-torn Yemen, basic hygiene is the first line of defense.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/081917_notebook_science-life_main.jpg?itok=yIZnuN5I" length="47841" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Researchers retract a paper when they realize they had sequenced the wrong snail’s genome</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51335</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/07/researchers-sequenced-wrong-snails-genome-retract-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers in China thought they had sequenced the genomes of two snails that help transmit diseases to other species — an important first step to stopping the spread. But their hopes were soon dashed after they realized they had misidentified one of the snails. The researchers published their findings earlier this year in the journal […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/07/researchers-sequenced-wrong-snails-genome-retract-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Researchers retract a paper when they realize they had sequenced the wrong snail’s genome&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 15:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Chemistry research community now has a dedicated network on SSRN — ChemRN</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/chemistry-research-community-now-has-a-dedicated-network-on-ssrn-chemrn</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/chemistry-research-community-now-has-a-dedicated-network-on-ssrn-chemrn</link>
	<description>Free community-driven network enables researchers to post preprints and working papers, share ideas and collaborate</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “The article must be retracted:” Journal pulls prostate cancer study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51338</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/07/article-must-retracted-journal-pulls-prostate-cancer-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A 2016 paper exploring the biology of prostate cancer has been retracted due to figure manipulation. According to the retraction notice, a reader contacted the journal Clinical Cancer Research in late 2016 with concerns that similar bands appeared multiple times in two images. The editors asked the paper’s corresponding author, Shahriar Koochekpour, about the issue […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/07/article-must-retracted-journal-pulls-prostate-cancer-study/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“The article must be retracted:” Journal pulls prostate cancer study&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sacrificed dog remains feed tales of Bronze Age ‘wolf-men’ warriors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sacrificed-dog-remains-feed-tales-bronze-age-wolf-men-warriors</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sacrificed-dog-remains-feed-tales-bronze-age-wolf-men-warriors</link>
	<description>Canine remnants of a possible Bronze Age ceremony inspire debate.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080317_BB_dog-warriors_main.jpg?itok=PngVtuDp" length="22413" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Opportunity for diversification: insights from species accumulation pattern in skipper butterflies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9350</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/07/opportunity-for-diversification-insights-from-species-accumulation-pattern-in-skipper-butterflies/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/600px-Heteropterus.morpheus.2490-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of beetle species on earth is more than the number of plant species. The number of species in butterflies and moths are likely less than half of beetle species on earth. Beetles, butterflies and moths along with all other insect species represent almost half of all eukaryotic species. What governs such variation in species diversity – why are some groups of organisms species rich, while others are species poor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern of species richness across different groups of organisms is broadly explained by the idea of ecological opportunity, which is based on two major components. First, evolution of a key character that provides the ability to utilize resources otherwise unavailable. Second, availability of the resources which can be facilitated through either extinction of competitive species or appearance of new resources or colonization to a new area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9355&quot; style=&quot;width: 810px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9355&quot; height=&quot;1040&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/800px-CogiaTyphedanus.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;This plate shows just a fraction of the species diversity within skipper butterflies.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By investigating the pattern of associations of skipper butterflies and their larval hostplant, we show that the monocot-feeding skippers diversified much more rapidly than the dicot-feeding ones (monocot and dicot being the two major classes flowering plants are traditionally grouped in). As a result, the monocot-feeding group represents approximately equal number of species as that of the dicot-feeding group, although the monocot-feeding group originated more recently. However, different subgroups within the monocot-feeding group have diversified at different rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To uncover the plausible reasons that could have influenced the differential rate of diversification within the monocot-feeding group, we compared the time when monocot-feeding skippers originated with the time of paleoclimatic events. We find that paleoclimatic events at distinct geological times have influenced diversification of monocot-feeding skippers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9354&quot; style=&quot;width: 1290px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9354&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/1280px-Brown_longtail_Urbanus_procne_2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;A brown longtail, a member of the skipper family&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Anne Toal, CC2.0&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, one subgroup of monocot-feeding skippers diversified on forest dwelling monocots when these plants themselves diversified owing to high atmospheric temperature around 50 million years ago. This diversification occurred in present day Africa, South Asia, and South-East Asia. Second, expansion of grasslands in South America around 40 million years ago facilitated diversification of another subgroup of monocot-feeding skippers which are broadly specialized on grasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, our comparative analyses reveal that the increased diversification of skipper butterflies is due to (i) evolution of the ability to feed on monocots, and (ii) subsequent availability of diverse monocot plants over a wide geographical area. Although we are not certain about the underlying mechanisms that would have facilitated diversification of grass feeding skippers, we predict that the geographical isolation mediated as a consequence of grassland expansion was a prominent factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/07/opportunity-for-diversification-insights-from-species-accumulation-pattern-in-skipper-butterflies/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Opportunity for diversification: insights from species accumulation pattern in skipper butterflies&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/600px-Heteropterus.morpheus.2490-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Surgical management of cancer-related lymphedema</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9370</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/07/surgical-management-cancer-related-lymphedema/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/lymphedema-povoski-review-2-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymphedema represents a generalized buildup of extracellular lymph fluid within the soft tissues of arms and legs. This results from an imbalance in the amount of lymphatic fluid that is being produced and the amount of lymphatic fluid that is being cleared from lymphatic channels into the venous circulatory system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymphedema is categorized as either primary lymphedema or secondary lymphedema. Primary lymphedema is a relatively rare condition and results from intrinsic structural or functional issues in the lymphatic drainage system secondary to abnormalities in the structure and/or function of the lymphatic channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondary lymphedema is far more common and is the result of extrinsic disruption in lymphatic transport. In the more developed western world, this is most frequently caused by the traumatic surgical disruption of the normal lymphatic pathways. Cancer treatment, especially surgery and radiation therapy can result in the development of lymphedema. Breast cancer surgery is the most common cause of secondary lymphedema in the arms. atients whose axillary lymph nodes are removed or irradiated as part of their therapy are at particularly high risk of developing this condition, which can arise years after surgery. Lymphedema in the legs is most commonly associated with gynecologic cancers, urologic cancers, melanoma, and lymphoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lymphedema has a major impact on the quality of life of affected patients, both in terms of increased morbidity and significant psychological effects. The skin and soft tissues of the affected limb become progressively swollen, firm, and tight feeling due to the buildup of entrapped lymphatic fluids. The swelling can feel uncomfortable or even painful, and may make movements more difficult. Most seriously, this condition makes the affected limb much more prone to repeated and potentially life-threatening skin and soft tissue infections. Many patients eventually develop depression as a consequence of the impact that lymphedema has on their well-being and their physical appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; style=&quot;width: 368px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;269&quot; src=&quot;http://media.springernature.com/lw785/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1186%2Fs12885-017-3444-9/MediaObjects/12885_2017_3444_Fig4_HTML.gif&quot; width=&quot;358&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Certified lymphedema therapist performing circumference tape measurements on a patient with breast cancer related right upper extremity lymphedema&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, there is no cure for lymphedema, which will affect patients for the rest of their lives. However, both non-surgical and surgical management strategies exist that attempt to reduce the buildup of extracellular lymph fluid within the affected limb and thus improve symptoms and reduce the risk of complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main non-surgical management strategy, Complex Decongestive Therapy (CDT), includes manual lymphatic drainage, compression therapy, exercise and skin care as well as a range of motion, breathing and posture exercises, and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surgical management strategies include ablative surgical methods, which aim at removal of the tissues affected by lymphedema, and physiological surgical methods, which aim to recreate normal or alternate avenues for lymph fluid to flow out of the affected limb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ablative surgical methods can be significantly invasive, and are directed towards the removal of the edematous superficial tissue layers of the affected limb. This includes the Charles procedure and suction-assisted lipectomy/liposuction. The Charles procedure represents a somewhat radical surgical procedure in which varying degrees of involved skin and subcutaneous tissue are excised from the affected limb, and can require coverage with skin grafts. Suction-assisted lipectomy/liposuction represents a much less invasive surgical procedure in which excess fat is removed from the affected limb using a suction cannula and liposuction device that is passed under the skin through multiple small incisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physiological surgical methods are directed towards reducing the lymphatic fluid burden in the affected limb by either improving lymphatic circulation by introducing healthy tissue into the affected limb or creating an alternate outflow pathway for lymph fluid. These methods require using sophisticated microsurgical and super-microsurgical techniques, to accomplish the physical reconnection of lymphatic channels to either small veins in the affected limb, or healthy lymphatic channels or tissues that can be harvested from other parts of the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While currently available surgical management strategies can result in dramatic improvement in symptoms and quality of life for patients, many formidable challenges remain for successful management of secondary lymphedema. It is hopeful that ongoing clinical research efforts will ultimately lead to more complete and sustainable treatment strategies and perhaps a cure for secondary lymphedema, its debilitating symptoms, and its potentially devastating resultant complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/07/surgical-management-cancer-related-lymphedema/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Surgical management of cancer-related lymphedema&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 09:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/lymphedema-povoski-review-2-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: The art of not fighting: Martial arts reduce child and teen aggression</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=28078</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/07/the-art-of-not-fighting-martial-arts-reduce-child-and-teen-aggression/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28091&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28091&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy.gif?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy.gif?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,471&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/07/the-art-of-not-fighting-martial-arts-reduce-child-and-teen-aggression/giphy-4/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; /&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.innerdrive.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Bradley Busch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a paradox – the idea that participating in aggressive sport can make people less aggressive. Yet this belief forms a core basis of many martial arts dating back thousands of years, and many famous practitioners (real and fictional) have preached the importance of self control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legendary martial artist Bruce Lee once noted that “emotion can be the enemy. If you give into your emotion, you lose yourself”. Or as Mr Miyagi said in &lt;i&gt;The Karate Kid&lt;/i&gt; the “lesson is not just karate only, the lesson is for whole life”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous research has demonstrated that this may well be the case, as participating in martial arts helps improve concentration and self-awareness, self-esteem, emotional stability and self-regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is it really true that martial arts also reduces aggression outside the dojo? Can participating in traditionally violent sports prove cathartic, helping young people develop self-discipline and in turn be less violent away from the sport? Writing in the journal of &lt;i&gt;Aggression and Violent Behaviour &lt;/i&gt;researchers from Israel and America report their findings from the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917300976?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;meta-analysis on the impact of martial arts on violent behaviours in children and teenagers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-28078&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Harwood and Michal Lavidor of Bar-Ilan University and Yuri Rassovsky of UCLA reviewed the existing research and found 300 potentially relevant papers. However, only twelve met their criteria for inclusion: they had to have a control group, as well as valid measures of the impact of martial arts on aggression, violence, anger or hostility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their analysis found that participating in martial arts did indeed have a significant impact in reducing aggression. Of the twelve studies reviewed, eleven showed a positive impact. Central to this was that martial arts reduced the rate of externalising behaviours in participants. Externalising behaviours included, but were not limited to, physical aggression, verbal and physical bullying, theft and vandalism. Through the teaching and practices of martial arts, participants were better able to gain a sense of control over both the situations and themselves, leading to less negative emotional responses and violent behaviours.  Statistically speaking, the average size of the effect of martial arts on these behaviours was 0.65, indicating a medium sized effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results were consistent regardless of the participants’ age or gender. Likewise, the amount of time spent training and if they practised their martial arts either in or outside of school made no significant difference. Given that the studies reviewed comprised a range of methodologies, including both longitudinal random control trials, these findings carry significant weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this meta-analysis was somewhat hampered by the sheer paucity of quality studies to have looked at the impact of martial arts on children and teenagers. As the authors put it, “the research on martial arts is sparse and many studies lack the statistical integrity to include them in a robust meta-analysis”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there are many different martial arts and they all vary in their techniques and philosophy. Unfortunately, there has also been little research that has actively compared the impact that these different combat sports have on reducing aggression. This is because many of the studies to date have been on people who participate in a combination of martial arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one study in this review that did report a negative impact on martial arts on aggressive behavior was on young boys participating in judo. This finding may have been due to the lack of meditation within the training sessions to help improve self control, which is a common aspect of many other martial arts. Further research would help us identify under which situations and which martial arts are most beneficial for helping adolescents with aggressive tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, this review raises some exciting implications for martial arts as an intervention for delinquent teenagers, especially those who demonstrate serious and consistent anti-social behaviours, who are at increased risk of becoming lifelong offenders. Encouraging them to engage in traditional “self-help” programmes can be tricky so participating in martial arts could potentially offer a different route. As the authors of the study note, “while psychologically orientated programmes often receive the bulk of the scientific interest, troubled youth often do not co-operate with these traditional approaches. Martial arts, may both complement and form a basis for further cooperation in psychological therapies”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to more traditional methods to reduce aggression, martial arts offer a cost-effective and fun alternative to enhance mental well-being. More research is clearly needed, but these initial findings are promising and seem to confirm the long-held paradoxical belief that participating in combat sports can help reduce rates of violence, anger and aggression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917300976?dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Reducing aggression with martial arts: A meta-analysis of child and youth studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bradley Busch&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-26102 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26102&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Bradley Busch&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/bradley-busch.png?w=409&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/bradley-busch.png?w=273&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/bradley-busch.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;409,450&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/29/what-is-the-psychological-state-underlying-clutch-performance-excelling-under-pressure/bradley-busch/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/bradley-busch.png?w=136&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;136&quot; /&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.innerdrive.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Bradley Busch&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Inner_Drive&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@Inner_Drive) &lt;/a&gt;for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bps-research-digest.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Bradley is a registered psychologist and director of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.innerdrive.co.uk/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;InnerDrive&lt;/a&gt;. He has work with Premiership and International footballers and is the author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Release-Your-Inner-Drive-Everything/dp/1785831992&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Release Your InnerDrive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28078/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/28078/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=28078&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 08:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Half of papers searched for online are free to read</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22418</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/s5q4bzZvIF4/nature.2017.22418</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Large study of open research analysed reader data from Unpaywall tool, which finds freely available versions of articles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22418&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22418&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/s5q4bzZvIF4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: SI units need reform to avoid confusion</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548135b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/zMxgEbAM0Xs/548135b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A flaw in the system leaves physicists grappling with dimensionless units.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 135 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548135b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548135b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/zMxgEbAM0Xs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Identification of essential genes for cancer immunotherapy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23477</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/TaY22kZXZj0/nature23477</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Somatic gene mutations can alter the vulnerability of cancer cells to T-cell-based immunotherapies. Here we perturbed genes in human melanoma cells to mimic loss-of-function mutations involved in resistance to these therapies, by using a genome-scale CRISPR–Cas9 library that consisted of around 123,000 single-guide RNAs, and profiled genes whose loss in tumour cells impaired the effector function of CD8+ T cells. The genes that were most enriched in the screen have key roles in antigen presentation and interferon-γ signalling, and correlate with cytolytic activity in patient tumours from The Cancer Genome Atlas. Among the genes validated using different cancer cell lines and antigens, we identified multiple loss-of-function mutations in APLNR, encoding the apelin receptor, in patient tumours that were refractory to immunotherapy. We show that APLNR interacts with JAK1, modulating interferon-γ responses in tumours, and that its functional loss reduces the efficacy of adoptive cell transfer and checkpoint blockade immunotherapies in mouse models. Our results link the loss of essential genes for the effector function of CD8+ T cells with the resistance or non-responsiveness of cancer to immunotherapies. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23477&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23477&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/TaY22kZXZj0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Spreadsheet Risks in Science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9019</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9019</link>
	<description>Errors in the use of spreadsheets such as Microsoft Excel could pose risks for science.

That's according to a preprint posted on arXiv from Ghada AlTarawneh and Simon Thorne of Cardiff Metropolitan University.



AlTarawneh and Thorne conducted a survey of 17 researchers from the University of Newcastle neuroscience research centre, ranging from PhD students to senior researchers. None of the respondants had any formal, certified training in spreadsheet use, with most (71%) being self-tau</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 11:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: A science BS detector; scholarly publishing’s 1%; a tenured professor is fired</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51343</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/05/weekend-reads-science-bs-detector-scholarly-publishings-1-tenured-professor-fired/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the retraction of a 35-year-old paper written by a cat, and the retraction of a study about a controversial gene editing technique. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: A BS detector for science? “Science is still the best way of knowing stuff. Darpa just wants to know what stuff science […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/05/weekend-reads-science-bs-detector-scholarly-publishings-1-tenured-professor-fired/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: A science BS detector; scholarly publishing’s 1%; a tenured professor is fired&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 14:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What Curiosity has yet to tell us about Mars</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-mars-rover-five-year-anniversary</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-mars-rover-five-year-anniversary</link>
	<description>Curiosity has revealed a lot about Mars in the last five years. But NASA’s rover still has work to do on the Red Planet.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 20:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080417_curiosity_selfie_free.jpg?itok=uvKxZpj1" length="32098" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: One creature’s meal is another’s pain in the butt</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/seagull-fur-seal-hookworm</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/seagull-fur-seal-hookworm</link>
	<description>Kelp and dolphin gulls in Patagonia have found a new food source. But they accidentally injure fur seal pups to get it.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 16:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/wt_fursealpups_free-zoom2.jpg?itok=quw91-MR" length="44396" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Nootropic Effects of Psychedelic and Addictive Substances</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22688</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/08/04/nootropic-effects-of-psychedelic-and-addictive-substances/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous article on the subject of nootropics, I was writing about brain enhancing effects of some medicines and natural compounds. There is, however, a large number of nootropics that received little recognition from official science and remain rather poorly studied. There is a good reason for this too – these compounds tend to be addictive or hallucinogenic. This article aims to cover what is known about the effects of these substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicotine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rather curious that &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/16/nicotine-and-nicotinic-receptors-in-disease-and-therapy/&quot;&gt;nicotine&lt;/a&gt;, a well-known addictive component of tobacco smoke, was confirmed to have nootropic effect. The research into this property of nicotine was triggered by observations that ex-smokers tend to complain about the lack of concentration and general decline in various aspects of cognitive abilities. It turned out that nicotine does improve episodic and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/07/04/how-do-we-improve-our-working-memory/&quot;&gt;working memory&lt;/a&gt;, as well as attention. Nicotine doses delivered via patches had positive effects (improved performance in cognitive tests) in adults with mild cognitive disorders, as well as in healthy non-smokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cannabis/marijuana and cognitive processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People of artistic professions often claim that smoking pot helps &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/12/14/decoding-creativity-its-in-the-genes/&quot;&gt;creativity&lt;/a&gt;. There is scientific evidence to substantiate these claims. Cannabinoids seem to temporarily increase communication between the left and right hemispheres of the brain thus creating a state of hyperconnectivity and allowing a loose flow of associations. This may explain the heightened creativity individuals experience when using marijuana. Reports of positive benefits include improved mood, lower levels of anxiety, stress, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/07/06/brooding-buddies-co-complaining-linked-with-depression-and-anxiety/&quot;&gt;depression&lt;/a&gt;, improved focus and fewer distractions, improved reaction times, more creative thoughts, greater verbal fluency, and better calculative complexity. These effects are largely dose-dependent, and taking higher amounts may lead to the opposite effects including sluggishness, lack of focus, nervousness, and impaired memory formation and recall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the negative long-term effects of cannabis on brain structure and function have been demonstrated beyond any reasonable doubt. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/11/15/cannabis-abuse-in-adolescence-cognitive-decline-in-later-life/&quot;&gt;cognitive decline&lt;/a&gt; associated with the use of cannabis is a serious medical problem, and lots of scientific research aims to gain insights into this problem and the potential approaches to reverse decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grey area: Psychedelic drugs (LSD, mushrooms) in microdosing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type “psychedelics” and “microdosing” in Google search, and you will be flooded with thousands of articles claiming that compounds like &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/05/psychedelic-assisted-therapy-the-mental-health-trip-of-the-future/&quot;&gt;LSD&lt;/a&gt; and psilocybin (active component of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/06/22/magic-mushrooms-for-mental-health/&quot;&gt;magic mushroom&lt;/a&gt;) have almost miraculous effect on human cognitive abilities. It appears that many inventors, researchers and innovators use psychedelic compounds in very small doses, occasionally or regularly, to reach a state of enhanced consciousness, get into flow, and work more productively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here is a problem: not a single proper scientific publication supports these claims. There is a good reason for this: due to their well-known hallucinogenic properties and serious potential side effects, psychedelics like LSD are banned in most countries around the world. In fact, LSD was banned in the US and UK back in 1960s. This means that the only peer-reviewed published research that could inform on the actual measurable effects of psychedelics as a nootropic were done 50 years ago. The most commonly cited work (Harman, et. al. (1966) “Psychedelic Agents in Creative Problem-Solving: A Pilot Study.” Psychedelic Reports 19, 211-27.) was published in 1966. Although the findings reported in this publication are interesting, the quality of this work in terms of general organization, the use of suitable control subjects, and statistical power is hardly satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hallucinogenic properties of psychedelics are well documented. Microdosing of these compounds for enhancement of cognitive abilities, however, has not been investigated scientifically. This leave lots of space for imagination and conspiracy theories. There were repeated calls from the research community to lift the ban on research into psychedelics, but so far they seem to have fallen on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous evidences that psychedelics can be used to treat various psychiatric disorders. Some resent studies indicate that administration of psylobicin in moderate doses is not associated with any significant short-term or long-term risk. When it comes to cognitive enhancement, none of the available peer-reviewed scientific publications confirm or rule out such a phenomenon. One interesting resent publication claims that exposure to microdoses of psilocybin creates a state of hyperconnectivity in the brain. The findings from functional MRI experiments show: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“that the structure of the brain’s functional patterns undergoes a dramatic change post-psilocybin, characterized by the appearance of many transient structures of low stability and of a small number of persistent ones that are not observed in the case of placebo. This means that the psychedelic state is associated with a less constrained and more intercommunicative mode of brain function, which is consistent with descriptions of the nature of consciousness in the psychedelic state.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the study indirectly points to the possibility of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/03/07/plan-a-cognitive-and-memory-enhancement-program/&quot;&gt;cognitive enhancement&lt;/a&gt; and creative stimulation under the influence of psychedelics. Nonetheless, a more definite confirmation of this phenomenon is yet to be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A word in defense of official science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People of a more adventurous nature tend to blame the science and medicine industry for slowness in recognizing the benefits of smart drugs. But let’s look at this problem from the perspective of researchers. Most drugs are safe, but from time to time people do experience serious side effects and even life-threatening complications. Nobody wants to be one of the unlucky few. If something goes wrong, you’ll have nobody but yourself to blame. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/05/mental-health-drug-approval-and-biomedical-research-in-the-21st-century/&quot;&gt;Regulatory bodies&lt;/a&gt; can recommend any given substance for any particular use only when they have sufficient evidence that a) confirms its effectiveness and b) shows that its side effects are mild and manageable, and/or its benefits far exceed the potential complications associated with its use (i.e., the risk is worth taking).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of novel nootropics is hampered by research, validation, and regulatory challenges. The road from the research laboratory to FDA approval is difficult, long, and costly. Pharmacological enhancement of healthy populations is fraught with ethical and philosophical pushbacks. Therapeutic effects observed in cognitively impaired patients often contradict those in healthy populations. Even approved drugs have issues with side effects and large individual differences. The long-term effects of nootropics are typically unknown. Most importantly, there is still much to be learned about the cellular and molecular basis for the various aspects of cognition. Once they are better understood, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2010/01/20/drugs-and-pharmacology-nineteenth-edition/&quot;&gt;pharmacologists&lt;/a&gt; will have much better ideas about the processes in the brain to target and how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to get carried away with the potential opportunities that nootropics might offer. But don’t forget classical approaches: proper &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/19/high-intensity-interval-training-and-brain-health/&quot;&gt;diet and exercise&lt;/a&gt; DO enhance brain functions. Many famous thinkers and creative people benefited from simple regular physical activities. Charles Dickens was spending several hours every day walking, sometimes for as much as 20 or 30 miles. Aristotle and Ludwig Van Beethoven are two other famous people who were known for their habit of wondering around while thinking. Physical activity pumps blood through your body and helps to deliver more oxygen to your brain. Regular exercise and healthy diet also keep your blood vessels healthy ensuring that this vital oxygenation is not reduced as you get older. Your normal lifestyle is responsible for your basic level of cognitive abilities. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/10/22/possible-medical-application-of-a-smart-drug/&quot;&gt;Smart drugs&lt;/a&gt; can be used to spike it up from time to time, but if the basic level is low, the spikes won’t go that high anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum it up, although an occasional joint may heighten your creativity, the regular use of cannabis is definitely not a good approach to enhance cognitive abilities. There is an acute lack of research on benefits (or absence of such) of psychedelics in cognitive enhancement. Virtually all online information on the benefits of psychedelics as cognitive enhancers are completely unsubstantiated by scientific evidence. Any positive or negative appraisals represent personal views of the articles’ authors rather than results of research studies. Your lifestyle influences you basic level of cognitive abilities – don’t ignore generally accepted good strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heishman SJ et al. (2010) Meta-analysis of the acute effects of nicotine and smoking on human performance. Psychopharmacology (2010) 210: 453. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3151730/&quot;&gt;10.1007/s00213-010-1848-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newhouse P et al. (2012) Nicotine treatment of mild cognitive impairment: a 6-month double-blind pilot clinical trial. Neurology 78, 91-101. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823efcbb&quot;&gt;10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823efcbb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wignall ND and de Wit H (2011) Effects of nicotine on attention and inhibitory control in healthy nonsmokers. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 19, 183-191. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/doi/10.1037/a0023292&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0023292&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan CJ et al. (2010) Hyper-priming in cannabis users: a naturalistic study of the effects of cannabis on semantic memory function. Psychiatry Res 176, 213-218. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2008.09.002&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.psychres.2008.09.002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giovanni Battistella G et al. (2014) Long-Term Effects of Cannabis on Brain Structure. Neuropsychopharmacology 39, 2041–2048; doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/npp.2014.67&quot;&gt;10.1038/npp.2014.67&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Filbey FM et al. (2014) Long-term effects of marijuana use on the brain. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 111, 16913–16918. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1415297111&quot;&gt;10.1073/pnas.1415297111&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studerus E et al. (2010) Acute, subacute and long-term subjective effects of psilocybin in healthy humans: a pooled analysis of experimental studies. Journal of Psychopharmacology  25, 1434 – 1452. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1177%2F0269881110382466&quot;&gt;10.1177/0269881110382466&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petri G et al. (2014) Homological Scaffolds of Brain Functional Networks. J R Soc Interface 11, 20140873. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2014.0873&quot;&gt;10.1098/rsif.2014.0873&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Wunderela-2973688/&quot;&gt;Wunderela&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Spread of misfolded proteins could trigger type 2 diabetes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spread-misfolded-proteins-could-trigger-type-2-diabetes</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/spread-misfolded-proteins-could-trigger-type-2-diabetes</link>
	<description>Experiments in mice raise the question of whether type 2 diabetes might be transmissible.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080317_AC_prion-diabetes_main.jpg?itok=7kxec-OC" length="12988" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: When kids imitate others, they’re just being human</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/imitation-kids-humans-bonobos</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/imitation-kids-humans-bonobos</link>
	<description>In imitation tests, kids readily performed nonsensical actions, but bonobos didn’t. The results hint that excessive imitation may be a uniquely human trait.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 14:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/080317_LS_imitation_main_free.jpg?itok=GGRIJHpM" length="23279" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The three-year delay: Journal finally retracts paper based on made-up data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51324</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/04/three-year-delay-elsevier-journal-finally-retracts-paper-based-made-data/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Three years after an investigation revealed a 2013 paper was based on fraudulent data, a journal has finally retracted it. The paper, published in Journal of Hazardous Materials, was one of seven articles by a team at the Institute of Microbial Technology (IMTECH) in Chandigarh, India that contain fabricated data, according to an investigation by […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/04/three-year-delay-elsevier-journal-finally-retracts-paper-based-made-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The three-year delay: Journal finally retracts paper based on made-up data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Healthy child, healthy future: Highlights from RCPCH conference 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9359</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/04/healthy-child-healthy-future-rcpch-conference-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Fotolia-WavebreakMediaMicro-co-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;RCPCH’s history dates back to 1928, when the British Paediatric Association (BPA) was founded.  The BPA was set up with the aims of advancing the study of paediatrics and to promote friendship amongst paediatricians. It started off with humble beginnings and a membership of six. With time the association became an organization that represented a growing specialty that worked towards seeking improvements in child health. The association received Royal College status in 1996. This year RCPCH celebrated its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rcpch.ac.uk/21birthday&quot;&gt;21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; birthday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rcpch.ac.uk/stroke-guideline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stroke in Childhood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stroke is often viewed as occurring primarily in the elderly. However, stroke is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stroke.org.uk/sites/default/files/uk_childhood_stroke_guidelines_dr_asmaa_abdelhamid.pdf&quot;&gt;top ten&lt;/a&gt; causes of death in children. It can occur in infants, children, and young adults as well as before birth. It has been found that the risk of stroke in children is greatest during the first year of life and it peaks during the &lt;a href=&quot;http://circ.ahajournals.org/content/119/3/e21.long&quot;&gt;perinatal period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9361&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9361 size-large&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/RCPCH-2017-21ST-birthday-NB-Nawsheen-1024x665.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Image: Nawsheen Boodhun&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RCPCH was recently granted funding by the Stroke Association to develop an evidence-based guideline on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rcpch.ac.uk/news/stroke-childhood-guideline-process&quot;&gt;Stroke in Childhood&lt;/a&gt;. The original guideline on stroke was published by the Royal College of Physicians (RCP) in 2004. The guidelines needed updating to reflect the best and most up-to-date clinical practice which utilize current evidence. May 2017 marked the launch of the updated RCPCH ‘Stroke in Childhood’ evidence-based clinical and parent guideline which was funded by the Stroke Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rcpch.ac.uk/stroke-guideline&quot;&gt;clinical guideline&lt;/a&gt; details the way in which stroke care should be handled and contains information covering the whole process from identification, diagnosis, management and rehabilitation of children and young people with arterial ischemic stroke and hemorrhagic stroke until their transition into adult care. It also contains guidance for parents providing information so families understand what a stroke is, why they occur, and how children and young people affected by stroke should be treated and cared for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Child refugee crisis, health and appropriate care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that we are now witnessing the highest levels of displacement on record. Refugees are those who have been forced to flee their country to escape war, violence and persecution. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unhcr.org/figures-at-a-glance.html&quot;&gt;leading causes&lt;/a&gt; of refugees leaving their countries are war and ethnic, religious and tribal violence. An unprecedented &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unhcr.org/figures-at-a-glance.html&quot;&gt;65.3 million&lt;/a&gt; people around the world have been forcibly displaced from their home where &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.savethechildren.org.uk/about-us/emergencies/child-refugee-crisis-appeal&quot;&gt;over half&lt;/a&gt; are under the age of 18. Around 53% of the refugees worldwide came from three countries: Somalia (1.1m), Afghanistan (2.7m) and Syria (4.9m). The top hosting locations of the worlds displaced people are: Asia and Pacific (14%), Africa (29%), Middle East and North Africa (39%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is basic human rights for migrants and refugees to have access to health services and experience the highest attainable standard of physical and mental health. However, the reality is such that there are around 10 million stateless people (one who is not a citizen of any country) who have been denied a nationality and access to basic human rights such as access to education, healthcare, financial protection for health, employment and freedom of movement. A lack of &lt;a href=&quot;http://who.int/migrants/en/&quot;&gt;Universal Health Coverage&lt;/a&gt; can lead to excessive costs for refugees and migrants, many of whom pay out of their own pocket for health services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9362&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9362 size-large&quot; height=&quot;351&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/RCPCH-2017-NB-3-1024x561.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Image: Nawsheen Boodhun&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Alf Dubs led a keynote session on ‘Refugee children in the UK and how to offer appropriate care’ on day 2 of the RCPCH conference. During his speech, he explained how those who were in the Jungle in Calais were kept in appalling conditions and that they were ‘existing, not living’. He spoke about the manner in which Brexit takes child refugees off of the political agenda and how the attitudes towards refugee and migrants are not helping the situation. Once a child refugee himself who arrived in the UK in 1939, Lord Alf Dubs ended his segment by highlighting that he would like to see the same opportunities available for child refugees now as he had. Day 2 was concluded by a segment from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rcpch.ac.uk/improving-child-health/us-voice-children-young-people-and-families/us-voice-children-young-people-an&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;Us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a moving session from the voice of children and young people on seeking asylum and being a refugee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a privilege to have the opportunity to attend the RCPCH conference this year which was interesting, informative and enjoyable. &lt;em&gt;BMC Pediatrics&lt;/em&gt; looks forward to attending future events where improvement of child health will be the focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9363&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9363 size-large&quot; height=&quot;384&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/RCPCH-2017-Ubuntu-NB-2-1024x614.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Image: Nawsheen Boodhun&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/04/healthy-child-healthy-future-rcpch-conference-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Healthy child, healthy future: Highlights from RCPCH conference 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Fotolia-WavebreakMediaMicro-co-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Publisher won’t retract two papers, despite university’s request</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51297</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/04/publisher-wont-retract-two-papers-despite-universitys-request/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Förster, a high-profile social psychologist, has agreed to retract multiple papers following an institutional investigation — but has also fought to keep some papers intact. Recently, one publisher agreed with his appeal, and announced it would not retract two of his papers, despite the recommendation of his former employer. Last month, the American Psychological […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/04/publisher-wont-retract-two-papers-despite-universitys-request/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Publisher won’t retract two papers, despite university’s request&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: We have an ingrained anti-profit bias that blinds us to the social benefits of free markets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27924</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/04/we-have-an-ingrained-anti-profit-bias-that-blinds-us-to-the-social-benefits-of-free-markets/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-1538307.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-28066&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;28066&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;404762 02: A British anti-capitalist protester carries a banner in front of riot police at a May Day demonstration May 1, 2002 in London. There were sporadic clashes with police throughout the day, but the demonstration was mostly peaceful. (Photo by Sion Touhig\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;May Day Anti-Capitalist Protest in London&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;May Day Anti-Capitalist Protest in London&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-1538307.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-1538307.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-1538307.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,671&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/04/we-have-an-ingrained-anti-profit-bias-that-blinds-us-to-the-social-benefits-of-free-markets/may-day-anti-capitalist-protest-in-london/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-1538307.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Harnessing the ‘base’ motive of material self-interest to promote the common good is perhaps the most important social invention mankind has yet achieved,” said the American economist Charles Schultz. And you can see why. While acknowledging its problems, many &lt;a href=&quot;https://unherd.com/2017/07/ctrl-alt-del-conservatives-must-reboot-capitalism/&quot;&gt;credit free market capitalism for the dramatic reduction over recent decades in the proportion of people in the world living in extreme poverty&lt;/a&gt;, not to mention rising health standards and technological advances. Conversely, according to some commentators, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/05/01/venezuela-collapsing-socialist-induced-chaos-yet-remains-corbynista/&quot;&gt;one only has to look to modern-day Venezuela to see the dangers of extreme anti-profit socialism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31434-001&quot;&gt;a new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Personality and Social Psychology&lt;/em&gt;, most of us have an instinctual anti-profit bias. We view for-profit companies and industries – upon which capitalism is based – with inherent distrust, assuming that the more profitable they are, the more harm they do to society. In fact, research shows the opposite is true: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0170840603024003910&quot;&gt;companies that make greater profits actually tend to contribute more value to society, for example in terms of their environmental responsibility and corporate philanthropy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors of the new paper, led by Amit Bhattacharjee at Erasmus University, believe this anti-profit bias leads many voters and politicians to endorse anti-profit policies that are likely to lead to the very opposite outcomes for society that they want to achieve. “Erroneous anti-profit beliefs may lead to systematically worse economic policies for society, even as they help people satisfy their social and expressive needs on an individual level” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27924&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through seven separate studies involving hundreds of online participants, the researchers present evidence that the anti-profit bias arises because we think about for-profit motives in a somewhat superficial, ego-centric fashion. Because the desire for profit is seen as based on selfish intent, we extrapolate to assume that the activities of for-profit companies and industries must be bad for society, disregarding the reality that selfish intents can have positive consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also refer to our own mundane “zero sum” experiences, such as buying a car, in which the seller’s profitable gain inevitable comes at our loss. We fail to consider how market forces operate on a massive scale, in which for-profit companies (competing in a free market with informed customers) need to innovate, behave fairly and develop a good reputation in order to be profitable over the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, in the first study, participants rated Fortune 500 companies in terms of how profitable they thought they were and how much they thought they engaged in bad business practices, such as operating at the expense of others with no concern for society. There was a clear pattern: the more profitable participants thought a company was, the more they assumed that it engaged in more bad business practices. In fact expert assessments of the firms shows the opposite pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another study, participants were presented with vignettes of different companies and either told they operated for-profit or not-for-profit. Participants rated the exact same companies, engaging in the same business activities, as more likely to cause social harm, and less likely to bring social benefit, if they were described as for-profit rather than not-for-profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhattacharjee and his team found that they could attenuate their participants’ anti-profit bias if they prompted them to think about how a long-term profit motive could encourage greater product innovation and quality, better treatment of staff, and more concern for reputation. However, thinking this way doesn’t seem to come naturally. Participants’ baseline judgments about for-profit companies were the same as when they were actively encouraged to assume that customers face few choices and have no information about firms’ reputations (which isn’t the case in a free market, profit-driven economy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings of an ingrained anti-profit bias generally held regardless of participants’ economic knowledge or political leanings. This was a US study so it remains to be seen if the same anti-profit bias will be found in other cultures. However, as the researchers point out, their participants “live in one of the most market-oriented societies in human history”, and yet “even as they experience the benefits of market exchange, people express little faith in the power of markets to create and reward value for society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31434-001&quot;&gt;Anti-Profit Beliefs: How People Neglect the Societal Benefits of Profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: A British anti-capitalist protester carries a banner in front of riot police at a May Day demonstration May 1, 2002 in London. By Sion Touhig/Getty Images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27924/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27924/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27924&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 08:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Chronic diseases spike in Middle East as conflicts rage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22371</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CFoOZerDnAU/nature.2017.22371</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Rising rates of chronic disease and deaths from violence can be curbed only if fighting is brought to an end, say researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22371&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22371&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CFoOZerDnAU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: First genetically engineered salmon sold in Canada</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22116</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ksivhHUyFLc/nature.2017.22116</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;US firm AquaBounty Technologies says that its transgenic fish has hit the market after a 25-year wait.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 148 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22116&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22116&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ksivhHUyFLc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Drug approval needs a helping hand</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548135a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/YxrmO0bSvSE/548135a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time for researchers to lend their expertise to expediting the arrival of cutting-edge therapies that are waiting in the wings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 135 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/548135a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548135a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/YxrmO0bSvSE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Neutrinos seen scattering off an atom’s nucleus for the first time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrinos-seen-scattering-atoms-nucleus-first-time</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutrinos-seen-scattering-atoms-nucleus-first-time</link>
	<description>New type of interaction confirms that neutrinos play by the rules.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 18:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080317_EC_neutrino_main.jpg?itok=JXXzqMUk" length="21310" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The solar system's earliest asteroids may have all been massive</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/solar-systems-earliest-asteroids-may-have-all-been-massive</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/solar-systems-earliest-asteroids-may-have-all-been-massive</link>
	<description>A team of astronomers says the original asteroids all came in one size: extra large.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 18:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080317_MT_asteroid_main_free.jpg?itok=kURxO7Gg" length="23276" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Happy birthday to Retraction Watch! (We’re 7.) And an update on our database.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51331</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/03/happy-birthday-retraction-watch-7-update-database/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;August 3rd is a big day around here — it’s our birthday. Today, we celebrate seven years since two science journalists decided, not exactly on whim but close to it, to launch a blog about retractions. Little did they know. (To hear our co-founder Ivan Oransky talk more about this milestone, check out his podcast […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/03/happy-birthday-retraction-watch-7-update-database/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Happy birthday to Retraction Watch! (We’re 7.) And an update on our database.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 16:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Giant armored dinosaur may have cloaked itself in camouflage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-armored-dinosaur-may-have-cloaked-itself-camouflage</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-armored-dinosaur-may-have-cloaked-itself-camouflage</link>
	<description>An armored dinosaur the size of a Honda Civic also wore countershading camouflage, a chemical analysis of its skin suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 16:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080217_lh_dinos_feat.jpg?itok=zSJGdGw4" length="46152" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC-series: July 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9346</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/03/highlights-of-the-bmc-series-july-2017/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4594-z&quot;&gt;Food hypersensitivity and eating out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food hypersensitivity (FH) encompasses both food allergies and non-allergic hypersensitivities and the key to minimizing symptoms and adverse health outcomes is avoidance of the food/allergen. As a parent, getting your child to eat the right food is challenging enough, but add the complexity of a FH and it becomes a whole lot harder; managing a FH child’s dietary needs is particularly challenging when eating out. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4594-z&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt; explored the experiences and behaviours of parents/caregivers when eating out with their FH child. Responses of the participants focused on three themes: ‘family context’, ‘child-focused concerns’, and ‘venue issues’. Eating out as a family was viewed as important to many of the participants; however the challenges associated with ensuring a safe eating out experience for their FH child meant that compromises were often made by at least one family member in order to provide a ‘safer’ venue for the child. Children were often frustrated/disappointed by limited food choices and caregivers believed that their child was ‘missing out’. This qualitative study provides insights into the experiences of caregivers of children with FH when they eat out, and may be of use in tailoring support and information provision to meet the needs of caregivers and children when eating out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Neurology: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcneurol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12883-017-0921-3&quot;&gt;Neurological symptom assessment in Wilson’s disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wilson’s disease (WD) is a rare genetic disorder which leads to impaired copper metabolism; pathological build-up of copper occurs mainly in the liver and the brain which results in liver disease and neuropsychiatric symptoms. Early diagnosis of WD is critical to improving treatment outcomes, but remains a challenge due to the plethora of symptoms with which patients may present, as well as the complexity of the existing clinical tools. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcneurol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12883-017-0921-3&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Neurology &lt;/em&gt;directly compared the two currently used clinical rating scales, in 65 patients receiving treatment for WD, and evaluated their feasibility for use in routine clinical practice. The neurological and psychiatric subscales of the two tools were found to be valuable for detailed assessment of neurological and psychiatric impairment in patients with WD. In contrast, the hepatic subscales showed low correlation with other established measures, underlining the need for further assessment of liver specific rating scales in WD. The authors also developed a short, patient reported, version of one of the scales and suggest its use as a pre-screening tool for the evaluation of WD patients with mild to moderate neurological symptoms, however further studies are required to fully evaluate this scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image of the month:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmczool.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40850-017-0018-x&quot;&gt;3D visualization of live insects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live imaging of whole invertebrates is possible using X-ray micro-computed tomography (micro-CT), but image quality is often compromised by the movement of live subjects. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmczool.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40850-017-0018-x&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Zoology&lt;/em&gt; demonstrates that temporary immobilization of live insects, using CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gas, during micro-CT imaging allows 3D visualization of the whole insect without motion artefacts, and enables repeat imaging at multiple time points, without adversely affecting the insects. The authors discuss the article further in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/31/non-destructive-3d-visualization-whole-body-live-insects-2/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-9347 size-full&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/BMC-Zoology.jpg&quot; width=&quot;807&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;Machine Learning to Predict Childhood PTSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is a type of anxiety disorder which may develop after an individual experiences a traumatic event. Approximately 20% of children will experience some kind of traumatic event before they are 16 years old, but only some go on to develop PTSD. How can we know which child is at risk for PTSD so that it can be prevented? A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-017-1384-1&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; is the first of its kind to use machine learning to identify risk factors for childhood PTSD; Machine learning is a computational approach designed to find patterns in data that will form reliable and accurate predictive models of specified events (in the case of this study, the occurrence of PTSD in a traumatized child). The study used data from a longitudinal study of children admitted to hospital following an injury; a wide variety of risk factors were assessed whilst the child was in hospital and PTSD was determined three months after hospital discharge. Machine Learning methods were applied to the data and models of risk for PTSD were built and tested for accuracy against the real life incidence of PTSD. A set of causal variables, measured around the time of trauma that predicted PTSD three months later were identified by the models. Author Glenn Saxe tells us more about the study in &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/10/machine-learning-predict-childhood-ptsd/&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpharmacoltoxicol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40360-017-0163-4&quot;&gt;Targeting angiogenesis in oral cancer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angiogenesis, the formation of new blood vessels from pre-existing vessels, is a vital physiological process in growth and development. Angiogenesis is also critical for growth and malignancy of tumors and inhibitors of angiogenesis are promising therapeutic targets for cancer treatment. Semaphorins are secreted proteins that act as axon guidance molecules during the development of the nervous system, but have recently been shown to prevent angiogenesis. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpharmacoltoxicol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40360-017-0163-4&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Pharmacology and Toxicology &lt;/em&gt;examined the potential therapeutic effects of overexpressing Semaforin-3 (Sema3), which is normally expressed at low levels in human oral cancer. Using a lentiviral vector, the authors overexpressed Sema3 in oral tumor cell lines; they demonstrate decreased tumor vasculature &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; and drastically suppressed size and capillary density of tumors in xenograft models of oral cancer &lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;. Thus, overexpression of Sema3A in oral cancer cells drastically suppresses the growth of oral cancer by inhibiting angiogenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Genetics:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenet.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12863-017-0535-1&quot;&gt;Tellin shell karyotypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tellins are a genus of marine bivalve molluscs and are one of the largest and most diverse families of bivalves. The taxonomy of tellins is chaotic, largely due to the diversity displayed by their shells. A study &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcgenet.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12863-017-0535-1&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;BMC Genetics&lt;/em&gt; reports a cytogenetic analysis of four tellin shell species. The authors analyzed the karyotypes (the number and appearance of chromosomes in the nucleus) of the four species, and mapped gene clusters using fluorescent in situ hybridization (FISH). The study demonstrates that tellin shells present diverse karyotype compositions. This technique of molecular karyotype analysis provides valuable information for tellin shell identification, and may be helpful for both taxonomic and phylogenetic purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/03/highlights-of-the-bmc-series-july-2017/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC-series: July 2017&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 13:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/BMCWordle-620x342-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Newspaper series prompts CDC to correct paper on Legionnaire’s disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51306</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/03/newspaper-series-prompts-cdc-correct-paper-legionnaires-disease/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Post-publication peer review isn’t just for scientists. Newspaper reporters can help correct the scientific record, too. The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has corrected a journal article on Legionnaire’s disease after the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette revealed what seems to be efforts by the researchers to misrepresent their data. In a series of articles […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/03/newspaper-series-prompts-cdc-correct-paper-legionnaires-disease/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Newspaper series prompts CDC to correct paper on Legionnaire’s disease&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: The intuition blindspot: just because you like going with your gut doesn’t mean you’re good at it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27900</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/03/the-intuition-blindspot-just-because-you-like-going-with-your-gut-doesnt-mean-youre-good-at-it/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-825698716.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27919&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27919&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark III&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cropped image of young woman eye&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1491555335&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;64&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cropped image of woman eye&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cropped image of woman eye&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-825698716.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-825698716.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-825698716.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/03/the-intuition-blindspot-just-because-you-like-going-with-your-gut-doesnt-mean-youre-good-at-it/cropped-image-of-woman-eye/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-825698716.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1750, Benjamin Franklin wrote: “There are three things extremely hard: steel, a diamond, and to know one’s self.” Since then, plenty of research has proven him right: we’re not much good at knowing ourselves and, sadly, we’re &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0963721411402478&quot;&gt;especially bad when it comes to judging traits in ourselves that we care about the most&lt;/a&gt;. Now Stefan Leach and Mario Weick at the University of Kent, Canterbury, have added to this sorry picture of human delusion, reporting in &lt;i&gt;Social Psychological and Personality Science&lt;/i&gt; that people who believe they’re intuitive are &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1948550617706732&quot;&gt;no better than anyone else at tasks that require intuition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27900&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leach and Weick recruited 178 students who completed the Preference for Intuition Scale (which asks respondents to indicate how much they agree or disagree with statements like “With most decisions, it makes sense to completely rely on your feelings”). Some also completed the Faith in Intuition Scale (which includes statements such as “I believe in trusting my hunches”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the participants completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_grammar_learning&quot;&gt;a task&lt;/a&gt; that involved copying out several non-sensical strings of between two and four letters. Unbeknown to the participants, there were complex rules that determined the ordering of these letter strings. After this, they were told that the strings all adhered to hidden grammatical rules and their next challenge was to use their “gut feelings” to decide whether new strings of letters adhered to the rules or not (in these kinds of tasks, implicit learning is thought to manifest consciously as “vague feelings” – intuitions – about what’s going on, though the individual can’t express what their new knowledge actually is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making their judgments, the participants answered questions designed to probe their confidence in their intuitions, how well they thought they did on the task, how much effort they put in, and the extent to which they felt they relied on intuition to decide if a sequence of letters was “correct” or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leach and Weick also ran another study, involving 222 people, which used rules governing the ordering of pictures of people rather than letters. These volunteers also completed a scale exploring their belief in the importance of intuition and their self-rated intuitive abilities before the task, and they answered post-test questions about how well they thought they’d done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of all this new data, as well as some data collected previously, showed that whether a participant considered him or herself to be intuitive or not had no bearing on their performance at judging the letter strings, or their grasp of the rules. When the participants were asked specifically about how confident they were that their particular intuitions regarding this task were accurate, a positive relationship with performance did emerge – but it was very weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier studies have found that people who consider themselves to be more intuitive also tend to believe that their intuitions &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/1999-05479-007&quot;&gt;lead to good results&lt;/a&gt;, and are useful. So these new findings are likely to come as bad news to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One caveat is that this research involved participants using their intuition to make judgments based on recently acquired knowledge. As the authors themselves stress, “the findings … should not be generalised to other facets of intuition, such as the intuitive decision-making of experts.” However, they added that, “it is interesting to note….that studies on expert intuitions often arrive at similar conclusions as the present research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1948550617706732&quot;&gt;Can People Judge the Veracity of Their Intuitions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27900/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27900/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27900&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 09:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Asia’s research leaders ask how universities can use data to drive sustainability</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/asias-research-leaders-ask-how-universities-can-use-data-to-drive-sustainability</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/asias-research-leaders-ask-how-universities-can-use-data-to-drive-sustainability</link>
	<description>The 4th Annual Asia Pacific Research Intelligence Conference brought together nearly 200 research executives</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 08:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Cosmic map reveals a not-so-lumpy Universe</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22413</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/mG4HhXEMvtY/nature.2017.22413</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Odd results could still be consistent with the ‘standard model’ of cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 143 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22413&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22413&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/mG4HhXEMvtY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Authors retract controversial NgAgo gene-editing study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22412</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/vgmLwpgmb1k/nature.2017.22412</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers pull study after several failed attempts by others to replicate findings describing a proposed alternative to CRISPR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22412&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/vgmLwpgmb1k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: ‘Autistic’ mice make littermates less social</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22411</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pd4wAtzsVa4/nature.2017.22411</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Mice genetically engineered to show autism-like symptoms can affect behaviour of unmodified animals when the two are kept together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22411&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22411&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pd4wAtzsVa4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ancient genomes show how maize adapted to life at high altitudes</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22403</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/C4aiC-66vkE/nature.2017.22403</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Changes to flowering times helped the staple crop spread into new areas thousands of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22403&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22403&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/C4aiC-66vkE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “The data have spoken:” Controversial NgAgo gene editing study retracted</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51317</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/data-spoken-controversial-ngago-gene-editing-study-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The author of a 2016 paper describing a potentially invaluable lab tool has retracted it, following heavy criticism from outside groups that could not reproduce the findings. The paper had already been tagged with an Expression of Concern by the journal, Nature Biotechnology, which included data from multiple groups casting doubt on the original findings. Although […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/data-spoken-controversial-ngago-gene-editing-study-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“The data have spoken:” Controversial NgAgo gene editing study retracted&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 20:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Light pollution can foil plant-insect hookups, and not just at night</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/light-pollution-can-foil-plant-insect-hookups-and-not-just-night</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/light-pollution-can-foil-plant-insect-hookups-and-not-just-night</link>
	<description>Upsetting nocturnal pollinators has daylight after-effects for Swiss meadow flowers.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 20:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080217_SM_llight-pollution_main_free.jpg?itok=NS5FTSrJ" length="16513" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: South Asia could face deadly heat and humidity by the end of this century</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-heat-india-pakistan-2100</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/extreme-heat-india-pakistan-2100</link>
	<description>If climate change is left unchecked, simulations show extreme heat waves in densely populated agricultural regions of India and Pakistan.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080117_AY_south-asian-heat_main_FREE.jpg?itok=flhlTye8" length="40668" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Your solar eclipse experience can help science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-science-solar-eclipse</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/citizen-science-solar-eclipse</link>
	<description>The Aug. 21 total solar eclipse offers a rare opportunity for crowdsourced data collection on a spectacular celestial phenomenon.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 18:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/080117_MT_eclipse_main_free.jpg?itok=NerE0YHg" length="16077" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Gene editing of human embryos gets rid of a mutation that causes heart failure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-gene-editing-human-embryos</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crispr-gene-editing-human-embryos</link>
	<description>Gene editing of human embryos can efficiently repair a gene defect without making new mistakes.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/articles/080217_TI_embryo-editing_main.jpg?itok=ZaPguUAo" length="20806" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A press release had “fake” and “NASA” in its headline. Then it was retracted.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51300</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/press-release-fake-nasa-headline-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday, struck — as it were — by a headline about an asteroid preparedness test, I took to Twitter:  Putting &quot;fake&quot; and &quot;NASA&quot; into a press release headline in today's climate: Risky, or Troll Level: Master? https://t.co/Wn0wypQm4z — Ivan Oransky (@ivanoransky) July 28, 2017 I couldn’t quite tell if this was a clever dig […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/press-release-fake-nasa-headline-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A press release had “fake” and “NASA” in its headline. Then it was retracted.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Author admits to manipulating more than a dozen images in 2013 paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51283</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/author-admits-manipulating-dozen-images-2013-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A former graduate student at the University of Hong Kong confessed to making “inappropriate modifications” to several figures in a 2013 paper in the Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC). According to the retraction notice, the authors identified issues in 13 images while reviewing the data; the paper’s first author, Yingying Lu, copped to manipulating the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/08/02/author-admits-manipulating-dozen-images-2013-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author admits to manipulating more than a dozen images in 2013 paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Against expectations, no evidence that toddlers with older siblings have superior Theory of Mind</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27774</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/02/against-expectations-no-evidence-that-toddlers-with-older-siblings-have-superior-theory-of-mind/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-527470944.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27888&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27888&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Corbis via Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;LS-9000&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A brother and sister run through the back garden of their South London home. We see the younger sibling - a boy of three leading his big sister by the hand in some sort of follow-my-leader game. He pulls hard to tow the girl along who wears Wellington boots that are too large for her and they both hold out their arms for stability. From a personal documentary project entitled \&amp;quot;Next of Kin\&amp;quot; about the photographer's two children's early years spent in parallel universes. Model released. (Photo by In Pictures Ltd.\/Corbis via Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1232985049&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Richard Baker&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;England - London - Follow-my-leader brother and sister&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;England – London – Follow-my-leader brother and sister&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-527470944.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-527470944.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-527470944.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,666&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/08/02/against-expectations-no-evidence-that-toddlers-with-older-siblings-have-superior-theory-of-mind/england-london-follow-my-leader-brother-and-sister/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/08/gettyimages-527470944.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When young kids play together there’s often a lot of negotiation involved: “That’s my bunny”, “No, it’s mine”, “OK, you have it”. There’s talk of emotion: “Why are you crying?”, “You took my bunny”. And role-play: “You be baddie”, “No, I’m super-bunny”. Perhaps it shouldn’t be too surprising then that &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cdev.12682/abstract&quot;&gt;a recent meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; found that young kids, aged 3 to 7, with more siblings have superior Theory of Mind (understanding other people’s mental states and perspectives – an important ability that benefits social and academic performance at school).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Cognition and Development&lt;/em&gt; asks whether the sibling advantage begins as early as toddlerhood, and whether it matters if a toddler’s sibling is older or younger. In fact, against expectations, toddlers with an older sibling showed no Theory of Mind advantage compared with only children, and toddlers with a younger sibling actually performed worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27774&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Élizabel Leblanc and her colleagues tested 227 two-year-olds (113 boys) on two age-appropriate Theory of Mind tasks. One was focused on perspective-taking and required the toddlers to show their mother a toy and in the process deal with various challenges, such the fact she had her eyes closed or was facing the wrong way. The other task pertained to diverging interests: the toddlers had to choose a book to give the researcher, either a children’s book for which she’d previously expressed dislike or an adult book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On average, the 112 kids with one or more older siblings and the 76 only children performed equally well at the two tasks. Number of older siblings made no difference to these results. Meanwhile, the 29 toddlers with a younger sibling (but no older siblings) performed worse at the perspective taking task than both only children and toddlers with an older sibling; they also performed worse at the divergent interests task than the kids with older sibs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, the researchers speculated, toddlers with a younger sibling are disadvantaged by their parents’ attention being diverted to their younger, infant sibling (the toddler also can’t engage in sophisticated play with an infant sibling). On the other hand, maybe toddlers without any siblings are able to match the performance of toddlers with older siblings because of the extra attention they receive from their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Future studies are required to investigate whether a putative negative effect of younger siblings is robust and apparent in the preschool years, whether it is limited to the toddlerhood period, and whether the mechanisms proposed here are indeed at work,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15248372.2017.1327438&quot;&gt;The More the Merrier? Sibling Composition and Early Manifestations of Theory of Mind in Toddlers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image credit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gettyimages.co.uk/search/photographer?family=editorial&amp;amp;photographer=Richard+Baker&quot; id=&quot;photographer&quot;&gt;Richard Baker&lt;/a&gt; / Getty Images Contributor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jopy.12333/abstract?campaign=wolacceptedarticle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27774/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27774/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27774&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 11:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Modern-day Alice trades looking glass for wormhole to explore quantum wonderland</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/wormhole-black-hole-quantum-entanglement</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/wormhole-black-hole-quantum-entanglement</link>
	<description>A new paper shows how the possibility of wormholes linking quantum-entangled black holes could be tested in the laboratory.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/080217_TS_wormholes_main_free.jpg?itok=zn_RJcAX" length="23927" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: New Service Providers Available on Science Exchange</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1112</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/08/new-service-providers-available-on-science-exchange/</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_1113&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/ocello&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Image of Colon Tumor Cells courtesy of OcellO&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1113&quot; height=&quot;164&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/DfHIVQBTSuCwchUJG6lg_OcellO-cultured-tissue-from-patient-colon-tumour-stem-cells-300x164.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;Image of Colon Tumor Stem Cells courtesy of OcellO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you aren’t exploring the latest cell culture models of human tissue for nonclinical and preclinical testing, you should be. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;That’s the bottom line of today’s Science Exchange service provider roundup — three of the five newest service providers on our platform are experts in developing predictive models. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Advances in predictive model systems&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/axiogenesis&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Axiogenesis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, based in Germany, develops iPSC-derived models of cardiac tissue, neurons, and other cell types. In late 2016, the company made the news when researchers at the United States FDA published a peer-reviewed study showing that Axiogenesis’s Cor.4U cardiomyocyte model was the most predictive model in cardiac safety tests. Last month, researchers at Wake Forest University used the Cor.4U model to develop a digitally trackable beating-heart biosensor. The future of cardiac safety clearly lies beyond hERG channel electrophysiology!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Generating tissue models with precise spatial resolution is possible using 3D bioprinting, in which &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tracking.cirrusinsight.com/466e66be-1ba2-4d51-a499-22dc4af918de/scienceexchange-com-labs-cypre-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Cypre Biotech&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is an expert. Based in San Francisco, USA, the company focuses on customizing the extracellular matrix of tumor microenvironment models to match certain cancer subtypes. Given the impact of new cancer drugs, including certain immunotherapies, on the tumor microenvironment, technologies such as that developed by Cypre are going to be needed for testing safety and efficacy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The third service provider in this roundup excelling in the development of clinically relevant microtissue models is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/ocello&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;OcellO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, headquartered in the Netherlands. Researchers at OcellO have published numerous peer-reviewed studies showing how combining three-dimensional tissue culture with high-throughput imaging can enable efficient, automated screening and phenotypic profiling. Their most recent publication showed that phenotypic screening of kinase inhibitors could reveal potential new targets for polycystic kidney disease (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/ocello/storefront&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;view abstract in the Resources section of the OcellO storefront&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Analytical methods for translational research&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;As model systems advance in complexity and throughput, analytical methods must keep pace. Two service providers new on Science Exchange are known for their expertise in developing reliable analytical methods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/pangaea-oncology-sa&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Pangaea Oncology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is one of the most prestigious laboratories in the world in the fields of molecular diagnostics, pathology, and related analysis services for translational research. We are thrilled to have the Pangaea team, led by expert Dr. Rafael Rosell and Nobel laureate Dr. Santiago Ramón y Cajal, join the Science Exchange platform! Pangaea Oncology was the first laboratory in Spain to be accredited to perform certain genetic tests for cancer in serum/plasma samples, advancing precision medicine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We also bring you &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/metis-laboratories&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Metis Laboratories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, whose analytical expertise centers on radiotracer-based assays. These assays remain one of the most sensitive and specific platforms for assessing ligand binding and compound distribution; however, complex handling requirements mean that outsourcing these studies is far more practical than developing radiotracer assays in house. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Connect with a new provider today!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you new to Science Exchange? &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.scienceexchange.com/hc/en-us&quot;&gt;See how it works.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 10:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Addiction to modern technology: what the science says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/addiction-to-modern-technology-what-the-science-says</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/addiction-to-modern-technology-what-the-science-says</link>
	<description>Free collection of articles highlights the latest trends in behavioral addiction</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 08:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: Project: Binaural cues and spatial hearing in ecological environments</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1441</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/project-binaural-cues-and-spatial-hearing-in-ecological-environments/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I previously laid out a few ideas for future research on spatial hearing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/some-propositions-for-future-spatial-hearing-research-i-the-ecological-situation-and-the-computational-problem/&quot;&gt;The ecological situation and the computational problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/some-propositions-for-future-spatial-hearing-research-ii-tuning-curves/&quot;&gt;Tuning curves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/some-propositions-for-future-spatial-hearing-research-iii-the-coding-problem/&quot;&gt;The coding problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I wrote a grant that addresses the first point. My project was rather straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To make binaural recordings with ear mics in real environments, with real sound sources (actual sounding objects) placed at predetermined positions. This way we obtain distributions of binaural cues conditioned on source direction, capturing the variability due to context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To measure human localization performance in those situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To try to see if a Bayesian model can account for these results, and possibly previous psychophysical results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was preselected but unfortunately not funded. I probably won't resubmit it next year, except perhaps with a collaboration. So here it is for everyone to read: my grant application, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/WordPress3/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Binaural-Hearing-Grant.pdf&quot;&gt;Binaural cues and spatial hearing in ecological environments&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. If you like it, if you want to do these recordings and experiments, please do so. I am interested in the results, but I'm happy if someone else does it. Please contact me if you would like to set up a collaboration, or discuss the project. I am especially interested in the theoretical analysis (ie the third part of the project). Our experience in the lab is primarily on the theoretical side, but also in signal analysis, and we have done a number of binaural recordings too and some psychophysics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 07:27:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Open Position: 5-year research fellow position in Neuromorphic Machine Learning</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-08-02:/2017/08/02/open-position-5-year-research-fellow-position-in-neuromorphic-machine-learning.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/08/02/open-position-5-year-research-fellow-position-in-neuromorphic-machine-learning.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a 5-year research position in the Biocomputation group at the University of Hertfordshire, under the supervision of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://researchprofiles.herts.ac.uk/portal/en/persons/michael-schmuker(fda08dd2-790b-4871-92cb-324b9f1e4267).html&quot;&gt;Dr. Michael Schmuker&lt;/a&gt;. This position offers the unique opportunity to explore the interdisciplinary field of neuromorphic machine learning, branching out into artificial intelligence, computational neuroscience, robotics and data science.  We are looking for excellent candidates who are keen to explore neuro-inspired machine learning and artificial intelligence using specialised hardware systems such as &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://apt.cs.manchester.ac.uk/projects/SpiNNaker/&quot;&gt;SpiNNaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://brainscales.kip.uni-heidelberg.de/public/index.html&quot;&gt;BrainScaleS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details and to apply please see the advert at &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.jobs.herts.ac.uk&quot;&gt;http://www.jobs.herts.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt; (reference 014832, deadline: 21st August 2017).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 07:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Nocturnal pollinators go dark under street lamps</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22395</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bQfejmxhVEk/nature.2017.22395</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Plants illuminated by artificial lights see a drop in the number of insects that move pollen at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22395&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22395&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bQfejmxhVEk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Drug companies flock to supercharged T-cells in fight against autoimmune disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22393</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CRAzZWfyIBI/nature.2017.22393</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers target suppressive cells to keep the body from attacking itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22393&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22393&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CRAzZWfyIBI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Iranian scientist to go on trial for espionage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22384</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ygBq_kWo-E4/nature.2017.22384</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Academics call for release of Ahmadreza Djalali, a disaster-medicine researcher who has been held in a Tehran prison for more than a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22384&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22384&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ygBq_kWo-E4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: ISWI chromatin remodellers sense nucleosome modifications to determine substrate preference</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23671</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/oqjnoREBaok/nature23671</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 ATP-dependent chromatin remodelers regulate access to genetic information by controlling nucleosome positions in vivo1. However, the mechanism by which remodelers discriminate between different nucleosome substrates is poorly understood. Considering that many chromatin remodeling proteins possess conserved protein domains that interact with nucleosomal features2, we employed a quantitative high-throughput approach, based on the use of a DNA-barcoded mononucleosome library, to profile the biochemical activity of human ISWI remodelers in response to a diverse set of nucleosome modifications. We show that accessory (non-ATPase) subunits of ISWI remodelers can distinguish between differentially modified nucleosomes, directing remodeling activity toward specific nucleosome substrates based on their modification state. Unexpectedly, we discover the nucleosome acidic patch3 as necessary for maximum activity of all ISWI remodelers evaluated. We find this dependence also extends to CHD and SWI/SNF family remodelers, suggesting the acidic patch may be generally required for chromatin remodeling. Critically, we observe that remodeling activity can be regulated by modifications neighboring the acidic patch, signifying it may act as a tunable interaction hotspot for ATP-dependent chromatin remodelers and, by extension, many other chromatin effectors that engage this region of the nucleosome surface4–9. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23671&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23671&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/oqjnoREBaok&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cancer genomics: Human metastases under scrutiny</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23535</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jU1Orx6m4Ho/nature23535</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Sequences of the DNA and RNA of 500 human cancers that have spread from their primary site in the body take us a step closer to the convergence of basic science and patient benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23535&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23535&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jU1Orx6m4Ho&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cell biology: Healthy skin rejects cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23534</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jyMyZK6h5bs/nature23534</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Live imaging shows that healthy skin cells surround and expel neighbours that have cancer-promoting mutations, revealing that tissues can recognize and eliminate mutant cells to prevent tumour initiation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23534&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23534&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jyMyZK6h5bs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Biotechnology: At the heart of gene edits in human embryos</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23533</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ufvhZUx3Ov0/nature23533</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The gene-editing technology CRISPR–Cas has been used in human embryos grown  in vitro  to correct a disease-associated mutation. The introduction of editing components at fertilization aided repair efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23533&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23533&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ufvhZUx3Ov0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Microbiology: The case of the mysterious messenger</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23532</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ORr1llFXCnA/nature23532</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Bacteria and archaea use an innate immune system called CRISPR–Cas to combat viral infection. The identification of a family of molecules that play a key part in this system deepens our understanding of such immunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23532&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23532&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ORr1llFXCnA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Metabolic control of TH17 and induced Treg cell balance by an epigenetic mechanism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23475</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/j1eJUoGZjIk/nature23475</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Metabolism has been shown to integrate with epigenetics and transcription to modulate cell fate and function. Beyond meeting the bioenergetic and biosynthetic demands of T-cell differentiation, whether metabolism might control T-cell fate by an epigenetic mechanism is unclear. Here, through the discovery and mechanistic characterization of a small molecule, (aminooxy)acetic acid, that reprograms the differentiation of T helper 17 (TH17) cells towards induced regulatory T (iTreg) cells, we show that increased transamination, mainly catalysed by GOT1, leads to increased levels of 2-hydroxyglutarate in differentiating TH17 cells. The accumulation of 2-hydroxyglutarate resulted in hypermethylation of the Foxp3 gene locus and inhibited Foxp3 transcription, which is essential for fate determination towards TH17 cells. Inhibition of the conversion of glutamate to α-ketoglutaric acid prevented the production of 2-hydroxyglutarate, reduced methylation of the Foxp3 gene locus, and increased Foxp3 expression. This consequently blocked the differentiation of TH17 cells by antagonizing the function of transcription factor RORγt and promoted polarization into iTreg cells. Selective inhibition of GOT1 with (aminooxy)acetic acid ameliorated experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis in a therapeutic mouse model by regulating the balance between TH17 and iTreg cells. Targeting a glutamate-dependent metabolic pathway thus represents a new strategy for developing therapeutic agents against TH17-mediated autoimmune diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23475&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23475&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/j1eJUoGZjIk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Proteins evolve on the edge of supramolecular self-assembly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23320</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/V-vZGa24uyI/nature23320</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The self-association of proteins into symmetric complexes is ubiquitous in all kingdoms of life. Symmetric complexes possess unique geometric and functional properties, but their internal symmetry can pose a risk. In sickle-cell disease, the symmetry of haemoglobin exacerbates the effect of a mutation, triggering assembly into harmful fibrils. Here we examine the universality of this mechanism and its relation to protein structure geometry. We introduced point mutations solely designed to increase surface hydrophobicity among 12 distinct symmetric complexes from Escherichia coli. Notably, all responded by forming supramolecular assemblies in vitro, as well as in vivo upon heterologous expression in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Remarkably, in four cases, micrometre-long fibrils formed in vivo in response to a single point mutation. Biophysical measurements and electron microscopy revealed that mutants self-assembled in their folded states and so were not amyloid-like. Structural examination of 73 mutants identified supramolecular assembly hot spots predictable by geometry. A subsequent structural analysis of 7,471 symmetric complexes showed that geometric hot spots were buffered chemically by hydrophilic residues, suggesting a mechanism preventing mis-assembly of these regions. Thus, point mutations can frequently trigger folded proteins to self-assemble into higher-order structures. This potential is counterbalanced by negative selection and can be exploited to design nanomaterials in living cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23320&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23320&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/V-vZGa24uyI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Genetic origins of the Minoans and Mycenaeans</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23310</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/oiCrRYpA4b0/nature23310</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The origins of the Bronze Age Minoan and Mycenaean cultures have puzzled archaeologists for more than a century. We have assembled genome-wide data from 19 ancient individuals, including Minoans from Crete, Mycenaeans from mainland Greece, and their eastern neighbours from southwestern Anatolia. Here we show that Minoans and Mycenaeans were genetically similar, having at least three-quarters of their ancestry from the first Neolithic farmers of western Anatolia and the Aegean, and most of the remainder from ancient populations related to those of the Caucasus and Iran. However, the Mycenaeans differed from Minoans in deriving additional ancestry from an ultimate source related to the hunter–gatherers of eastern Europe and Siberia, introduced via a proximal source related to the inhabitants of either the Eurasian steppe or Armenia. Modern Greeks resemble the Mycenaeans, but with some additional dilution of the Early Neolithic ancestry. Our results support the idea of continuity but not isolation in the history of populations of the Aegean, before and after the time of its earliest civilizations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23310&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23310&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/oiCrRYpA4b0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Persistent anthrax as a major driver of wildlife mortality in a tropical rainforest</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23309</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/AJdzht4DRAs/nature23309</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Anthrax is a globally important animal disease and zoonosis. Despite this, our current knowledge of anthrax ecology is largely limited to arid ecosystems, where outbreaks are most commonly reported. Here we show that the dynamics of an anthrax-causing agent, Bacillus cereus biovar anthracis, in a tropical rainforest have severe consequences for local wildlife communities. Using data and samples collected over three decades, we show that rainforest anthrax is a persistent and widespread cause of death for a broad range of mammalian hosts. We predict that this pathogen will accelerate the decline and possibly result in the extirpation of local chimpanzee (Pan troglodytes verus) populations. We present the epidemiology of a cryptic pathogen and show that its presence has important implications for conservation. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 82 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23309&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23309&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/AJdzht4DRAs&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Integrative clinical genomics of metastatic cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23306</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/RGOwWaF2u18/nature23306</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Metastasis is the primary cause of cancer-related deaths. Although The Cancer Genome Atlas has sequenced primary tumour types obtained from surgical resections, much less comprehensive molecular analysis is available from clinically acquired metastatic cancers. Here we perform whole-exome and -transcriptome sequencing of 500 adult patients with metastatic solid tumours of diverse lineage and biopsy site. The most prevalent genes somatically altered in metastatic cancer included TP53, CDKN2A, PTEN, PIK3CA, and RB1. Putative pathogenic germline variants were present in 12.2% of cases of which 75% were related to defects in DNA repair. RNA sequencing complemented DNA sequencing to identify gene fusions, pathway activation, and immune profiling. Our results show that integrative sequence analysis provides a clinically relevant, multi-dimensional view of the complex molecular landscape and microenvironment of metastatic cancers. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23306&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23306&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/RGOwWaF2u18&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Correction of a pathogenic gene mutation in human embryos</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23305</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/b1hnluWc5uI/nature23305</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Genome editing has potential for the targeted correction of germline mutations. Here we describe the correction of the heterozygous MYBPC3 mutation in human preimplantation embryos with precise CRISPR–Cas9-based targeting accuracy and high homology-directed repair efficiency by activating an endogenous, germline-specific DNA repair response. Induced double-strand breaks (DSBs) at the mutant paternal allele were predominantly repaired using the homologous wild-type maternal gene instead of a synthetic DNA template. By modulating the cell cycle stage at which the DSB was induced, we were able to avoid mosaicism in cleaving embryos and achieve a high yield of homozygous embryos carrying the wild-type MYBPC3 gene without evidence of off-target mutations. The efficiency, accuracy and safety of the approach presented suggest that it has potential to be used for the correction of heritable mutations in human embryos by complementing preimplantation genetic diagnosis. However, much remains to be considered before clinical applications, including the reproducibility of the technique with other heterozygous mutations. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23305&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23305&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/b1hnluWc5uI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Correction of aberrant growth preserves tissue homeostasis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23304</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/jO2vUH2yf3Q/nature23304</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Cells in healthy tissues acquire mutations with surprising frequency. Many of these mutations are associated with abnormal cellular behaviours such as differentiation defects and hyperproliferation, yet fail to produce macroscopically detectable phenotypes. It is currently unclear how the tissue remains phenotypically normal, despite the presence of these mutant cells. Here we use intravital imaging to track the fate of mouse skin epithelium burdened with varying numbers of activated Wnt/β-catenin stem cells. We show that all resulting growths that deform the skin tissue architecture regress, irrespective of their size. Wild-type cells are required for the active elimination of mutant cells from the tissue, while utilizing both endogenous and ectopic cellular behaviours to dismantle the aberrant structures. After regression, the remaining structures are either completely eliminated or converted into functional skin appendages in a niche-dependent manner. Furthermore, tissue aberrancies generated from oncogenic Hras, and even mutation-independent deformations to the tissue, can also be corrected, indicating that this tolerance phenomenon reflects a conserved principle in the skin. This study reveals an unanticipated plasticity of the adult skin epithelium when faced with mutational and non-mutational insult, and elucidates the dynamic cellular behaviours used for its return to a homeostatic state. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23304&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23304&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/jO2vUH2yf3Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A Braf kinase-inactive mutant induces lung adenocarcinoma</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23297</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zIDhacRItNA/nature23297</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The initiating oncogenic event in almost half of human lung adenocarcinomas is still unknown, a fact that complicates the development of selective targeted therapies. Yet these tumours harbour a number of alterations without obvious oncogenic function including BRAF-inactivating mutations. Inactivating BRAF mutants in lung predominate over the activating V600E mutant that is frequently observed in other tumour types. Here we demonstrate that the expression of an endogenous Braf(D631A) kinase-inactive isoform in mice (corresponding to the human BRAF(D594A) mutation) triggers lung adenocarcinoma in vivo, indicating that BRAF-inactivating mutations are initiating events in lung oncogenesis. Moreover, inactivating BRAF mutations have also been identified in a subset of KRAS-driven human lung tumours. Co-expression of Kras(G12V) and Braf(D631A) in mouse lung cells markedly enhances tumour initiation, a phenomenon mediated by Craf kinase activity, and effectively accelerates tumour progression when activated in advanced lung adenocarcinomas. We also report a key role for the wild-type Braf kinase in sustaining Kras(G12V)/Braf(D631A)-driven tumours. Ablation of the wild-type Braf allele prevents the development of lung adenocarcinoma by inducing a further increase in MAPK signalling that results in oncogenic toxicity; this effect can be abolished by pharmacological inhibition of Mek to restore tumour growth. However, the loss of wild-type Braf also induces transdifferentiation of club cells, which leads to the rapid development of lethal intrabronchiolar lesions. These observations indicate that the signal intensity of the MAPK pathway is a critical determinant not only in tumour development, but also in dictating the nature of the cancer-initiating cell and ultimately the resulting tumour phenotype. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23297&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zIDhacRItNA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: The evolution of the host microbiome as an ecosystem on a leash</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23292</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Uy6zBnLBDbk/nature23292</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The human body carries vast communities of microbes that provide many benefits. Our microbiome is complex and challenging to understand, but evolutionary theory provides a universal framework with which to analyse its biology and health impacts. Here we argue that to understand a given microbiome feature, such as colonization resistance, host nutrition or immune development, we must consider how hosts and symbionts evolve. Symbionts commonly evolve to compete within the host ecosystem, while hosts evolve to keep the ecosystem on a leash. We suggest that the health benefits of the microbiome should be understood, and studied, as an interplay between microbial competition and host control. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 43 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23292&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23292&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Uy6zBnLBDbk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Tumours with class 3 BRAF mutants are sensitive to the inhibition of activated RAS</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23291</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/96XXZyzl7Do/nature23291</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Approximately 200 BRAF mutant alleles have been identified in human tumours. Activating BRAF mutants cause feedback inhibition of GTP-bound RAS, are RAS-independent and signal either as active monomers (class 1) or constitutively active dimers (class 2). Here we characterize a third class of BRAF mutants—those that have impaired kinase activity or are kinase-dead. These mutants are sensitive to ERK-mediated feedback and their activation of signalling is RAS-dependent. The mutants bind more tightly than wild-type BRAF to RAS–GTP, and their binding to and activation of wild-type CRAF is enhanced, leading to increased ERK signalling. The model suggests that dysregulation of signalling by these mutants in tumours requires coexistent mechanisms for maintaining RAS activation despite ERK-dependent feedback. Consistent with this hypothesis, melanomas with these class 3 BRAF mutations also harbour RAS mutations or NF1 deletions. By contrast, in lung and colorectal cancers with class 3 BRAF mutants, RAS is typically activated by receptor tyrosine kinase signalling. These tumours are sensitive to the inhibition of RAS activation by inhibitors of receptor tyrosine kinases. We have thus defined three distinct functional classes of BRAF mutants in human tumours. The mutants activate ERK signalling by different mechanisms that dictate their sensitivity to therapeutic inhibitors of the pathway. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23291&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23291&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/96XXZyzl7Do&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Artificial light at night as a new threat to pollination</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23288</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/-fVMdE-EPXc/nature23288</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Pollinators are declining worldwide and this has raised concerns for a parallel decline in the essential pollination service they provide to both crops and wild plants. Anthropogenic drivers linked to this decline include habitat changes, intensive agriculture, pesticides, invasive alien species, spread of pathogens and climate change. Recently, the rapid global increase in artificial light at night has been proposed to be a new threat to terrestrial ecosystems; the consequences of this increase for ecosystem function are mostly unknown. Here we show that artificial light at night disrupts nocturnal pollination networks and has negative consequences for plant reproductive success. In artificially illuminated plant–pollinator communities, nocturnal visits to plants were reduced by 62% compared to dark areas. Notably, this resulted in an overall 13% reduction in fruit set of a focal plant even though the plant also received numerous visits by diurnal pollinators. Furthermore, by merging diurnal and nocturnal pollination sub-networks, we show that the structure of these combined networks tends to facilitate the spread of the negative consequences of disrupted nocturnal pollination to daytime pollinator communities. Our findings demonstrate that artificial light at night is a threat to pollination and that the negative effects of artificial light at night on nocturnal pollination are predicted to propagate to the diurnal community, thereby aggravating the decline of the diurnal community. We provide perspectives on the functioning of plant–pollinator communities, showing that nocturnal pollinators are not redundant to diurnal communities and increasing our understanding of the human-induced decline in pollinators and their ecosystem service. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23288&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23288&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/-fVMdE-EPXc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Elsässer et al. reply</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23278</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/fauFusp06B0/nature23278</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 E7 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23278&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/fauFusp06B0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: On the role of H3.3 in retroviral silencing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23277</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/B2RW89xlc9M/nature23277</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 E1 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23277&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23277&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/B2RW89xlc9M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: 50 &amp; 100 Years Ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548039a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/SkWtOLs1AFw/548039a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 548 39 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/548039a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/548039a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/SkWtOLs1AFw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Virgo detector joins LIGO in the search for gravitational waves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/virgo-detector-joins-ligo-search-gravitational-waves</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/virgo-detector-joins-ligo-search-gravitational-waves</link>
	<description>The Virgo detector near Pisa, Italy, has begun searching for subtle ripples in the fabric of spacetime.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 19:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/08/main/blogposts/080117_EV_ticker_virgo_free.jpg?itok=SoBEleyt" length="47797" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
