<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Signal Propagation and Logic Gating in Networks of Integrate-and-Fire Neurons</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-06-20:/2018/06/20/signal-propagation-and-logic-gating-in-networks-of-integrate-and-fire-neurons.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/06/20/signal-propagation-and-logic-gating-in-networks-of-integrate-and-fire-neurons.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Transmission of signals within the brain is essential for cognitive function, but it is not clear how neural circuits support reliable and accurate signal propagation over a sufficiently large dynamic range. Two modes of propagation have been studied: synfire chains, in which synchronous activity travels through feedforward layers of a neuronal network, and the propagation of fluctuations in firing rate
across these layers. In both cases, a sufficient amount of noise, which was added to previous models from an external source, had to be included to support stable propagation. Sparse, randomly connected networks of spiking model neurons can generate chaotic patterns of activity. We investigate whether this activity, which is a more realistic noise source, is sufficient to allow for signal transmission. We find that, for rate-coded signals but not for synfire chains, such networks support robust and accurate signal reproduction through up to six layers if appropriate adjustments are made in synaptic strengths. We investigate the factors affecting transmission and show that multiple signals can propagate simultaneously along different pathways. Using this feature, we show how different types of logic gates can arise within the architecture of the random network through the strengthening of specific synapses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 22/06/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 14:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Are Dyslexics More Entrepreneurial?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23742</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/20/are-dyslexics-more-entrepreneurial/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is rather common: it is estimated that around 5-10% of individuals are dyslexic. Despite an apparent disability, some are famous, like Tom Cruise or Richard Branson. Obviously, they do not suffer from a lack of intelligence and are, in fact, quite successful in the business world. So what is going on in their brains? Are they developing some compensatory mechanisms that help them to do things better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epidemiological research studies indicate that dyslexics develop coping strategies to compensate for their weaknesses, which helps them in later life. The resilience that they acquire while in school often helps them to be more successful in developing a business, in being an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics show that there are twice more dyslexics among entrepreneurs when compared to the general population. However, dyslexics are uncommon in higher management. They also tend to have a different business management style. Thus, they do better in startups and are better at handling particular types of businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is usually first identified when a child goes to school and struggles with scrambled text. Dyslexic children have difficulty in reading texts, interpreting them, and explaining the meaning of the text to others, even though they can be very intelligent otherwise. Dyslexia often results in poor academic performance, undue pressure, and psychological trauma. Each dyslexic child needs to learn to cope with these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although dyslexic children are as intelligent as their peers at school, they are often labeled as less capable. Children with dyslexia are often targets of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/03/school-bullying-forgive-ignore-or-revenge/&quot;&gt;bullying in school&lt;/a&gt;. Poor self-image at school often leads to worsening of self-esteem in many of these kids. As helping dyslexic children is not easy, they are often left to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s going on in the dyslexic brain? Neurological basis of dyslexia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a common disorder, dyslexia is the subject of multiple studies. Researchers agree that those living with dyslexia may have differences in the brain relative to non-dyslexic children, and these differences are the subject of intense clinical research. The recent explosion in brain imaging technology is helping us gain a deeper understanding of the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurological theory of dyslexia is one of the earliest. The theory was proposed about a century ago when British physicians Morgan and Hinshelwood described dyslexia as a “visual word blindness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of adults &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/07/14/living-with-traumatic-brain-injury/&quot;&gt;living with brain trauma&lt;/a&gt; in the left parietal region demonstrated that many of these people develop reading difficulties. They find it challenging to process the optical image of letters. Thus, the early theory was that those with dyslexia have developmental defects in the parietal region of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left parietal involvement was also somewhat confirmed during pathological examination of the brains of those who died at an earlier age and were known to be dyslexic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important theory focuses on delayed brain lateralization in dyslexia. It is thought that some people have weak or insufficient brain lateralization that hinders the understanding of languages. This theory was the subject of multiple studies in the second half of last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest research into the neurophysiology of those living with dyslexia seems to indicate that dyslexia is phonological in nature: dyslexics have difficulty in manipulating the phoneme parts of speech. It is possible that there are developmental issues in the visual tract or other visual mechanisms in the brain may be contributing to the difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from defects in a specific subsystem of the vision pathway, researchers think that there are other brain developmental issues involved as well. It is entirely possible that people with dyslexia have temporal processing impairment, and therefore they are not able to process information fast enough. Thus, dyslexia is considered the result of multi-system deficits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyslexia is probably the result of deficits in the brain at multiple levels. There is an impaired phoneme discrimination resulting in difficulty in understanding spelling. Visual perceptual impairment leads to further worsening of word recognition, and phonological awareness impairment causes speech disturbances. In the center of all this is delayed temporal processing. The end result is delayed speech development, difficulties in reading and comprehending texts, and poor academic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What makes a dyslexic a successful person?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Leonardo da Vinci to Einstein, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/04/16/opening-the-classroom-door-for-children-with-autism/&quot;&gt;children with learning disabilities&lt;/a&gt; prove that there is a limited link between disability and intelligence. Children with dyslexia are at least equally intelligent to non-dyslexic children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The higher success of individuals with dyslexia in certain professions is probably the result of resilience or compensatory mechanisms that they cultivate during the school days to overcome their difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these kids may develop better skills for interacting with others. They may focus more on specific arts or sciences. Many of them may not concentrate on studies and instead start doing business at an early age. This means that they can be found in any profession, and in the long run they are equally successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compensatory mechanisms developed at a young age may provide an edge over others in specific areas when the children grow up. Even though dyslexics may score poorly in school, they may outscore other children in practical life since they spend more time perfecting their verbal skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an entrepreneur, dyslexics are known to be good at delegating tasks, they are excellent mentors, and they are often creative. All of these qualities usually make them more successful entrepreneurs, though they may not be that good in roles where there is less space for creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving success with dyslexia is perhaps about learning different skills, mastering different approaches to solving the tasks, and developing strategies to compensate for certain limitations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habib, M. (2000) The neurological basis of developmental dyslexia: An overview and working hypothesis. &lt;em&gt;Brain&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;123&lt;/em&gt;(12), 2373–2399. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/123.12.2373&quot;&gt;10.1093/brain/123.12.2373&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke, R., Scallan, S., Mann, R., &amp;amp; Alexander, G. (2015) Clinicians with dyslexia: a systematic review of effects and strategies. &lt;em&gt;The Clinical Teacher&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;12&lt;/em&gt;(6), 394–398. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/tct.12331&quot;&gt;10.1111/tct.12331&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logan, J. (2009) Dyslexic entrepreneurs: the incidence; their coping strategies and their business skills. &lt;em&gt;Dyslexia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;15&lt;/em&gt;(4), 328–346. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/dys.388&quot;&gt;10.1002/dys.388&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logan, J. (2018) Analysis of the incidence of dyslexia in entrepreneurs and its implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toffalini, E., Pezzuti, L., &amp;amp; Cornoldi, C. (2017) Einstein and dyslexia: Is giftedness more frequent in children with a specific learning disorder than in typically developing children? &lt;em&gt;Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;62&lt;/em&gt;, 175–179. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intell.2017.04.006&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.intell.2017.04.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yu, X., Zuk, J., &amp;amp; Gaab, N. What Factors Facilitate Resilience in Developmental Dyslexia? Examining Protective and Compensatory Mechanisms Across the Neurodevelopmental Trajectory. &lt;em&gt;Child Development Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;0&lt;/em&gt;(0). &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/cdep.12293&quot;&gt;10.1111/cdep.12293&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 14:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How to help your toddler be helpful (with caveats)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/help-toddler-kids-social-skills</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/help-toddler-kids-social-skills</link>
	<description>Even very young toddlers like to help, a social skill that’s linked to later success in school and life.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/061918_RE_helping_feat.jpg?itok=9uAeIgWx" length="32503" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: ICTP - ICTP Cancels Elsevier Subscription</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ictp.it/about-ictp/media-centre/news/2018/6/elsevier.aspx</guid>
	<link>https://www.ictp.it/about-ictp/media-centre/news/2018/6/elsevier.aspx</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;ICTP [&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;International Centre for Theoretical Physics] &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;has decided to cancel its subscription to Elsevier's bundle of science journals after negotiations with the publisher failed to produce an acceptable solution for the Centre.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The growing costs of the contract, which has been in effect since 2001, did not represent a good value for money, according to ICTP Director Fernando Quevedo, who made the decision after lengthy discussions with ICTP scientists.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;ICTP remains committed to offering the highest level of research support to its scientists, many of whom come from countries that lack resources such as access to top science journals,&quot; he said. However, he added, the costs of the subscription contract with Elsevier were becoming unsustainable, and negotiations with the publisher failed to produce a satisfactory result. &quot;The proposed new contract did not allow the flexibility that a relatively small institute like ICTP requires to strategically distribute its budget,&quot; explained Quevedo.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Quevedo assured the ICTP community that the Centre, through its Marie Curie Library, would do its best to minimize the impact of the Elsevier cancellation. He noted that ICTP will keep post-termination access rights to 53 journals that it has historically subscribed to, for contents published between 1995 and 2017.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scientists with further questions can contact the Marie Curie Library information desk. The Library has prepared a web page listing alternative, legal, full-text sources for science papers. Scientists can also use the Library's document delivery service to request papers. The Library will monitor the trend of requests to measure the effects of the Elsevier cancellation. Any comments/suggestions are welcome.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Science institutes and universities around the world have been steadily staging revolts against the high costs of large publishers' bundled journal packages by cancelling their subscriptions. The Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition (SPARC), which advocates for open access to research output, tracks these cancellations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Scottish Open Data – how do we get there? – Codethecity Studio</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://codethecity.co.uk/2018/06/19/scottish-open-data-how-do-we-get-there/</guid>
	<link>https://codethecity.co.uk/2018/06/19/scottish-open-data-how-do-we-get-there/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is an oft-repeated joke in which a tourist, completely lost in the Irish countryside, asks an old fellow who is leaning on a gate at the edge of a field, “Can you tell me how to get to Dublin?” After a long pause, the old guy replies, “Well, you don’t want to start from here”. Previously, I covered open data in Scotland from 2010 to the present. Now I look ahead, but to get there we need to start from where we currently find ourselves. Scottish open data publishing – now Earlier this week I spent a couple of hours pulling this list together as a first snapshot of the current open data publishing landscape. The intention is to present an accurate precis of the current state, within the available time to do the research. If I have missed anything, or got it wrong, let me know and I will fix it. There have been sporadic attempts – of varying size, cost, and success – to make Scottish open data available. How these were initiated or funded varies. Examples include bodies such as Nesta, individual local authorities, groups such as the Scottish Cities Alliance (SCA), and by the Scottish Government....&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: CHeLabS | CinqueColonne.it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.cinquecolonne.it/chelabs.html</guid>
	<link>http://www.cinquecolonne.it/chelabs.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;[Google Translate] CHeLabS [Cultural Heritage Open Laboratory System]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaboration of some CNR, Insean - Itabc - Ism Institutes, and some partnerships at national level, including the International Council on monuments and sites and the International Universitat de Vic - Universitat Central de Catalunya, have launched the first official initiative within the CHeLabS (Cultural Heritage Open Laboratory System) project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CHeLabS was born as a contribution to the award winning project Cnr/MIUR SM@RTINFRA-SSHCH, with the aim of promoting research and innovation in the protection of cultural heritage, through a model of inclusive and participatory territorial system based on the principles of Open Access and sharing. Cultural heritage is at the heart of this vision, becoming a place of dynamic integration between people, experiences and specialisations. This multidisciplinary context calls for a constant dialogue between the plurality of knowledge, as well as an overall culture, bearers of dynamics that generate creativity and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: How green is our valley?: five-year study of selected LIS journals from Taylor &amp; Francis for green deposit of articles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://insights.uksg.org/article/10.1629/uksg.406/</guid>
	<link>https://insights.uksg.org/article/10.1629/uksg.406/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:  This study reviews content from five different library and information science journals: Behavioral &amp;amp; Social Sciences Librarian, Collection Management, College &amp;amp; Undergraduate Libraries, Journal of Electronic Resources Librarianship and Journal of Library Administration over a five-year period from 2012–2016 to investigate the green deposit rate. Starting in 2011, Taylor &amp;amp; Francis, the publisher of these journals, waived the green deposit embargo for library and information science, heritage and archival content, which allows for immediate deposit of articles in these fields. The review looks at research articles and standing columns over the five years from these five journals to see if any articles were retrieved using the OA Button or through institutional repositories. Results indicate that less than a quarter of writers have chosen to make a green deposit of their articles in local or subject repositories. The discussion outlines some best practices to be undertaken by librarians, editors and Taylor &amp;amp; Francis to make this program more successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A misconduct probe — which led to 20 retraction requests — took four years. Why?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66964</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/20/a-misconduct-probe-which-led-to-20-retraction-requests-took-four-years-why/</link>
	<description>A probe into the work of a researcher who studied natural products for cancer had many stops and starts along the way — including five extensions granted by the U.S. Office of Research Integrity — according to documents obtained by Retraction Watch. Following a public records request, we recently obtained a copy of the report … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/20/a-misconduct-probe-which-led-to-20-retraction-requests-took-four-years-why/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;A misconduct probe — which led to 20 retraction requests — took four years. Why?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: La riforma Ue sul copyright online potrebbe davvero distruggere Internet per come lo conosciamo?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.corriere.it/tecnologia/cards/riforma-ue-copyright-online-potrebbe-davvero-distruggere-internet-come-conosciamo/votazione-commissione-giuridica-parlamento-europeo_principale.shtml</guid>
	<link>https://www.corriere.it/tecnologia/cards/riforma-ue-copyright-online-potrebbe-davvero-distruggere-internet-come-conosciamo/votazione-commissione-giuridica-parlamento-europeo_principale.shtml</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;[Google translate] Could the EU reform of online copyright really destroy the Internet as we know it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text is currently being submitted to the Legal Affairs Committee of the European Parliament. Many believe that its adoption would be a blow to freedom of expression. Charging in particular Articles 11 and 13&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European project to reform online copyright continues on its path through the long series of votes required to obtain its final approval. The text is about to be voted on by the Legal Affairs Committee of the European Parliament, which is examining it starting today, 20 June. This is an important step, because - as Saverio Cavalcanti, of the law firm Dentons, explains - &quot;often the position of the European Parliament reflects that of the Committee on Legal Affairs, even if the next steps remain (in particular, the vote of the EU Council)&quot;. The appeal signed last April by 147 organisations to the ambassadors of the Member States of the Union not to rush the debate and not to give the Bulgarian Presidency a mandate to negotiate with Parliament has not served any purpose. Some have even suggested that the reform - proposed in 2016 by the then EU Commissioner for Digital Economy Günther Oettinger - could &quot;destroy the Internet as we know it&quot;. According to a group of MEPs represented by Julia Reda, European Parliament rapporteur for the copyright reform dossier and member of the German Pirate Party, &quot;the project restricts freedom of expression online and makes it difficult for small publishers and innovative startups. It should also be noted that legislation may limit the use of text &amp;amp; data mining. And to think that the Commission text, which is the result of a series of public consultations, was created to address and resolve some elements of imbalance in the digital market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open Access and Impact of Research Infrastructures » Blog Archive » AREA Science Park</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.areasciencepark.it/events/open-access-and-impact-of-research-infrastructures/</guid>
	<link>https://www.areasciencepark.it/events/open-access-and-impact-of-research-infrastructures/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;[Google Translate] Open Access and Impact of Research Infrastructures  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Google Translate] The impact, access and future perspectives of research infrastractures (RIs) in Trieste and Eastern Europe  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday 18 and Tuesday 19 June will be the first major proESOF event dedicated to European research infrastructures &quot;Towards ESOF2020 Trieste European City of Science Open Access and Impact of Research Infrastructures&quot;. The event will also deal with the infrastructure necessary for the transition to a &quot;low carbon economy&quot; and renewable energy. The first day will be an event dedicated to experts in the field to be held in Porto Vecchio while Tuesday, June 19 the event will be open to the public and will be held from 9 am to 4.45 pm at the Hydrodynamic Station, Porto Vecchio. Bruno della Vedova, Vice President of Fit and Head of the Scientific Programme of Esof 2020 explains: &quot;The objective of the two tables is to frame science as an integral element for understanding and addressing the fundamental issues of contemporary societies, including sustainability&quot;. &quot;The task of scientists - he continues - to analyze and propose solutions in an integrated way between countries for this two-day event will participate many researchers from the Balkans and Central and Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Each year painted lady butterflies cross the Sahara — and then go back again</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/painted-lady-butterflies-migration-sahara-africa</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/painted-lady-butterflies-migration-sahara-africa</link>
	<description>Painted ladies migrate the farthest of any butterfly.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061818_LR_butterfly-est_feat.jpg?itok=9C69m2gX" length="40491" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: New trial finds that frequent aerobic exercise reduces the hard-to-treat “negative symptoms” of schizophrenia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34066</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/20/new-trial-finds-that-frequent-aerobic-exercise-reduces-the-hard-to-treat-negative-symptoms-of-schizophrenia/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-929514508.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34067&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34067&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Vector icon of heartbeat near running man&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cardio training icon&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cardio training icon&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1748,1715&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/20/new-trial-finds-that-frequent-aerobic-exercise-reduces-the-hard-to-treat-negative-symptoms-of-schizophrenia/cardio-training-icon/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-929514508.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aerobic exercise – any activity that gets your heart pumping harder – improves &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/04/19/10-ways-that-running-changes-your-mind-and-brain/&quot;&gt;mood, anxiety and memory.&lt;/a&gt; It can help people with major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder and anxiety disorder. Now there’s evidence, from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00167/full&quot;&gt;randomised controlled trial&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;i&gt;Frontiers in Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt;, that a programme of regular aerobic exercise also reduces psychopathology in people diagnosed with schizophrenia. And it seems to have a particular impact on so-called “negative” symptoms, such as apathy and loss of emotional feeling, which are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25528757&quot;&gt;not improved by standard drug treatments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[W]hile antipsychotics [drug treatments] are essential in treating schizophrenia, interventions other than antipsychotic treatment…may be needed to achieve better outcomes,” write the authors of the new study, led by Peng-Wei Wang at Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34066&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers recruited 62 patients, all of whom had received a diagnosis of schizophrenia at least a year ago, and whose antipsychotic medication dosage had been stable for at least three months. These participants were randomly allocated into either an aerobic exercise group (30 minutes of “vigorous” aerobic exercise, taking into account each participant’s maximum heart rate) or a control group who performed stretching exercises (25 minutes of flexibility, toning and balance exercises), with a goal of five sessions a week, for 12 weeks. Not all participants managed to stick to the minimum requirement of three sessions per week for the full three months. But 24 in the exercise group and 22 in the control group did complete the study.  (There were no significant differences in gender make-up, age of onset of schizophrenia, or mean dosage of antipsychotics between the two groups.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A psychiatrist who was blind to the group allocations used a standard schizophrenia symptom evaluation scale to interview and evaluate all the participants at the start of the study; at the end of the 12 week intervention; and again, three months on. The control group showed no improvements in positive (e.g. hallucinations and delusions) or negative symptoms, or general psychopathology, during the intervention or the follow-up period. But for the aerobic exercise group, it was a different story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the 12-week intervention, their overall psychopathology and level of negative and positive symptoms decreased. Three months later, these improvements had been maintained (and, in the case of negative symptoms, actually continued to improve). Also, the more severe their negative symptoms and general psychopathology at the start of the study, the bigger their improvements by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These results imply that [aerobic exercise] could be a good non-pharmacotherapeutic intervention for antipsychotic-treated patients with schizophrenia,” the researchers conclude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various possible explanations for the effects. Vigorous exercise can boost levels of the neurotransmitter glutamate (other work has found that enhancing glutamate function can improve negative symptoms of schizophrenia); increase levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (which is involved in repairing damaged brain cells and triggering the growth of new ones; low levels of BDNF are associated with symptoms of schizophrenia); and also help regulate the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis – the stress response system. “HPA dysfunction is an important characteristic in schizophrenia,” the authors note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But is a one-off 12-week programme really enough to produce lasting – and even escalating – improvements?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers did not collect data on how much exercise the aerobic group did in the three months between the end of the 12-week intervention and the final assessment. If the participants continued to exercise, this may have accounted for the ongoing improvements. Future research will have to explore this. But if an exercise programme does have to be maintained, given all the manifold benefits, surely that’s no bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00167/full?utm_source=F-AAE&amp;amp;utm_medium=EMLF&amp;amp;utm_campaign=MRK_648100_68_Psychi_20180522_arts_A&quot;&gt;Effect of Aerobic Exercise on Improving Symptoms of Individuals With Schizophrenia: A Single Blinded Randomized Control Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 08:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How Gender Summits have shaped Elsevier’s role in the research community</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-gender-summits-have-shaped-elseviers-role-in-the-research-community</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-gender-summits-have-shaped-elseviers-role-in-the-research-community</link>
	<description>Elsevier CEO Ron Mobed talks about the importance of gender diversity in science</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 07:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: With this new system, robots can ‘read’ your mind</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-brain-waves-read-your-mind</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/robots-brain-waves-read-your-mind</link>
	<description>Giving robots instructions via brain waves and hand gestures could help the machines operate more safely and efficiently.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 04:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061918_MT_robot-mind-control_feat.jpg?itok=zcnhBGdi" length="28730" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Workshop &quot;POLLI:BRIGHT&quot;. La citizen science e la Notte dei Ricercatori | Università degli Studi di Siena</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unisi.it/unisilife/eventi/workshop-pollibright-la-citizen-science-e-la-notte-dei-ricercatori</guid>
	<link>https://www.unisi.it/unisilife/eventi/workshop-pollibright-la-citizen-science-e-la-notte-dei-ricercatori</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
p.p1 {margin: 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px 0.0px; font: 12.0px 'Helvetica Neue'; color: #454545}

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Google translate] Citizen science meets the researcher's night: a promising partnership. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concepts of &quot;open science&quot;, &quot;participatory research&quot; and &quot;science&quot; have recently become more and more established. (citizen science) which refer to new ways of carrying out research in many fields, from ecology to social sciences, climatology and astronomy, from neuroscience to medicine, and information technology. Although the first experiences of citizen science date back to the mid-nineteenth century, today, thanks to the new digital technologies, citizen science is increasingly establishing itself as an approach that can provide effective monitoring systems and increasingly important research tools.  Not least the role of the citizen science in public engagement and participatory teaching. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar, of a scientific and operational nature, will be the occasion to introduce the topic of citizen science and explore new partnerships both for the Siena University and with other Tuscan universities and secondary and high schools.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 03:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: To combat an expanding universe, aliens could hoard stars</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-expanding-universe-aliens-could-hoard-stars</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/combat-expanding-universe-aliens-could-hoard-stars</link>
	<description>An advanced alien civilization might combat the impact of dark energy by harvesting stars.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061918_EC_aliens-cosmic-preppers_feat.jpg?itok=QEYyGGg4" length="41946" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Unlocking the Potential of OERs in Gateway Courses: A Case Study – Bronx EdTech Showcase</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://commons.hostos.cuny.edu/bronxedtech/2018/06/18/unlocking-the-potential-of-oers-in-gateway-courses-a-case-study/</guid>
	<link>http://commons.hostos.cuny.edu/bronxedtech/2018/06/18/unlocking-the-potential-of-oers-in-gateway-courses-a-case-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The amount of money students spend on textbooks has led to a contentious debate on better methods of the use of textbooks in courses. Clearly, many students are simply not purchasing required materials and/or they fail to factor in the textbook costs when deciding whether or not to take a class.  For CUNY faculty, this is both a challenge and an opportunity.  Many CUNY students are from the most economically challenged county in America (Bronx) and studying in the most expensive city in America (New York). For many students, even an older edition of a book is a stretch. Open Educational Resources (OERs) aim to make it easier on students’ wallets by making textbook-free courses.Hostos students will lead the workshop by describing their experiences using Lumen’s Waymaker for Introduction to Sociology in the Fall of 2017.  Then, data will be presented to compare OER sections with non-OER sections.  Since the OER was utilized in a section with all ESL students and a hybrid section, the OER sections will be compared to similar sections from other semesters in which a traditional textbook was part of required course materials.  Data comparing retention, course and exam in addition to student feedback will be included in the presentation and other variables (i.e. demographics, teaching interventions, Supplemental Instruction Peer Leaders, and modality) will also be considered. A brief show-and-tell will guide the audience through several elements of specifics of the data that was gathered during the semester.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Community call: Open source technology development for science communications and publishing | Events | eLife</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://elifesciences.org/events/08b40301/community-call-open-source-technology-development-for-science-communications-and-publishing</guid>
	<link>https://elifesciences.org/events/08b40301/community-call-open-source-technology-development-for-science-communications-and-publishing</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Users and developers of emerging technology for publishing are invited to share, learn and collaborate in an open call.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: 2a Jornada RCUB per a editors de revistes cientifiques de la UB | Blog CRAI Universitat de Barcelona</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://blogcrai.ub.edu/2018/06/19/2a-jornada-rcub-per-a-editors-de-revistes-cientifiques-de-la-ub/</guid>
	<link>https://blogcrai.ub.edu/2018/06/19/2a-jornada-rcub-per-a-editors-de-revistes-cientifiques-de-la-ub/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): 2nd RCUB day for publishers of scientific journals at the UB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;El Dr. Ernest Abadal ha dictat la conferència titulada Els reptes de les revistes científiques, on ha volgut remarcar d’on venim (dels anys de la digitalització i de l’accés obert) i on som: a l’era de la ciència oberta amb un full de ruta molt clar: Horitzó 2020 (H2020) el Programa Marc de la Comissió Europea per a la recerca i la innovació on hi brinden valors com la transparència, la cooperació i l’efectivitat.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;Dr. Ernest Abadal has given the conference entitled The Challenges of Scientific Journals , where he wanted to emphasize where we came from (from the years of digitization and open access) and where we are: in the era of open science with a sheet very clear route: Horizon 2020 (H2020) the Framework Program of the European Commission for research and innovation where they provide values ​​such as transparency, cooperation and effectiveness.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open Science Toolbox</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.osc.uni-muenchen.de/toolbox/open-science-toolbox.pdf</guid>
	<link>https://www.osc.uni-muenchen.de/toolbox/open-science-toolbox.pdf</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;A Collection of Resources to Facilitate Open Science Practices&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: University of Nigeria, Nsukka Open Education Resources (OER) |authorSTREAM</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.authorstream.com/Presentation/locosseminaq-3476703-university-nigeria-nsukka-open-education-resources-oer/</guid>
	<link>http://www.authorstream.com/Presentation/locosseminaq-3476703-university-nigeria-nsukka-open-education-resources-oer/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;University of Nigeria is an Open Educational Resources (OER). We provide online educational material or resources for teaching and learning. Here you can find learning resources such as Lecture Notes, Journal Articles, Books, Courseware, Reports, Thesis &amp;amp; Dissertations. Search here over 2,727 free and open educational resources.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Sportwissenschaftler der Universität in Koblenz mit Award geehrt | Der Metternicher</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://der-metternicher.de/2018/06/sportwissenschaftler-der-universitaet-in-koblenz-mit-award-geehrt/</guid>
	<link>https://der-metternicher.de/2018/06/sportwissenschaftler-der-universitaet-in-koblenz-mit-award-geehrt/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title translation: Sports scientist of the University of Koblenz honored with award | The Metternicher&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Für das Projekt KNSU – „KompetenzNetzwerk SportUnterricht“, geleitet von Dr. Marlis Minnich vom Institut für Sportwissenschaften und Institut für Wissensmedien der Universität Koblenz-Landau, wurde mit dem OER Award RLP 2018 ausgezeichnet. Unter mehreren nominierten Projekten erzielte es den 1. Platz im Bereich „Hochschulbildung“. Prof. Dr. Konrad Wolf, rheinland-pfälzischer Minister für Wissenschaft, Weiterbildung und Kultur, unterstützte den Award neben Bildungsministerin Dr. Stefanie Hubig als Schirmherr, ehrte die Gewinner mit einer Laudatio und überreichte ihnen Urkunden wie auch Schecks über das Preisgeld von jeweils 1.000 Euro.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): For the project KNSU - &quot;CompetenceNetwork SportTeaching&quot;, headed by Dr. med. Marlis Minnich from the Institute of Sports Science and the Institute of Knowledge Media at the University of Koblenz-Landau has been awarded the OER Award RLP 2018. Among several nominated projects, it took 1st place in the field of higher education. Prof. Dr. Konrad Wolf, Rhineland-Palatinate Minister for Science, Further Education and Culture, supported the award alongside Minister of Education Dr. Ing. Stefanie Hubig as patron, honored the winners with a laudatory speech and handed them certificates as well as checks on the prize money of 1,000 euros each.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: RIED: REUNI+D: una red universitaria para la construcción colaborativa de conocimiento</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://blogderied.blogspot.com/2018/06/reunid-una-red-universitaria-para-la.html</guid>
	<link>https://blogderied.blogspot.com/2018/06/reunid-una-red-universitaria-para-la.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;English Translation: &quot;RIED: REUNI + D: a University Network for the Collaborative Construction of Knowledge&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;El movimiento educativo abierto hace referencia al software libre, la formación y los contenidos abiertos o accesibles y la ciencia abierta, considerando la educación como un derecho de todos y un motor de desarrollo social que debe tender a incentivar la construcción y diseminación universal del conocimiento. Con esta finalidad, se construye una Red de Grupos de Investigación consolidados denominada REUNI+D (Red Universitaria de Investigación e Innovación Educativa) (Ref. EDU2014-54943-REDT) que pretende promover, de forma coordinada, acciones de formación abierta y difundir los resultados de investigación e innovación educativa considerando los criterios de la ciencia abierta.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation: &quot;The open educational movement refers to free software, education and open content and open science, considering education as a right of all and an engine of social development that should offer an incentive for the construction and universal formulation of knowledge. The Network of Consolidated Research Groups REUNI + D (Ref. EDU2014-54943-REDT) was created to promote, in a coordinated manner, open training actions, and to disseminate research results and educational innovation considering the criteria of the open science.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: On Jupiter, lightning flashes from storms swirling at the poles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-lightning-flashes-storms-swirling-poles</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/jupiter-lightning-flashes-storms-swirling-poles</link>
	<description>After almost 40 years, scientists have discovered that Jupiter has lightning that is similar to lightning on Earth — it just happens in a different place.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060818_LR_notebook-jupter-lightning_feat.jpg?itok=eRWozHki" length="12706" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Interactive Education and OER – LibraryBuzz</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://library.citytech.cuny.edu/blog/interactive-education-and-oer/</guid>
	<link>https://library.citytech.cuny.edu/blog/interactive-education-and-oer/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;In our blog post series, we’ve explored how OER offer an alternative to high textbook costs, rely on Creative Commons licenses to enable sharing/distribution, and represent an educational trend that is spreading across CUNY  and beyond.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: The Evidence that Open Government Data Improves Developing Economies - ICTworks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ictworks.org/the-evidence-that-open-government-data-improves-developing-economies/</guid>
	<link>https://www.ictworks.org/the-evidence-that-open-government-data-improves-developing-economies/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;In 2009, the United States launched the data.gov portal. Since then there has been a rapid increase in the systematic opening of government data around the world. The 2016 Open Data Barometer, published annually by the World Wide Web Foundation, found that 79 of the 115 countries surveyed had official open data initiatives. Similarly, as part of the Open Government Partnership, some 70 countries have now issued National Action Plans, the majority of which contain strong open data commitments designed to foster greater transparency, generate economic growth, empower citizens, fight corruption, and more generally enhance governance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: SMC Partners with OpenStax to Increase Use of Free Textbooks on Campus</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.smc.edu/NewsRoom/Pages/OpenStax.aspx</guid>
	<link>https://www.smc.edu/NewsRoom/Pages/OpenStax.aspx</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;SMC was chosen after a rigorous application process that included demonstrating willingness to drive adoption of open educational resources (OER): a total of 31 institutions applied. The selected colleges and universities will receive individualized consulting from OpenStax—an initiative of Rice University and supported by philanthropic foundations including the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Michelson 20MM Foundation, Google Inc., among others—and join a cohort of schools advocating widespread use of OER at their schools. The 2016-2017 cohort of partner schools saw a 150 percent increase in student use of OER in the 2017-2018 academic year, saving an additional 50,000 students $4.9 million.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: ISKME Names New Board Chair and Expands Board With Higher Education Data Expert - Press Release - Digital Journal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/3820688</guid>
	<link>http://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/3820688</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;As the open educational resources (OER) movement to advance equitable access to high quality education gains a stronger foothold in states, schools, and colleges, the Institute for the Study of Knowledge Management in Education (ISKME) is helping shape the infrastructure and engagement to make this possible. ISKME manages OER Commons, the nation's digital library of record for OER, partnering with states and education institutions in both K-12 and higher education to develop their own collections of openly licensed teaching and learning materials tied to standards, curated by teams of teachers, librarians, and curriculum specialists. ISKME trains educators in the practice of open education, and is leading the way in developing needed infrastructure for OER expansion through metadata sharing and development of authoring tools to support communities of practice in schools, colleges, and library systems.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: FAO - News Article: FAO launches Open Access for all publications</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.fao.org/news/story/en/item/1141504/icode/</guid>
	<link>http://www.fao.org/news/story/en/item/1141504/icode/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;As of today, FAO will implement an Open Access policy, enabling maximal reach and ease of use for FAO knowledge products. FAO has been disseminating knowledge since its foundation in 1945, and its publications have been freely accessible in the FAO online Document Repository since 1998. The new Open Access policy goes a step further; not only ensuring that FAO's wealth of knowledge remains easily accessible to users around the world, but actively encouraging and providing a framework for the broader use, reproduction and dissemination of this material.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Utrecht University - Research Data Manager: building towards Open Science (0.9 - 1.0 FTE) - Dutch Techcentre for Life Sciences</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dtls.nl/jobs/utrecht-university-research-data-manager-building-towards-open-science-0-9-1-0-fte/</guid>
	<link>https://www.dtls.nl/jobs/utrecht-university-research-data-manager-building-towards-open-science-0-9-1-0-fte/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;We are looking for a Data Manager (for research data) to further expand the Research Data Management team at the University Library (UB). Besides this position we also have two positions for a Consultant Research Data Management. The data manager will be involved in large-scale research projects or will work on a more general level at our faculties. As a data manager you work on datamanagement issues during every phase of the data cycle. You play a crucial role in securing the quality of research data in all its manifestations, in this way enabling optimal use and reuse of the data. On a detailed level, you work on complex data(processing) issues, and, if necessary, give your input to improve processes or systems. You assist researchers in the planning of collecting, managing and publishing data, both in new or ongoing projects. You are co-responsible for creating your own assignments, and preferably work on two or three assignments at the same time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Together We Witnessed History At #BIO2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1585</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/together-we-witnessed-history-at-bio2018/</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1585&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-937dd8a elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;937dd8a&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-98579d1 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;98579d1&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-85ef566 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;85ef566&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The theme of this year’s BIO International Convention was “Make History”, and it did just that&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; The event, hosting over 1,800 exhibitors and thousands of speakers, drew over 18,289 global attendees and facilitated more than 46,000 one-on-one meetings during its 4-day duration (setting a Guinness World Record for “The Largest Business Partnering Event”). BIO attracted companies, academic centers, patient groups, researchers, investors, and even celebrities such as cancer survivor and award-winning journalist Robin Roberts as well as director, actor, and advocate Rob Reiner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We had the honor of participating in this historic conference, and so we’d like to share select highlights with you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;KEYNOTE SPEECHES &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;I believe in dreaming big and focusing small ~ great words to live by. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RobinRoberts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@RobinRoberts&lt;/a&gt; BIOConvention &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JimGreenwood?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@JimGreenwood&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/bio2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#bio2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/x2VsBiJS35&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/x2VsBiJS35&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;— Jennifer Landress (@jlandress) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jlandress/status/1004002670661853184?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 5, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tweet capturing the Robin Roberts’ interview with BIO’s chief Jim Greenwood&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Robin Roberts, ABC’s Good Morning America journalist, kicked off BIO. She discussed her triumphant victory over cancer and her trailblazing career in journalism during her interview with BIO president and chief executive officer Jim Greenwood.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;She also acknowledged how the collective work of people such as those attending BIO is the reason she is alive today.“This is the importance of why I want to meet with this group, to say thank you for the life-saving bone marrow transplant that I had,” she said, “It’s not about what we accomplish, it’s about what we overcome.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Roberts also noted in her conversation with Greenwood, that she believed “in dreaming big and focusing small.” In other words, accomplishing great things takes time; Rome wasn’t built in a day, as the saying goes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Actor/Director Rob Reiner to address Bio Int. Conv. about his son overcoming battle w/addiction &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/t3jAFpkYjN&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/t3jAFpkYjN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;— Doug Cope (@dcopewbz) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dcopewbz/status/1004362448625963009?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tweet showing Reiner’s interview with BIO’s chief Jim Greenwood&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Another keynote speaker was well-known actor and director Rob Reiner. Reiner urged the audience to continue working on drug research. He also shared a personal story about his son overcoming drug addiction and said, “We have a long way to go in trying to understand what causes people to want to use and how to treat them. There is no question about it; it’s an epidemic. I mean it’s rife across this country…people talk about doing something and don’t do anything about it.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;ANNOUNCEMENT &amp;amp; AWARDS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;BIO has become a launching platform for new partnerships, ventures, and awards. To illustrate, U.S. Health and Human Services (HHS) unveiled a new initiative called DRIVe (Division of Research, Innovation, and Ventures) to come up with new solutions to some of the toughest health security challenges we are faced with such as early detection of illness and sepsis. Another announcement that caught everyone’s attention was a five-year alliance between Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson (J&amp;amp;J) and Boston University – an attempt to change the way we detect and treat lung cancer today. J&amp;amp;J will fund a Lung Cancer Center at Boston University Medical Center as part of this new alliance. Just as important, the Henri A. Termeer Biotechnology Visionary Award was given to Dr. Sue Desmond-Hellmann, CEO of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, for the innovative spirit and transformative impact on patients’ lives. This is the first-ever award created in honor of the late Genzyme CEO who was instrumental in transforming Boston into a thriving hub of life science research, development and innovation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;WORLD AT BIO&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Thousands of attendees from over 74 different countries &lt;/span&gt;participated in&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; the event, and most of the essential biotech hubs and nations had a presence in the form of pavilions and summits at the event. For example, a “conference-within-a-conference” called the China Summit was one of the country-specific meetings at BIO which highlighted the complexities of the world’s second-largest biotech market, and among other vital issues focused on the importance of collaboration between U.S. and China in the scientific research and business.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Great turnout at the China Summit at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BIO2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BIO2018&lt;/a&gt; – great timing too given news flow like CStone/Blueprint deal &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%24BPMC&amp;amp;src=ctag&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;$BPMC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ST1PnJjCsJ&quot;&gt;https://t.co/ST1PnJjCsJ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/sq13t1Gpxw&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/sq13t1Gpxw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;— Josh Berlin (@BioPharmaJosh) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BioPharmaJosh/status/1003683091515396102?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 4, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tweet gives a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;glimpse of the China Summit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Canada’s presence at BIO couldn’t be ignored &lt;/span&gt;either.&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Economic development and tech transfer teams, businesses, scientists, and government officials from The Great White North were seen everywhere. A prominent Canadian politician from Nova Scotia even gave a forward-looking speech on the future of Canada’s bioeconomy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Challenging &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BIOConvention?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@BIOConvention&lt;/a&gt; delegates to a game &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BIO2018?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#BIO2018&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/bio2018cdn?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#bio2018cdn&lt;/a&gt; visit booth #651. See you soon &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/UK7BMeXgGg&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UK7BMeXgGg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;— BIOTECanada (@BIOTECanada) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BIOTECanada/status/1004429860964425728?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tweet showing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;an &lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ice hockey game at the Canada Pavilion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;UNCONVENTIONAL BIOTECH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Medical Research Institute (MRI), the new, unconventional biotech startup that operates independently of profits and investors, was introduced at the BIO International Convention by Dr. Penny Heaton, the institute’s CEO. The organization is a non-profit spinoff of the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation — the world’s wealthiest charity. Dr. Penny Heaton described the mission and approach of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Medical Research Institute and discussed the roles of both organizations and their strategies to combat infectious diseases globally. MRI aims to develop products that will potentially eradicate diarrheal disease and end the TB epidemic.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;PARTY AT BIO&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Although we didn’t attend the over-the-top party called&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fiercebiotech.com/biotech/unofficial-party-at-bio-featured-dancers-plastered-company-logos-outraging-leadership&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;PABNAB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, our team had a great time interacting with our customers and partners at BIO.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;team-science-exchange&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-1586 size-large aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;852&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/image1-769x1024.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Team Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;FDA at BIO&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The world’s most powerful regulator, Scott Gottlieb, was also present. During the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fireside Chats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;BIO 2018,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; the FDA commissioner expressed his thoughts on developing lower-cost generics and biosimilars. He also shed light on other things such as gene therapy, the opioid crisis, more opportunities for patients, and the new Right to Try law.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPOTTED INNOVATIONS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Many innovative technologies and businesses also caught our attention. To illustrate, innovations like real-time patient monitoring, video collaboration tools, 3D cell cultures, AI-enabled knowledge databases, microfluidic platforms, virtual reality 3D molecular visualization, and new inventive liquid biopsy technologies were big head-turners at the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In addition, we learned about new innovative initiatives by biotech companies, big and small alike. One such company is Recombinetics; they employ gene-editing technology not just to improve human health but also to improve the health, well-being and productivity of animals. The company’s gene-editing technology can potentially be used to create animals with welfare traits, such as pigs that don’t need to be castrated, hornless cattle, heat-tolerant livestock and other disease-resistant animals.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Another example is Alnylam Pharmaceuticals. In his “Bio Buzz” Interview, John Maraganore, the company’s CEO, talked about an entirely new class of medicines derived from the Nobel Prize-winning discovery of advances in RNA interference (RNAi). With investigational RNAi therapeutics, it is possible to block the production of disease-causing proteins. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Just as important, Amgen shared its approach to treating migraines. The company believes a new method of theirs can treat a problem that affects nearly one billion people across the globe – migraines!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you couldn’t attend, we hope our coverage of this year’s BIO convention gave you a sense of its scale, history and importance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 15:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Neurotic folk spend more time doing chores</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34060</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-183807870.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34061&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34061&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;she is tired of doing all the houseworkFOR MORE IMAGES IN THIS SERIES, PLEASE VISIT OUR LIGHTBOX:\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1300720051&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;OrangeDukeProductions&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;38&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman wants to pull out her hair..&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woman wants to pull out her hair..&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1824,1644&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/woman-wants-to-pull-out-her-hair/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-183807870.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If personality traits are a genuine concept and not merely an artefact of psychologists’ imagination, then how people choose to spend their time ought to correlate with their scores on personality questionnaires, notwithstanding the constraints of life that prevent us from doing what we want. In fact, there are relatively few studies that have looked at correlations between traits and everyday behaviour, and of those that have, many relied on student volunteers (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20170518-the-everyday-habits-that-reveal-our-personalities&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for an overview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published earlier this year in &lt;em&gt;Collabra&lt;/em&gt; helps plug this research gap – Julia Rohrer and Richard Lucas analysed the “Big Five” trait personality scores of over 1,300 German volunteers (part of a nationally representative sample), average age 51 years, who on three successive years completed detailed diaries of what they had been up to the day before. Specifically, they indicated whether they had spent any time, and if so how much, on nine key activities the previous day, including socialising, work, chores and watching TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34060&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings, controlling for age and gender, will mostly make comfortable reading for personality psychologists. For instance, consistent with trait theory, high scorers on conscientiousness spent more time working and studying, whether they were full-time employed or not. Similarly, strong extraverts, the highly agreeable and open-minded were more likely to report socialising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few other findings are more nuanced and intriguing. For instance, the highly conscientiousness were no more or less likely to report watching TV the previous day, but they reported watching it for less time. Meanwhile, extraversion, emotional stability, agreeableness and conscientiousness all went together with less time spent reading. In contrast, openness to experience was correlated with reading, and a trend toward reading for longer. Openness also correlated with time spent playing sports. Cultural activities, which typically correlate with openness, were not assessed in this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-105&quot; style=&quot;width: 2238px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 14.52.53.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34062&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34062&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 14.52.53&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2238,1352&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/neurotic-folk-spend-more-time-doing-chores/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-14-52-53.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;Rohrer and Lucas 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intriguing findings concerned chores – against trait theory, the highly conscientiousness were no more likely to say they’d spent time on chores (even though orderliness is a key facet of conscientiousness), perhaps because they had everything in order already, whereas the highly neurotic (i.e. people with low emotional stability who typically experience more low moods) were more likely to say they’d done some chores the previous day, and for longer. Again it’s speculation, but perhaps this is because the emotionally unstable find disorder and clutter more upsetting, while at the same time not necessarily being particularly adept at keeping order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a trend toward agreeableness correlating with doing chores. This chimes with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886917303094&quot;&gt;previous study&lt;/a&gt; that found, more specifically, that agreeableness correlated with spending more time ironing and washing up. The likely explanation in both cases is that highly agreeable people are more concerned with doing things that benefit others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach of asking people whether they’d performed an activity at all, and if so, for how long, also threw up some interesting contradictions. For instance, high scorers on openness were more likely to report socialising, yet at the same time, they tended to report doing so for less time than low scorers, perhaps because they had so many other competing demands on their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main weakness of this new data is its reliance (as in so much personality research) on people’s self-reports of their traits and behaviour, and the memory challenge for them of recalling what they’d been doing the previous day and for how long. Nonetheless, the findings serve to complement similar efforts using different approaches. “Our study suggests that even under the constraints of everyday life, personality shows modest [effect sizes were in the range of .1 to .2] but meaningful associations with daily patterns,” Rohrer and Lucas concluded. “Personality therefore qualifies as a real-world phenomenon, exerting its influence beyond the context of the research laboratory and allowing for strong descriptions of human life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.collabra.org/articles/10.1525/collabra.112/&quot;&gt;Only so Many Hours: Correlations between Personality and Daily Time Use in a Representative German Panel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 7 ways you can use our SDG Resource Centre</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/7-ways-you-can-use-our-sdg-resource-centre</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/7-ways-you-can-use-our-sdg-resource-centre</link>
	<description>Interactive platform by RELX Group lets you find news, research and reports on sustainable development around the world</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 13:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Madagascar’s predators are probably vulnerable to toxic toads</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/madagascar-invasive-asian-common-toads-predators-toxin</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/madagascar-invasive-asian-common-toads-predators-toxin</link>
	<description>The Asian common toad, an invasive species in Madagascar, produces a toxin in its skin that’s probably toxic to most of the island’s predators.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/061818_SZ_toads-wild-things_feat.jpg?itok=NLnZeZR4" length="27748" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Fecal transplant paper pulled for “personal issue”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66721</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/19/fecal-transplant-paper-pulled-for-personal-issue/</link>
	<description>Last month, the Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition pulled an article on fecal transplantation for a reason that, well, doesn’t pass the sniff test. The paper, by Sonia Michail of Children’s Hospital Los Angeles, appeared online in October 2017 and described a randomized controlled trial of fecal transplants to treat kids with ulcerative colitis. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/19/fecal-transplant-paper-pulled-for-personal-issue/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Fecal transplant paper pulled for “personal issue”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Appoints Two New Executives to Accelerate Growth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1580</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/science-exchange-appoints-two-new-executives-to-accelerate-growth/</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;elementor elementor-1580&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-inner&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-section-wrap&quot;&gt;
							&lt;section class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-575fb96 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default elementor-section elementor-top-section&quot; data-element_type=&quot;section&quot; data-id=&quot;575fb96&quot;&gt;
						&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-row&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-4335506 elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column&quot; data-element_type=&quot;column&quot; data-id=&quot;4335506&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-wrap&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-element elementor-element-2fd5b9a elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor&quot; data-element_type=&quot;text-editor.default&quot; data-id=&quot;2fd5b9a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-widget-container&quot;&gt;
					&lt;div class=&quot;elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Veteran marketing and business development executives join &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt; to help lead the company through its next phase of growth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, June 14, 2018 &lt;/b&gt;— Science Exchange, the&lt;i&gt; leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, has appointed senior team members Rob Mihalko as Vice President of Marketing and Alex Slater as Vice President of Business Development and General Manager Europe. Both executives, reporting to Science Exchange CEO Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., will add to an already talented management team that is driving industry-leading solutions to improve the quality and efficiency of scientific research around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mihalko is a leading expert in business commerce and procurement and has extensive experience in successfully implementing go-to-market strategies for business-to-business marketplaces on a global scale. As VP of Marketing, Mihalko will be responsible for Science Exchange’s worldwide marketing activities. He will lead the way in aligning Science Exchange’s brand and product positioning with global marketing programs to boost awareness, sales and adoption of the company’s industry-leading R&amp;amp;D marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Science Exchange, Mihalko was Global Vice President of Solution &amp;amp; Customer Marketing for SAP Ariba, where he led marketing and product initiatives that transformed SAP Ariba into the world’s leading procurement and business commerce company. He also has held several senior marketing, product and finance roles with leading technology companies, including Microsoft, and was a management consultant with A.T. Kearney, advising senior executives on strategy, sourcing and supply chain transformation initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m delighted to have joined such a passionate and mission-driven team at Science Exchange,” said Mihalko. “I’m looking forward to helping the company build on its leadership position in the outsourced research market and support its growth in new verticals and geographies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a VP of Business Development and General Manager Europe, Alex Slater will be spearheading Science Exchange’s continued expansion into the European market. Slater brings 23 years of business development experience within contract research organizations to Science Exchange, spanning the entirety of drug discovery, from basic research to clinical development. He has also led business development teams in Europe and Asia for Covance and, most recently, was the VP Global Business Development at Eurofins Pharma Discovery Services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his new role, Slater will provide key leadership and support of Science Exchange’s business development and expansion efforts in Europe. He will work with the global business development team to stimulate provider and researcher recruitment and expand the European support team that will give researchers the personalized scientific support they expect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“From my initial interactions with Elizabeth Iorns and the team at Science Exchange, I was impressed by their passion and commitment to simplifying researchers’ access to the services they need,” said Slater. “I look forward to working with such a driven team and helping expand the company’s European presence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We work in a rapidly changing environment, and so it’s critical for us to hire people that share our ambitious vision and have the expertise to help us execute it successfully,” said Elizabeth Iorns, CEO of Science Exchange. “I’m thrilled to be welcoming our two new team members, who each bring vast experience to Science Exchange, and I look forward to working closely with them in our mission to enable scientific breakthroughs through connections.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 10:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: New literature review warns that current sexual assault interventions might actually increase offending among high-risk men</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34047</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-178019463.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34048&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34048&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4.5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 40D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Stop rape culture&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1368553387&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;David Kam&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;30&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0005&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Stop Rape Culture&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Stop Rape Culture&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/stop-rape-culture/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-178019463.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology can help people one person at a time, but it also holds the promise of changing society at a mass scale, through campaigns to change attitudes and behaviour. One such endeavour is the development of programmes to reduce the rates of sexual assault of women on university campuses. But in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917303646&quot;&gt;literature review&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Aggression and Violent Behavior&lt;/em&gt;, researchers from the University of California make the case that such programmes may not just be ineffective, but counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34047&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 the US passed its Violence Against Women Act; in response most US university campuses launched programmes that aimed to reduce sexual assault by raising awareness, changing attitudes and behaviours and encouraging bystanders to take a stand. But there has been little systematic evaluation of these programmes, and the evidence for any benefits is thus far thin. Of the 140 college-based behaviour change programmes studied by the Center for Disease Control, it recommended only three on the balance of evidence; all three focused on changing bystander action and two of the three merely showed “promise of effectiveness”. Other reviews have produced slightly more positive conclusions but often with weak effects or without evidence of actual behaviour change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.34.50.png&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-34051 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34051&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.34.50&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845?w=374&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845?w=282&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;374,398&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-34-50.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;“Newish interventions have a thin evidence base, more work needed” is not a clamouring call for alarm, but based on their review of the field, Neil Malamuth and his team suspect there may be something worse at play: a boomerang effect.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly become clear that well-meaning interventions in other contexts can have the opposite effect to that intended; we’ve previously covered instances of backfiring interventions that aimed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/07/08/the-imagined-contact-intervention-for-reducing-prejudice-can-backfire/&quot;&gt;reduce prejudice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/02/23/the-backfire-effect-correcting-false-beliefs-about-vaccines-can-be-surprisingly-counterproductive/&quot;&gt;correct false beliefs on vaccine&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/11/pressuring-employees-to-be-do-gooders-can-backfire-badly/&quot;&gt;encourage employees to behave better in the workplace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason boomerang effects are such a concern in the domain of sexual assault is that most interventions are being designed and evaluated around a broad target group – men – rather than looking at effects on the most high-risk individuals. Yet we know from previous evidence that the people most likely to respond contrarily are those most disposed to the problem behaviour in the first place. For instance, an &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0193841X16666196&quot;&gt;intervention intended to reduce acceptance of violent video games&lt;/a&gt; in students was effective for many participants, but post-intervention, those who had been classified as living a delinquent lifestyle became more enthusiastic about playing the games.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://refhub.elsevier.com/S1359-1789(17)30364-6/rf0040&quot;&gt;Another study&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated that an anti-violence campaign was effective in increasing opposition to violence in people low in trait aggression, but those who were highly aggressive became more enthusiastic about violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boomerang effects seem to happen when participants experience reactance: anger stemming from the sense that a mode of life or thinking is threatened combined with “motivated reasoning” – like finding reasons to doubt the source of the message. In the midst of reactance, the person sees themselves as defiantly resisting preachy attempts to deny them their entitlement.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is reactance likely to happen with the men most likely to commit sexual assault? Well, consider this profile of high-risk individuals: they tend to have hostility towards women, experience sexual arousal when physical force is involved, and have an impersonal sexual orientation (intimacy is not a prerequisite for what they seek in sex). As well as these sex-related factors, they tend to be anti-social, highly entitled and narcissistic. Evidence suggests these individuals are less likely to respond to cues of sexual disinterest, feeling that women are really into them or will be eventually, and they react more aggressively to interpersonal rejection. This seems a potent recipe for reactance.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.31.14.png&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-34050 alignright&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34050&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-19 09.31.14&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845?w=370&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845?w=212&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;370,524&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/19/new-literature-review-most-sexual-assault-interventions-are-likely-to-increase-offending-among-high-risk-men/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-19-09-31-14.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;There isn’t much evidence from existing anti-sexual assault programmes on specifically how these high-risk individuals respond, but smaller-scale experimental work reveals troubling signs. Messages promoting gender equality and greater consideration for women lead to lower aggressive tendencies for men already low in sexist attitudes, but more aggression among those who held more sexist attitudes from the start. A video intended to reduce acceptance of rape myths and increase victim empathy worked for men who had no history of sexually aggressive behaviour, but the high-risk men showed a boomerang effect. On the other hand, some experimental studies have shown some intervention content can have the desired effect on high-risk individuals, e.g. improving victim empathy. But if you hit the target on some occasions, and shoot yourself in the foot on others, you would want to take a good look at your technique before rolling it out nationwide.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger is that interventions could produce impressive-seeming results simply because the low-risk majority perceive sexual assault as even more deplorable than they already did – while the (roughly 30 per cent) of higher-risk men become even more intent on their agenda. Of course, such interventions may prevent certain sexual assaults – for example, through limiting predation opportunities through galvanising bystanders to act. But surely we should be working to maximise impact on those likely to commit the bulk of the assaults, rather than fire up their motivation still further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178917303646&quot;&gt;Sexual assault interventions may be doing more harm than good with high-risk males&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Highlights of the BMC series: May 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10259</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/19/highlights-bmc-series-may-2018/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/BMC-series-highlight-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12888-018-1740-9&quot;&gt;The role of oxytocin receptor gene (OXTR) DNA methylation (DNAm) in human social and emotional functioning: a systematic narrative review.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neurotransmitter Oxytocin is widely known for its role in the regulation of social bonding as well as romantic attachment. It was initially discovered over 100 years ago after an extract derived from the human posterior pituitary gland was found to cause uterine contractions in pregnant cats. Since 1909 our understanding of this nonapeptide has somewhat progressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Impairment of methylation appeared to suggest increased prevalence of mood and anxiety disorders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxytocin binds a G protein coupled receptor that is coded for by the OXTR gene. Binding of oxytocin to its receptor unleashes a signalling cascade within the cell, leading to both psychological and physiological changes.  Much attention has been given to the OXTR gene as its expression essentially controls the rate limiting step in the oxytocin signalling process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A meta-analysis published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; this month looks at the possibility of a link between OXTR gene methylation and corresponding changes in social and emotional behaviour in human populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is still insufficient evidence to draw strong conclusions, early findings point towards a correlation between specific elevated patterns of methylation and impaired cognitive and social emotional behaviour. Conversely, impairment of methylation appeared to suggest increased prevalence of mood and anxiety disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish these patterns with greater certainty, more research is required to understand the relationship between OXTR gene methylation and OXTR expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-018-5399-4&quot;&gt;Sound pressure levels generated at risk volume steps of portable listening devices: types of smartphone and genres of music.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-10261&quot; height=&quot;201&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/headphones-300x201.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;It is thought that approximately 36% of the world’s population currently use a smart phone, with around 2.1 billion worldwide users reported in 2016. A significant number of these smartphone owning individuals are likely to take advantage of music playing applications found ubiquitously across most smartphone models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, listening to music on a smartphone or personal listening device comes with a risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organisation (WHO) have warned many young adults are at risk of developing recreational noise induced hearing loss due to frequent exposure to noisy environments. It is thought that nearly 50% of young people aged from 12- 35 years of age in developed counties are exposed to dangerously high levels of music through their personal listening devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone manufacturers have now implemented their own recommendations for minimum volumes at which hearing loss may occur. However these volumes vary, even within different smartphone models issued by the same company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;, authors Gibbeum Kim and Woojae Han put 6 smartphones to the test, using four genres of Korean pop music to determine the first risk volume level as defined by each device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results indicated a considerable 8-dB difference in sound pressure levels detected across the six devices, with dance-pop music having the highest output level of the genres tested. Based on these conclusions, the implementation of an international standard for safe use output volume is suggested across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMC International Health and Human Rights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcinthealthhumrights.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12914-018-0160-8&quot;&gt;Causes of death among street-connected children and youth in Eldoret, Kenya.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is common knowledge that homeless people will have lower life expectancy on average than their housed and settled counterparts. One recent study estimated the homeless youth of San Francisco to have a mortality rate that was 10 times that of the general population. Drug related deaths and suicide featured as the most common causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, little information exists on the causes of youth mortality in low and middle-income countries. A recent study published &lt;em&gt;in BMC International Health and Human Rights&lt;/em&gt; has documented the causes of death among street connected youth in Eldoret, Western Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of death of in Eldoret differ considerably from those in San Francisco. In Eldoret, HIV accounted for 37% of all deaths, killing 59% of females included in the study and roughly a quarter of all men. Among the male population, the greatest cause of death was assault, accounting for nearly 50% of recorded deaths in men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deaths for reasons such as these are largely preventable. The authors advocate appropriate responses such as targeted HIV treatment programs and child protection systems to decrease the prevalence of assault and HIV and thus avoidable youth mortality in these areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcevolbiol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12862-018-1155-8&quot;&gt;Phylogenomic analysis of Apoidea sheds new light on the sister group of bees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-medium wp-image-10262&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/wasp-300x298.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;This study published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt; investigates the evolutionary history of apoidea, a superfamily that includes apoid wasps and bees. A barrier to understanding the evolution of apoidea has been the difficulty in determining the geological age of bees as well as their phylogenetic origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Ohl’s group from the Institute for Evolution and Biodiversity Science in Berlin have pooled and analysed target DNA enrichment sites and transcriptomic sequence data, covering all major lineages in the apoidea superfamily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ammoplanina, a family of predatory wasps, began to lose their taste for thrips around 128 million years ago. Over time, they acquired a plant-based diet and evolved into what we now know as the modern bee. Further research must be done to understand the specific traits that enabled this radical dietary change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Ethics: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedethics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12910-018-0268-3&quot;&gt;Conscientious objection to participation in abortion by midwives and nurses: a systematic review of reasons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enshrined in the European Convention on Human Rights, is the right to freedom of thought conscience and religion. The freedom to manifest these beliefs, however, can be limited by law if thought to pose a risk to public health for example, or infringe on the rights and freedoms of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conscientious objection was widely accepted, despite largely polarised viewpoints on either side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under most abortion laws enacted across the developed world, a conscience clause is included, permitting the conscientious objection of healthcare professionals to opt out of providing such services on moral grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heated debate has ensued regarding the extent to which the rights of healthcare professionals to refuse provision of abortion services should be limited, in case this should infringe on a woman’s legal right to the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This review, published in &lt;em&gt;BMC Medical Ethics&lt;/em&gt;, aims to elucidate the reasons given for declining to participate in abortion on grounds of conscience. Surprisingly, it was found the viewpoints of midwives and nurses were largely absent from this debate, despite being the recommended providers of abortion services by the WHO. Across the literature studied, conscientious objection was widely accepted, despite largely polarised viewpoints on either side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, better representation of all relevant healthcare professionals in the debate and the consideration of all viewpoints is necessary when discussing such a sensitive topic, in order to inform beneficial health policy in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Oral Health: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcoralhealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12903-018-0523-5&quot;&gt;Cone beam computed tomography in implant dentistry: recommendations for clinical use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10263&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10263&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/skull-300x267.gif&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Image taken from manuscript&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the ages of 35 to 44, 69% of US citizens are reported to have lost at least one tooth. 15 million of this population will have undergone crown and bridge replacements for missing teeth, while only 3 million of these have been reported to have had dental implants. However this number is said to be growing by half a million every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dental implants may be surgically inserted into a patient’s jaw, in order to support the introduction of a prosthetic element such as a crown or bridge. Cone beam computed tomography (CBCT) is a useful tool, providng high-quality, 3-dimensional images of surrounding tissues to aid this process. The low cost and reasonable dose of radiation administered has caused the popularity of this method to increase over recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;BMC Oral Health&lt;/em&gt; this month, Michael Bornstein’s group from the University of Leuven in Belgium review current literature to provide recommendations for the future use of CBCT imaging. Due to relatively high radiation doses, its clinical usage should be justified. For example, the authors advise to limit CBCT to cases involving post-operative complications following dental implant insertion, as well as the avoidance of this procedure in long term maintenance and follow up of dental implants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lack of standardisation of radiation dose and image quality between different CBCT machines further prompted calls for more research to consistently achieve the lowest diagnostically acceptable radiation dose possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/19/highlights-bmc-series-may-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Highlights of the BMC series: May 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 08:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/BMC-series-highlight-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Mental Illness Overlap</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/NZbmpmdASFU/scientificamerican0718-76</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 76 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-76&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mark Fischetti&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A distinct set of genes may underlie several psychiatric conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/NZbmpmdASFU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: 50, 100 &amp; 150 Years Ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/_hneDobOTtE/scientificamerican0718-75</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 75 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-75&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Daniel C. Schlenoff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation and discovery as chronicled in Scientific American&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/_hneDobOTtE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Sex and Drugs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/N00lph2hjXo/scientificamerican0718-74</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 74 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-74&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Steve Mirsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animals' inner lives are stranger than we can imagine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/N00lph2hjXo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Final Mysterians</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Z86rtyCQ6No/scientificamerican0718-73</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 73 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-73&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Michael Shermer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are consciousness, free will and God insoluble mysteries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Z86rtyCQ6No&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Recommended</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/SWS34Kr7Oc8/scientificamerican0718-72</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 72 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-72&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/SWS34Kr7Oc8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Buzz Kill</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/-Gbisvf4zn4/scientificamerican0718-66</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 66 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-66&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Dan Strickman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mosquito-borne diseases spread, scientists are fighting back with new poisons, traps and genetic engineering techniques&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/-Gbisvf4zn4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Building a Weather-Smart Grid</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/EjTQROUAfQM/scientificamerican0718-60</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 60 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-60&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Peter Fairley&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewable energy will rule only when weather data drive the design of a new electric grid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/EjTQROUAfQM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Letters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/vFq9FMOVmHY/scientificamerican0718-6</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 6 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-6&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/vFq9FMOVmHY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Battle of the Brains</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/vTec13XzCSU/scientificamerican0718-58</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 58 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-58&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Josh Fischman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs beat their domesticated rivals, cats, in a new attempt to measure cognitive power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/vTec13XzCSU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Clocks within Our Cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/l_OZi1G-RiA/scientificamerican0718-50</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 50 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-50&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Veronique Greenwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the body's cycles went from folk medicine to modern science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/l_OZi1G-RiA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Real Paleo Diet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/uiv4C8TPrp4/scientificamerican0718-42</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 42 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-42&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Peter S. Ungar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microscopic wear patterns on fossil teeth reveal what our ancestors ate—and provide insights into how climate change shaped human evolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/uiv4C8TPrp4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Barriers between Realities</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/r7sTvX4Oo5s/scientificamerican0718-4</link>
	<description>&lt;div style=&quot;white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/jump?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Advertisment&quot; src=&quot;http://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/ad?iu=/285//rss&amp;amp;sz=728x90&amp;amp;t=abr=!NN2;pos=top;tile=1;ptile=1&amp;amp;c=123456789?&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.nature.com/common/includes/header/images/backgrounds/01/leaderboard_side.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 14px; border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0; display: inline;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 4 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mariette DiChristina&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/r7sTvX4Oo5s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Science of Antiscience Thinking</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/g9snsbTnX7w/scientificamerican0718-36</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 36 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-36&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Douglas T. Kenrick, Adam B. Cohen, Steven L. Neuberg &amp;amp; Robert B. Cialdini&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convincing people who doubt the validity of climate change and evolution to change their beliefs requires overcoming a set of ingrained cognitive biases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/g9snsbTnX7w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Crossing the Quantum Divide</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/nE6MccqTlWE/scientificamerican0718-28</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 28 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-28&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Tim Folger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The universe according to quantum mechanics is strange and probabilistic, but our everyday reality seems nailed down. New experiments aim to probe where—and why—one realm passes into the other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/nE6MccqTlWE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Next Round of Merger Mania</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/Ia80KuhtrZ0/scientificamerican0718-26</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 26 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-26&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: David Pogue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 ideas for new companies that probably won't exist—but should&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/Ia80KuhtrZ0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Killer Infection: Is It Your Genes?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/drakPsj_E6k/scientificamerican0718-24</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 24 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-24&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Claudia Wallis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subtle mutations can undermine our ability to fend off a specific bug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/drakPsj_E6k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Blue's Clues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/mzQ3IO3z4jg/scientificamerican0718-23</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 23 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-23&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Matthew Hutson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealthy families invest more in boys, backpack sales suggest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/mzQ3IO3z4jg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Smart Walls</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/UYGDHzj9Sig/scientificamerican0718-22</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 22 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-22&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Prachi Patel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special paint turns a surface into a giant touch sensor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/UYGDHzj9Sig&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: Quick Hits</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/aS00L62W-no/scientificamerican0718-21</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 21 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-21&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Tanya Lewis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/aS00L62W-no&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Scientific American: The Power of Science Museums</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~3/2t128mPUmeA/scientificamerican0718-20</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientific American 319, 20 (2018).  
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20&quot;&gt;doi:10.1038/scientificamerican0718-20&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new air and space museum director talks about the next generation of explorers and the post-truth era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/scientificamerican/rss/current/~4/2t128mPUmeA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/scientificamerican/rss/current">Scientific American - nature.com science feeds</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Venus’ thick atmosphere speeds up the planet’s spin</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/venus-thick-atmosphere-speeds-planets-spin</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/venus-thick-atmosphere-speeds-planets-spin</link>
	<description>Venus’ thick atmosphere can push on mountains on the surface, changing its rotation period by a few minutes every day.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 19:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061518_LG_venus_feat.jpg?itok=dsXYQiS9" length="15291" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: How Weather Influences the Brain?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23740</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/18/how-weather-influences-the-brain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We all know that the weather can strongly influence our mood and productivity. Many people feel better when the weather is nice and sunny. It is thus not surprising that people more often feel unhappy and depressed in winter. There is even a medical condition known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/02/08/winter-depression-new-discoveries-in-treatment-of-seasonal-affective-disorder/&quot;&gt;winter depression&lt;/a&gt;. Still, some researchers believe that our brain functions better during the cold days. In this article, I’ll briefly analyze what happens in our brain in relation to weather-related mood and mind changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific studies indicate that weather conditions such as high temperature and humidity can impair mental performance by affecting brain neurochemistry. For instance, it is believed that thermal stress can cause cognitive impairment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent study has investigated the impact of thermal stress on cognitive functions in soldiers spending at least one year in desert conditions. The evaluation of memory and cognitive functions indicated there is a decline in cognitive performance in hot climates when compared to normal weather. The decline was most pronounced for attention, concentration, verbal memory, and psychomotor performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another recent study has investigated the impact of sand and dust storms on children’s cognitive function. Using mathematical analysis and word-recognition test scores, how prenatal exposure to sand and dust storms affects the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/12/13/how-does-starting-school-early-impact-educational-attainment/&quot;&gt;cognitive performance of children &lt;/a&gt;was evaluated. The authors found a decline in both test scores, as well as a later beginning of counting and speaking in whole sentences in children prenatally exposed to storms. The findings imply that this kind of weather jeopardizes the cognitive functions of the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, results from scientific research on the effects of temperature on cognitive functions are quite mixed and contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One study investigated &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/13/how-temperature-affects-people-with-multiple-sclerosis/&quot;&gt;how temperature affects the cognitive performance of subjects with multiple sclerosis&lt;/a&gt;. Healthy subjects were included as controls. The researchers correlated cognitive status with temperature in both study groups. In patients with multiple sclerosis, unlike in healthy subjects, the higher temperatures were associated with worsening cognitive status. These findings confirmed that warmer outdoor temperatures lead to a higher incidence of clinical exacerbation and T2 lesion activity in subjects with this condition (T2 lesions represent the white spots observed by MRI that are used to diagnose and track the progress of multiple sclerosis).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to cognitive functions in cold weather, studies have shown both impairments and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, one study investigated the impact of exposure to the cold and the following rewarming on working memory and executive functions in 10 young males. The results demonstrated a decline in the test results when the subjects were exposed to 10°C, and these impairments persisted for one hour during the rewarming period. Although the underlying mechanisms were not tested, the authors suggested that acute vascular changes in the brain could explain the observed changes. According to the authors, another explanation could be a deregulation of catecholamine levels, particularly important for complex attentional functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other findings suggest that winter helps to wake up our mind and makes us think more clearly. It is well known that the brain utilizes glucose as its main energy source. Thus, when glucose is depleted, brain functioning is jeopardized. Energy, i.e., glucose, is also used for the regulation of body temperature, especially in extremely hot or cold conditions. It seems that more energy (glucose) is needed to cool down than to warm up the body. Thus, warm temperatures are more likely to deplete glucose levels and thus impair brain function and clarity of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been suggested that high temperatures increase the risk of mental disorders, especially in the elderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One recent study has analyzed data on emergency admissions linked to mental diseases and daily temperatures over a period of more than 10 years in 6 different cities. The results indicated that high temperatures might jeopardize mental health and be responsible for the exacerbation of symptoms of mental diseases. For instance, according to the results, more than 30% of admissions for anxiety were attributed to hot temperatures. Exposure to hot temperatures leads to reactions in the body that may cause an increase in stress hormone levels and brain temperature. Additionally, extremely hot weather may deregulate the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2018/01/10/tryptophan-in-mood-anxiety-and-depression/&quot;&gt;dopamine and serotonin levels&lt;/a&gt; (these neuromediators are important for the feeling of happiness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to widespread belief, weather can affect our mood. Although a lack of sunshine is commonly linked to seasonal depression, some researchers believe that not all individuals respond similarly to weather changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has linked an individual’s self-reported daily mood with the objective weather over a 30 day period. Large individual differences have been found in how people react to the weather. Accordingly, four distinct types of weather responders have been identified: summer lovers (i.e., a better mood with warmer weather and more sun), summer haters (i.e., a worse mood with warmer weather and more sun), rain haters (i.e.,  a bad mood on rainy days), and unaffected (i.e., no particular association between weather and mood). Interestingly, adolescents and their mothers are often the same type, suggestive of familial weather reactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of both scientific and popular literature permits the conclusion that extreme weather conditions can affect our cognitive function and mood. Most likely, this is caused by a decline in the brain’s energy source (glucose), which needs to be used for thermoregulation. Also, it is evident that extreme temperatures affect the level of catecholamines in the brain (such as dopamine and serotonin). Still, it seems that there is some individual variability in the brain’s response to weather, and it may run in the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saini, R., Srivastava, K., Agrawal, S., Das, R. C. (2017) Cognitive deficits due to thermal stress: An exploratory study on soldiers in deserts. &lt;em&gt;Med Journal Armed Forces India&lt;/em&gt;. 73(4):370-374. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mjafi.2017.07.011&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.mjafi.2017.07.011&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li, Z., Chen, L., Li, M., Cohen, J. (2018) Prenatal exposure to sand and dust storms and children’s cognitive function in China: a quasi-experimental study.&lt;em&gt; The Lancet. Planetary Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2(5): e214-e222. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2542-5196(18)30068-8&quot;&gt;10.1016/S2542-5196(18)30068-8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leavitt, V.M., Sumowski, J.F., Chiaravalloti, N., Deluca, J. (2012) Warmer outdoor temperature is associated with worse cognitive status in multiple sclerosis. &lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt;. 78(13): 964-968. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31824d5834&quot;&gt;10.1212/WNL.0b013e31824d5834&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muller, M.D., Gunstad, J., Alosco, M.L., Miller, L.A., Updegraff, J., Spitznagel, M.B., Glickman, E,L. (2012) Acute cold exposure and cognitive function: evidence for sustained impairment. &lt;em&gt;Ergonomics&lt;/em&gt;. 55(7): 792-798. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00140139.2012.665497&quot;&gt;10.1080/00140139.2012.665497&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee, S., Lee, H., Myung, W., Kim, E.J., Kim, H. (2018) Mental disease-related emergency admissions attributable to hot temperatures.&lt;em&gt; The Science of Total Environment&lt;/em&gt;.616-617: 688-694. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.10.260&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.10.260&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klimstra, T.A., Frijns, T., Keijsers, L., et al. (2011) Come rain or come shine: individual differences in how weather affects mood.&lt;em&gt; Emotion&lt;/em&gt;. 11(6): 1495-1499. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0024649&quot;&gt;10.1037/a0024649&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Phone apps are helping scientists track suicidal thoughts in real time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/phone-apps-are-helping-scientists-track-suicidal-thoughts-real-time</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/phone-apps-are-helping-scientists-track-suicidal-thoughts-real-time</link>
	<description>Researchers are using smartphones to tap into the ups and downs of suicidal thinking that occur over hours and days, hoping to help prevent suicides.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061518_BB_suicide_feat.jpg?itok=gwGKjHMY" length="22451" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal holds firm on decision not to retract Macchiarini paper, despite outside pressure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66729</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/18/journal-holds-firm-on-decision-not-to-retract-macchiarini-paper-despite-outside-pressure/</link>
	<description>Earlier this year, the president of the Karolinska Institute, Ole Petter Ottersen, contacted the journal Respiration, saying KI had conducted an investigation and determined that a 2015 paper co-authored by once-lauded surgeon Paolo Macchiarini had been tainted by misconduct. Please retract the paper, Ottersen said. When the journal said no — opting to publish correspondence … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/18/journal-holds-firm-on-decision-not-to-retract-macchiarini-paper-despite-outside-pressure/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journal holds firm on decision not to retract Macchiarini paper, despite outside pressure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 12:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The most ancient African baobabs are dying and no one knows why</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-ancient-african-baobabs-are-dying-and-no-one-knows-why</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-ancient-african-baobabs-are-dying-and-no-one-knows-why</link>
	<description>Scientists aren’t sure what’s killing the oldest African baobabs, nine of which have lost big chunks or died in the last 13 years.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061218_sm_baobab_feat.jpg?itok=737an4Fw" length="57006" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Edinburgh breaks silence to announce Stancheva retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24684</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/18/edinburgh-breaks-silence-to-announce-stancheva-retractions/</link>
	<description>In October 2017, I brought an exclusive story of a mysterious sacking at the University of Edinburgh. The molecular biologist and epigenetics researcher Irina Stancheva was removed from her post as senior lecturer at the Scottish university, in total secret, all online traces of her employment rapidly deleted (even a promo video on Vimeo), her … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/18/edinburgh-breaks-silence-to-announce-stancheva-retractions/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Edinburgh breaks silence to announce Stancheva retractions&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 10:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Researchers have compared different cognitive strategies for falling out of love</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34035</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/18/researchers-have-compared-different-cognitive-strategies-for-falling-out-of-love/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-18 10.00.47.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34039&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34039&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2018-06-18 10.00.47&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2482,1476&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/18/researchers-have-compared-different-cognitive-strategies-for-falling-out-of-love/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/screenshot-2018-06-18-10-00-47.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;i&gt;You’ve Lost that Lovin’ Feeling&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;Nothing Compares 2 U&lt;/i&gt;, there’s no shortage of songs about heartbreak. None, I suspect, contains the line, “Now it’s time to give negative reappraisal a go.” But whether you’ve just been dumped or you’ve done the dumping, if you’re still in love with your ex, this could be your best strategy for falling out of love and moving on, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/buy/2017-37800-001&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; published in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Romantic break-ups can have serious consequences including insomnia, reduced immune function, broken heart syndrome, depression and suicide,” note the authors, Sandra Langeslag and Michelle Sanchez at the University of Missouri, St Louis. Strategies that help people to fall out of love could relieve the agony of unrequited love or make it easier to get out of a dysfunctional relationship.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34035&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langeslag and Sanchez recruited 20 women and four men for their study. (As it was hard to get male volunteers, they decided to sacrifice gender balance in favour of having enough participants for the statistical analysis). All these people had experienced a romantic break-up, were still upset about it, and could supply 28 digital pictures of their ex. These pictures had to include a range of facial expressions, and show the ex-partner in different situations (all non-intimate), to mimic the kinds of real-world reminders the participants might endure – seeing their ex on the street, or on social media, for example.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the lab, the researchers showed the participants their full collection of pictures four times over. In between seeing each shot, they were prompted to engage in one of three potential strategies to down-regulate love, and then report on a sliding scale how “in love” and how generally positive or negative they felt. One strategy was “love reappraisal” (they were presented with statements such as “It’s okay to love someone I’m no longer with”, for example.) Another involved simple distractions (between photos, they were asked to think about their favourite food, for example). There was also a control, in which they were asked to think about nothing in particular. And finally, there was “negative reappraisal” which involved reminding themselves of the negative qualities of their ex partners (prompts included ‘What is an annoying habit of your ex?’ for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While neither love reappraisal or distraction changed how in love the participants reported feeling, negative reappraisal of the ex did. Negative reappraisal also made the participants feel more negative in the moment – but such short-term discomfort may be worth enduring if this strategy helps people to get over a break-up, the researchers write.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is an “if”, however. As Langeslag and Sanchez concede, this study only looked at feelings of love immediately after each photo was presented. The practicalities of the strategy also remain unclear. If you know you’re going to bump into your ex at work, say, should you be focusing on their negative qualities during every commute in – or would an occasional bout of negative reappraisal have the same effect? And what exactly would using the negative reappraisal strategy mean in terms of how long it takes you to get over the relationship?&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To evaluate which regulation strategies would best help people cope with a break-up, it would be essential to consider both the short-term and long-term effects,” the researchers write. It will also be important to study more men.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-37800-001&quot;&gt;Down-regulation of love feelings after a romantic break-up: Self-report and electrophysiological data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Emma Young&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 08:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Meet the scientific sleuths: A dozen who’ve had an impact on the scientific literature</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66827</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/17/meet-the-scientific-sleuths-ten-whove-had-an-impact-on-the-scientific-literature/</link>
	<description>Over the years, we have written about a number of the sleuths who, on their own time and often at great risks to their careers or finances, have looked for issues in the scientific literature. Here’s a sampling: Elisabeth “Eagle Eyes” Bik showed that one in 25 papers she examined had evidence of inappropriate image manipulation. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/17/meet-the-scientific-sleuths-ten-whove-had-an-impact-on-the-scientific-literature/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Meet the scientific sleuths: A dozen who’ve had an impact on the scientific literature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 13:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Ayahuasca, the Psychedelic Antidepressant?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9563</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9563</link>
	<description>A traditional Amazonian psychedelic brew is an effective and rapid-acting antidepressant, according to a paper just published. But the new study revives some long-standing questions.



Ayahuasca is a mixture of herbs, traditionally used for spiritual and therapeutic purposes. The main active ingredients are N,N-DMT, a potent psychedelic, and several molecules that inhibit the enzyme MAO. The MAO inhibitors serve to prevent the N,N-DMT from being broken down by the digestive system, allowing</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 11:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Citric Acid Increases Balloon Inflation (aka sour taste makes you more risky)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-9114495217435618263</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/ov3aJNm8pqM/citric-acid-increases-balloon-inflation.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zBSefDNygnw/WyXO2IRUipI/AAAAAAAAMjA/QjycpncUbFICyUMKxuHLsFerwo6DRdkCACLcBGAs/s1600/BART%2Banimation.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;250&quot; data-original-width=&quot;325&quot; height=&quot;246&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zBSefDNygnw/WyXO2IRUipI/AAAAAAAAMjA/QjycpncUbFICyUMKxuHLsFerwo6DRdkCACLcBGAs/s320/BART%2Banimation.gif&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=foy3ZVokjFM&quot;&gt;Balloon Analog Risk Task (BART)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; – Joggle Research for iPad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Risk taking and &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;one's response(s) to 'risk' (properties in the world)&quot;&gt;risk preference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are complex constructs measured by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www8.gsb.columbia.edu/decisionsciences/research/tools/dospert&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;e.g. Domain-Specific Risk-Taking (DOSPERT) scale&quot;&gt;self-report questionnaires&lt;/a&gt; (“propensity”), laboratory tasks, and the frequency of real-life behaviors (smoking, alcohol use, etc).  A recent mega-study of 1507 healthy adults by &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frey et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt; measured risk preference using six questionnaires (and their subscales), eight behavioral tasks, and six frequency measures of real-life behavior.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Table 1 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frey et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/b&gt;Risk-taking measures used in the Basel-Berlin Risk Study.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WW_jJU2MAoM/WyYOTho4x3I/AAAAAAAAMjM/PedhILXXXhAC7z_E65rZG7VVHFtb4G8kQCLcBGAs/s1600/Risk-taking%2Bmeasures%2Bused%2Bin%2BRisk%2BStudy.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;1374&quot; data-original-width=&quot;846&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-WW_jJU2MAoM/WyYOTho4x3I/AAAAAAAAMjM/PedhILXXXhAC7z_E65rZG7VVHFtb4G8kQCLcBGAs/s640/Risk-taking%2Bmeasures%2Bused%2Bin%2BRisk%2BStudy.png&quot; width=&quot;394&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;-- click on image for a larger view --&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The authors were interested in whether they could extract a general factor of risk preference (&lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt;), analogous to the general factor of intelligence (&lt;i&gt;g&lt;/i&gt;). They used a bifactor model to account for the general factor as well as specific, orthogonal factors (seven in this case). The differing measures above are often used interchangeably and called “risk”, but the general factor &lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt; only...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;...explained substantial variance across propensity measures and frequency measures of risky activities but did not generalize to behavioral measures. Moreover, there was only one specific factor that captured common variance across behavioral measures, specifically, choices among different types of risky lotteries (F7). Beyond the variance accounted for by R, the remaining six factors captured specific variance associated with health risk taking (F1), financial risk taking (F2), recreational risk taking (F3), impulsivity (F4), traffic risk taking (F5), and risk taking at work (F6). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other words, the behavioral tasks didn't explain &lt;i&gt;R&lt;/i&gt; at all, and most of them didn't even explain common variance across the tasks themselves (F7 below).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NvHZJti7iq4/WyYe2ow-O9I/AAAAAAAAMjY/ANaZhvIbsZosPib1TjcnMTG39_zAaOaTQCLcBGAs/s1600/Bifactor%2Bmodel%2Bwith%2Ball%2Brisk-taking%2Bfactors.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;558&quot; data-original-width=&quot;980&quot; height=&quot;227&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NvHZJti7iq4/WyYe2ow-O9I/AAAAAAAAMjY/ANaZhvIbsZosPib1TjcnMTG39_zAaOaTQCLcBGAs/s400/Bifactor%2Bmodel%2Bwith%2Ball%2Brisk-taking%2Bfactors.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fig. 2 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot;&gt;Frey et al., 2017&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/b&gt; Bifactor model with all risk-taking measures, grouped by measurement tradition. &lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;BART is outlined in red&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's where we come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-26164-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Sour Promotes Risk-Taking: An Investigation into the Effect of Taste on Risk-Taking Behaviour in Humans&quot;&gt;recent study&lt;/a&gt; on “risk” and taste. The headlines were either misleading (&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/d-brief/2018/06/07/a-sour-taste-in-your-mouth-means-youre-more-likely-to-take-risks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A%20DiscoverBlogs%20%28Discover%20Blogs%29&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Sour Taste in Your Mouth Means You’re More Likely to Take Risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;) or downright false &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; no lemons were used (&lt;a href=&quot;https://neurosciencenews.com/sour-taste-risk-taking-9293&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;When Life Gives You Lemons, You Take More Risks&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; and this doozy (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spring.org.uk/2018/06/fruit-risks.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Fruit That Helps You Take Risks – May Help Depressed And Anxious&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To assess risk-tasking, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-26164-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vi and Obrist (2018)&lt;/a&gt; administered the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12075692&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Balloon Analog Risk Task&lt;/a&gt; (BART) to 70 participants in the UK and 71 in Vietnam. They were randomly assigned to one of five taste groups [&lt;i&gt;yes, n=14 each&lt;/i&gt;] of Bitter (caffeine), Salty (sodium chloride), Sour (citric acid), Umami (MSG), and Sweet (sugar, presumably). They were given two rounds of BART and consumed 20 ml of flavored drink or plain water before each (in counterbalanced order).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[Remember that BART didn't load on a general factor of risk-taking, nor did it capture common variance across behavioral tasks.]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As in the animation above (and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://static-content.springer.com/esm/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-018-26164-3/MediaObjects/41598_2018_26164_MOESM1_ESM.mp4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video made by the authors&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, the participant “inflates” a virtual balloon via mouse click until they either stop and win a monetary reward, or else they pop the balloon and lose money. The number of clicks (pumps) indicates risk-taking behavior. Overall, the Vietnamese students (all recruited from the School of Biotechnology and Food Technology at Hanoi University) appeared to be riskier than the UK students (but I don't know if this was tested directly). The main finding was that both groups clicked more after drinking citric acid than the other solutions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-h3NSxvowELA/WyYwfajUsPI/AAAAAAAAMjo/NKMwiaEliIQn8-6ZiC7qQCkk-0Kfr6B3ACLcBGAs/s1600/UK%2Bparticipants.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;338&quot; data-original-width=&quot;471&quot; height=&quot;286&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-h3NSxvowELA/WyYwfajUsPI/AAAAAAAAMjo/NKMwiaEliIQn8-6ZiC7qQCkk-0Kfr6B3ACLcBGAs/s400/UK%2Bparticipants.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HHMqBb3kop8/WyYwfbyVuVI/AAAAAAAAMjk/GGLi-6lrhlYLpMWqCzGAEkVZDlWErYVHgCLcBGAs/s1600/Vietnamese%2BParticipants.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;366&quot; data-original-width=&quot;482&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HHMqBb3kop8/WyYwfbyVuVI/AAAAAAAAMjk/GGLi-6lrhlYLpMWqCzGAEkVZDlWErYVHgCLcBGAs/s400/Vietnamese%2BParticipants.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why would this this balloon pumping be more vigorous after tasting a sour solution? We could also ask, why were the Vietnamese subjects more risk-averse after drinking salt water, and riskier (relative to UK subjects) after drinking sugar water?&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; We simply don't know the answer to any of these questions, but the authors weren't shy about extrapolating to clinical populations:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;For example, people who are risk-averse (e.g., people with anxiety disorders or depression) may benefit from a sour additive in their diet. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Smelling lemon oil is relaxing, but tasting citric acid promotes risk:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prior work has, for instance, shown that in cases of psychiatric disorders such as depression, anxiety, or stress-related disorders the use of lemon oils proved efficient and was further demonstrated to reduce stress. While lemon and sour are not the same, they share common properties that can be further investigated with respect to risk-taking.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We're really not sure how any of this works. The authors offered many more analyses in the Supplementary Materials, but they didn't help explain the results. Although the sour finding was interesting and observed cross culturally, would it &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sxbegle/status/1005073824981794817&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;replicate&lt;/a&gt; using groups larger than n=14?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Footnotes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; From &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frey et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;The term “risk” refers to properties of the world, yet without a clear agreement on its definition, which has ranged from probability, chance, outcome variance, expected values, undesirable events, danger, losses, to uncertainties. People’s responses to those properties, on the other hand, are typically described as their “risk preference.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The video conveniently starts by illustrating risk as skydiving, which bears no relation to being an adventurous eater.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: purple;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The group difference in umami had a cultural explanation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Frey R, Pedroni A, Mata R, Rieskamp J, Hertwig R. (2017). &lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Risk preference shares  the psychometric structure of major psychological traits&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Science Advances&lt;/i&gt; 3(10):e1701381.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vi CT, Obrist M. (2018). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-26164-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sour promotes risk-taking: an investigation into the effect of taste on risk-taking behaviour in humans&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/i&gt; 8(1):7987.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WoJSjBdMSGU/WyY41zY-nEI/AAAAAAAAMj4/EjjPKkU2SrcYN1gONSCDcYxE0WmgodVrACLcBGAs/s1600/F1.large%2Bbart.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;829&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1400&quot; height=&quot;236&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-WoJSjBdMSGU/WyY41zY-nEI/AAAAAAAAMj4/EjjPKkU2SrcYN1gONSCDcYxE0WmgodVrACLcBGAs/s400/F1.large%2Bbart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://advances.sciencemag.org/content/3/10/e1701381.full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Frey et al., 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=ov3aJNm8pqM:wdqSCnHh5sM:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/ov3aJNm8pqM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 10:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
        <enclosure url="https://static-content.springer.com/esm/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41598-018-26164-3/MediaObjects/41598_2018_26164_MOESM1_ESM.mp4" length="" type="text/html"/>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: How to kill zombie citations; wanted: 6,000 new journals; does peer review matter anymore?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66806</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/16/weekend-reads-how-to-kill-zombie-citations-wanted-6000-new-journals-does-peer-review-matter-anymore/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured a retraction and replacement of a diet study in the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/16/weekend-reads-how-to-kill-zombie-citations-wanted-6000-new-journals-does-peer-review-matter-anymore/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: How to kill zombie citations; wanted: 6,000 new journals; does peer review matter anymore?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 13:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Max Plank Florida Institute for Neuroscience: MPFI Scientist Secures a $2.4 Million Grant to Investigate Inhibitory Circuits in the Cerebral Cortex</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/?p=10887</guid>
	<link>https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/news-and-media/news/mpfi-scientist-secures-a-2-4-million-grant-to-investigate-inhibitory-circuits-in-the-cerebral-cortex/</link>
	<description>&lt;h4&gt;The project will focus on applying advanced imaging technologies paired with precise genetic techniques to disentangle how inhibitory circuits in the cortex are constructed.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Hiroki Taniguchi, Ph.D., a Research Group Leader at the Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience (MPFI) has been awarded a $2.4 million five-year grant by the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Over the life of the grant the Taniguchi Lab will take a closer look at a class of brain cells known as inhibitory interneurons, studying how members of this diverse cell type assemble into specific circuits in various regions of the cerebral cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cerebral cortex is arguably the brain’s most complex structure, endowing us with extraordinary abilities such as sensory perception, language, and cognition. Underlying these capabilities are the intricate connections made by the neurons that reside within, enabling complex encoding and processing of information. Interneurons in the cortex normally act to balance, refine and shape information processing, but their dysfunction has been implicated in a wide array of brain disorders such as autism, schizophrenia and epilepsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their critical importance, comprehensive wiring diagrams of interneuron circuits and the exact principles that guide their assembly have remained rather elusive. One challenging aspect hindering the design of a concrete cortical blueprint, is the sheer diversity of interneurons and principle neurons they form connections with. Each individual type of interneuron is thought to make specific connections depending on a principle neuron’s location, function, and depth within the cortex. Until very recently, neuroscientists lacked readily available tools sensitive enough to study these connections at a cell-type specific resolution. Overcoming this obstacle, the Taniguchi lab has designed novel genetic tools and incorporated them into the established technique of retrograde monosynaptic labeling, producing unprecedented results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their powerful technique now allows for the precise tracing of connections from individual types of interneurons. MPFI scientists will be able to determine how inhibitory connections form during development and elucidate the organization of specific inhibitory inputs on varying types of principle neurons. Uncovering these principles will dramatically improve our understanding of cortical circuits as well as pioneer novel approaches for the diagnosis and treatment of prominent brain disorders.&lt;br /&gt;
“Cortical interneurons are a unique cell class with rich diversity, containing numerous types with distinctive features and functional properties.” Notes Dr. Taniguchi, “This crucial funding will allow us to probe individual types of interneurons, better establishing the principles behind their wiring. Addressing this critical topic will lead to a better understanding of inhibitory circuit design and the future development of novel therapies for neuropsychiatric disorders.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant described in this release is supported by the National Institutes of Health, Award Number R01MH11591701. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the National Institutes of Health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 20:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.maxplanckflorida.org/feed/">Max Planck Florida Institute for Neuroscience</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Large Hadron Collider is getting an upgrade</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/large-hadron-collider-getting-upgrade</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/large-hadron-collider-getting-upgrade</link>
	<description>Revamping the accelerator’s equipment will increase the rate of proton collisions.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 18:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/061518_EC_lhc-upgrade_feat.jpg?itok=NXObPZE0" length="57094" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Magnetic fields may be propping up the Pillars of Creation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetic-fields-may-be-propping-pillars-creation</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/magnetic-fields-may-be-propping-pillars-creation</link>
	<description>Scientists made a map of the magnetic field within the Pillars of Creation, a star-forming area depicted in an iconic Hubble Space Telescope image.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 17:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061518_EC_pillars-of-creation_feat.jpg?itok=N3tCYkWt" length="26690" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In 1968, scientists thought they were close to detecting gravity waves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/1968-scientists-thought-they-were-close-detecting-gravity-waves</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/1968-scientists-thought-they-were-close-detecting-gravity-waves</link>
	<description>Despite an unverified discovery in 1968, spacetime ripples remained elusive for nearly 50 years.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/051618_CM_notebook_50YA-weber_feat.jpg?itok=CoBZhumS" length="32466" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: University of Liverpool announces it’s investigating someone for misconduct. But don’t ask who.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66738</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/15/university-of-liverpool-announces-its-investigating-someone-for-misconduct-but-dont-ask-who/</link>
	<description>Transparency begins …. with a T, as Ali G once said. That seems to be extent of the University of Liverpool’s commitment to openness, at least in the handling of an ongoing misconduct investigation at the UK institution. We know this much: The school in late 2017 launched an inquiry into one of its scientists … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/15/university-of-liverpool-announces-its-investigating-someone-for-misconduct-but-dont-ask-who/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;University of Liverpool announces it’s investigating someone for misconduct. But don’t ask who.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Leaf-cutter ants pick up the pace when they sense rain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/leaf-cutter-ants-pick-pace-when-they-sense-rain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/leaf-cutter-ants-pick-pace-when-they-sense-rain</link>
	<description>Leaf-cutter ants struggle to carry wet leaves, so they run to avoid rain.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/052118_YHL_leaf-cutter_feat.jpg?itok=XZ0fWTiH" length="27573" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: BMC Ecology Image Competition Announcement 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10248</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/15/bmc-ecology-image-competition-announcement-2018/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-1_Overall-winner_Podocnemis-expansa_Ana-Carolina-Lima​-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that the 6th annual &lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; image competition launches today! We are calling for ecologists around the world to submit their images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created the competition as a chance for ecologists to share their research and photographic skills, and celebrate the intersection of art and science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three previous competitions (the overall winners of which can be seen on this page) have certainly achieved this, providing us with superb images demonstrating the complex web of interactions that ecologists are dedicated to unraveling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winning images from previous years have attracted substantial attention not just from ecologists but also from the wider public, featuring in international media outlets such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2017/aug/18/bmc-ecology-image-competition-2017-in-pictures&quot;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iflscience.com/editors-blog/awardwinning-photos-taken-during-actual-scientific-research-this-year/&quot;&gt;IFL&lt;/a&gt; Science, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/getting-big-picture-bmc-ecology-image-competition-winners/&quot;&gt;Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-33718151&quot;&gt;the BBC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging the competition will be the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/about/editorial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Section Editors&lt;/a&gt;, who are experts in biodiversity, ecosystems, ecological models, and behavioral ecology. The overall winner will be chosen by a special guest judge, whose identity will be announced later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall winner will receive a cash prize of £250 (~ €300/$325), while the runner-up will receive £100 (€125/$150). Additional prizes of £50 (€65/$75) will be awarded for those images selected by the Section Editors that best represent their section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10250&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-10250&quot; height=&quot;384&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/2016-winner-sunset-1024x614.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;2016’s overall winner by Davide Gaglio, the striking landscape of the Kgalagadi Transfrontier Park during sunrise.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Davide Gaglio&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to submit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is affiliated with a research institution can enter. All entrants should agree to release the images under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons license&lt;/a&gt; , which states that the images can be freely shared, reused and modified as long as they are properly attributed to the photographer. BMC does not retain the rights to the images. And each entrant can submit five images at most to this competition. We ask that entries be submitted to one of the five categories listed below and that they depict a specific ecological interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Behavioral and physiological ecology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conservation ecology and biodiversity research&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Community, population, and macroecology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Landscape ecology and ecosystems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theoretical ecology and models&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will consider all images from photos to data visualizations, or a mixture of both – as long as they are &lt;strong&gt;striking&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;meaningful&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;creative&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please email your images to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&quot;&gt;bmcecol@biomedcentral.com&lt;/a&gt; with the subject line “&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology Image Competition&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following information must be included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Category:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Description (Max. 300 words):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;File type:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data attribution (if applicable):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Affiliation:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact details of Research Institute:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I agree to release this image under a Creative Commons License:  Y/N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter handle (optional):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please attach your image entry to your email. All images must conform to the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A minimum 300dpi (1831 x 1831 pixels for a raster image).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In one of the allowable formats – EPS, PDF (for line drawings), PNG, TIFF,  JPEG, BMP, DOC, PPT [&lt;em&gt;Please note that it is the responsibility of the author(s) to obtain permission from the copyright holder to reproduce figures or tables that have previously been published elsewhere.&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In line with our policies on open access, entry to the competition implies release of the images under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&quot;&gt;creative commons license&lt;/a&gt;, to allow file sharing with proper attribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting regular updates on the competition throughout the coming months, so don’t forget to keep up to date by reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt; or by following us on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BMC_series&quot;&gt;@BMC_series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing date for entries is &lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Sep 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, with winners being announced in November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10251&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-10251&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/2015-winner-sunbird-1024x769.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;2015’s overall winner, by Mohamed Shebl, “Palestinian sunbird female forages on &lt;em&gt;Echinops sp&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Mohamed Shebl&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the links below to see a full list of winning and highly commended images from the past four years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1472-6785-13-6&quot;&gt;2013 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-014-0024-6&quot;&gt;2014 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-015-0053-9&quot;&gt;2015 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bmcecol.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12898-016-0090-z&quot;&gt;2016 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/08/18/bmc-ecology-image-competition-2017-the-winning-images/&quot;&gt;2017 competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/15/bmc-ecology-image-competition-announcement-2018/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Ecology&lt;/em&gt; Image Competition Announcement 2018&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 08:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/08/Figure-1_Overall-winner_Podocnemis-expansa_Ana-Carolina-Lima​-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The number of teens who report having sex is down</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/number-teens-who-report-having-sex-down</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/number-teens-who-report-having-sex-down</link>
	<description>About 40 percent of high school students are having sex, the lowest amount in the last three decades.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 23:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061418_ac_teens_feat_free.jpg?itok=t90PppSu" length="36411" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Appoints Two New Executives to Accelerate Growth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1360</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/science-exchange-appoints-two-new-executives-to-accelerate-growth/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Veteran marketing and business development executives join Science Exchange to help lead the company through its next phase of growth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, June 14, 2018 –&lt;/b&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BUSINESS WIRE&lt;/a&gt;)–Science Exchange, the&lt;i&gt; leading marketplace for outsourced R&amp;amp;D&lt;img alt=&quot;™&quot; class=&quot;wp-smiley&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/2122.png&quot; style=&quot;height: 1em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, has appointed senior team members Rob Mihalko as Vice President of Marketing and Alex Slater as Vice President of Business Development and General Manager Europe. Both executives, reporting to Science Exchange CEO Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., will add to an already talented management team that is driving industry-leading solutions to improve the quality and efficiency of scientific research around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob Mihalko is a leading expert in business commerce and procurement and has extensive experience in successfully implementing go-to-market strategies for business-to-business marketplaces on a global scale. As VP of Marketing, Mihalko will be responsible for Science Exchange’s worldwide marketing activities. He will lead the way in aligning Science Exchange’s brand and product positioning with global marketing programs to boost awareness, sales and adoption of the company’s industry-leading R&amp;amp;D marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to joining Science Exchange, Mihalko was Global Vice President of Solution &amp;amp; Customer Marketing for SAP Ariba, where he led marketing and product initiatives that transformed SAP Ariba into the world’s leading procurement and business commerce company. He also has held several senior marketing, product and finance roles with leading technology companies, including Microsoft, and was a management consultant with A.T. Kearney, advising senior executives on strategy, sourcing and supply chain transformation initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m delighted to have joined such a passionate and mission-driven team at Science Exchange,” said Mihalko. “I’m looking forward to helping the company build on its leadership position in the outsourced research market and support its growth in new verticals and geographies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a VP of Business Development and General Manager Europe, Alex Slater will be spearheading Science Exchange’s continued expansion into the European market. Slater brings 23 years of business development experience within contract research organizations to Science Exchange, spanning the entirety of drug discovery, from basic research to clinical development. He has also led business development teams in Europe and Asia for Covance and, most recently, was the VP Global Business Development at Eurofins Pharma Discovery Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his new role, Slater will provide key leadership and support of Science Exchange’s business development and expansion efforts in Europe. He will work with the global business development team to stimulate provider and researcher recruitment and expand the European support team that will give researchers the personalized scientific support they expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“From my initial interactions with Elizabeth Iorns and the team at Science Exchange, I was impressed by their passion and commitment to simplifying researchers’ access to the services they need,” said Slater. “I look forward to working with such a driven team and helping expand the company’s European presence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We work in a rapidly changing environment, and so it’s critical for us to hire people that share our ambitious vision and have the expertise to help us execute it successfully,” said Elizabeth Iorns, CEO of Science Exchange. “I’m thrilled to be welcoming our two new team members, who each bring vast experience to Science Exchange, and I look forward to working closely with them in our mission to enable scientific breakthroughs through connections.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 21:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Underwater fiber-optic cables could moonlight as earthquake sensors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/underwater-fiber-optic-cables-could-moonlight-earthquake-sensors</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/underwater-fiber-optic-cables-could-moonlight-earthquake-sensors</link>
	<description>The seafloor cables that ferry internet traffic across oceans may soon find another use: detecting underwater earthquakes.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061318_MT_optical-fiber_feat.jpg?itok=DjYNgEOG" length="21152" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Two years of stonewalling: What happened when a scientist filed a public records request for NASA code</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66117</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/14/two-years-of-stonewalling-what-happened-when-a-scientist-filed-a-public-records-request-for-nasa-code/</link>
	<description>Retraction Watch readers may know Nathan Myhrvold, who holds a PhD in physics, as the former chief technology officer at Microsoft, or as the author of Modernist Cuisine. They may also recall that he questioned a pair of papers in Nature about dinosaurs. In that vein, he has also been raising concerns about papers describing … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/14/two-years-of-stonewalling-what-happened-when-a-scientist-filed-a-public-records-request-for-nasa-code/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Two years of stonewalling: What happened when a scientist filed a public records request for NASA code&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 17:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Swirling gases reveal baby planets in a young star’s disk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/swirling-gases-reveal-baby-planets-young-stars-disk</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/swirling-gases-reveal-baby-planets-young-stars-disk</link>
	<description>A new technique pinpointed three planets forming around a young star about 330 light-years from Earth.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061318_LG_baby-planets_feat.jpg?itok=00_ir_2Z" length="16854" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These newfound frogs have been trapped in amber for 99 million years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/frogs-fossils-amber-tropical-forest</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/frogs-fossils-amber-tropical-forest</link>
	<description>Trapped in amber, 99-million-year-old frog fossils reveal the amphibians lived in a wet, tropical climate.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061318_CG_amber-frog_feat.jpg?itok=C5WC7pwP" length="28539" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: An awkward correction later, these researchers have a warning for would-be authors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66663</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/14/an-awkward-correction-later-these-researchers-have-a-warning-for-would-be-authors/</link>
	<description>Mitchell Knutson learned to take a journal’s policies seriously the hard way. Early in 2017, Knutson, a professor at the University of Florida in Gainesville who studies iron metabolism, had findings he and his team were excited about publishing in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS). So they submitted a manuscript on … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/14/an-awkward-correction-later-these-researchers-have-a-warning-for-would-be-authors/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;An awkward correction later, these researchers have a warning for would-be authors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Technology and critical thinking: What can American and Haitian nursing students learn from each other?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/technology-and-critical-thinking-what-can-american-and-haitian-nursing-students-learn-from-each-other</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/technology-and-critical-thinking-what-can-american-and-haitian-nursing-students-learn-from-each-other</link>
	<description>Lessons learned from our annual journeys to Haiti</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 11:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: ‘3 of your 5-a-day’ labels keep the fruit and veggies away</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10239</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/14/3-5-day-labels-keep-fruit-veggies-away/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/smoothies-2253430_640-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do we make sure that nutrition labels making the 5-a-day claim aren’t being used to falsely give the impression that a product is healthy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO 5-a-day fruit and vegetable (FV) guidelines generally recommend consideration of fruit juice as only one FV portion regardless of quantity, for reasons based on processing and fiber breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a product claims to contain two or more portions of your 5-a-day FV, this should come from more than one fruit or vegetable and it should also be ensured that that the serving size is appropriate and the amounts of saturated fat, salt and sugar are limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are government schemes in place in various countries, manufacturers will sometimes make their own claims on food packaging, which are not covered by government regulations. Provided that manufacturers are following the best practice guidelines for the industry, this should mean that the product contains 80g (or more) of fruit or vegetables in one serving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food product labels which highlight the healthy component of a product can have positive impacts of healthy dietary profiles. However, if the ‘healthy component’ of a product is exaggerated, this could lead to negative effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, researchers from Bournemouth University carried out a study, recently published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which investigated the impact of a ‘3 of your 5-a-day’ versus a ‘1 of your 5-a-day’ smoothie product label on subsequent FV consumption. Using an acute experimental design, 194 participants (90 males, 104 females) were randomized to consume a smoothie labelled as either ‘3 of your 5-a-day’ or ‘1 of your 5-a-day’ in full, following a usual breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two FV product labels were used. Each product label stated the product as a ‘smoothie’, included the smoothie flavor, and stated either ‘3 of your 5-a-day’ or ‘1 of your 5-a-day’, using the recognized national UK logo for the 5-a-day FV message. All participants were asked to look at their smoothie before consumption and were required to consume their smoothie in full, although neither the label nor the message were mentioned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequent FV consumption was assessed using 24-h recalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors found that exposure to a ‘3 of your 5-a-day’ FV label following a usual breakfast resulted in reduced subsequent FV consumption compared to exposure to a ‘1 of your 5-a-day’ label. This can probably be explained by the fact that consumers felt they had achieved higher adherence to the dietary goal by consuming the product with this label and therefore allowed themselves lower adherence with subsequent FV consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect viewed was largely driven by changes in consumption in usual high FV consumers, in females, and in vegetable as opposed to fruit consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this study indicate the potentials dangers of providing exaggerated information on food product labels with regards to FV provision. Greater regulation may be required to ensure accuracy in these types of messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/14/3-5-day-labels-keep-fruit-veggies-away/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;‘3 of your 5-a-day’ labels keep the fruit and veggies away&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 08:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/smoothies-2253430_640-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open and Shut?: The OA Interviews: Taylor &amp; Francis' Deborah Kahn discusses Dove Medical Press</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882.post-2195350375857806932</guid>
	<link>https://poynder.blogspot.com/2018/06/the-oa-interviews-taylor-francis.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The open-access publisher Dove Medical Press has a controversial past and I have written about the company on a number of occasions (&lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2008/11/open-access-interviews-dove-medical.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-linked-to-alabama-shooting.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2016/02/why-i-wont-be-doing-that-video.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2017/07/on-sponsorship-transparency-scholarly.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xKYVoxqnpn0/Wx_OcJHaw9I/AAAAAAAAdVg/aZquOe3byWkSVJhEy5PVi53aqxv4mCNlwCLcBGAs/s1600/Kahn.jpg&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;448&quot; data-original-width=&quot;336&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xKYVoxqnpn0/Wx_OcJHaw9I/AAAAAAAAdVg/aZquOe3byWkSVJhEy5PVi53aqxv4mCNlwCLcBGAs/s200/Kahn.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Deborah Kahn&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;When Dove was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebookseller.com/news/taylor-francis-buys-open-access-journal-publisher-dove-medical-644721&quot;&gt;acquired&lt;/a&gt; by Taylor &amp;amp; Francis last September it was assumed (by me at least) that controversy had become a thing of the past for the publisher.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Seven months after the purchase, however, a medical technology company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://minervasurgical.com/&quot;&gt;Minerva Surgical&lt;/a&gt; took the unusual step of publishing a &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/minerva-surgical-requests-immediate-retraction-of-misleading-intl-journal-of-womens-health-publication-that-compares-novasure-to-minerva-sponsored-by-hologic-300637791.html&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; alleging that &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/I1I7CrkEYwi8nAVEQSwP-n3?domain=dovepress.com&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; published in Dove’s &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;International Journal of Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;’&lt;/i&gt;s Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt; makes “material misleading statements” about the nature of a study funded by a rival in “clear violation of the COPE guidelines.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result, Minerva said, the paper should be retracted immediately.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;To discuss this latest incident, Dove’s background, and some of the “historical issues” the publisher has faced, Taylor &amp;amp; Francis’ Director, Medicine and Open Access, agreed to do a Q&amp;amp;A with me, which I publish below.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of the latest controversy Kahn says, “our investigations show that the peer review was carried out to high standards and that the journal behaved well, and the authors responses have satisfied us that the complaints are unfounded.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the historical issues, she adds, the naysayers were wrong to have doubted Dove’s probity. “We went through very detailed due diligence, carrying out an extremely thorough process, when we acquired Dove Medical Press. We were satisfied that, after some historical issues, improvements had been made to their peer review process working with the OASPA membership team … Eight months on from our acquisition, Dove are performing well in all areas, we remain confident that we got value for money, and are delighted that they are part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are one or two places in the Q&amp;amp;A where readers may feel there is a little repetition. If so, this is because the interview was done by email in a staged way. I have, however, not edited the text as I am keen to publish Kahn’s answers exactly as she emailed them to me. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;The Q&amp;amp;A begins …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: I am wondering why Taylor &amp;amp; Francis (T&amp;amp;F) decided to buy Dove Medical Press? I have seen the short &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.taylorandfrancisgroup.com/dove-medical-press-joins-taylor-francis-group/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; published at the time, which talks of Dove journals having Impact Factors (and of T&amp;amp;F wanting to expand in OA and medical journals) but I am also aware that the perception in the market is that (as this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/U80xCjRvnlfnGj58ot4-9e3?domain=statnews.com&quot;&gt;puts it&lt;/a&gt;), titles from Dove “tend to rank poorly on impact factor”. Can you say more about why T&amp;amp;F chose to buy Dove? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Open Access and Medical publishing are both strategically important areas of investment and growth for Taylor &amp;amp; Francis. So we were delighted when we were able to enter into discussions with Dove Medical Press, as they fit so well with our plans. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove Medical Press is a small and entrepreneurial company, with staff based in Auckland and Macclesfield, all of whom are committed to excellent service to authors, and high-quality peer review. They publish around 100 journals, of which 12 have impact factors ranging from 1.7 to 7 –  almost all of them placed within the top two quartiles of the Journal Citation Report. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two more titles are set to receive Impact Factors in the next release of the JCR. The vast majority of the rest of the journals are indexed in the DOAJ, PubMed and the Emerging Sources Citation Index (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mjl.clarivate.com/cgi-bin/jrnlst/jlresults.cgi?PC=EX&quot;&gt;ESCI&lt;/a&gt;). All of these indexes perform in-depth checks on the quality and integrity of the contents of journals before accepting them for indexing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We chose to buy Dove because we were impressed by the quality of their content, the quality of their peer review, their focus on author experience, and their loyal author following, with a high percentage of repeat authors. We rated it a very good business in its own right and knew that we would learn from them as we continued to develop our own open access offerings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: How much did T&amp;amp;F pay for Dove?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; This wasn’t disclosed at the time of acquisition. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://informa.com/media/press-releases-news/latest-news/informa-extends-open-access-position-and-capability-with-addition-of-dove-medical-press/&quot;&gt;press statement&lt;/a&gt; released by Informa, our parent company. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Yes, I saw that, but I was hoping you could tell me anyway? Frankly, I don’t understand why this information needs to be secret, although I suppose it fits with the secrecy that has always surrounded Dove. When I interviewed Dove’s Tim Hill in 2008 he refused to tell me who the owners of Dove were and denied that (despite what some believed) there was any connection between Libertas Academica (LA) and Dove, or with him (aside from the fact that the owner of LA was his son). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then, when in 2010 I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2016/02/why-i-wont-be-doing-that-video.html&quot;&gt;emailed him&lt;/a&gt; to point out that New Zealand Companies House records that he had one time been the sole director and shareholder of LA, and had in fact  been a director of LA when he told me in 2008 that there was no connection, he responded, “Henceforth I will not be providing you with any comment or information on any subject.” In 2016, I tried to make contact with Dove directors Graeme Peterson and Kevin Toale, neither of whom responded. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can you tell me why there has always been this kind of secrecy surrounding Dove? OA advocates argue that scholarly publishing is primarily funded by the taxpayer and so should be transparent both in process and financing. There is now also a widespread belief that there should be even greater transparency with regard to medical research, and those who publish it, not least because it is felt that pay-to-publish OA has made it easier for pharmaceutical and medical device companies to use scholarly papers as marketing tools. Do you agree that there are dangers here and that greater transparency is essential? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; I do believe that there should be transparency in all scholarly publishing, both in traditional subscription and open access publishing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/&quot;&gt;COPE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/&quot;&gt;OASPA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wame.org/&quot;&gt;WAME&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/&quot;&gt;DOAJ&lt;/a&gt; have collaborated to identify &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/resources/guidelines-new/principles-transparency-and-best-practice-scholarly-publishing&quot;&gt;Principles of Transparency and Best Practice in Scholarly Publishing&lt;/a&gt;, and these principles form part of the criteria on which membership applications to those organizations are evaluated. All Dove journals are &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/2JeQrsr&quot;&gt;included in the DOAJ&lt;/a&gt; and have “&lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/faq#thetick&quot;&gt;the tick&lt;/a&gt;”, which means they have met the high level of compliance to these criteria. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;All Dove journals are also members of COPE and have met their membership criteria also.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I don’t think that there has been secrecy around Dove Medical Press. Information about the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.companieshouse.gov.uk/company/04967656&quot;&gt;has been available from Companies House&lt;/a&gt; since they came into existence in 2003. Nothing in our due diligence suggested anything to the contrary. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tim Hill (from Dove) is Tom Hill’s father, and he may have helped his son establish Libertas Academica in the first instance. However, Tim Hill was not involved in the direction or any of the operations of Libertas Academica. No current Dove staff have ever worked with or as part of Libertas Academica, nor do the two companies share any operations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Dove is registered in the UK but, as I understand it, the company actually operates out of New Zealand. Did that present any particular issues during the negotiation process? Does it present any difficulties today?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Dove has offices in both Macclesfield and Auckland with 1/3 of the staff in the UK and 2/3 in New Zealand. These two locations are actually a real advantage, as it means we can offer global coverage and 24-hour customer service. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apart from a few late night and early morning meetings for people in both locations, there are few disadvantages, and as a bonus I have been very much enjoying getting to know Auckland, and reacquainting myself with Macclesfield which is close to where I grew up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Founders and directors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Dove had quite a number of directors. Who did T&amp;amp;F deal with when negotiating the purchase? Was Dove’s MD involved in the negotiations? Apart from the company’s directors (who I believe have all left), have most Dove staff remained with the company? Has the Dove Press Publisher remained?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Dove had three founders all of whom were involved in the negotiations. They have left the business, but almost all of the staff have remained. Dove has a very loyal staff, and it seems has much lower staff turnover than other publishing companies I have worked in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Unfortunately, you didn’t answer my question about the Dove Press Publisher Tim Hill. Is he still with the company? You also did not say whether the Dove MD Graeme Peterson was involved in the negotiations. I would be grateful if you could address these questions? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; The founders of the company were Philip Smith, Kevin Toale and Tim Hill, all of whom have left the company, and with whom we negotiated. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Philip Smith was Managing Director of Dove. Graeme Peterson has never been the Managing Director of Dove. When he became a Director of Dove, he was (and still is) Managing Director of Prime Global (previously Prime Medica). The Companies House listing clearly shows that he was Company Secretary and Director of Dove from 2004 to 2017. His listing shows his occupation as Managing Director, but this was of Prime Global not of Dove.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: You talk of three founders of Dove. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2008/11/open-access-interviews-dove-medical.html&quot;&gt;spoke to&lt;/a&gt; Tim Hill in 2008, he told me the company was founded by “a group of former publishing executives, mostly from ADIS International” and that it was owned by “six private individuals”. Companies House records show there were four directors of the company – Graeme Peterson, Philip Smith, Kevin Toale and John Stolz. The shareholders included Peterson, Smith, Toale, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/william-dolben-96b526/&quot;&gt;William Dolben&lt;/a&gt; (CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.contentednet.com/corporate/content/solutions&quot;&gt;ContentEd&lt;/a&gt;, which offers “a complete publishing service for the pharmaceutical industry”), a company called JSI Communications (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jsi.co.uk/&quot;&gt;medical communications company&lt;/a&gt; owned by John Stolz, who &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsgroups.derkeiler.com/Archive/Comp/comp.sys.mac.misc/2005-09/msg00037.html&quot;&gt;appears&lt;/a&gt; also to have also acted as a Dove commissioning editor) and the T&amp;amp;A Hill Family Trust (which I assume is connected with Tim Hill). Who were the three founders you talked to?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;As I said above, the company was founded by Kevin Toale, Philip Smith and Tim Hill. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;RP: Was T&amp;amp;F aware at the time it made a bid for Dove how controversial the company was? For instance, Dove was one of the first OA publishers to attract criticism for spamming authors (and was &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/-89XCkRwomfOXnW92SxTN6x?domain=gunther-eysenbach.blogspot.co.uk&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;dubbed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; a “black sheep” by Gunther Eysenbach); it has featured on Retraction Watch fairly regularly; it was at one time on Jeffrey Beall’s list of “Potential, possible, or probable predatory scholarly open-access publishers”; it was caught in the &lt;/i&gt;Science&lt;i&gt; open access &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/6eXJCmZ2EotjP5JzyFPaUzP?domain=science.sciencemag.org&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;sting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; (for which it had its &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/RZdxCn5Yzpc73GOv9C5KQYw?domain=oaspa.org&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;membership of OASPA terminated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;); it got mixed up in the &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/qRp7Co2vOqfrPXqE2t8TftA?domain=poynder.blogspot.co.uk&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Dr Amy Bishop incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;; and one of its peer reviewers &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/bz-FCpYRz0unOzMm4tEpNuO?domain=retractionwatch.com&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;roundly condemned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; its publishing platform, saying that it did not even allow reviewers to reject papers. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Did any of this concern T&amp;amp;F during the negotiation process? If so, why did it go ahead with the purchase? What exactly does T&amp;amp;F do in terms of due diligence before it acquires another company? Did it go through this process in the case of Dove?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; We went through very detailed due diligence, carrying out an extremely thorough process, when we acquired Dove Medical Press. We were satisfied that, after some historical issues, improvements had been made to their peer review process working with the OASPA membership team. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/dove-medical-press-reinstated-as-oaspa-members/&quot;&gt;led to their OASPA membership being reinstated&lt;/a&gt;, resulted in an extremely robust peer review process described in detail in their peer review schematic on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/editorial_policies.php?content_id=3526&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In fact, some of the additional checks they have added since that schematic was published go way beyond what most publishers do in their peer review process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;These are in addition to the usual ethical checks which quality medical journals perform, and include: checking the affiliations of all authors and checking retractionwatch.com to identify whether any of the authors have been involved in unethical practices; manuscripts being checked for duplicate submission or publication and run through the SciDetect software; and IP address checks to make sure that there is no COI between author, reviewer and Editor. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Due diligence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Publishing a schematic is surely a good idea. What is key, of course, is routinely following that process. But you didn’t answer my question: what exactly does T&amp;amp;F do in the way of due diligence before it acquires another company?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; All papers submitted to Dove go through the same rigorous process which, as I said, is more rigorous than that on the schematic and than many I have seen in other publishers. Any implication that this is not routinely followed is unfounded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as due diligence is concerned, as part of Informa, all acquisitions by Taylor &amp;amp; Francis go through a very detailed and thorough due diligence. Cross-functional teams of experts from Finance, Legal, Tax, Treasury and Communications meet weekly with the business leads to analyse and assess the risks and considerations concerning any acquisition and follow a detailed process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No acquisition is complete until all questions are answered in detail, and there has been a thorough review by Informa’s senior management. This process was followed with this acquisition. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On Dove’s membership of OASPA: I think it would be fair to say that this has been more of an on-off affair than the above might imply. The timeline is this: Dove joined OASPA in late 2009; Dove withdrew from OASPA on 7th April 2010; Dove applied to join again in May 2012; Dove was re-accepted on 12th July 2012; Dove’s membership was terminated by OASPA on 5th November 2013. Dove reapplied in June 2015 and was accepted on 23rd September 2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;What is not clear is why Dove withdrew from OASPA in 2010. What we do know is that it occurred in the wake of the Amy Bishop affair, in which publicity was given to a controversial paper authored by her and published by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/international-journal-of-general-medicine-journal&quot;&gt;Dove’s International Journal of General Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;. Controversially, Bishop added the names of her minor children as co-authors of the paper. At the time (February 2010) I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-linked-to-alabama-shooting.html&quot;&gt;wrote an article&lt;/a&gt; about the incident in which I raised the issue of ownership and transparency, and quoted Peter Suber saying, “I am deeply suspicious of publishers who are unwilling to disclose their owners. We need that kind of transparency to be able to investigate whether the owners have financial interests, e.g. with pharma companies, that might compromise the integrity of their journals.” When I asked OASPA for the reason Dove had withdrawn I was told, “We had a few exchanges by email following your article and they then withdrew their membership. I asked them if they could give me a reason but they gave none.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here it is worth noting that co-founder of OASPA Gunther Eysenbach &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/response-to-the-recent-article-in-science/#comment-5201&quot;&gt;has repeatedly alleged&lt;/a&gt; that Dove engages in “questionable publishing practices”. And at the time when OASPA terminated Dove’s membership in 2013 he referred back to the Amy Bishop paper and said that it had disappeared from its website without “any proper retraction notice/process”. (The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/effects-of-selective-serotonin-reuptake-inhibitors-on-motor-neuron-sur-peer-reviewed-article-IJGM&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; appears to have been reposted later, again with no indication of its disappearance and reappearance). This will all be part and parcel of what you call Dove’s “historical issues”, but did none of this really give T&amp;amp;F any pause for thought? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; I have already discussed the very detailed due diligence we went through which satisfied us that there are no issues that should concern us with their operations. And in working closely with Dove in the eight months since the acquisition, I have been impressed by their high standards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is absolutely no evidence of any misconduct on Dove’s part, and despite persistent attempts to find some over the years, it doesn’t seem that you have evidence of any wrongdoing either. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is clear that in the two cases you mention, Bishop and Bohannon, authors who set out to deceive the system managed to do so. This showed up some inadequacies in the peer review processes of those journals. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result of the Bohannon sting in 2013 and their OASPA membership being terminated, Dove worked closely with OASPA to improve their editorial processes and the OASPA Membership Committee were satisfied with those improvements. As I mentioned earlier, Dove also continue to enhance those processes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: While we are on the historical issues, in 2011 I was contacted by a US-based publisher who said that Dove had on two occasions launched a journal “identical or nearly identical” to this publisher’s own journals. The publisher added that only after a great deal of pressure from them did Dove change the titles of the two copycat journals. The publisher also pointed out that nine of Dove’s journals had the same EiC, many of which journals were unrelated to that EiC’s specialism. I do not know if this is still the case, but can you confirm that Taylor &amp;amp; Francis would not sanction such things? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; None of the current Dove senior management know anything about this allegation. Dove do have Editors-in-Chief who edit more than one journal, but only in their own specialist area and never more than two or three. Taylor &amp;amp; Francis also have some Editors-in-Chief editing multiple journals, but again only in their specific subject field.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;New controversy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: As you note, many of these things may be historical issues. However, it seems that the controversy over Dove continues after the acquisition. Seven months after T&amp;amp;F purchased Dove, for instance, its &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;International Journal of Women's Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; published &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/I1I7CrkEYwi8nAVEQSwP-n3?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; that has attracted some worrying criticism – as reported recently by STAT. The paper in question compared patient satisfaction with two competing devices for endometrial ablation, and concluded that the product developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/yfJsCv2YjAf7LWNxwCNJUzh?domain=minervasurgical.com&quot;&gt;Minerva Surgical&lt;/a&gt; was inferior to the competing product developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/RbqrCwpEkBHGVL8Klin2NQY?domain=hologic.com&quot;&gt;Hologic&lt;/a&gt; (which funded the study). On April 26th Minerva published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/weEmCxkVlDi1RJMkEU6eZLm?domain=prnewswire.com&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; alleging that the Dove article makes “material misleading statements” about the nature of the study and that this is “a clear violation of the COPE guidelines”. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Writing in STAT, Adam Marcus and Ivan Oransky say, “We can’t judge the essence of Minerva’s claims, although some — particularly that paid personnel for a device maker biased the selection process for patients in the trial — are quite troubling and would constitute grounds for retraction.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;When I raised this on Twitter, T&amp;amp;F &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/D8IeCyP6mEtr2NXZOtmXtBv?domain=twitter.com&quot;&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; that it was “currently working with the editor-in-chief to look into the concerns surrounding this paper”. But in light of Dove’s history does it not cause you some concern that this has occurred not long after the acquisition?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; It is an unfortunate fact of life that all publishers are having to field more and more disputes between academics and researchers. It is keeping COPE very busy, and there are few journals or publishers who have avoided being featured on Retraction Watch’s pages. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the case of the &lt;i&gt;International Journal of Women’s Health&lt;/i&gt; paper our investigations show that the peer review was carried out to high standards and that the journal behaved well, and the authors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; responses have satisfied us that the complaints are unfounded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As per ethical guidelines, we have offered the complainant the chance to write a Letter to the Editor with his concerns, which we would publish along with a response from the authors. However, he has not chosen to do so as yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Can I just check what you are saying: you see nothing untoward or unusual in a publisher appearing fairly frequently on Retraction Watch? And are you implying that the cases COPE deals with are generally the result of disputes between academics and researchers, not of misconduct, faulty peer review or conflicts of interest?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Actually, I don’t. The fact that publishers are amending the scholarly record when they find that there are errors in the literature is a healthy thing. I would be worried if a publisher never retracted anything. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/why-high-profile-journals-have-more-retractions-1.15951&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in Nature shows that journals with higher impact factors have higher levels of retractions, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/why-high-profile-journals-have-more-retractions-1.15951&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; suggests that higher levels of retractions may in fact be a good thing. In fact, this second paper finds that the rising number of retractions is most likely to be caused by a growing propensity to retract flawed and fraudulent papers, and there is little evidence of an increase in the prevalence of misconduct. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And no, you are misinterpreting my previous comment. The cases COPE see fall into nine areas, as outlined in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/core-practices&quot;&gt;core practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On the issue of COIs: My understanding is that the MD of Dove was also the MD of a Medical Education and Communication Companies (MECC), and so presumably was engaged in publication planning. As I noted above, two of the other shareholders appear to have been running MECCs and/or providing publication services for pharmaceutical companies. Do you think that being a shareholder and/or MD of a medical publisher while also being the shareholder and MD or owner of a MECC might raise conflict of interest issues?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; This is a misunderstanding on your part. The MD of Dove was Philip Smith who did not run any other company. As for the shareholders, shareholders in any organization will have a number of interests. None of the shareholders you refer to played an active role in the organization or its operations. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;COIs?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: In March 2017 Dove &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prweb.com/releases/dove-press/nanomedicine-academy/prweb14143325.htm&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it was sponsoring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.northeastern.edu/nanomedicineacademy/&quot;&gt;The Nanomedicine Academy of Minority Serving Institutions at Northeastern University&lt;/a&gt;. The Director and co-founder of this Academy is listed as being on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/journal-editor-international-journal-of-nanomedicine-eic5&quot;&gt;editorial board&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/international-journal-of-nanomedicine-journal&quot;&gt;The International Journal of Nanomedicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, which is a Dove journal and has an impact factor of 4.300. Its website also says that it is indexed in PubMed and Medline. As such, it would seem to be one of the journals that attracted T&amp;amp;F to Dove (In fact, it was singled out for mention in the Informa &lt;a href=&quot;https://informa.com/media/press-releases-news/latest-news/informa-extends-open-access-position-and-capability-with-addition-of-dove-medical-press/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; you cited earlier). The EiC of the journal is the other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.che.neu.edu/news/faculty/368?page=8&quot;&gt;co-founder&lt;/a&gt; of the Nanomedicine Academy, and appears to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/search_results.php?search_word=%22thomas+j+webster%22&quot;&gt;published over 100 papers&lt;/a&gt; with Dove, almost exclusively (if not exclusively) in his own journal (two of the papers seem to have been co-authored with the Director of The Academy). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;I must assume that T&amp;amp;F would have established this during the due diligence process it undertook, and so is comfortable with the arrangement. But I cannot help but think that some would feel it raises conflict of interest issues. What would you say to those who might be concerned about it? Or am I simply misunderstanding the situation and how these things work?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Journals and Publishers often sponsor conferences and educational courses of various types. I think that if you look at the Academy, you will see that it is an academic partnership dedicated to providing education in nanomedicine to minority populations. This sounds like a great educational initiative, and I cannot see any COI from a Publisher donating to an initiative of this kind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as the Editor publishing in his own journal is concerned, COPE guidelines do not preclude editors submitting to their own journals. They do expect journals to “have a procedure for handling submissions from editors or members of the editorial board that will ensure that the peer review is handled independently of the author/editor”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/editorial_policies.php?content_id=3523&quot;&gt;clear guidance&lt;/a&gt; on Editors publishing in their own journals whereby &lt;i&gt;“Editors-in-Chief must declare any financial and/or personal conflict of interest for each submitted manuscript, and decisions on manuscripts in which they have a conflict of interest will be made by another editor”. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No Dove Editor is involved in the peer review of a paper that they are author on, and this is the case with the papers published by this editor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: After SAGE bought Dove’s sister company Libertas Academica it had to &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/ImX0CzpBnGHMwRg6WCLIc6L?domain=plus.google.com&quot;&gt;conclude&lt;/a&gt; that following “detailed review” it was unlikely that many of LA’s journals would be successful over the long-term. As a result, it shuttered over ¼ of those it had acquired. I wonder if Dove might have to do the same. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;On Twitter T&amp;amp;F &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/D8IeCyP6mEtr2NXZOtmXtBv?domain=twitter.com&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; “When any list joins T&amp;amp;F we go through an integration phase where we check on all processes and standards and integrate / amalgamate the best of what both orgs do. This is a process that has happened with Dove and is on-going.” Do you anticipate having to close many Dove journals? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; As I said earlier, Libertas Academica had no connection with Dove and was not a sister company so there is no comparison between the two companies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is good publishing practice to regularly review the journals portfolio, and make changes accordingly. Dove had done this review prior to become part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis and had decided to cease the publication of some journals which were not receiving enough quality submissions to sustain them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We reviewed this list together and agreed with their plans. Some of these journals were closed prior to the acquisition but not all had gone through the process by that point, so some are currently being closed. At the end of this process 92 journals will remain. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Journal closures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: We may disagree over the definition of a sister company, but as noted earlier, the former MD of Libertas Academica is the son of Tim Hill. And according to New Zealand Companies House it was Tim Hill who registered LA, and he was listed as a shareholder until at least 2009. Does that not suggest to you that the companies were connected?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Please see my previous response on this. No Dove staff, now and previously, have ever been involved in the direction or operations of Libertas Academica.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On the issue of journal closures, Wikipedia reports that in 2013 Dove published 131 journals. Unless I am miscounting, the Dove website currently lists 136 journals. This would seem to suggest that 44 (32%) of them are due to be closed – which is a higher percentage than were closed at LA. Is it normal for such a high percentage of journals to be closed after an acquisition? Is T&amp;amp;F still confident that it got value for money in buying Dove?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove Press has launched 136 journals in the last 14 years. Some of these were not successful and were closed. It is not uncommon for this to be the case, and for publishers to close journals which are not thriving. When we acquired Dove they were publishing 109 journals, and we were aware of and agreed with their plans to close 17 of them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eight months on from our acquisition, Dove are performing well in all areas, we remain confident that we got value for money, and are delighted that they are part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Thank you for answering my questions. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 06:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Richard Poynder)</author>
  <source url="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/7961882/posts/default">Open and Shut?</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Does the Mediterranean diet prevent heart attacks? NEJM retracts (and replaces) high-profile paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66677</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/13/does-the-mediterranean-diet-prevent-heart-attacks-nejm-retracts-and-replaces-high-profile-paper/</link>
	<description>The New England Journal of Medicine has retracted a 2013 paper that provided some proof that the Mediterranean diet can directly prevent heart attacks, stroke, and other cardiovascular problems. The original paper, “Primary Prevention of Cardiovascular Disease with a Mediterranean Diet,” has been cited 1,759 times, according to Clarivate Analytics’ Web of Science. But the findings haven’t … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/13/does-the-mediterranean-diet-prevent-heart-attacks-nejm-retracts-and-replaces-high-profile-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Does the Mediterranean diet prevent heart attacks? NEJM retracts (and replaces) high-profile paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Mars rover Opportunity is sleeping, not dead, NASA says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-rover-opportunity-sleeping-not-dead-nasa-says</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mars-rover-opportunity-sleeping-not-dead-nasa-says</link>
	<description>Opportunity is hunkered down in a deep sleep on Mars to ride out what’s looking to be a long dark dust storm.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 20:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061318_LG_mars-opportunity_feat.jpg?itok=PU8rZdw6" length="16240" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What I actually learned about my family after trying 5 DNA ancestry tests</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/family-dna-ancestry-tests-review-comparison</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/family-dna-ancestry-tests-review-comparison</link>
	<description>Ancestry results vary widely depending on which company you use.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/062318_reviews_feat.jpg?itok=o2ltJna7" length="40478" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: DNA testing can bring families together, but gives mixed answers on ethnicity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-testing-ancestry-family-tree</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dna-testing-ancestry-family-tree</link>
	<description>DNA testing has become a new way for millions of Americans to expand their family trees and learn something about themselves, but results vary widely.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/062318_genetics3_opener_1200_REV.jpg?itok=6G36ftLU" length="16849" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s what narwhals sound like underwater</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-narwhals-sound-underwater</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-narwhals-sound-underwater</link>
	<description>Scientists eavesdropped while narwhals clicked and buzzed. The work could help pinpoint how the whales may react to more human noise in the Arctic.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061318_LR_narwhal_feat.jpg?itok=zrtne2Pc" length="40979" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Antarctica has lost about 3 trillion metric tons of ice since 1992</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/antarctica-lost-3-trillion-metric-tons-ice-since-1992-sea-level-rise</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/antarctica-lost-3-trillion-metric-tons-ice-since-1992-sea-level-rise</link>
	<description>Antarctica’s rate of ice loss has sped up since 1992 — mostly in the last five years, raising global sea level by almost 8 millimeters on average.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 17:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061218_LH_antarctica-ice-melt_feat.jpg?itok=85Qf9_NJ" length="33024" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 ways Elsevier is making the world of research more transparent</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-ways-elsevier-is-making-the-world-of-research-more-transparent</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-ways-elsevier-is-making-the-world-of-research-more-transparent</link>
	<description>Our open science initiatives include new ways to measure journal impact and support the reproducibility of research</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 15:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal corrects, but will not retract, controversial paper on internet porn</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66613</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/13/journal-corrects-but-will-not-retract-controversial-paper-on-internet-porn/</link>
	<description>Dismissing concerns of the Committee on Publication Ethics and extensive allegations of misconduct, a journal has corrected, but is refusing to retract, a 2016 paper linking online pornography to sexual dysfunction in men. The article, “Is internet pornography causing sexual dysfunctions? A review with clinical reports,” appeared last year in Behavioral Sciences, which is published … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/13/journal-corrects-but-will-not-retract-controversial-paper-on-internet-porn/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journal corrects, but will not retract, controversial paper on internet porn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Unhealthy sleep patterns and risk of metabolic syndrome</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10224</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/13/unhealthy-sleep-patterns-risk-metabolic-syndrome/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/sleep-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like good diet and exercise, sleep is a critical component to overall health. Current sleep guidelines recommend that adults between the ages of 26 and 64 sleep 7-8 hours per night and practice healthy sleep hygiene which includes limiting daytime naps to 30 minutes, avoiding stimulants such as caffeine and energy drinks before bedtime and avoiding heavy or rich foods before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous research has shown that insufficient as well as excessive sleep are associated with health-related conditions such as hypertension, obesity, diabetes, cardiovascular events or mortality and stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolic syndrome, which is highly prevalent in Korea, is defined as a metabolic disorder consisting of at least three of the following: elevated waist circumference, high triglyceride levels, low high-density ‘good’ cholesterol levels (HDL-C), hypertension and high fasting glucose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Seoul National University College of Medicine have carried out the largest study examining a dose-response relationship between sleep duration and metabolic syndrome and its components in 133,608 Korean men and women aged 40-69 years. To do this, they used data from the HEXA study, a large-scale community-based study conducted in Korea during the years 2004-2013, which included information on socio-demographic characteristics, medical history, medication use, family history, lifestyle factors, diet, physical activity, and reproductive factors for women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep duration was assessed by asking the question: “In the past year, on average, how many hours/minutes of sleep (including daytime naps) did you take per day?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-10227 size-medium&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/slimming-2728331_640-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;The study, published today in &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, finds that compared to individuals who sleep six to seven hours per day, men who sleep fewer than six hours are more likely to have metabolic syndrome and higher waist circumference. Women who sleep fewer than six hours are more likely to have higher waist circumference. Furthermore, sleeping more than ten hours per day was associated with metabolic syndrome and increased levels of triglycerides in men, and with metabolic syndrome, higher waist circumference, higher levels of triglycerides and blood sugar, as well as low HDL-C in women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact mechanisms for the gender differences observed are unclear but a possible explanation is that women experiencing menopausal transition face erratic fluctuations and eventual decline in estrogens as well as ovarian estradiol which may lead to frequent sleep disruptions, a common characteristic of long sleep duration. Another theory is that women may have shorter circadian periods which contributes to higher insomnia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-10228 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;169&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/macaron-2462247_640-300x169.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;The biological mechanisms that underlie the association between sleep duration and metabolic syndrome are also unclear but potential factors include levels of hormones which increase appetite and caloric intake or reduce energy expenditure in people who sleep less than seven hours per day, which may lead to increased waist circumference and development of obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the cross-sectional, observational nature of this study does not allow for conclusions about cause and effect. Estimates of sleep duration were based on self-report data rather than objective measures and may reflect ‘time in bed’, actual time spent asleep or time people believed they slept. Also, as the study did not distinguish between daytime naps and nighttime sleep, their impact on health could not be assessed separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/13/unhealthy-sleep-patterns-risk-metabolic-syndrome/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Unhealthy sleep patterns and risk of metabolic syndrome&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 08:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/sleep-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Jessus critics defiant, reactionary cock-up and Chicken of Dishonour Legion</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24510</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/13/jessus-critics-defiant-reactionary-cock-up-and-chicken-of-dishonour-legion/</link>
	<description>ch science revolution is happening, and the corrupt elites are scared. As the daily Le Monde started brought into the public light the Catherine Jessus affair with its whitewashed data manipulation and the growing academic protest against such institutional endorsement of research misconduct, a counter-revolution put its foot in. A signature list in the worst … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/13/jessus-critics-defiant-reactionary-cock-up-and-chicken-of-dishonour-legion/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Jessus critics defiant, reactionary cock-up and Chicken of Dishonour Legion&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 05:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Honoring Karen Hunter — a pioneer of digital publishing and library services</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/honoring-karen-hunter-a-pioneer-of-digital-publishing-and-library-services</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/honoring-karen-hunter-a-pioneer-of-digital-publishing-and-library-services</link>
	<description>In her four decades at Elsevier, she led groundbreaking initiatives in scholarly communications in partnership with the research community</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This heavy element has a football-shaped atomic nucleus</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heavy-element-has-football-shaped-atomic-nucleus</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heavy-element-has-football-shaped-atomic-nucleus</link>
	<description>Three nobelium isotopes have oblong nuclei, and some sport a ‘bubble’ center.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061218_ec_nobelium_feat_free.jpg?itok=uy-MsXHs" length="10302" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In her short life, mathematician Emmy Noether changed the face of physics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/emmy-noether-theorem-legacy-physics-math</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/emmy-noether-theorem-legacy-physics-math</link>
	<description>A century after she published a groundbreaking mathematical theory, Emmy Noether gets her due.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/062318_noether_opener_opt1.jpg?itok=yAtcz1_e" length="36706" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Open science: 4 ways Elsevier is contributing to a more inclusive world of research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-4-ways-elsevier-is-contributing-to-a-more-inclusive-world-of-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-4-ways-elsevier-is-contributing-to-a-more-inclusive-world-of-research</link>
	<description>We’re giving researchers more options to share more kinds of information</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
