<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: Colliding black holes are reported for a fifth time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/colliding-black-holes-are-reported-fifth-time</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/colliding-black-holes-are-reported-fifth-time</link>
	<description>LIGO spots another merger, this time with less fanfare.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111617_to_ticker-black-hole_free.jpg?itok=T_g2qGxQ" length="20650" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Criminal Brain: Fact or Fiction?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23105</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/16/criminal-brain-fact-or-fiction/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;When we are confronted with the acts of excessive and unprovoked violence, we can’t help but wonder what is wrong with individuals committing such crimes. Think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/04/18/mass-murderer-psychology-the-patterns-of-horror/&quot;&gt;serial killers&lt;/a&gt;: what motivates them? Both researchers and society, in general, have wanted to know how to explain the extreme brutality observed in some people. In most cases, they have no mental disorders that could explain their behavior. Even without going to the extremes, most of us did at some point in life come across people whose level of aggressiveness seemed beyond any reasonable explanation. Think of a hooligan looking for any excuse to pick a fight and beat someone up. Or a young boy torturing a defenseless animal with a smile on his face.  Multiple theories were invented to this end, ranging from religious explanations (satanic possession) to scientific and psychological theories that involve a variety of mental disorders or problems with brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that excessive aggressiveness and criminal tendency might be heritable traits gained popularity with the publication of Dr. Cesare Lombroso’s book “Criminal Man” in 1878. In the book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/05/18/decoding-the-neural-pathway-from-psychopathy-to-serial-murder/&quot;&gt;Lombroso &lt;/a&gt;introduced the concept of the “born criminal”. He also developed the field of criminal anthropology that studied specific anatomical differences between normal and criminal individuals. Lombroso’s theory contributed to the science of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/02/15/star-wars-yesterdays-sci-fi-is-todays-reality/&quot;&gt;eugenics &lt;/a&gt;that played a crucial role in the Nazi ideology of selective breeding of a superior race and the policy of exterminating the &lt;em&gt;Untermenschen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Lombroso was eventually proven wrong, the concept that criminal behavior might be linked with genes survived. Evidence that criminal and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/03/who-is-and-is-not-a-violent-sexual-offender/&quot;&gt;violent behaviors &lt;/a&gt;run in some families was a particularly strong argument to investigate the issue further. These investigations produced rather interesting discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question to what degree the predisposition for crime might be genetically determined was first answered by a twin study performed in Denmark. Twins are ideal subjects for genetic research: identical twins have exactly the same sets of genes, while non-identical twins are as similar to each other as usual brothers and sisters. However, both identical and non-identical twins, if brought up together, can be considered as having the same upbringing. The study compared the rate of crime offenses among the identical twins with this rate in non-identical twins. It turned out that a Danish man with an identical twin who has a criminal record is 50% more likely to be an offender himself, as compared with the average Danish man. In non-identical twins, the chances of both of them having the criminal records are 15-30% higher than the average for the population. The findings definitely point to a degree of genetic predisposition. In addition, another study performed in Sweden has shown that when the identical twins were brought up separately, the chances of developing a criminal career were higher among children from parents with criminal records, even when the children were brought up in law-abiding adopted families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twin studies can detect correlations but certainly can’t help in finding out which genes are behind these correlations. The study performed in the Netherlands provided important information on the possible identity of such genes. Researchers have studied genetic defects in one particular family with 14 males spanning 4 generations that displayed an unusually high level of aggression and criminal offenses. The subjects in question had very low IQ (around 85) and were prone to impulsive behavior and physical and sexual violence. The researchers found a specific hereditary defect in the family: the gene for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/12/06/the-science-of-raising-a-friendly-psychopath/&quot;&gt;monoamine oxidase A&lt;/a&gt; (MAOA) was mutated. Mutation prevented the enzyme from working properly. This is important as this enzyme is responsible for breaking down neurotransmitters, including serotonin, dopamine, and noradrenaline. A lack of MAOA activity leads to the rising of neurotransmitter levels in the brain and they, in turn, cause the over-excitation of neurons. The gene for MAOA is located on the X chromosome, and this explains why high levels of aggression were observed only in males. Meanwhile, females have a second X chromosome with the non-mutated functional version of the gene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important question, which sparked fierce ethical debate, is to what extent criminal behavior might indeed be genetically programmed. This is a classic discussion of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/12/06/the-science-of-raising-a-friendly-psychopath/&quot;&gt;nature vs nurture&lt;/a&gt;. To what extent do our genes make us who we are? We easily accept the fact that some people are born smarter or physically stronger than the rest of us. We know that genes are involved in making these individuals who they are. Genes responsible for stronger muscles or better brain connections allow these people to excel where others may struggle. Nonetheless, the idea that some of us are born with a predisposition for a higher level of aggression or reduced empathy appears very unpalatable to many people. However, this idea makes perfect biological sense. We evolved as hunter-gatherers, and at this stage of our evolutionary history, aggressiveness was crucially important for survival. Genetically, we didn’t change since the Stone Age. And this aggressiveness still plays an important role in our society, from competition in the workplace to multiple armed conflicts around the world. Aggression levels, like many other human behavioral traits, can be genetically determined to a degree. This means that there is variability: in some people, the level of aggressiveness is very low, while in others it can be quite high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggressiveness still doesn’t equal crime: although violent crime requires a perpetrator to be aggressive, the two things are not the same. Social factors still play a key role when it comes to the expression of aggressive behavior. It works the same way with other genetic attributes. A born athlete will never reach his Olympic dream and could turn into a couch potato if they don’t train. Most scientists, even the very successful ones, are not born geniuses: they simply worked and studied hard. Similarly, people with a predisposition for higher levels of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/06/20/the-role-of-serotonin-and-glutamine-in-aggression/&quot;&gt;aggression &lt;/a&gt;are at higher risk of becoming criminals when they are exposed to the social factors that lead them in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baum ML (2013) The Monoamine Oxidase A (MAOA) Genetic Predisposition to Impulsive Violence: Is It Relevant to Criminal Trials? Neuroethics 6, 287-306. doi: 10.1007/s12152-011-9108-6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brunner HG; Nelen MR; van Zandvoort P; Abeling NGGM; van Gennip AH; Wolters EC; Kuiper MA; Ropers HH; van Oost BA (1993) X-linked borderline mental retardation with prominent behavioral disturbance: phenotype, genetic localization, and evidence for disturbed monoamine metabolism. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 52 (6): 1032–9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PubMed_Identifier&quot;&gt;PMID&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8503438&quot;&gt;8503438&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buades-Rotger, M., &amp;amp; Gallardo-Pujol, D. (2014). The role of the monoamine oxidase A gene in moderating the response to adversity and associated antisocial behavior: a review. Psychology Research and Behavior Management, 7, 185–200. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.2147/PRBM.S40458&quot;&gt;10.2147/PRBM.S40458&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christiansen KO. Seriousness of criminality and concordance among Danish twins. In: Hood R, editor. Crime, Criminology and Public Policy. The Free Press; New York: 1974. pp. 63–77.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrington DP, Gundry G, West DJ (1975) The familial transmission of criminality. Med Sci Law 15(3):177-86. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177/002580247501500306&quot;&gt;10.1177/002580247501500306&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hunter P (2010) The psycho gene. EMBO Rep. 11 (9): 667–9. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038%2Fembor.2010.122&quot;&gt; 10.1038/embor.2010.122&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendler, K. S., Lönn, S. L., Morris, N. A., Sundquist, J., Långström, N., &amp;amp; Sundquist, K. (2014). A Swedish national adoption study of criminality. Psychological Medicine, 44(9), 1913–1925. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291713002638&quot;&gt;10.1017/S0033291713002638&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/search?author1=Rose+McDermott&amp;amp;sortspec=date&amp;amp;submit=Submit&quot;&gt;McDermott&lt;/a&gt; R et al. (2009) Monoamine oxidase A gene (MAOA) predicts behavioral aggression following provocation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 106, 2118–2123. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0808376106&quot;&gt;10.1073/pnas.0808376106&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taylor S (2013) Criminal Minds: The Infuence of the Monoamine Oxidase AGenotype and Environmental Stressors on Aggressive Behaviour. Burgmann Journal II, 71-77. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.academia.edu/8745313/Criminal_Minds_The_Influence_of_the_Monoamine_Oxidase_A_Genotype_and_Environmental_Stressors_on_Aggressive_Behaviour&quot;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/TheDigitalArtist-202249/&quot;&gt;TheDigitalArtist&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: WHO asks dozens of journals to correct papers on diagnostic tool developed by former collaborators</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52636</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/asks-dozens-journals-correct-papers-diagnostic-tool-developed-former-collaborators/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In one of the largest such requests we’ve ever heard of, the World Health Organization has asked 46 journals to correct articles that refer to a bone fracture risk diagnostic tool as developed or endorsed by the WHO. By WHO’s count, the tool — known as Fracture Risk Assessment Tool (FRAX), which has come under […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/asks-dozens-journals-correct-papers-diagnostic-tool-developed-former-collaborators/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WHO asks dozens of journals to correct papers on diagnostic tool developed by former collaborators&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A physics journal agreed to retract a paper several months ago. It’s still not retracted.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52606</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/physics-journal-agreed-retract-paper-several-months-ago-still-not-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A physics journal says it has planned for several months to retract a 2006 paper by a prominent researcher with multiple retractions, after a concerned reader notified the editor about extensive duplication. But, more than seven months after receiving the complaint, the journal Thin Solid Films has not yet taken action. So what’s taking so […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/16/physics-journal-agreed-retract-paper-several-months-ago-still-not-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A physics journal agreed to retract a paper several months ago. It’s still not retracted.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, artificial limbs weren’t nearly as responsive</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-artificial-limbs-werent-nearly-responsive</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-artificial-limbs-werent-nearly-responsive</link>
	<description>Artificial limbs have come a long way since 1967.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/102717_CM_50YA_prosthetic_main.jpg?itok=dt2mynco" length="22789" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: The new faces of data science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-new-faces-of-data-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/the-new-faces-of-data-science</link>
	<description>Today’s data scientists are using interdisciplinary methods to take the field into the future</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 11:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Study casts doubt on whether adult brain’s memory-forming region makes new cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/study-casts-doubt-whether-adult-brain-hippocampus-makes-new-cells</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/study-casts-doubt-whether-adult-brain-hippocampus-makes-new-cells</link>
	<description>An examination of 54 human brains suggests that adults don’t grow new neurons in the hippocampus, contrary to several widely accepted studies.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_LS_hippocampus_feat.jpg?itok=_Gvy5Jts" length="91104" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: People who think they exercise less than their peers die earlier, regardless of their actual activity levels</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32582</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/16/people-who-think-they-exercise-less-than-their-peers-die-earlier-regardless-of-their-actual-activity-levels/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32592&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-520166146.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32592&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32592&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;FangXiaNuo&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Man with a basketball in a locker room&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/16/people-who-think-they-exercise-less-than-their-peers-die-earlier-regardless-of-their-actual-activity-levels/man-with-a-basketball-in-a-locker-room/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-520166146.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Adjusting for actual physical activity, individuals who perceived themselves as less active than others were up to 71 per cent more likely to die in the follow-up period&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organization (WHO), physical inactivity is the fourth-leading risk factor for global mortality, causing an estimated 3.2 million deaths around the world annually. Readers of this blog need no convincing that it’s important to be active every day. But is spending more time on it enough to reduce the risk of early death? Not necessarily. How we perceive this activity turns out to be just as important. We learn of this from the authors of an &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31316-001&quot;&gt;intriguing study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Health Psychology&lt;/i&gt; devoted to physical activity and mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32582&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octavia Zahrt and Alia Crum at Stanford University were inspired by an &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2007/04/16/is-the-benefit-of-exercise-a-placebo-effect/&quot;&gt;earlier experiment&lt;/a&gt; involving hotel room attendants who completed a 20-minute intervention informing them that their daily work satisfied exercise recommendations and highlighting the benefits of this active lifestyle. This intervention not only shifted room attendants’ perceptions, but also resulted in health improvements including lower blood pressure and reductions in weight and body fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zahrt and Crum examined data from 61,141 Americans (selected to be representative of the general population) to determine whether the way we think about our own physical activity could be of major and long-term significance for health. The data came from the US National Health Interview Survey and the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, which included questions assessing how much exercise individuals think they get compared with their peers. The surveys also asked respondents detailed questions about actual physical activity they had undertaken. The researchers cross-checked these survey data against the National Death Index records as they stood 21 years after the exercise surveys had been completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers expected, perceived physical activity relative to peers was closely associated with risk of dying. Even after adjusting for actual levels of physical activity, individuals who perceived themselves as less active than others were up to 71 per cent more likely to die in the follow-up period than those who perceived themselves as more active. One can say with confidence that individuals’ perceptions about their level of physical activity were strongly related to their longevity, even after accounting for the effects of actual physical activity and other known determinants of mortality such as smoking or obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few potential explanations. A convincing one is that perceptions can affect motivation. For instance, a room attendant’s awareness that she is getting exercise at work might increase her confidence and commitment to a healthy lifestyle, and motivate her to act on this “active” identity. Conversely, longitudinal research shows that individuals who perceive themselves as unfit compared with their friends are less likely to exercise a year later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another potential mechanism is that perceptions can have emotional consequences. Public health messages often warn of the “life-threatening consequences” of physical inactivity. A person’s perception that she/he is inactive might thus lead to fear and stress about not getting enough exercise, with harmful consequences for health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still another explanation is that our positive beliefs and expectations can directly induce physiological responses, even following inert treatments, as shown by the placebo effect (similarly, negative expectations can lead to a harmful “nocebo effect”). Following this logic, participants in the current research who failed to realise that they were getting good exercise may not have experienced its full physiological benefits. Conversely, negative expectations related to the belief that one is not getting enough exercise could have become self-fulfilling because of nocebo-like effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we are not able to give a conclusive answer to the question of which of these mechanisms is most important. Perhaps a constellation of them? Or maybe there is another, unknown process involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the mechanisms at play, what do these results mean for mere mortals, and for those who are involved in promoting an active lifestyle? Instead of working out, should we stand in front of the mirror and repeat to ourselves “I’m an active and physically fit person”? To be clear, the authors warn that their findings don’t mean exercise is unimportant. Separate from the influence of our perceptions, physical activity continues to be a crucial determinant of health. However, a more thorough understanding of these results could help us optimise public health messages, finding the happy medium between highlighting that people need to exercise more, but not to the extent that they become downhearted about the exercise they do get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further studies will doubtlessly bring us more answers, but before that happens, let’s get up, walk away from the desk, and look at our activity with friendlier eyes than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-31316-001&quot;&gt;Perceived physical activity and mortality: Evidence from three nationally representative U.S. samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-14208&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;14208&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tomasz Witkowski - doktor psychologii.\r\nPwsin 2006\/10\/20\r\nfot.K.Zuczkowski&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tomasz Witkowski – doktor psychologii. Pwsin 2006/10/20 fot.K.Zuczkowski&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=682&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1181,1772&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/24/why-do-we-enjoy-reality-tv-researchers-say-its-more-about-empathy-than-humiliation/tomasz-witkowski-doktor-psychologii-pwsin-20061020fot-k-zuczkowski/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_6069.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Dr Tomasz Witkowski&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Tomasz is a psychologist and science writer who specialises in debunking pseudoscience in the field of psychology, psychotherapy and diagnosis. He has published over a dozen books, dozens of scientific papers and over 100 popular articles (some of them in &lt;em&gt;Skeptical Inquirer&lt;/em&gt;). In 2016 his latest book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Psychology-Led-Astray-Science-Therapy/dp/1627346090&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychology Led Astray: Cargo Cult in Science and Therapy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was published by BrownWalker Press. He blogs at &lt;a href=&quot;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;https://forbiddenpsychology.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32582/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32582/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32582&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 09:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Improved diagnostics fail to halt the rise of tuberculosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23000</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/v5vn30w_OSc/nature.2017.23000</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;TB remains a big killer despite the development of a better test for detecting the disease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23000&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/v5vn30w_OSc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cyclin D–CDK4 kinase destabilizes PD-L1 via Cul3SPOP to control cancer immune surveillance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25015</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4cul-bAjJac/nature25015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Treatments that target immune checkpoints, such as the one mediated by programmed cell death protein 1 (PD-1) and its ligand PD-L1, have been approved for treating human cancers with durable clinical benefit1,2. However, many cancer patients fail to respond to anti-PD-1/PD-L1 treatment, and the underlying mechanism(s) is not well understood3–5. Recent studies revealed that response to PD-1/PD-L1 blockade might correlate with PD-L1 expression levels in tumor cells6,7. Hence, it is important to mechanistically understand the pathways controlling PD-L1 protein expression and stability, which can offer a molecular basis to improve the clinical response rate and efficacy of PD-1/PD-L1 blockade in cancer patients. Here, we report that PD-L1 protein abundance is regulated by cyclin D-CDK4 and the Cullin 3SPOP E3 ligase via proteasome-mediated degradation. Inhibition of CDK4/6 in vivo elevates PD-L1 protein levels, largely by inhibiting cyclin D–CDK4-mediated phosphorylation of SPOP and thereby promoting SPOP degradation by APC/CCdh1. Loss-of-function mutations in SPOP compromise ubiquitination-mediated PD-L1 degradation, leading to increased PD-L1 levels and reduced numbers of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) in mouse tumors and in primary human prostate cancer specimens. Notably, combining CDK4/6 inhibitor treatment with anti-PD-1 immunotherapy enhances tumor regression and dramatically improves overall survival rates in mouse tumor models. Our study uncovers a novel molecular mechanism for regulating PD-L1 protein stability by a cell cycle kinase and reveals the potential for using combination treatment with CDK4/6 inhibitors and PD-1/PD-L1 immune checkpoint blockade to enhance therapeutic efficacy for human cancers. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature25015&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature25015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4cul-bAjJac&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Firing patterns in the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-15:/2017/11/15/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/15/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Julia will present the paper by Naud et al (2008) 'Firing patterns in the AdEx IF model'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article the authors explore the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model as a good tool to simulate large-scale spiking neuron networks.
They show that the AdEx model generates multiple firing patterns in response to the parameter values.
In order to describe the transition from one pattern to another, the phase diagrams are analysed in the article.
To further classify the firing patterns, the transient response to step current is studied.
The analytical solutions are given for continuous adaptation, initial bursting, regular bursting, tonic spiking and irregular spiking as a response to the constant current.
It is also concluded, that the network simulations of a large systems, such as thalamocortical, require the description of different neuron types.
Parameter sets for three neuron types are provided, but further work is needed to extend this to a larger number of neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full article could be found here: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 21:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How dad’s stress changes his sperm</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-dad-stress-changes-sperm</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-dad-stress-changes-sperm</link>
	<description>Stress may change sperm via packets of RNA in the epididymis, a mouse study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 20:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111517_LS_spermstress_feat.jpg?itok=m4GYdBfl" length="8306" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The brain’s helper cells have a hand in learning fear</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-helper-cells-astrocytes-learning-fear</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-helper-cells-astrocytes-learning-fear</link>
	<description>After a traumatic experience, rat brains release inflammatory signals that come from astrocytes, suggesting a new role for the brain’s “helper” cells.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 19:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_BO_astrocytes_fear_main.jpg?itok=-QbFqRxr" length="45533" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In science, some big risks are worth the rewards</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-some-big-risks-are-worth-rewards</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/science-some-big-risks-are-worth-rewards</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill says scientists sometimes take risks that can lead to significant rewards and important discoveries.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers inspired by SN 10 scientists’ research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-inspired-sn-10-scientists%E2%80%99-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-inspired-sn-10-scientists%E2%80%99-research</link>
	<description>Readers wanted to know more about the scientists' research who were profiled in &quot;The SN 10: Scientists to watch.&quot;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Haze keeps Pluto cool by kicking heat out to space</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/haze-keeps-pluto-cool-kicking-heat-out-space</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/haze-keeps-pluto-cool-kicking-heat-out-space</link>
	<description>Pluto may be the only place in the solar system whose atmosphere is kept cool by solid hazes, not warmed by gas.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111417_LG_plutohaze_feat.jpg?itok=RFYal-3_" length="21493" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How Asian nomadic herders built new Bronze Age cultures</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-asian-nomadic-herders-built-new-bronze-age-cultures</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/how-asian-nomadic-herders-built-new-bronze-age-cultures</link>
	<description>Ancient steppe herders traveled into Europe and Asia, leaving their molecular mark and building Bronze Age cultures.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_nomads_main.jpg?itok=fuuMCUTF" length="30596" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal replaces anti-vaccine paper it retracted for missing conflicts, “number of errors”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52616</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/journal-replaces-anti-vaccine-paper-retracted-missing-conflicts-number-errors/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal retracted a paper about how conflicts of interest might be influencing research into the link between vaccines and autism because — wait for it — the authors failed to disclose conflicts of interest. According to the retraction notice, the editors retracted the paper without the authors’ agreement, because the authors had a host […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/journal-replaces-anti-vaccine-paper-retracted-missing-conflicts-number-errors/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal replaces anti-vaccine paper it retracted for missing conflicts, “number of errors”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 16:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO of Science Exchange Elected to the Board of Directors of the Drug, Chemical &amp; Associated Technologies Association (DCAT)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1185</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/elizabeth-iorns-ph-d-ceo-of-science-exchange-elected-to-the-board-of-directors-of-the-drug-chemical-associated-technologies-association-dcat/</link>
	<description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elizabeth-DCAT-2-Image.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Elizabeth Iorns elected to DCAT Board&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1187&quot; height=&quot;179&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elizabeth-DCAT-2-Image-300x179.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, November 15, 2017 &lt;/strong&gt;– &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform for outsourced research and development (R&amp;amp;D) services, announced today that Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO of Science Exchange, has been elected to serve her first term on the Board of Directors of the Drug, Chemical &amp;amp; Associated Technologies Association (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dcat.org&quot;&gt;DCAT&lt;/a&gt;) beginning November 1, 2017.  Members of DCAT’s Board of Directors are charged with the important work of guiding the organization’s strategic initiatives and activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to have Dr. Iorns join the Board of Directors,” said DCAT Executive Director Margaret Timony. “She brings a unique mix of leadership experiences that will add a valuable perspective to the board.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am honored to join the board and work together with this great team to address key initiatives related to the pharmaceutical industry,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “Our mission at Science Exchange is to help accelerate innovation and scientific discoveries, and as a scientist myself, I feel joining DCAT’s board is a perfect opportunity for me to share my ideas and insights to support and advance its programs and services.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About DCAT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.sidekickopen04.com/e1t/c/5/f18dQhb0S7lC8dDMPbW2n0x6l2B9nMJW7t5XYg1pNBLMW2BFXSH1px69sW5wvxsz56dGNDf3sZLX602?t=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dcat.org&amp;amp;si=6467023554215936&amp;amp;pi=635dcd19-3532-498c-8c9d-33b9023d9790&quot;&gt;Drug, Chemical &amp;amp; Associated Technologies Association (DCAT) &lt;/a&gt;is a not-for-profit, global business development association whose unique membership model integrates both innovator and generic drug manufacturers and suppliers of ingredients, development and manufacturing services, and related technologies. We are committed to provide programs, events and services that help our members meet their business objectives, expand their network of customers and suppliers, and gain insight into industry trends, markets, and those issues impacting pharmaceutical development and manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore Science Exchange’s network of qualified service providers for:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/contract-manufacturing-services?indexType=services&quot;&gt;Contract Manufacturing Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/biologics-manufacturing?page=1&quot;&gt;Biopharmaceutical Manufacturing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/bioprocess-scale-up-development-and-validation?page=1&quot;&gt;Bioprocess Development, Validation and Scaleup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/manufacturing-api?page=1&quot;&gt;Manufacturing, API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/marketplace/evaluation-of-api-suppliers?page=1&quot;&gt;API Sourcing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 16:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Silver Lab: NeuroMatic 3.0 Released</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://silverlab.org/?p=1757</guid>
	<link>http://silverlab.org/2017/11/15/neuromatic-3-0-released/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neuromatic.thinkrandom.com/&quot;&gt;NeuroMatic&lt;/a&gt;, developed by the Silver Lab’s Jason Rothman, is a collection of WaveMetrics Igor Pro software tools for acquiring, analyzing and simulating electrophysiological data. By merging a wide range of tools into a single package, NeuroMatic facilitates a more integrated style of research. Being open source and of modular design, NeuroMatic allows users to develop their own analysis functions that can be easily incorporated into NeuroMatic’s framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 3.0 is available for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neuromatic.thinkrandom.com/&quot;&gt;free download&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Version 3.0 Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data acquisition via NIDAQ or ITC devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continous, episodic and triggered acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;online analysis during acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;import functions for Axograph, Pclamp (ABF) and HDF5 files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scaling, averaging, time-scale alignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;max, min, level, rise/decay time, slope measurements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stability/stationarity analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;event detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waveform template matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spike detection and spike-raster plots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inter-spike-interval and peri-stimulus time histograms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;curve fitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waveform pulse generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stoichastic synaptic release simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synaptic plasticity simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integrate-and-fire (IAF) simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;single-compartment Hodgkin-Huxley-like simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compact easy-to-use interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extra space for your own buttons and controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modular design as a basis for your own functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;semi-automatic macro generation for batch processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s extensive library of built-in functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s publication-quality graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;access to Igor’s detailed command history log&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Igor runs on Macintosh and Windows computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://silverlab.org/feed/">The Silver Lab</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Oops — paper included proofreader’s query</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52540</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/caught-notice-oops-paper-included-proofreaders-query/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Concise Review: Mesenchymal Stem Cells in Neurodegenerative Diseases What Caught Our Attention: Everyone makes mistakes — but some are more amusing than others. In one recent correction, the publisher (Wiley) admitted to including a proofreader’s query in the published manuscript. But didn’t say what the query was. We looked around, and think we found the added […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/15/caught-notice-oops-paper-included-proofreaders-query/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Oops — paper included proofreader’s query&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Coconut crabs are a bird’s worst nightmare</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/coconut-crab-bird-attack</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/coconut-crab-bird-attack</link>
	<description>A biologist witnesses a coconut crab taking out a blue-footed booby and documents the balance of the animals in an Indian Ocean archipelago.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111317_SZ_coconutcrab_feat.jpg?itok=MOY5-kjV" length="44086" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Men and women interpret the sexual intent behind dating behaviours very differently</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32548</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/15/men-and-women-interpret-the-sexual-intent-behind-dating-behaviours-very-differently/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-17&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-155442288.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32571&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32571&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;10&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1275660887&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;The Power of Forever Photography&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;45&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Retro 70's Couple on a Date at the Roller Rink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Retro 70’s Couple on a Date at the Roller Rink&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2108,1422&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/15/men-and-women-interpret-the-sexual-intent-behind-dating-behaviours-very-differently/retro-70s-couple-on-a-date-at-the-roller-rink/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155442288.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Men tend to overestimate the sexual intent behind women’s behaviours on a date&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re out one evening with someone you met recently – you take your date’s hand in yours, or compliment your date’s appearance, or you kiss him or her passionately. For each behaviour, how likely is it that you wanted to have sex with that person for the first time? Researchers have put this question to heterosexual women, then they’ve asked men how they would interpret a woman’s intentions if she had behaved in these ways. The contrast in their answers is striking: men judge woman’s sexual intent as much higher than women do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could conclude from this that men read sex into situations where it isn’t there. But another explanation could be that men aren’t far off – it’s just that women under-report their true intentions. Which is closer to the truth? And what about men’s own sexual intentions – do women get those right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-30260-001&quot;&gt;new article&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Personality and Social&lt;/i&gt; Psychology,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;involving hundreds of US participants recruited online, Isabelle Engeler from IESE Business School and Priya Raghubir at New York University shine some light on the different ways men and women interpret the same dating behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32548&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers asked some of their participants what their sexual intent would be if they acted in various ways on a date, and then to estimate the intent of another person of the same or opposite sex if they’d acted in those same ways. Consistent with past research, women’s ratings of their own sexual intention were 23 per cent lower than men’s average estimates of female intent based on the same behaviours and comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out if this might partly be due to women underestimating their own intentions, the researchers reversed the order of the questions for other participants – they first estimated other people’s sexual intentions based on a given set of behaviors, and only after this, stated their own intentions based on their display of the same behaviours. The idea behind reversing the questions is that you normalise the topic and relax the person into answering more honestly when you turn the focus to them (the researchers reasoned that women in particular might feel under pressure to answer in a socially appropriate manner, especially when the first question was focused on them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the question order reversed, women provided higher ratings of their own sexual intent – arguably because they were now answering more honestly. This shrunk the gap between their own and men’s perspective on their intentions to eight per cent. Based on a comparison of women’s answers depending on whether they were asked the question about their own intentions first or second, the researchers’ best guess is that around half of the perspective gap between genders is the result of women underreporting their intent, and the rest due to men’s overestimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about men’s and women’s interpretation of men’s sexual intent? Some past studies suggested that women overestimate male sexual intentions, albeit to a smaller degree than men’s overestimation of women’s intent. In the current research, the standard question sequence reproduced this finding. But in the reversed question sequence, the gap closed, suggesting that any female overestimation of men’s intentions is “entirely (100 per cent) attributable to men underreporting their sexual intentions.” In fact, there was even an indication that women may be underestimating what men really want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results suggest that, at least in a heterosexual context in America, both sexes are wary of public revelation of their sexual intentions, and tend to downplay them. But women are fairly accurate at reading what men are really after. Men, by contrast, are prone to overestimate women’s intentions, in line with their own interests. Engeler and Raghubir conclude that “there seems to remain a substantial gap in how women and men interpret dating situations, which could lead to problematic misunderstandings between dating partners’ intentions in actually wanting to have sex.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-30260-001&quot;&gt;Decomposing the Cross-Sex Misprediction Bias of Dating Behaviors: Do Men Overestimate or Women Underreport Their Sexual Intentions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32548/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32548/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32548&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 09:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How is research assessment changing? Watch video highlights from “Transforming Research&quot; conference</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-is-research-assessment-changing-watch-video-highlights-from-transforming-research-conference</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-is-research-assessment-changing-watch-video-highlights-from-transforming-research-conference</link>
	<description>15 experts share their thoughts on mapping science, quantifying uncertainty, and understanding the path dependence of a research field</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 03:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: African scientists get their own open-access publishing platform</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23018</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4EaEcwWaPYE/nature.2017.23018</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Venture will launch next year and seeks to strengthen continent’s science by helping academics share work more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.23018&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.23018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4EaEcwWaPYE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Hazy skies cool down Pluto</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22996</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PQWJ_Y72ORc/nature.2017.22996</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Complex chemistry in the dwarf planet’s upper atmosphere may explain one of its biggest mysteries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22996&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22996&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PQWJ_Y72ORc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Puerto Rico struggles to assess hurricane’s health effects</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22973</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5JM_0vBs59k/nature.2017.22973</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;While dealing with their own losses, public-health researchers are regrouping to study the aftermath of Hurricane Maria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 282 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22973&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22973&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5JM_0vBs59k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Microbiota: A high-pressure situation for bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24760</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Ekm6fIczY2g/nature24760</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Analyses in mice suggest that dietary salt increases blood pressure partly by affecting some of the microbes that inhabit the gut. The implications of this work for hypertension warrant further study in humans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24760&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24760&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Ekm6fIczY2g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cancer immunotherapy: The dark side of PD-1 receptor inhibition</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24759</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/r3x8bfcfBMU/nature24759</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Inhibiting the protein PD-1 can activate T cells that trigger immune responses against tumour cells. But it emerges that, in mice, this immunotherapy exacerbates a cancer that involves the T cells themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24759&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24759&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/r3x8bfcfBMU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Archaeology: Inequality has deep roots in Eurasia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24758</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/YUZujZhgyMI/nature24758</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A study of 64 archaeological sites across four continents shows that the growth of agricultural and political systems provoked economic disparities, more so in Eurasia than in North America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24758&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/YUZujZhgyMI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: PD-1 is a haploinsufficient suppressor of T cell lymphomagenesis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24649</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/gv_bwtco9Js/nature24649</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 T cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas are a heterogeneous group of highly aggressive malignancies with poor clinical outcomes. T cell lymphomas originate from peripheral T cells and are frequently characterized by genetic gain-of-function variants in T cell receptor (TCR) signalling molecules. Although these oncogenic alterations are thought to drive TCR pathways to induce chronic proliferation and cell survival programmes, it remains unclear whether T cells contain tumour suppressors that can counteract these events. Here we show that the acute enforcement of oncogenic TCR signalling in lymphocytes in a mouse model of human T cell lymphoma drives the strong expansion of these cells in vivo. However, this response is short-lived and robustly counteracted by cell-intrinsic mechanisms. A subsequent genome-wide in vivo screen using T cell-specific transposon mutagenesis identified PDCD1, which encodes the inhibitory receptor programmed death-1 (PD-1), as a master gene that suppresses oncogenic T cell signalling. Mono- and bi-allelic deletions of PDCD1 are also recurrently observed in human T cell lymphomas with frequencies that can exceed 30%, indicating high clinical relevance. Mechanistically, the activity of PD-1 enhances levels of the tumour suppressor PTEN and attenuates signalling by the kinases AKT and PKC in pre-malignant cells. By contrast, a homo- or heterozygous deletion of PD-1 allows unrestricted T cell growth after an oncogenic insult and leads to the rapid development of highly aggressive lymphomas in vivo that are readily transplantable to recipients. Thus, the inhibitory PD-1 receptor is a potent haploinsufficient tumour suppressor in T cell lymphomas that is frequently altered in human disease. These findings extend the known physiological functions of PD-1 beyond the prevention of immunopathology after antigen-induced T cell activation, and have implications for T cell lymphoma therapies and for current strategies that target PD-1 in the broader context of immuno-oncology. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24649&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24649&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/gv_bwtco9Js&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Salt-responsive gut commensal modulates TH17 axis and disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24628</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/lCMZVaJzIMY/nature24628</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 A Western lifestyle with high salt consumption can lead to hypertension and cardiovascular disease. High salt may additionally drive autoimmunity by inducing T helper 17 (TH17) cells, which can also contribute to hypertension. Induction of TH17 cells depends on gut microbiota; however, the effect of salt on the gut microbiome is unknown. Here we show that high salt intake affects the gut microbiome in mice, particularly by depleting Lactobacillus murinus. Consequently, treatment of mice with L. murinus prevented salt-induced aggravation of actively induced experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis and salt-sensitive hypertension by modulating TH17 cells. In line with these findings, a moderate high-salt challenge in a pilot study in humans reduced intestinal survival of Lactobacillus spp., increased TH17 cells and increased blood pressure. Our results connect high salt intake to the gut–immune axis and highlight the gut microbiome as a potential therapeutic target to counteract salt-sensitive conditions. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24628&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24628&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/lCMZVaJzIMY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Progress in and promise of bacterial quorum sensing research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24624</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QU2Sxrwt2xY/nature24624</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 This Review highlights how we can build upon the relatively new and rapidly developing field of research into bacterial quorum sensing (QS). We now have a depth of knowledge about how bacteria use QS signals to communicate with each other and to coordinate their activities. In recent years there have been extraordinary advances in our understanding of the genetics, genomics, biochemistry, and signal diversity of QS. We are beginning to understand the connections between QS and bacterial sociality. This foundation places us at the beginning of a new era in which researchers will be able to work towards new medicines to treat devastating infectious diseases, and use bacteria to understand the biology of sociality. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 313 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24624&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24624&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QU2Sxrwt2xY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Genome sequence of the progenitor of the wheat D genome Aegilops tauschii</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24486</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/4qGLdNs8lrg/nature24486</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Aegilops tauschii is the diploid progenitor of the D genome of hexaploid wheat (Triticum aestivum, genomes AABBDD) and an important genetic resource for wheat. The large size and highly repetitive nature of the Ae. tauschii genome has until now precluded the development of a reference-quality genome sequence. Here we use an array of advanced technologies, including ordered-clone genome sequencing, whole-genome shotgun sequencing, and BioNano optical genome mapping, to generate a reference-quality genome sequence for Ae. tauschii ssp. strangulata accession AL8/78, which is closely related to the wheat D genome. We show that compared to other sequenced plant genomes, including a much larger conifer genome, the Ae. tauschii genome contains unprecedented amounts of very similar repeated sequences. Our genome comparisons reveal that the Ae. tauschii genome has a greater number of dispersed duplicated genes than other sequenced genomes and its chromosomes have been structurally evolving an order of magnitude faster than those of other grass genomes. The decay of colinearity with other grass genomes correlates with recombination rates along chromosomes. We propose that the vast amounts of very similar repeated sequences cause frequent errors in recombination and lead to gene duplications and structural chromosome changes that drive fast genome evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24486&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24486&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/4qGLdNs8lrg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Visualization of chemical modifications in the human 80S ribosome structure</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24482</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/PR2FiMkO6_c/nature24482</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Chemical modifications of human ribosomal RNA (rRNA) are introduced during biogenesis and have been implicated in the dysregulation of protein synthesis, as is found in cancer and other diseases. However, their role in this phenomenon is unknown. Here we visualize more than 130 individual rRNA modifications in the three-dimensional structure of the human ribosome, explaining their structural and functional roles. In addition to a small number of universally conserved sites, we identify many eukaryote- or human-specific modifications and unique sites that form an extended shell in comparison to bacterial ribosomes, and which stabilize the RNA. Several of the modifications are associated with the binding sites of three ribosome-targeting antibiotics, or are associated with degenerate states in cancer, such as keto alkylations on nucleotide bases reminiscent of specialized ribosomes. This high-resolution structure of the human 80S ribosome paves the way towards understanding the role of epigenetic rRNA modifications in human diseases and suggests new possibilities for designing selective inhibitors and therapeutic drugs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24482&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/PR2FiMkO6_c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Structural basis of nucleotide sugar transport across the Golgi membrane</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24464</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Sqjpq1uAqC8/nature24464</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Glycosylation is a fundamental cellular process that, in eukaryotes, occurs in the lumen of both the Golgi apparatus and the endoplasmic reticulum. Nucleotide sugar transporters (NSTs) are an essential component of the glycosylation pathway, providing the diverse range of substrates required for the glycosyltransferases. NSTs are linked to several developmental and immune disorders in humans, and in pathogenic microbes they have an important role in virulence. How NSTs recognize and transport activated monosaccharides, however, is currently unclear. Here we present the crystal structure of an NST, the GDP–mannose transporter Vrg4, in both the substrate-free and the bound states. A hitherto unobserved requirement of short-chain lipids in activating the transporter supports a model for regulation within the highly dynamic membranes of the Golgi apparatus. Our results provide a structural basis for understanding nucleotide sugar recognition, and provide insights into the transport and regulatory mechanism of this family of intracellular transporters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24464&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24464&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Sqjpq1uAqC8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Quantitative microbiome profiling links gut community variation to microbial load</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24460</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/YWBx8x-xrQU/nature24460</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Current sequencing-based analyses of faecal microbiota quantify microbial taxa and metabolic pathways as fractions of the sample sequence library generated by each analysis. Although these relative approaches permit detection of disease-associated microbiome variation, they are limited in their ability to reveal the interplay between microbiota and host health. Comparative analyses of relative microbiome data cannot provide information about the extent or directionality of changes in taxa abundance or metabolic potential. If microbial load varies substantially between samples, relative profiling will hamper attempts to link microbiome features to quantitative data such as physiological parameters or metabolite concentrations. Saliently, relative approaches ignore the possibility that altered overall microbiota abundance itself could be a key identifier of a disease-associated ecosystem configuration. To enable genuine characterization of host–microbiota interactions, microbiome research must exchange ratios for counts. Here we build a workflow for the quantitative microbiome profiling of faecal material, through parallelization of amplicon sequencing and flow cytometric enumeration of microbial cells. We observe up to tenfold differences in the microbial loads of healthy individuals and relate this variation to enterotype differentiation. We show how microbial abundances underpin both microbiota variation between individuals and covariation with host phenotype. Quantitative profiling bypasses compositionality effects in the reconstruction of gut microbiota interaction networks and reveals that the taxonomic trade-off between Bacteroides and Prevotella is an artefact of relative microbiome analyses. Finally, we identify microbial load as a key driver of observed microbiota alterations in a cohort of patients with Crohn’s disease, here associated with a low-cell-count Bacteroides enterotype (as defined through relative profiling). 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24460&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/YWBx8x-xrQU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Influenza: A broadly protective antibody</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551310a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QnLgRgfIR2o/551310a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A single antibody uses multiple antiviral mechanisms to block the replication of influenza B viruses in mice and ferrets. The development could inform research into improved flu vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 310 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551310a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551310a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QnLgRgfIR2o&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Computer science: Visionary of virtual reality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551298a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ykIeA9kPgF4/551298a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Aldo Faisal explores the immersive journey of technology pioneer Jaron Lanier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 298 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551298a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551298a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ykIeA9kPgF4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Economics: How science got a golden ticket</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551297a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/UkdtKIHP0rk/551297a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Ehsan Masood hails an account of the mixed implications of governments valuing research as an investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 297 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551297a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551297a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/UkdtKIHP0rk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Bioethics: Justice in genomics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551296a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hz9Brx1gz9k/551296a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Rosario Isasi examines a study on the societal impact of grand sequencing projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 296 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/551296a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/551296a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hz9Brx1gz9k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These spiders may have the world’s fastest body clocks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-spiders-may-have-worlds-fastest-body-clocks</link>
	<description>Three orb-weaving spiders may have the shortest circadian clocks yet discovered among animals.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 21:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_MQ_circadianspider_feat.jpg?itok=DHOahyNj" length="29463" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Simulating the universe using Einstein’s theory of gravity may solve cosmic puzzles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lumpy-universe-einstein-general-relativity</link>
	<description>Better simulating the dense parts of the universe could improve scientists’ view of how the universe evolves.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 20:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_lumpy_feat_rev_crop.jpg?itok=5XovTMk_" length="39584" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New camera on Palomar telescope will seek out supernovas, asteroids and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/zwicky-transient-facility-palomar-telescope</link>
	<description>The Zwicky Transient Facility at Palomar Observatory in California will seek supernovas, black holes and asteroids.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/111317_LG_zwicky_feat.jpg?itok=xOpxnWJA" length="14347" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: The Puzzle of Multiple Personality Disorder</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23056</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/11/14/the-puzzle-of-multiple-personality-disorder/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2011/08/28/behind-the-masks-the-mysteries-of-dissociative-identity-disorder/&quot;&gt;Dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a&gt; (DID, commonly referred to as multiple personality disorder) is well known to the general public through multiple movies and books. However, the disease remains poorly understood and rather mysterious for the medical specialists. The definition of this disorder implies that a patient has at least two distinctive and relatively long-lasting identities (sometimes called “alters”) that manifest themselves in a person’s behavior. Their presence is accompanied by memory impairments that cannot be explained by usual forgetfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are no clear clinical criteria to help in the diagnostics. There is a whole range of dissociative disorders that range from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/22/improve-cognition-with-a-trip-down-memory-lane/&quot;&gt;daydreaming&lt;/a&gt; and lapses in attention to serious pathologies. The diagnostics rely on descriptive data rather than something measurable. This leads to lots of confusion, controversies, and inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the incidence of multiple personality disorder varied wildly. For a long time, the condition was considered among the rarest psychological disorders, with less than 100 cases described before 1944. The incidence of DID rose sharply in the 1970s–1980s, reaching 20,000 by the end of the century. In addition, this growth was accompanied by the increase in the number of alters reported in patients, from just one to 13–16 by the 1980s. These changes in the statistics might have been caused by increasing recognition of the disease symptoms among practitioners, but also led to the growing skepticism in the research community about the very existence of this distinct condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variability on the geographic distribution of this condition is substantial too: the disorder is diagnosed in the US much more frequently than anywhere else. The overwhelming majority of publications on this condition originate from North America, making some researchers believe that DID is a purely American disease confined to this continent. This further adds to the skepticism of many health practitioners: there are no reasons to believe that qualified specialists capable of recognizing this condition are vastly underrepresented in other developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is little clarity regarding what causes the disorder. The iatrogenic hypothesis suggests that DID can be a result of psychotherapeutic treatment, while the traumatogenic hypothesis states that the disease develops as a result of severe &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/09/15/coping-with-trauma-in-netflixs-unbreakable-kimmy-schmidt/&quot;&gt;trauma&lt;/a&gt;, usually in childhood. Some researchers believe that most cases of DID are pseudogenic, i.e., simulated. There is an opinion that many patients want to believe that they have the disorder, to explain the inconsistencies in their own behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incidence of DID is 5–9 times higher in females compared to males. Again, there is no agreement among specialists regarding what causes such a big gender difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential reasons for the sharp increase in the incidence of DID were examined in the scientific literature. Although there are many possible explanations for this phenomenon, the iatrogenic explanation appears to be the most substantiated. The unusually large number of diagnosis in the 1980s were clustered around a small number of practitioners, many of whom used &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/01/09/the-neurological-mechanisms-behind-hypnosis/&quot;&gt;hypnosis&lt;/a&gt; as a therapeutic tool. It is quite possible that under the influence of hypnosis the patients with a higher level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;suggestibility&lt;/a&gt; may start to believe that they are suffering from split personality disorder, and behave accordingly. The level of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/10/03/hypnotic-susceptibility-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;hypnotisability&lt;/a&gt; of people with the diagnosis of DID is known to be the highest among any clinical population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of the DID diagnosis numbers also correlated with the growing number of split personality cases in the criminal court cases. The defense on the basis of DID was rarely successful, as it was often assumed that the defenders simply pretend to have the disorder to avoid taking responsibility for their crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opinion exists that the manifestations of DID are simply the consequences of other disorders such as bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and borderline personality disorder. Many patients diagnosed with DID have previous history of these and other psychiatric conditions. Another theory suggests that the manifestations of DID are the consequences of trauma. There is plenty of clinical cases in support of this theory, but not so much statistical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it is well proven that people with DID are at higher risk of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/09/27/ketamine-for-rapid-treatment-of-depression/&quot;&gt;depression &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/09/10/back-to-school-suicides/&quot;&gt;suicide&lt;/a&gt;. The patients often suffer from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/24/how-does-post-traumatic-stress-disorder-change-the-brain/&quot;&gt;post-traumatic stress disorder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/22/from-abuse-to-addiction-the-withdrawal-period-makes-the-difference/&quot;&gt;substance abuse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/02/mindfulness-for-children-may-prevent-anxiety-and-mental-illness/&quot;&gt;anxiety&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/21/could-brain-stimulation-be-a-therapy-for-anorexia-nervosa/&quot;&gt;eating disorders&lt;/a&gt;. Such statistics are not uncommon in other psychiatric conditions, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, there is a shortage of proper neurological studies of this disorder. Nobody knows what exactly causes it and what kind of changes take place in the brains of patients diagnosed with this disease. The brain imaging data from patients with DID do not reveal any specific diagnostic patterns. Several studies demonstrated that the changes in personality state in the DID patients are associated with certain changes in the blood flow in the brain. There are also differences in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/12/17/exercise-to-keep-your-brain-healthy/&quot;&gt;brain blood flow&lt;/a&gt; patterns between patients with DID and healthy control subjects. It remains uncertain if these differences can be used in the diagnostics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of how real the majority of DID cases are is yet to be fully answered. In general, researchers agree that there are cases with very pronounced and obvious manifestations that would be rather hard to explain without invoking the concept of DID. However, when it comes to less severe cases, the diagnostic remains really problematic. This creates a problem for patients, as not knowing the specific diagnosis means the lack of clarity with treating the problem. Also, there is no consensus regarding how to treat the split personality disorder. Various psychotherapeutic and hypnotherapeutic techniques are currently used, but their efficacy remains unknown due to the absence of controlled randomised clinical trials. Clearly, there is a lot of room for further research in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maldonado, JR; Spiegel D (2008) Dissociative disorders — Dissociative identity disorder (Multiple personality disorder). In Hales RE; Yudofsky SC; Gabbard GO; with foreword by Alan F. Schatzberg. The American Psychiatric Publishing textbook of psychiatry (5th ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Pub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reinders AA (2008) Cross-examining dissociative identity disorder: Neuroimaging and etiology on trial. Neurocase. 14 (1): 44–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1080%2F13554790801992768&quot;&gt;10.1080/13554790801992768&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris J (1996) Review-Essay: Dissociative Symptoms, Dissociative Disorders, and Cultural Psychiatry. Transcult Psychiatry. 33 (1): 55–68. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F136346159603300104&quot;&gt;10.1177/136346159603300104&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kihlstrom JF (2005) Dissociative disorders. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology. 1 (1): 227–53. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1146%2Fannurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&quot;&gt;10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.1.102803.143925&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atchison M, McFarlane AC (1994) A review of dissociation and dissociative disorders. The Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry. 28 (4): 591–9. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3109%2F00048679409080782&quot;&gt;10.3109/00048679409080782&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piper A, Merskey H (2004) The persistence of folly: A critical examination of dissociative identity disorder. Part I. The excesses of an improbable concept. Canadian Journal of Psychiatry. &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt; (9): 592–600. PMID &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15503730&quot;&gt;15503730&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spiegel D, Loewenstein RJ, Lewis-Fernández R, Sar V, Simeon D, Vermetten E, Cardeña E, Dell PF (2011) Dissociative disorders in DSM-5. Depression and Anxiety. 28 (9): 824–852. doi:&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002%2Fda.20874&quot;&gt;10.1002/da.20874&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/geralt-9301/&quot;&gt;geralt&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52598</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a mystery: How did a nonexistent paper rack up hundreds of citations? Pieter Kroonenberg, an emeritus professor of statistics at Leiden University in The Netherlands, was puzzled when he tried to locate a paper about academic writing and discovered the article didn’t exist. In fact, the journal—Journal of Science Communications—also didn’t exist. Perhaps Kroonenberg’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/phantom-reference-made-article-got-almost-400-citations/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The “phantom reference:” How a made-up article got almost 400 citations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52589</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, a colleague of emergency medicine doctor Daniel Waxman sent him some newly reported findings that took him by surprise. Waxman knew from the title of a press release about the recent paper — “Nearly Half of U.S. Medical Care Comes From Emergency Rooms” — that something was wrong. Immediately I said, that’s not […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/14/journal-silently-fixes-emergency-care-paper-misleading-press-coverage/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal silently fixes emergency care paper — after misleading press coverage&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ancient spiral galaxy is 11 billion years old</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-spiral-galaxy-11-billion-years-old</link>
	<description>The most ancient spiral galaxy seen to date is 11 billion years old and could help reveal how galaxies sprout arms.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_LG_spiral-galaxy_est_main_no-black.jpg?itok=DXcU2AYJ" length="33806" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New blood pressure guidelines put half of U.S. adults in unhealthy range</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-blood-pressure-guidelines</link>
	<description>New hypertension guidelines broaden the range of those considered to have high blood pressure and emphasize lifestyle changes to combat the condition.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/111317_AC_hypertension_main_FREE.jpg?itok=wqMUf2rO" length="22129" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: China fires up next-generation neutron-science facility</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/EUma8ce4MBU/nature.2017.22976</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Beam generator puts country in elite company for doing experiments in materials science and other fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 284 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22976&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22976&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/EUma8ce4MBU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Study shows how easy and effective it is for Facebook ads to target your personality</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32433</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/study-shows-how-easy-and-effective-it-is-for-facebook-ads-to-target-your-personality/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_media-20&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-11-13 17.38.22.png&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32535&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32535&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-11-13 17.38.22&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2032,1818&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/study-shows-how-easy-and-effective-it-is-for-facebook-ads-to-target-your-personality/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/screenshot-2017-11-13-17-38-22.png?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Examples of ads used in the study: (A) targeted at high and low extraversion users, (B) at high and low openness users. via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Matz et al, 2017 / Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, Facebook’s founding president Sean Parker admitted his concerns that by focusing on social validation, Facebook was designed to exploit “a vulnerability in human psychology”. Added to this, and amidst the current furore around fake news, imagine if adverts on Facebook could be adapted to target your personality, significantly increasing the odds that people like you will click on the ads and then buy the associated products. A timely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt; shows just how easy and effective it is to target web users according to their personality, a technique that the researchers call “psychological persuasion”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32433&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research, led by Sandra Matz at Columbia Business School, used data previously gathered via the myPersonality.org app. Millions of people took personality tests and agreed for the app to access their history of Likes on Facebook (for instance, whether they had “liked” Lady Gaga or the TV series Battlestar Galactica).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a subsample of 65,000 users of the app, Matz and her team identified Likes which correlated strongly with scores on one of the main personality traits, but were neutral as regards the others. For example, they found that liking the US rapper Shwayze correlated with extraversion, but not with scores on the other main personality traits, and that liking Stargate SG1 correlated with introversion, but not the other traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an initial study, the researchers then created variations of a professional ad for a beauty product, either designed to appeal to extraverts (e.g. tagline: “Dance like no one’s watching, but they totally are”), or to introverts (e.g. tagline: “Beauty doesn’t have to shout”). They then used Facebook’s marketing tool to target the two ads deliberately either at people likely to be introverted (because they had “liked” a page identified earlier as correlated with introversion) or likely to be extraverted (again, because they had liked one of the pages known to be liked more often by high scorers in extraversion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results from this ad campaign, which reached over three million users, were clear: when the ad design matched users’ personality, it was 1.54 times more likely to lead to a purchase of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second study was similar, but this time the researchers looked for Likes that correlated with low or high openness-to-experience, a trait that’s associated with creativity, aesthetic appreciation and a desire to try out new things. For instance, liking the BBC drama The Fall correlated with high openness whereas liking the Farm Town game correlated with low openness. The researchers then created versions of an ad for a crossword app designed to appeal to people with low or high openness-to-experience. In a campaign reaching over 84,000 users, when the ad design matched users’ personality, they were 1.38 times more likely to click the ad, and 1.31 times more likely to buy the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Matz and her team used their approach to target ads for a bubble shooting game at a subsample of Facebook users already signed up to similar games (such as FarmVille). The pattern of likes for this group showed they are likely more introverted than average. The researchers therefore compared an ad designed to appeal to introverts (tagline “Phew! Hard day? How about a puzzle to wind down with?”) with the app company’s standard advertising spiel (i.e. “Ready? FIRE! Grab the latest puzzle shooter now! Intense action and brain-bending puzzles!”). The ad designed to appeal to introverts was more 1.3 times more likely to be clicked on and 1.2 times more likely to be purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers said their results showed the “effectiveness of psychological targeting in the context of real-life digital mass persuasion; tailoring persuasive appeals to the psychological profiles of large groups of people allowed us to influence their actual behaviours and choices.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Persuasive appeals that were matched to people’s extraversion or openness-to- experience level resulted in up to 40 per cent more clicks and up to 50 per cent more purchases than their mismatching or unpersonalized counterparts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They added that this approach could be used for good (for example, to boost the effectiveness of public health campaigns) or ill (imagine if online gambling companies started using these techniques).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads tailored to your personality could just be the start. As apps and tracking software become more sophisticated (especially via wearable devices), it may be possible to gather data in real-time about users’ current mood or emotional state and then tailor ads accordingly, both in terms of their content, but also their timing. “Hence, extrapolating from what one does to who one is likely just the first step in a continuous development of psychological mass persuasion,” Matz and her team concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Psychological targeting as an effective approach to digital mass persuasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1710966114&quot;&gt;Matz et al/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32433/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32433/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32433&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 20:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Philosophical critique exposes flaws in medical evidence hierarchies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/critique-medical-evidence-hierarchies</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/critique-medical-evidence-hierarchies</link>
	<description>Rankings of research methods for validity of medical evidence suffer from logical flaws, an in-depth philosophical critique concludes.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 19:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/110917_TS_evidence-hierarchy_main.jpg?itok=ZYD7w4g-" length="22695" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The Lord Howe stick insect is officially back from the dead</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lord-howe-stick-insect-extinction</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/lord-howe-stick-insect-extinction</link>
	<description>New genomic sequencing confirms that stick insects discovered near Lord Howe Island are the assumed-extinct Lord Howe stick insect.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_notebook-introducing_feat.jpg?itok=zvvZ4kWF" length="46931" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange Scientific Provider Elion Labs Presenting New Research at the AAPS Annual Meeting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1180</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/11/science-exchange-scientific-provider-elion-labs-presenting-new-research-at-the-aaps-annual-meeting/</link>
	<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Breakthrough in drug product particle analysis using machine learning&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Biopharma researchers can access Elion’s new services from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;scienceexchange.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elion-at-AAPSsmaller.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Science Exchange and Elion at AAPS&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1182&quot; height=&quot;188&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Elion-at-AAPSsmaller-300x188.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO, CA, and LOUISVILLE, CO, November 13, 2017 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;– &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the world’s leading and most secure enterprise platform for outsourced research and development, is proud to announce that Elion Labs, provider of analytical development and drug product characterization services, will present exciting new research at the 2017 AAPS (American Association of Pharmaceutical Scientists) Annual Meeting, the most comprehensive event for innovations in bioanalysis, formulation, and product characterization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Elion’s expertise has helped bring numerous clinical products to market. Their AAPS research poster presentation (Abstract M8003) introduces a novel method for drug product analysis, using machine learning and advanced image analysis to improve particle detection, enumeration, and classification. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Machine learning approaches open up exciting new possibilities for analyzing particles in biologics, and ultimately, for better analyzing a broad range of complex data sets,”  said John Gabrielson, Ph.D., CEO and Founding Partner of Elion Labs. “We hope that our research will help biopharmaceutical researchers develop safer, more effective drugs and deliver them to patients faster.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Elion and Science Exchange will exhibit at booth 2337 at AAPS, meeting drug discovery and development researchers and representatives of regulatory agencies seeking the latest, innovative services available for pharmaceutical analysis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We’re proud to participate in this year’s conference alongside Elion, who are true thought leaders in analytical research,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., CEO and Co-Founder of Science Exchange. “And because they’re part of the Science Exchange network, biopharmaceutical researchers can access Elion’s technologies immediately under our pre-existing master service agreement that covers IP and confidentiality.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;More information about Elion Labs and their innovative services can be found at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/elion-labs&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com/labs/elion-labs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Elion Labs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elion Labs, based in Louisville, Colorado, USA, was founded to serve the analytical development and product characterization needs of the biopharmaceutical industry. Elion offers a variety of services, including analytical method development, qualification and validation; analytical characterization testing of biologics; formulation development; training in highly specialized analytical techniques; comprehensive data analysis including visualization and interpretation of complex data sets; technical and regulatory writing; and technical consulting. They are committed to providing all services with unmatched professionalism, quality, and speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Science Exchange&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange is the world’s leading and most secure platform for outsourced research, providing an efficient procure-to-pay platform for ordering 6,000+ services from a network of more than 2,500 qualified scientific service providers, all with pre-established contracts in place that protect client intellectual property and confidentiality. The platform increases access to innovation and improves productivity, freeing scientists from administrative tasks and delays associated with sourcing, establishing and managing service provider contracts. Additionally, the Science Exchange enterprise program enables large R&amp;amp;D organizations to consolidate research outsourcing spend into a single strategic relationship, driving efficiency, improving transparency and oversight, and delivering cost savings. Since being founded in 2011, Science Exchange has raised more than $58 million from Norwest Venture Partners, Maverick Capital Ventures, Union Square Ventures, Collaborative Fund, Index Ventures, OATV, the YC Continuity Fund, and others. For more information, visit www.ScienceExchange.com. Follow the company on Twitter @ScienceExchange.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 16:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lawyers call libel suit against journal and critic “lawless” but “well written”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52575</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/lawyers-call-libel-suit-journal-critic-lawless-well-written/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A $10 million defamation suit filed by a Stanford University professor against a critic and a journal may be an assault on free speech, according to one lawyer, but at least it’s “well written.” Kenneth White, a lawyer at Southern California firm Brown White &amp;amp; Osborn who frequently blogs about legal issues related to free […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/lawyers-call-libel-suit-journal-critic-lawless-well-written/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lawyers call libel suit against journal and critic “lawless” but “well written”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Dear peer reviewer, please read the methods section. Sincerely, everyone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52518</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/caught-notice-dear-peer-reviewer-please-read-methods-section-sincerely-everyone/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Plasma contributes to the antimicrobial activity of whole blood against Mycobacterium tuberculosis What Caught Our Attention: A big peer review (and perhaps academic mentorship) fail.  These researchers used the wrong anticoagulant for their blood samples, leading them to believe that certain blood components were fighting microbes. The authors counted the number of colonies to show […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/13/caught-notice-dear-peer-reviewer-please-read-methods-section-sincerely-everyone/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Dear peer reviewer, please read the methods section. Sincerely, everyone&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Joe Biden: “Your work will bring hope to millions of people”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/joe-biden-your-work-will-bring-hope-to-millions-of-people</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/joe-biden-your-work-will-bring-hope-to-millions-of-people</link>
	<description>At the UN, the former VP recognizes the Lancet Oncology Commission and Elsevier for their contributions to the Cancer Moonshot initiative</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Cholera pandemics are fueled by globe-trotting bacterial strains</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cholera-pandemics-are-fueled-globe-trotting-bacterial-strains</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cholera-pandemics-are-fueled-globe-trotting-bacterial-strains</link>
	<description>International cholera strains, rather than local ones, have caused raging epidemics, according to research that examined the bacteria’s DNA.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110917_AC_cholera-outbreak_main.jpg?itok=iNw3MkJr" length="43598" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Very intelligent people make less effective leaders, according to their peers and subordinates</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32398</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/very-intelligent-people-make-less-effective-leaders-according-to-their-peers-and-subordinates/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_32415&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-473843606.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32415&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32415&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;businessman in suit with brain over head&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ismagilov&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;businessman with brain&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;businessman with brain&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1847,1624&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/13/very-intelligent-people-make-less-effective-leaders-according-to-their-peers-and-subordinates/businessman-with-brain/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-473843606.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Leaders who stand intellectually apart and are prone to complex language may be less inspiring&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly intelligent people tend to make good progress in the workplace and are seen as fit for leadership roles: overall, smarter is usually associated with success. But if you examine the situation more closely, as does &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14279-001&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Applied Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, you find evidence that too much intelligence can harm leadership effectiveness. Too clever for your own good? Let’s look at the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32398&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Antonakis at the University of Lausanne and colleagues recruited 379 mid-level leaders (27 per cent women, average age 38) at private companies in 30 mainly European countries, working in areas ranging from banking and telecoms to hospitality and retail. Each participant completed a personality questionnaire and a well-validated measure of intelligence, the Wonderlic Personnel Test. Their average IQ was 111 (the average for the general population is 100), with a fairly even spread of scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers also had access to third-party ratings of the participants’ leadership performance from eight people: either peers or subordinates of the leader, who rated them on the Multifactor Leadership Questionnaire, which explores the degree to which the leader demonstrates various leadership styles, some known to be useful (e.g. a “transformational style” which inspires, or an “instrumental” style that removes stumbling blocks), others detrimental (e.g. a passive, hands-off style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, women tended to employ better leadership styles, and to a lesser extent so did older leaders, but the bulk of the variance was accounted for by personality and intelligence. Like so much previous work, intelligence showed a positive linear relationship with leadership effectiveness, but this association flattened out and then reversed at an IQ of about 120. For leaders with higher intelligence than this, their scores in transformational and instrumental leadership were lower, on average, than less smart leaders; and beyond an IQ of 128, the association with less effective leadership was clear and statistically significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of note is that Antonakis’ team also predicted that very high intelligence would correlate not only with less use of effective leadership methods, but also greater use of harmful leadership styles (such as laissez-faire leadership). The data didn’t bear this out. Very smart leaders weren’t falling prey to bad approaches, they were struggling to use the good ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of several recent psychological studies investigating how there can be “too much of a good thing”. For leaders, this can apply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//digest.bps.org.uk/2015/08/17/having-strong-political-skills-can-be-a-handicap-in-the-workplace/&quot;&gt;political skills&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//digest.bps.org.uk/2017/06/14/with-leader-charisma-its-possible-to-have-too-much-of-a-good-thing/&quot;&gt;charisma&lt;/a&gt;. Intelligence is perhaps more surprising, given its well-established association with positive outcomes. The new findings can’t tell us why very smart people seem to make poorer leaders, but it’s possible leaders who stand intellectually apart and are prone to complex language are less inspiring, and they may find it difficult to anticipate what will prove a challenge to others, and how to reduce tasks to an appropriate level of simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must remember, however, that the issue isn’t whether, on balance, intelligence benefits leadership – it does – but whether it does so at every level of increasing intelligence. Antonakis’ team also speculate that the levels at which a leader’s intelligence delivers diminishing or reversing returns may depend on the relative intelligence of their team members, so these results don’t necessarily tell us the optimal IQ for all leaders. But they do suggest that in a social world, even highly advantageous traits can come with some drawbacks. And they also give defensive managers an excuse for a poor performance review: “I’m too clever for these guys!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-14279-001&quot;&gt;Can super smart leaders suffer from too much of a good thing? The curvilinear effect of intelligence on perceived leadership behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32398/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32398/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32398&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 08:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: World’s carbon emissions set to spike by 2% in 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22995</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/snhc4pE7Lyw/nature.2017.22995</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Increased coal use in China appears to be driving the first increase in global greenhouse-gas output since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 283 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22995&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22995&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/snhc4pE7Lyw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Race for quantum supremacy hits theoretical quagmire</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22993</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/qepdQzC77Mg/nature.2017.22993</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s far from obvious how to tell whether a quantum computer can outperform a classical one, says Philip Ball.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22993&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22993&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/qepdQzC77Mg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Archaeologists say human-evolution study used stolen bone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22984</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/s1GMt9lYXfQ/nature.2017.22984</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Bizarre tale of theft and suspicious packages casts doubt on claims for early-human occupation in northern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 279 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22984&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22984&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/s1GMt9lYXfQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: High-jumping beetle inspires agile robots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22981</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/IbXzFd13L-s/nature.2017.22981</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Machines could get themselves out of a sticky spot, thanks to an insect that can right itself without using its legs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22981&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/IbXzFd13L-s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Lab mice's ancestral ‘Eve’ gets her genome sequenced</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22974</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/XopkqJ1aPF4/nature.2017.22974</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Effort aims to help scientists understand how generations of inbreeding have altered the genetics of research rodents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 551 281 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22974&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22974&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/XopkqJ1aPF4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A non-canonical Notch complex regulates adherens junctions and vascular barrier function</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24998</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/BJpT2Sv5AhU/nature24998</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The vascular barrier that separates blood from tissues is actively regulated by the endothelium and is essential for transport, inflammation, and haemostasis1. Haemodynamic shear stress plays a critical role in maintaining endothelial barrier function2, but how this occurs remains unknown. Here, using an engineered organotypic model of perfused microvessels and confirming in mouse models, we identify that activation of the Notch1 transmembrane receptor directly regulates vascular barrier function through a non-canonical, transcription independent signalling mechanism that drives adherens junction assembly. Shear stress triggers Dll4-dependent proteolytic activation of Notch1 to reveal the Notch1 transmembrane domain—the key domain that mediates barrier establishment. Expression of the Notch1 transmembrane domain is sufficient to rescue Notch1 knockout-induced defects in barrier function, and does so by catalysing the formation of a novel receptor complex in the plasma membrane consisting of VE-cadherin, the transmembrane protein tyrosine phosphatase LAR, and the Rac1 GEF Trio. This complex activates Rac1 to drive adherens junction assembly and establish barrier function. Canonical Notch transcriptional signalling is highly conserved throughout metazoans and is required for many processes in vascular development, including arterial-venous differentiation3, angiogenesis4, and remodelling5; here, we establish the existence of a previously unappreciated non-canonical cortical signalling pathway for Notch1 that regulates vascular barrier function, and thus provide a mechanism by which a single receptor might link transcriptional programs with adhesive and cytoskeletal remodelling. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24998&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24998&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/BJpT2Sv5AhU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: IL11 is a crucial determinant of cardiovascular fibrosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24676</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5Ik8RBw0SjU/nature24676</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Fibrosis is a final common pathology in cardiovascular disease1. In the heart, fibrosis causes mechanical and electrical dysfunction1,2 and in the kidney, it predicts the onset of renal failure3. Transforming growth factor β1 (TGFB1) is the principal pro-fibrotic factor4,5 but its inhibition is associated with side effects due to its pleiotropic roles6,7. We hypothesised that downstream effectors of TGFB1 in fibroblasts could be attractive therapeutic targets and lack upstream toxicities. Using integrated imaging-genomics analyses of primary human fibroblasts, we found that Interleukin 11 (IL11) upregulation is the dominant transcriptional response to TGFB1 exposure and required for its profibrotic effect. IL11 and its receptor (IL11RA) are expressed specifically in fibroblasts where they drive non-canonical, ERK-dependent autocrine signalling that is required for fibrogenic protein synthesis. In mice, fibroblast-specific Il11 transgene expression or Il11 injection causes heart and kidney fibrosis and organ failure whereas genetic deletion of Il11ra1 is protective against disease. Thus, inhibition of IL11 prevents fibroblast activation across organs and species in response to a range of important pro-fibrotic stimuli. These data reveal a central role of IL11 in fibrosis and we propose inhibition of IL11 as a new therapeutic strategy to treat fibrotic diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24676&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5Ik8RBw0SjU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A Jurassic gliding euharamiyidan mammal with an ear of five auditory bones</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24483</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/z5F4t1IpEpE/nature24483</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Gliding is a distinctive locomotion type that has been identified in only three mammal species from the Mesozoic era. Here we describe another Jurassic glider that belongs to the euharamiyidan mammals and shows hair details on its gliding membrane that are highly similar to those of extant gliding mammals. This species possesses a five-boned auditory apparatus consisting of the stapes, incus, malleus, ectotympanic and surangular, representing, to our knowledge, the earliest known definitive mammalian middle ear. The surangular has not been previously identified in any mammalian middle ear, and the morphology of each auditory bone differs from those of known mammals and their kin. We conclude that gliding locomotion was probably common in euharamiyidans, which lends support to idea that there was a major adaptive radiation of mammals in the mid-Jurassic period. The acquisition of the auditory bones in euharamiyidans was related to the formation of the dentary-squamosal jaw joint, which allows a posterior chewing movement, and must have evolved independently from the middle ear structures of monotremes and therian mammals. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature24483&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature24483&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/z5F4t1IpEpE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Publishing’s day of reckoning; an Impact Factor discount — on lunch; a prize for negative results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52571</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/11/weekend-reads-publishings-day-reckoning-impact-factor-discount-lunch-prize-negative-results/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured mass resignations from a journal’s editorial board, software that writes papers for you, and a retracted retraction. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “Academic journal publishing is headed for a day of reckoning,” says librarian Patrick Burns. (The Conversation) A Beijing BBQ joint, named after The Lancet, is offering discounts to researchers who […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/11/weekend-reads-publishings-day-reckoning-impact-factor-discount-lunch-prize-negative-results/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Publishing’s day of reckoning; an Impact Factor discount — on lunch; a prize for negative results&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Why the wiggle in a crowd’s walk can put a wobble in a bridge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-wiggle-crowds-walk-can-put-wobble-bridge</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-wiggle-crowds-walk-can-put-wobble-bridge</link>
	<description>New simulations can better predict when pedestrians cause a bridge to shimmy.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110917_EC_wobbly-bridge_main_FREE.jpg?itok=wGThiQ8t" length="38803" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: A journal retracted a paper when authors couldn’t pay. Then it retracted the retraction.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52561</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-retracted-paper-authors-couldnt-pay-retracted-retraction/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Oops. A plant journal recently retracted a 2017 paper, saying the authors couldn’t pay the page charges ($110/page). The notice has since disappeared, and the journal announced on Twitter Thursday it was issued in error. The paper is now intact on the journal’s site. This isn’t the first time the journal has withdrawn a statement […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-retracted-paper-authors-couldnt-pay-retracted-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A journal retracted a paper when authors couldn’t pay. Then it retracted the retraction.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 15:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Quantum computers take a step forward with a 50-qubit prototype</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/quantum-computers-take-step-forward-50-qubit-prototype</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/quantum-computers-take-step-forward-50-qubit-prototype</link>
	<description>Race to build ever-more-powerful processors edges the technology closer to being able to best traditional machines.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/110917_EC_quantum-computer_main.jpg?itok=seg8VLlX" length="39954" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journal to assemble “senior editorial committee” to review paper that led to board resignations</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52559</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-assemble-senior-editorial-committee-review-paper-led-board-resignations/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Following heavy criticism of its decision to correct — instead of retract — a paper accused of plagiarism, Scientific Reports is adding an editor’s note to the paper and forming a committee to review the case. The 2016 paper in question has been accused of plagiarism by a researcher at Johns Hopkins, Michael Beer. Following […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/10/journal-assemble-senior-editorial-committee-review-paper-led-board-resignations/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Journal to assemble “senior editorial committee” to review paper that led to board resignations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ancient European farmers and foragers hooked up big time</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-european-farmers-and-foragers-hooked-big-time</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-european-farmers-and-foragers-hooked-big-time</link>
	<description>Interbreeding escalated in regionally distinct ways across Neolithic Europe.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110917_BB_neolithic_mating_main.jpg?itok=p4B9HvCs" length="26380" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: To (m)eat or not to (m)eat? Ethical dilemmas in food choice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9600</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/10/to-meat-or-not-to-meat-ethical-dilemmas-in-food-choice/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/meat-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘You are what you eat’ – The concept that you need to eat good food in order to be fit and healthy has gained meaning on a wider scale. While good dietary choices boost one’s own health, they can also benefit the planet. Dietary guidelines often give quantitative recommendations for the intake of animal products; however, in light of increasing encouragement to eat less meat to lessen the effects of climate change, consumers have become more concerned by the environmental impacts associated with meat production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Flickr: Anders Steen Nilsen&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-9603 size-full&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/cows.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;Raising animals for food requires enormous amounts of land, food, energy, and water and causes animal suffering. According to a&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldwatch.org/files/pdf/Livestock%20and%20Climate%20Change.pdf&quot;&gt; report&lt;/a&gt; published by the Worldwatch Institute, a staggering 51% or more of global greenhouse gas emissions are caused by animal agriculture. Meat consumption in the European Union has reduced and stabilized at around 42m tons over the last 15 years, and with the number of gluten-free products available doubling every year in Europe and the US, there has been in an increase in the consumption of plant proteins from beans and lentils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong claims like ‘You can’t be a meat-eating environmentalist’ have spurred disputes between vegetarians and meat-eaters but more and more people are trying to make major changes to their diets. New labels such as ‘flexitarians’ (only eat meat sometimes) and ‘reducetarians’ (aim to eat less meat) are an indication of how different groups of people are making efforts to cut down on their meat consumption one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conscious customer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do consumers choose their foods when they have to consider dietary guidelines as well as the potential environmental impact of their purchasing behaviors?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-017-4875-6&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published yesterday in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the first to investigate potential dilemmas between health and environmental considerations when purchasing animal food. The authors of the study specifically look at the socio-demographic profiles of individuals reporting health and environmental dilemmas when purchasing meat, fish and dairy products, and compare the diet quality of individuals with and without dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cross-sectional study involves 22,936 subjects from the NutriNet-Santé cohort study. Volunteers were recruited via multimedia campaigns and completed a set of self-administered, web-based questionnaires assessing dietary intake, physical activity, anthropometric characteristics, lifestyle, socioeconomic conditions and health status. At inclusion and once a year thereafter, participants were invited to complete three non-consecutive 24-h dietary records, which were validated against urinary biomarkers. In order for a dilemma to be assessed, participants were asked to rate items on a 4-point Likert scale: strongly disagree/disagree/agree/strongly agree to statements including: “I purchase [meat/fish/dairy products] for health issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of the study show that around 10% of individuals are torn between health and environmental considerations when purchasing meat or fish, and this is the case for only 5% for dairy products. Older participants, women, and low income individuals are more likely to report facing this dilemma. Participants who report dilemmas for meat and dairy products consume less of these foods and have a better dietary quality overall. In addition, participants with a meat dilemma show better adherence to meat/fish/eggs guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability and the way forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-9619 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/11/fruits.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;The results of this study indicate that having environmental concerns is not contradictory to adherence with nutritional guidelines. National dietary guidelines should therefore be adapted to take into account both health and environmental sustainability as we are already seeing in some countries, such as Germany, where dilemmas in food choice will probably be lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we cannot say with certainty that eating a vegetarian diet is any better for the environment, we do need to acknowledge and understand that there are trade-offs in what foods we choose to eat. For example, flying in green beans from Kenya to the UK may be seen as unsustainable due to air miles, but it also supports up to 1.5 million people in some of the poorest regions of Sub-Saharan Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately though, if you are contributing to food waste, then your diet is unsustainable regardless of whether you are a vegan, vegetarian, or a meat eater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/11/10/to-meat-or-not-to-meat-ethical-dilemmas-in-food-choice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;To (m)eat or not to (m)eat? Ethical dilemmas in food choice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/10/meat-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Moderate alcohol consumption improves foreign language skills</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32378</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/10/moderate-alcohol-consumption-improves-foreign-language-skills/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;giphy&quot; class=&quot; size-full wp-image-32391 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32391&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;giphy&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845?w=480&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;480,270&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/10/moderate-alcohol-consumption-improves-foreign-language-skills/giphy-6/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/giphy.gif?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alcohol is not exactly known for its brain-boosting properties. In fact, it impairs all kinds of cognitive functioning, including working memory and the ability to ignore distractions. So it really should make it harder for someone to speak in a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as Fritz Renner of Maastricht University in the Netherlands, and colleagues, point out in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0269881117735687&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Psychopharmacology&lt;/i&gt;, “contrary to what would be expected based on theory, it is a widely held belief among bilingual speakers that alcohol consumption improves foreign language fluency, as is evident in anecdotal evidence from numerous discussions in social and popular media.” And in welcome news for holiday drinkers (not to mention language students) everywhere, it turns out that, at least at moderate levels, this belief seems to be right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32378&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test the effect of alcohol on foreign language skills, Renner and his fellow researchers recruited 50 German students in their second year of an undergraduate degree in psychology at Maastricht University in the Netherlands. Maastricht is close to the German border and the university attracts many German students, all of whom must pass a Dutch language exam before they can attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, the students drank either 250ml of chilled water or 250ml of bitter lemon and enough vodka to generate a moderate blood alcohol concentration of about 0.04 per cent (the precise amount of vodka varied, according to gender and body weight). About 15 minutes after finishing the drink – by which time alcohol would have been absorbed into the bloodstream – the students were instructed to argue either for or against animal testing in Dutch, for two minutes. Two native Dutch speakers, who didn’t know which students had drunk what, rated the students’ language performance in terms of overall quality, understandability, vocabulary, pronunciation, word selection and fluency. Finally, the students completed an arithmetic task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renner and his colleagues predicted that while alcohol might increase the students’ &lt;i&gt;perceptions &lt;/i&gt;of how well they’d spoken in Dutch, they would in fact perform worse, based on the judges’ ratings, than the students who’d drunk water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn’t what they found. The vodka drinkers didn’t rate their own language performance any higher than the water-drinkers did. Neither did they do any worse on the arithmetic task. But they did receive better scores for their Dutch language skills, both overall and specifically for pronunciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why might this be? Some people feel nervous when speaking in a foreign language. It may be that the anxiety-reducing effects of a relatively small amount of alcohol improved their performance,  but this needs further investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The findings of this study need replication in future studies, testing participants learning languages other than Dutch and varying the amount of alcohol that is consumed to further explore the effects of acute alcohol consumption on foreign language proficiency,” Renner and his fellow researchers concluded. At least, it shouldn’t be too tricky to find students willing to volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the researchers noted in their paper, however, the amount of alcohol will be important in determining effects. The level in this study equated to a drink or two. As anyone who’s ever drunk more than that knows, at higher levels, slurring sets in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0269881117735687&quot;&gt;Dutch courage? Effects of acute alcohol consumption on self-ratings and observer ratings of foreign language skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32378/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32378/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32378&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Resurrected malaria strategy saves thousands of lives in Africa</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22982</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ANgkOvcKgmo/nature.2017.22982</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Pre-emptively treating kids for malaria is working, despite logistical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22982&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ANgkOvcKgmo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: South Africa tackles crime at sea with ship-spotting satellites</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22977</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1jrVcjODqAo/nature.2017.22977</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Automated vessel-tracking system aims to spy poachers and smugglers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22977&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22977&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1jrVcjODqAo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/human-speech-spectrum-frequency-range-formants.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This talk is based on the article &quot;Human Speech Spectrum, Frequency Range, Formants&quot; by Bernd Noack; Research Director CNRS (Centre Nationnal de la Recherche Scientifique), LIMSI-CNRS, France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk Anuradha will summarise the article and attempt to explain some fundamental features of human speech.
In particular, she will show the range of frequencies typically used by men and women.
She will also explain the role of formants (concentration of energy at particular frequency) in speech communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vowels play an important part in the formation of words and how they are vocalised.
In fact, as will be shown much of the energy in human speech is used in the production of vowels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anuradha will also demonstrate how the human voice can be heard against the background of a full orchestra, even though the total sound from the orchestra is much louder than the singer (typically a soprano).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, she will show the relationship between distance and received speech level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 10/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 23:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This deep-sea fish uses weird eyes to see in dark and light</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/deep-sea-fish-uses-weird-eyes-see-dark-and-light</link>
	<description>The eyes of deep-sea fish called pearlsides contain cells that look like rods but act like cones.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110817_LH_fish-eye_main.jpg?itok=5NpA4wzX" length="18975" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Firing patterns in the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-11-09:/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/11/09/firing-patterns-in-the-adaptive-exponential-integrate-and-fire-model.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Julia will present the paper by Naud et al (2008) 'Firing patterns in the AdEx IF model'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the article the authors explore the adaptive exponential integrate-and-fire model as a good tool to simulate large-scale spiking neuron networks.
They show that the AdEx model generates multiple firing patterns in response to the parameter values.
In order to describe the transition from one pattern to another, the phase diagrams are analysed in the article.
To further classify the firing patterns, the transient response to step current is studied.
The analytical solutions are given for continuous adaptation, initial bursting, regular bursting, tonic spiking and irregular spiking as a response to the constant current.
It is also concluded, that the network simulations of a large systems, such as thalamocortical, require the description of different neuron types.
Parameter sets for three neuron types are provided, but further work is needed to extend this to a larger number of neuron types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full article could be found here: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&quot;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2798047/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 17/11/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 19:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Crested pigeons sound the alarm with their wings</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/crested-pigeons-sound-alarm-their-wings</link>
	<description>Crested pigeons have specialized feathers that signal danger when they flee from an apparent threat.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 18:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110917_HT_pigeon-feathers_main.jpg?itok=k72tOCnY" length="16843" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52537</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This week, we received a press release that caught our attention: A company is releasing software it claims will write manuscripts using researchers’ data.  The program, dubbed “Manuscript Writer,” uses artificial intelligence (AI) to generate papers, according to the company that created it, sciNote LLC. A spokesperson explained the software generates a first draft the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/newly-released-ai-software-writes-papers-go-wrong/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Newly released AI software writes papers for you — what could go wrong?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 15:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Honeybees fumble their way to blueberry pollination</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/honeybees-fumble-their-way-blueberry-pollination</link>
	<description>Blueberry flowers drive honeybees to grappling, even stomping a leg or two down a bloom throat, to reach pollen.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110817_SM_blueberry-bee_main_FREE.jpg?itok=1vVhe8R5" length="15648" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52531</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Carlo Croce, a cancer researcher who has faced numerous research misconduct allegations, recently accused a former lab member of misconduct. Although an institutional probe did not support that allegation, Croce’s efforts have led to a retraction. In November 2015, Croce and another cancer researcher at Ohio State University (OSU), Ramiro Garzon, contacted PLOS ONE, alleging […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/09/carlo-croce-facing-misconduct-allegations-accuses-former-colleague-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Carlo Croce, facing misconduct allegations, accuses former colleague of misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 13:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Can evolutionary psychology and personality theory explain Trump’s popular appeal?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32297</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-632198430.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32369&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32369&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1D X Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;WASHINGTON, DC - JANUARY 20:  U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on the West Front of the U.S. Capitol on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. In today's inauguration ceremony Donald J. Trump becomes the 45th president of the United States.  (Photo by Chip Somodevilla\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1484914722&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2017 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;840&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2500&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.0003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Donald Trump Is Sworn In As 45th President Of The United States&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,683&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/09/can-evolutionary-psychology-and-personality-theory-explain-trumps-popular-appeal/donald-trump-is-sworn-in-as-45th-president-of-the-united-states/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-632198430.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago today, Donald J Trump, a man with no political or military experience, defied expectations, winning the election to become the 45th president of the United States. Nearly 63 million voted for him, including, and in spite of his reputation for sexism, over half of all white women. In an &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;open-access paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Evolutionary Studies in Imaginative Culture&lt;/em&gt;, Dan McAdams, one of the world’s leading experts in personality psychology, proposes an explanation for Trump’s popular appeal that is grounded in evolutionary psychology, personality theory and the social psychology of leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32297&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump encapsulates, and his personality is perfectly suited to, “dominance-oriented leadership”, McAdams explains, in contrast to “prestige leadership”, as exemplified by Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prestige leadership emerged more recently in our evolutionary history and is grounded in the cultural transmission of ideas and skills. Individuals who acquire expertise, and who have the ability to effectively organize other experts, are respected for their knowledge and wisdom and seen as legitimate leaders for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, dominant leadership is based on fear and power and dates farther back in our evolutionary past. To many Americans, Trump’s bombastic style and persona and proclamations have a “primal appeal”. Describing Trump as more “overtly aggressive” than any other political figure, “physically big and dynamic”, “insulting” and “egregiously self-promoting”, McAdams likens Trump’s “incendiary tweets” to the “charging displays” of an alpha male chimp, “designed to intimidate”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to the dominance approach to leadership is the derogation of experts – Trump has previously stated he knows more than military generals and has no need for economists. Related to this is the espousal of an essentialist view that sees some individuals as inherently superior to others. Trump consistently boasts about his superior intelligence and abilities over others. He displays what social psychologists call “hubristic pride” – celebrating who he is (brilliant and powerful, in his view), rather than the work and effort he has invested (upon which “authentic pride” is based).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dominant leader is especially appealing in a climate of fear. Trump has pushed this view – highlighting the dangers of outsiders, be they Mexican immigrants or Islamist terrorists, while also speaking of the economic “carnage” afflicting the country. Throughout his life, Trump has advocated a Hobbesian view of human culture. Even as long ago as 1981, he said “Man is the most vicious of all animals, and life is a series of battles ending in victory or defeat”. Against the enemies he invokes, and in these dangerous times, Trump “confidently assures Americans that he will deliver them from the chaos,” McAdams writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s personality is perfectly suited to this particular approach to leadership, McAdams observes. He has an unusual mix of extremely high extraversion, low agreeableness, and extreme narcissism. The first two traits contribute to his ability and willingness to forge opportunistic, short-term coalitions, but then to drop them as soon as they no longer fulfill his needs, just as alpha chimpanzees do with their potential rivals. Indeed, McAdams observes that “the case of Donald Trump shows how much humans turn out to be like chimps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Trump’s narcissism (and his essentialist view of ability and status) is likely appealing to voters who crave authoritarian rule – that is, submission to a strong leader, adherence to strict rules, and an aggressive, intolerant approach to outsiders and liberals (polls suggest authoritarianism has risen in the US over the last decade). A leader who believes confidently in, and frequently brags about, his own abilities, and strength and power, is highly appealing to these voters who have what social psychologists call a right-wing authoritarian attitude and social dominance orientation, meaning they believe strongly in the superiority of their own group over others, and who want a leader who endorses and represents this superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McAdams concludes by writing that he does not wish to dismiss or denigrate the many other explanations put forward for the rise of a man described by people from all political persuasions as “a serial liar, a sexual predator, a swindler, a narcissist, and a bully”. There are “many reasons” McAdams writes, [but] “the view advanced here is that Trump holds a deep and primal appeal for millions of Americans at this time in our history because of how effectively he channels the psychology of dominance – a way of thinking and feeling about leadership in groups that traces back many millions of years in human evolution, to our primate heritage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.academicstudiespress.com/index.php/ESIC/article/view/45&quot;&gt;The Appeal of the Primal Leader: Human Evolution and Donald J. Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: U.S. President Donald Trump delivers his inaugural address on January 20, 2017 in Washington, DC. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32297/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32297&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 12:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: See these first-of-a-kind views of living human nerve cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/see-these-first-kind-views-living-human-nerve-cells</link>
	<description>A catalog of live brain cells reveals stunning diversity and intricate shapes, and may help scientists understand the abilities of the human brain.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/112517_scivis_opener.jpg?itok=ZMscbWH5" length="28751" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How text mining is changing the way we tackle chronic disease</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-text-mining-is-changing-the-way-we-tackle-chronic-disease</link>
	<description>Researchers are working with Pathway Studio to design innovative treatments using simulations of complex diseases</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 11:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Physicists shrink plans for next major collider</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/xmPIEmDBp1I/nature.2017.22983</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Large Hadron Collider’s failure to detect new particles beyond the Higgs has eroded the case for Japan’s proposed linear accelerator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22983&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22983&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/xmPIEmDBp1I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: EPA OKs first living pest-control mosquito for use in United States</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/epa-oks-first-living-pest-control-mosquito-use-united-states</link>
	<description>Feds approve non-GM male tiger mosquitoes for sale as fake dads to suppress local pests.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 23:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/blogposts/110817_SM_mosquito-brief_main_FREE.jpg?itok=t0Icb6c-" length="18319" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52498</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Nobel Prize Physiology 2017 (for their discoveries of molecular mechanisms controlling the circadian rhythm) is On Fiction as There Is No Molecular Mechanisms of Biological Clock Controlling the Circadian Rhythm. Circadian Rhythm Is Triggered and Controlled By Divine Mechanism (CCP – Time Mindness (TM) Real Biological Clock) in Life Sciences  What Caught Our Attention: This isn’t a retraction — rather, it’s […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-nearly-unreadable-paper-criticizing-2017-nobel-pick/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: A nearly unreadable paper criticizing 2017 Nobel pick&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 19:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Scientists replaced 80 percent of a ‘butterfly’ boy’s skin</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-replaced-80-percent-butterfly-boys-skin</link>
	<description>By correcting genes in stem cells and growing new skin in the lab, a new therapy repaired a genetic skin disease.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 18:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110717_ti_skin_main_FREE.jpg?itok=yFx4Jxp7" length="36819" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This star cheated death, exploding again and again</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/star-cheated-death-exploding-again-and-again</link>
	<description>The weirdest supernova ever has lasted more than three years, and may be the third outburst from the same star.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110817_LG_supernova_main.jpg?itok=aebav9xx" length="26058" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52505</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, a Swedish government funding agency announced 325 recipients of grants in Natural and Engineering Sciences. We don’t normally write about grant announcements, but we’re flagging this one because one recipient may be familiar to our readers. It is Peter Eklöv of Uppsala University, a co-author of a now-retracted Science paper about the potential […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/caught-notice-author-controversial-retracted-paper-earns-swedish-govt-grant/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Caught Our Notice: Author of controversial retracted paper earns Swedish gov’t grant&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: Is a thermostat conscious?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1464</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/is-a-thermostat-conscious/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A theory of consciousness initially proposed by David Chalmers (in his book the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Conscious-Mind-Search-Fundamental-Philosophy/dp/0195117891&quot;&gt;Conscious Mind&lt;/a&gt;) is that consciousness (or experience) is a property of information processing systems. It is an additional property, not logically implied by physical laws; a new law of nature. The theory was later formalized by Giulio Tononi into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_information_theory&quot;&gt;Integrated Information Theory&lt;/a&gt;, based on Shannon’s mathematical concept of information. One important feature of this theory is it is a radical form of panpsychism: it assigns consciousness (to different degrees) to virtually anything in the world, including a thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bewitched experiment of thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/modern-panpsychism-about-the-integrated-information-theory-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;I have criticized IIT previously&lt;/a&gt; on the grounds that it fails to define in a sensible way what makes a conscious subject (eg a subsystem of a conscious entity would be another conscious entity, so for example your brain would produce an infinite number of minds). But here I want to comment specifically on the example of the thermostat. It is an interesting example &lt;a href=&quot;https://annakaharris.com/chalmers/&quot;&gt;brought up by Chalmers in his book&lt;/a&gt;. The reasoning is as follows: a human brain is conscious; a mouse brain is probably conscious, but with a somewhat lower degree (for example, no self-consciousness). As we go down the scale of information-processing systems, the system might be less and less conscious, but why would it be that there is a definite threshold for consciousness? Why would a billion neurons be conscious but not a million? Why would a million neurons be conscious but not one thousand? And how about just one neuron? How about a thermostat? A thermostat is an elementary information-processing system with just two states, so maybe, Chalmers argue, the thermostat has a very elementary form of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To claim that a thermostat is conscious defies intuition, but I would not follow Searle on insisting that the theory must be wrong because it assigns consciousness to things that we wouldn’t intuitively think are conscious. As I argued in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/the-substrate-of-consciousness/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, to claim that biology tells us that only brains are conscious is to use circular arguments. We don’t know whether anything else than a brain is conscious, and since consciousness is subjective, to decide whether anything is conscious is going to involve some theoretical aspects. Nonetheless, I am skeptical that a thermostat is conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to examine the Bewitched experiment of thought. In the TV series Bewitched, Samantha the housewife twitches her nose and everyone freezes except her. Then she twitches her nose and everyone unfreezes, without noticing that anything happened. For them, time has effectively stopped. The question is: was anyone experiencing anything during that time? To me, it is clear that no one can experience anything if time is frozen. In fact, that whole time has not existed at all for the conscious subject. It follows that a substrate with a fixed state (e.g. hot/cold) cannot experience anything, because time is effectively frozen for that substrate. Experience requires a flow of time, a change in structure through time. I leave it open whether the interaction of the thermostat with the room might produce experience for that coupled system (see below for some further thoughts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is “information”?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my view, the fallacy in the initial reasoning is to put the thermostat and the brain in the same scale. That scale is the set of information-processing systems. But as I have argued before (mostly following Gibson’s arguments), &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xix-does-the-brain-process-information/&quot;&gt;it is misleading to see the brain an information-processing system&lt;/a&gt;. The brain can only be seen to transform information of one kind into information of another kind by an external observer, because the very concept of information is something that makes sense to a cognitive/perceptual system. The notion of information used by IIT is Shannon information, a notion from communication theory. This is an extrinsic notion of information: for example, neural activity is informative about objects in the world in the sense that properties of those objects can be inferred from neural activity. But this is totally unhelpful to understand how the brain, which only ever gets to deal with neural signals and not things in the world, sees the world (see this argument in more detail in my paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/early/2017/07/31/168237&quot;&gt;Is coding a relevant metaphor for the brain?&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s clarify with a concrete case: does the thermostat perceive temperature? The thermostat can be in different states depending on temperature, but from its perspective, there is no temperature. There are changes in state that seems to be unrelated to anything else (there is literally nothing else for the thermostat). One could replace the temperature sensor with some other sensor, or with a random number generator, and there would be literally no functional change in the thermostat itself. Only an external observer can link the thermostat’s state with temperature, so the thermostat cannot possibly be conscious of temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, Shannon’s notion of information is inappropriate to understand consciousness. Instead of extracting information in the sense of communication theory, what the brain might do is build models of sensory (sensorimotor) signals from its subjective perspective, in the same way as scientists make models of the world with observations (=sensory signals) and experiments (=actions). But this intrinsic notion of information, which corresponds eg to laws of physics, is crucially not what Shannon’s notion of information is. And it is also not the kind of information that a thermostat is dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inappropriate notion of information leads to what in my view is a rather absurd quantitative scale of consciousness, according to which entities are more or less conscious along a graded scale (phi). Differences in consciousness are qualitative, not quantitative: there is dreaming, being awake, being self-conscious or not, etc. These are not different numbers. This odd analog scale arises because Shannon information is counted in bits. But information in the sense of knowledge (science) is not counted in bits; there are different kinds of knowledge, they have different structure, relations between them etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subjective physics of a thermostat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let us not throw away Chalmers’ interesting experiment of thought just now. Let us ask, following Chalmers: what does it feel like to be a thermostat? We will examine it not with Shannon’s unhelpful notion of information but with what I called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1311.3129&quot;&gt;subjective physics&lt;/a&gt;”: the laws that govern sensory signals and their relations to actions, from the perspective of the subject. This will define my world from a functional viewpoint. Let’s say I am a conscious thermostat; a homunculus inside the thermostat. All I can observe is a binary signal. Then there is a binary action that I can make, which for an external observer corresponds to turning on the heat. What kind of world does that make to me? Let’s say I’m a scientist homunculus, what kind of laws about the world can I infer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m a conventional thermostat, then the action will be automatically triggered when the signal is in a given state (“cold”). After some time, the binary signal will switch and so will the action. So in fact there is an identity between signal and action, which means that all I really observe is just the one binary signal, switching on and off, probably with some kind of periodicity. This is the world I might experience, as a homunculus inside the thermostat (note that to experience the periodicity requires memory, which a normal thermostat doesn’t have). In a way, I’m a “locked-in” thermostat: I can make observations, but I cannot freely act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that I am not locked-in and have a little more free will, so I can decide whether to act (heat) or not. If I can, then my world is a little bit more interesting: my action can trigger a switch of the binary signal, after some latency (again requiring some memory), and then when I stop, the binary signal switches back, after a time that depends on how much time my previous action lasted. So here I have a world that is much more structured, with relatively complex laws which in a way defines the concept of “temperature” from the perspective of the thermostat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if a thermostat were conscious, then we have a rough idea of the kind of world it might experience (although not how it feels like), and even in this elementary example, you can’t measure these experiences in bits - let alone the fact that a thermostat is not conscious anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 14:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=52488</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;When examining the roles of conflicts of interest in academic publishing, most research focuses on transparency around the payments authors receive. But what about journal editors? According to a new Peer J preprint, two-thirds of editors at prominent journals received some type of industry payment over the last few years – which, at many journals, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/11/08/editors-top-medical-journals-receive-industry-payments-report/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Most editors of top medical journals receive industry payments: report&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: A 30-minute lesson in the malleability of personality has long-term benefits for anxious, depressed teenagers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=32165</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-155427885.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-32264&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;32264&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This series aims to portrait tattooed people in their professional and private lives.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;alvarez&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Portrait of a tattooed person&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2000,1500&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/11/08/a-30-minute-lesson-in-the-malleability-of-personality-has-long-term-benefits-for-anxious-depressed-teenagers/portrait-of-a-tattooed-person/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/11/gettyimages-155427885.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many effective psychological therapies to help teenagers with depression, anxiety or other mental health problems. Unfortunately, for various reasons, most teenagers never get access to a professional therapist. To overcome this problem, some researchers are exploring the potential of brief, “single-session” interventions that can be delivered cheaply and easily to many at-risk teenagers outside of a clinical context. In &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;, Jessica Schleider and John Weisz at Harvard University &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;present extremely promising results&lt;/a&gt; from their trial of a 30-minute computer session teaching depressed and anxious teenagers that personality is malleable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-32165&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible, the participating teenagers needed to have problematic anxiety and/or depression. Ninety-six teenagers took part, aged 12 to 15, mostly White American. Forty-eight of them were assigned to the 20-to-30-minute session about the malleability of personality. The others, who had the same baseline symptom levels, acted as controls and spent an equal amount of time in a computer-based session of “supportive therapy” learning about emotions and how it’s helpful to talk about them. The idea was this would match the experience of being enrolled in the personality change session in all ways except for the all-important content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personality session was self-administered on computer and taught the teenagers about neuroplasticity and the idea that behaviours arise from thoughts and feelings in their brains, and that brains are always changing. They heard from older youths saying they believe people can change, and from others saying how they’d used belief in our capacity for change (a “growth mindset”) to cope with problems like embarrassment or rejection. The teenagers learned strategies for applying these principles to themselves and they wrote notes to younger children about the malleability of personality traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary message of the intervention, the researchers said, is that “personal attributes are malleable if we systematically – and with appropriate supports – act to change them. Essentially it reinforces beliefs in &lt;em&gt;behavioral&lt;/em&gt; control over the kinds of people we are can can become.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the teens completed a series of psychological measures before and immediately after whichever session they took part in, and then they took the same measures again three, six, and nine-months later. Their parents also completed some of the same measures about their child. To avoid their own expectations affecting the results, the researchers were kept unaware of which teens were in which condition until the end of the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promising findings include that the teens in the personality change session showed more rapid declines in depression, and nine months later their depression scores had declined more than the control participants’ scores (33 per cent fewer of them now had clinically severe levels of depression, compared with 11 per cent fewer among the control group). These benefits were mirrored in parents’ ratings of their children’s depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results for anxiety weren’t as good, but still showed promise – the personality change intervention led to greater declines in symptoms at nine months based on parents’ reports, although not based on the teenagers’ self-reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hoped, compared with the controls, the teenagers in the personality change intervention reported a stronger increase in their belief that your personality is something you can change. Further clues as to how the personality change intervention helped the teenagers come from measures of their belief in their ability to deal with adversity by controlling their own behavior (e.g. whether they agreed with statements like “I can be popular with kids my age, if I really try”; “I can do well on tests if I try really hard”) and their own emotions (e.g. “I can usually find something good to like, even in a bad situation” or ““When I have a problem that I can’t change, I can do something to take my mind off it.”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the follow-up period, the teens in the personality change intervention showed larger increases in their sense of control over their own behavior, as compared with the control participants (there was no difference in their sense of control over their emotions). This makes sense given the personality intervention’s focus on behavioral control as a means to influence our personalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schleider and Weisz said their “mindset” intervention teaching that personality is malleable is “highly cost-effective and scalable”, meaning it could be delivered to all new pupils arriving at a secondary school, for example. They added “these are the first findings we know of suggesting that a 30-minute, self-administered program may help reduce depression, and to a lesser degree, anxiety, in high-symptom and high-risk youths.” They believe the intervention may have such strong and enduring effects because it focuses on “‘keystone beliefs’ of high developmental relevance to adolescents”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage is that for any teens who end up in therapy, the brief personality change session could help lay the groundwork in terms of motivation and helpful beliefs about personal control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the results are encouraging, larger trials are needed, the researchers noted, including with teenagers from more ethnically diverse and less affluent backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.12811/abstract&quot;&gt;A single-session growth mindset intervention for adolescent anxiety and depression: 9-month outcomes of a randomized trial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Psych_Writer/status/818794319385690113&quot;&gt;currently writing a book about personality change&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/32165/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=32165&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 12:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Human study supports theory on why dengue can be worse the next time around</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/human-study-supports-theory-why-dengue-can-be-worse-next-time-around</link>
	<description>The amount of dengue antibodies leftover in the blood may up the chances of a severe second dengue infection, a study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110317_AC_dengue_main.jpg?itok=33-PiDDR" length="45293" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Q&amp;A: German pharma start-up leader on the importance of knowledge in a fast-changing industry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-german-pharma-start-up-leader-on-the-importance-of-knowledge-in-a-fast-changing-industry</link>
	<description>Till Erdmann, Managing Director Myelo Therapeutics, on the challenges for young businesses in healthcare and how to tackle them</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 09:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How to increase your grant success rates with insights, discovery and decisions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-to-increase-your-grant-success-rates-with-insights-discovery-and-decisions</link>
	<description>Elsevier’s VP of Academic and Government Strategic Alliances examines the challenges of research funding – and introduces a new solution</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 08:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Face it: Sheep are just like us when it comes to recognizing people</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/face-it-sheep-are-just-us-when-it-comes-recognizing-people</link>
	<description>Sheep trained to recognize celebrity faces demonstrate that the animals have face-recognition capabilities similar to humans and other primates.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/11/main/articles/110717_MQ_sheep-face_main.jpg?itok=nUIHJaCl" length="41366" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
