<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Science News: Borrowed genes give mums the blues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borrowed-genes-give-mums-blues</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/borrowed-genes-give-mums-blues</link>
	<description>Scientists have genetically modified chrysanthemums to be “true blue” for the first time.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 19:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072617_ED_blue-flower_main.jpg?itok=ZdjFY2Lc" length="30787" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Balloons will broadcast the 2017 solar eclipse live from on high</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/balloons-broadcast-2017-solar-eclipse-livestream</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/balloons-broadcast-2017-solar-eclipse-livestream</link>
	<description>Astrophysicist Angela Des Jardins is coordinating the first-ever livestream of a solar eclipse filmed from balloons.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 17:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071017_LG_eclipse_main.jpg?itok=8YZDZOgh" length="26313" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Expert eavesdroppers occasionally catch a break</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/expert-eavesdroppers-occasionally-catch-break</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/expert-eavesdroppers-occasionally-catch-break</link>
	<description>Acting Editor in Chief Elizabeth Quill discusses the many ways we watch, listen and learn about science.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 17:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Readers question hominid family tree</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-hominid-family-tree</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/readers-question-hominid-family-tree</link>
	<description>Readers sent feedback on hominid origins, fast cameras, slimy sea creatures and more.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Perovskites power up the solar industry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perovskites-power-solar-industry</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/perovskites-power-solar-industry</link>
	<description>Perovskites are the latest hot materials in solar energy production.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/080517_feat_perovskite_main.jpg?itok=AgTwxXIn" length="33457" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: More hints of Martian hot springs may hold promise for Mars 2020 mission</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-hints-martian-hot-springs-may-hold-promise-mars-2020-mission</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/more-hints-martian-hot-springs-may-hold-promise-mars-2020-mission</link>
	<description>An analysis of ridges in a crater of Margaritifer Terra on Mars offers evidence of ancient hot springs and also hints at the potential for finding signs of life.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 15:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072517_AY_mars_main.jpg?itok=peQjAHkU" length="36017" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Nurturing the Brain – Part 11, Magnesium</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22677</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/26/nurturing-the-brain-part-11-magnesium/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is everywhere – it does not occur free in nature, only in combination with other elements, but it is the eighth most abundant chemical element in the Earth’s crust and the third most abundant element in seawater; it is even the ninth most abundant in the Milky Way. In the human body, magnesium is the fourth most abundant ion and the eleventh most abundant element by mass, being stored in bones, muscles, and soft tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is fundamental for health: it is essential to all cells and to the function of hundreds of enzymes, including enzymes that synthesize DNA and RNA, and enzymes involved in cellular &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;energy metabolism&lt;/a&gt;, many of which are vital. Magnesium is involved in virtually every major metabolic and biochemical process in our cells and it plays a critical role in the physiology of basically every single organ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low plasma levels of magnesium are common and are mostly due to poor dietary intake, which has lowered significantly in the last decades. Magnesium can be found in high quantities in foods containing &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/19/the-brain-gut-axis-part-2-brain-gut-microbiota-communication/&quot;&gt;dietary fiber&lt;/a&gt;, including green leafy vegetables, legumes, nuts, seeds, and whole grains. But although magnesium is widely distributed in vegetable and animal foods, some types of food processing can lower magnesium content up to 90%. Also, the soil used for conventional agriculture is becoming increasingly deprived of essential minerals. In the last 60 years, the magnesium content in fruit and vegetables has decreased by around 20 to 30%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptomatic magnesium deficiency due to low dietary intake in healthy people is not very frequent, but a consistently poor dietary supply of magnesium has insidious effects. Magnesium deficiency alters biochemical pathways and increases the risk of a wide range of diseases over time, namely &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2006/12/21/hypertension-drugs-affect-alzheimers/&quot;&gt;hypertension&lt;/a&gt; and cardiovascular diseases, metabolic diseases, osteoporosis, and migraine headaches, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the brain, magnesium is an important regulator of neurotransmitter signaling, particularly glutamate and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2007/06/25/yoga-increases-gaba-levels-in-brain/&quot;&gt;GABA&lt;/a&gt;, the main neurotransmitters by modulating the activation of NMDA glutamate receptors and GABA&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; receptors. It also contributes to the maintenance of adequate calcium levels in the cell through the regulation of calcium channels’ activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These physiological roles make magnesium an essential element in important neuronal processes. Magnesium participates in the mechanisms of synaptic transmission, neuronal plasticity, and consequently, learning and memory. Accordingly, increased levels of magnesium in the brain have been shown to promote multiple mechanisms of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/25/exercise-and-brain-aging/&quot;&gt;synaptic plasticity&lt;/a&gt; that enhance different forms of learning and memory, and delay age-related cognitive decline. Increased levels of magnesium in the brain have also been linked to an increased proliferation of neural stem cells, indicating that it may promote the generation of new neurons (neurogenesis) in adulthood. This is an important feature because neurogenesis is a key mechanism in the brain’s structural and functional adaptability, in cognitive flexibility, and in mood regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium supplementation has also been shown to modulate the neuroendocrine system and to improve sleep quality by promoting slow wave (deep) sleep, which, among many other functions, is also important for cognition and memory consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, magnesium may enhance the beneficial effects of exercise in the brain, since it has been shown to increase the availability of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/06/26/blood-glucose-and-the-brain-sugar-and-short-term-memory/&quot;&gt;glucose&lt;/a&gt; in the blood, muscle, and brain, and diminish the accumulation of lactate in the blood and muscles during exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just as increasing magnesium levels can be beneficial, magnesium deficiency can have serious harmful effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium has important roles in the regulation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/08/08/stress-shortens-life/&quot;&gt;oxidative stress&lt;/a&gt;, inflammatory processes and modulation of brain blood flow. In circumstances of magnesium deficiency, all of these functions can potentially be dysregulated, laying ground for neurological disorders. Also, in a context of low magnesium availability in the brain, NMDA glutamate receptors, which are excitatory, may become excessively activated, and GABAA receptors, which are inhibitory, may become insufficiently activated; this can lead to neuronal hyperactivity and to a condition known as glutamate excitotoxicity. This causes an excessive accumulation of calcium in neurons, which in turn leads to the production of toxic reactive oxygen species and, ultimately, to neuronal cell death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magnesium deficiency has been associated with several neurological and psychiatric diseases, including migraine, epilepsy, depression, schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, stress, and neurodegenerative diseases. Magnesium supplementation has shown beneficial effects on many of these conditions, as well as in post-stroke, post-traumatic &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/01/traumatic-brain-injury-can-deep-sleep-be-neuroprotective/&quot;&gt;brain injury&lt;/a&gt;, and post-spinal cord injury therapies. This therapeutic action is likely due to its action in blocking NMDA glutamate receptors and decreasing excitotoxicity, in reducing oxidative stress and inflammation, and in increasing blood flow to the brain, all of which are determinant in the outcome of these conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple benefits to be obtained from magnesium, both from a health promotion, and from a disease prevention and management perspective. The recommended daily intake of magnesium is of 320mg for females and 420mg for males. Too much magnesium from food sources has no associated health risks in healthy individuals because the kidneys readily eliminate the excess. However, there is a recommended upper intake level for supplemental magnesium, since it can cause gastrointestinal side effects. So, keep it below 350mg/day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chen HY, et al (2014). Magnesium enhances exercise performance via increasing glucose availability in the blood, muscle, and brain during exercise. PLoS One, 9(1):e85486. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0085486&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pone.0085486&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;de Baaij JH, et al (2015). Magnesium in man: implications for health and disease. Physiol Rev, 95(1):1-46. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://physrev.physiology.org/content/95/1/1.long&quot;&gt;10.1152/physrev.00012.2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Held K, et al (2002). Oral Mg(2+) supplementation reverses age-related neuroendocrine and sleep EEG changes in humans. Pharmacopsychiatry, 35(4):135-43. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thieme-connect.com/DOI/DOI?10.1055/s-2002-33195&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.pbb.2004.01.006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jia S, et al (2016). Elevation of Brain Magnesium Potentiates Neural Stem Cell Proliferation in the Hippocampus of Young and Aged Mice. J Cell Physiol, 231(9):1903-12. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/jcp.25306/abstract&quot;&gt;10.1002/jcp.25306&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Institutes of Health, Office of Dietary Supplements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/Magnesium-HealthProfessional/&quot;&gt;Magnesium Fact Sheet for Health Professionals &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slutsky I, et al (2010). Enhancement of learning and memory by elevating brain magnesium. Neuron. 2010 Jan 28;65(2):165-77. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(09)01044-7&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.neuron.2009.12.026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Brett_Hondow-49958/&quot;&gt;Brett_Hondow&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Controversial CRISPR paper earns second editorial note</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51187</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/controversial-crispr-paper-earns-second-editorial-note/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Against the authors’ objections, Nature Methods has added an expression of concern to a 2017 paper that drew fire for suggesting a common gene editing technique could cause widespread collateral damage to the genome. The latest note — the second to be added in two months — alerts readers to an alternative interpretation of the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/controversial-crispr-paper-earns-second-editorial-note/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Controversial CRISPR paper earns second editorial note&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: PLOS ONE retracts paper after researcher admits to fabricating data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51179</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/plos-one-retracts-paper-researcher-admits-fabricating-data/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;On June 19, 2017, the U.S. Office of Research Integrity published its first misconduct finding of the year. The ORI reported that Brandi M. Baughman — a former research training awardee at the National Institute of Environmental and Health Sciences (NIEHS) — had “falsified and/or fabricated data” in 11 figures in a 2016 paper published in PLOS […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/26/plos-one-retracts-paper-researcher-admits-fabricating-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PLOS ONE retracts paper after researcher admits to fabricating data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: We’re ready for the Charles River Annual Research Symposium!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1108</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/07/were-ready-for-the-charles-river-annual-research-symposium/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;by Annie Chen, Event Marketing Specialist, Science Exchange | &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scienceexchange.com&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We are excited to attend the annual research symposium hosted by Charles River, a leading service provider on the Science Exchange network — and we hope to see you there!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Join your colleagues and industry experts from Bluebird, Janssen, Pfizer, and Amgen in Carlsbad, CA September 11–13 at Charles River’s biotech symposium, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cvent.com/events/annual-biotech-symposium-biotechnology-derived-therapeutics-perspectives-on-nonclinical-development/event-summary-a32daae4dce048aea021e98df2e54435.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biotechnology-Derived Therapeutics: Perspectives on Nonclinical Development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;With five different session tracks, join Charles River to learn about:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biotherapeutic development programs and related case studies&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Biomolecules and modifications to prolong a molecule’s half-life&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Preclinical development of inhaled therapeutics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Microphysiology systems for biotherapeutics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Arrive one day early and attend the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cvent.com/events/annual-biotech-symposium-biotechnology-derived-therapeutics-perspectives-on-nonclinical-development/event-summary-a32daae4dce048aea021e98df2e54435.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;pre-symposium workshop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; titled, Where Does My Protein Go and Why Does It Matter? The Role of PK/PD in Biotherapeutics on Sunday, September 10.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Discounted room rates are available until August 11 and special registration fees are available to SOT BTSS members.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.criver.com/e/60962/4dce048aea021e98df2e54435-aspx/d3chlv/555769021&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register Now!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/labs/charles-river-discovery-cr&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Charles River Research Symposium&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1109&quot; height=&quot;146&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/CRL-header-footer-1024x249.png&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 11:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Quantum tunneling takes time, new study shows</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tunneling-takes-time-new-study-shows</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/quantum-tunneling-takes-time-new-study-shows</link>
	<description>A new measurement disfavors the idea that electrons can escape atoms instantaneously.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072417_ec_quantumtunneling_free.jpg?itok=IHxWiIvB" length="16825" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: The great misunderstanding about peer review and the nature of scientific facts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1430</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/the-great-misunderstanding-about-peer-review-and-the-nature-of-scientific-facts/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I organized a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computational-neuroscience-of-sensory-systems.org/workshop-on-emerging-models-in-scientific-communication-and-discussion/&quot;&gt;workshop on the future of academic publication&lt;/a&gt;. My point was that our current system, based on private pre-publication peer review, is archaic. I noted that the way the peer review system is currently organized (where external reviewers judge both the quality of the science and the interest for the journal) represents just a few decades in the history of science. It can hardly qualify as the way science is or should be done. It is a historical feature. For example, only one of Einstein’s papers was formally peer-reviewed; Crick &amp;amp; Watson’s DNA paper was not formally peer-reviewed. Many journals introduced external peer review in the 1960s or 1970s to deal with the growth in the number and variety of submissions (see e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4528400/&quot;&gt;Baldwin, 2015&lt;/a&gt;); before that, editors would decide whether to publish the papers they received, depending on the number of pages they could print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the possibilities that offers the internet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/a-vision-of-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;it seems that there is no reason anymore to couple t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/a-vision-of-the-post-journal-world/&quot;&gt;he two current roles of peer review&lt;/a&gt;: editorial selection and scientific discussion. One could simply share their work online, get feedback from the community to discuss the work, and then let people recommend papers to their colleagues and &lt;a href=&quot;http://romainbrette.fr/free-the-journals/&quot;&gt;compile all sorts of reader’s digests&lt;/a&gt;. No time wasted in multiple submissions, no prestige misattributed to publications in glamour journals, who do not do a better a job than any other journal at pointing errors and frauds. Just the science and the public discussion of science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a lot of resistance to this idea, namely the idea that papers should be formally approved by peer reviewers before they are published. Because otherwise, so many people claim, the scientific world would be polluted by all sorts of unverified claims. It would not be science anymore, just gossip. I have attributed this attitude to conservatism, first because as noted above this system is a rather recent addition to the scientific enterprise, and second because papers &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; published before peer review. We call those “preprints”, but really these are scientific papers made public, so by definition they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; published. I follow the preprints in my field and I don’t see any particular loss in quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I think I was missing a key element. The more profound reason why many people, in particular experimental biologists, are so attached to peer review is in my view that they hold naive philosophical views about the notion of truth in science. A paper should be peer-reviewed because otherwise you can’t cite it as a true fact. Peer review validates science, thanks to experts who make sure that the claims of the authors are actually true. Of course it can go wrong and reviewers might miss something, but it is the purpose of peer review. This view is reflected in the tendency, especially in biology journals, to choose titles that look like established truths: “Hunger is controlled by HGRase”, instead of “The molecular control of hunger”. Scientists and journalists can then write revealed truths with a verse reference, such as “Hunger is controlled by HGRase (McDonald et al., 2017)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great misunderstanding is that truth is a notion that applies to logical propositions (for example, mathematical theorems), not to empirical claims. This has been well argued by Popper, for example. Truth is by nature a theoretical concept. Everything said is said with words, and in this sense it always refers to theoretical concepts. One can only judge whether observations are congruent with the meaning attributed to the words, and that meaning necessarily has a theoretical nature. There is no such thing as an “established fact”. This is so even of what we might consider as direct observations. Take for example the claim “The resting potential of neurons is -70 mV”. This is a theoretical statement. Why? First, because to establish it, I have recorded a number of neurons. If you test it, it will be on a different neuron, which I have not measured. So I am making a theoretical claim. Probably, I also tested my neurons with a particular method (not mentioning a particular region and species). But my claim makes no reference to the method by which I have made the inference. That would be the “methods” part of my paper, not the conclusion, and when you cite my paper, you will cite it because of the conclusion, the “established fact”, you will not be referring to the methods, which you consider are the means to establish the fact. It is the role of the reviewers to check the methods, to check that they do establish the fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these are trivial remarks. It is not just that the method matters. The very notion of an observation always implicitly relies on a theoretical background. When I say that the resting potential is -70 mV, I mean that there is a potential difference of -70 mV across the membrane. But that’s not what I measure. I measure the difference in potential between some point outside the cell and the inside of a patch pipette whose solution is in contact with the cell’s inside. So I am assuming the potential is the same in all points of the cytosol, even though I have not tested it. I am also implicitly modeling the cytosol as a solution, even though the reality is more complex than that, given the mass of charged proteins in it. I am assuming that the extracellular potential is constant. I am assuming that my pipette solution reasonably matches the actual cytosol solution, given that “solution” is only a convenient model. I am implicitly making all sorts of theoretical assumptions, which have a lot of empirical support but are still of a theoretical nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried with this example to show that even a very simple “fact” is actually a theoretical proposition, with many layers of assumptions. But of course in general, papers typically make claims that rely less firmly on accepted theoretical grounds, since they must be “novel”. So it is never the case that a paper definitely proves its conclusions. Because conclusions have a theoretical nature, all that can be checked is whether observations are consistent with the authors’ interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the goal of peer review can’t be to establish the truth. If it were the case, then why would reviewers ever disagree? They disagree because they cannot actually judge whether a claim is true; they can only say whether they are personally convinced. This makes the current peer review system extremely poor, because all the information we get is: two anonymous people were convinced (and maybe others were not, but we’ll never find out). What would be more useful would be to have an open public discussion, with criticisms, qualifications and alternative interpretations fully disclosed for anyone to read and make their own opinion. In such a system, the notion of a stamp of approval on a paper would simply be absurd; why hide the disapprovals? There is the paper, and there is the scientific discussion of the paper, and that is all there needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some concern these days that peer reviewed research is unreliable. Well, science is unreliable. That is almost what defines it: it can be criticized and revised. Seeing peer review as the system that establishes the scientific truth is not only a historical error, it is a great philosophical error, and a dangerous bureaucratic view of science. We don’t need editorial decisions based on peer review. We need free publication (&lt;a href=&quot;http://biorxiv.org/&quot;&gt;we have it&lt;/a&gt;) and we need open scientific discussion (&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubpeer.com/&quot;&gt;it’s coming&lt;/a&gt;). That’s all we need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 10:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Booty more amusing than ass, according to first in-depth study of the funniness of English words</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27334</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/26/booty-more-amusing-than-ass-according-to-first-in-depth-study-of-the-funniness-of-english-words/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-484958654.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27419&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27419&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;9&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A donkey on an island off the west coast of Ireland looks as though he is laughing. Shot in Black and White.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1403960790&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mariongalt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.001&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Laughing Donkey&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Laughing Donkey&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1415&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/26/booty-more-amusing-than-ass-according-to-first-in-depth-study-of-the-funniness-of-english-words/laughing-donkey/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-484958654.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was at primary school, we used to type out the word “BOOBIES” using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calculator_spelling&quot;&gt;upside-down digits&lt;/a&gt; on our electronic calculators and we thought it was hilarious. This was an all-boys school in the late 80s, cut us some slack. And anyway, maybe we weren’t so daft. The word (although spelt differently as “Booby”) was among the top-three most funny words as identified in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13428-017-0930-6&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Behaviour Research&lt;/em&gt;, which is the first in-depth investigation of the perceived funniness of individual English words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the 5000 words that were studied, Booty was rated the funniest of all, scoring 4.32 on average on a scale from 1 (not funny at all) to 5 (most funny). The lowest scoring word was Rape with an average of 1.18. The researchers Tomas Engelthaler and Thomas Hills at the University of Warwick, England hope their findings will provide a useful resource, a “highly rudimentary ‘fruit fly’ version” of humour” for &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-26/edition-4/how-many-psychologists-does-it-take-explain-joke&quot;&gt;researchers studying the psychology of what makes us laugh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27334&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 821 participants for the study (average age 35; 58 per cent were female) were recruited via Amazon’s Mechanical Turk online survey website. To ease them into the challenge, they each began by rating 11 “calibrator words” selected from pilot research because they’d attracted a wide range of funniness scores from high (Turd, scored at 3.78 in pilot research) to low (Drought, scored 1.13). After this, each participant rated the funniness of  approximately 200 more words selected at random from the 5000-word pool (taken from earlier studies into the subjective perception of English words). Participants were instructed to make their ratings based on their first and immediate reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 words to attract the highest funniness ratings were, in descending order from most funny:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Booty, Tit, Booby, Hooter, Nitwit, Twit, Waddle, Tinkle, Bebop, Egghead, Ass and Twerp&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 words to attract the lowest funniness ratings were, starting with the most humourless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rape, Torture, Torment, Gunshot, Death, Nightmare, War, Trauma, Rapist, Distrust, Deathbed, Pain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers main objective was to create a useful data-set for future experiments into humour (similar to how others have created average ratings of concreteness, arousal, &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/05/18/why-do-so-many-people-dislike-the-word-moist/&quot;&gt;pleasantness&lt;/a&gt; and age-of-acquisition for other words), but they did perform a few comparisons with their findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, the researchers looked at the words for which men and women most strongly differed in the funniness ratings they gave, including the following which were rated funnier on average by men than women:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bondage, Birthmark, Orgy, Brand, Chauffeur, Doze, Buzzard, Czar, Weld, Prod, Corn, Raccoon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the following words, which were rated as funnier by women than men:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Giggle, Beast, Circus, Grand, Juju, Humbug, Slicker, Sweat, Ennui, Holder, Momma, Sod&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the following words were those that attracted the most similar high funniness ratings across both sexes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chug, Fluff, Scrotum, Jabber, Joke, Buttocks, Boon, Yank, Tinker, Prance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the words that tended to attract high funniness ratings and seeing how they have scored for other dimensions in previous research, Engelthaler and Hills found that they tended to be less frequent and to take people longer to recognise as words. Another thing: whereas previous research has found that we tend to have a positive bias towards words, finding most of them to be positive in tone and meaning, the current research found that we have a bias toward seeing most words as more unfunny than funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, time for me to stop all this jabber, I’m going to waddle off for a tinkle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13428-017-0930-6&quot;&gt;Humor norms for 4,997 English words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27334/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27334/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27334&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 09:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: How personalized metrics can change behavior and improve research performance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-personalized-metrics-can-change-behavior-and-improve-research-performance</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/how-personalized-metrics-can-change-behavior-and-improve-research-performance</link>
	<description>Using SciVal, Queen’s University Belfast worked with Elsevier’s Research Metrics team to increase citations and change its approach to publishing</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 09:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Big names in statistics want to shake up much-maligned P value</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22375</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oZsASln3Z2w/nature.2017.22375</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;One of scientists’ favourite statistics — the  P  value — should face tougher standards, say leading researchers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22375&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22375&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oZsASln3Z2w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: 'True blue' chrysanthemum flowers produced with genetic engineering</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22365</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hDgsWbx6v0w/nature.2017.22365</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists added two genes to the plant's genome to get the new hue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22365&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22365&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hDgsWbx6v0w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: China’s quest to become a space science superpower</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547394a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/IMSmRgZUL6s/547394a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;With major spaceflight milestones behind it, China is working to build an international reputation for space science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 394 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547394a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547394a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/IMSmRgZUL6s&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Brain’s stem cells slow ageing in mice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547389a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/-sON1YoqqaA/547389a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Transplanted cells offer middle-aged rodents an increased lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 389 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547389a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547389a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/-sON1YoqqaA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: HIV milestone, discrimination suit and China's AI plans</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547384a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/p0HMohZzH38/547384a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 21–27 July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 384 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547384a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547384a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/p0HMohZzH38&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: More universities must confront sexual harassment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547379a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/YcXSRu3nTdY/547379a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Too many institutions give low priority to tackling sexual misconduct in science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 379 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547379a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547379a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/YcXSRu3nTdY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: In vivo FRET–FLIM reveals cell-type-specific protein interactions in Arabidopsis roots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23317</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/nIjsZVVakvE/nature23317</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 During multicellular development, specification of distinct cell fates is often regulated by the same transcription factors operating differently in distinct cis-regulatory modules, either through different protein complexes, conformational modification of protein complexes, or combinations of both. Direct visualization of different transcription factor complex states guiding specific gene expression programs has been challenging. Here we use in vivo FRET–FLIM (Förster resonance energy transfer measured by fluorescence lifetime microscopy) to reveal spatial partitioning of protein interactions in relation to specification of cell fate. We show that, in Arabidopsis roots, three fully functional fluorescently tagged cell fate regulators establish cell-type-specific interactions at endogenous expression levels and can form higher order complexes. We reveal that cell-type-specific in vivo FRET–FLIM distributions reflect conformational changes of these complexes to differentially regulate target genes and specify distinct cell fates. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23317&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23317&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/nIjsZVVakvE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Derivation of ground-state female ES cells maintaining gamete-derived DNA methylation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23286</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/j3wz3Nie17w/nature23286</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Inhibitors of Mek1/2 and Gsk3β, known as 2i, enhance the derivation of embryonic stem (ES) cells and promote ground-state pluripotency in rodents. Here we show that the derivation of female mouse ES cells in the presence of 2i and leukaemia inhibitory factor (2i/L ES cells) results in a widespread loss of DNA methylation, including a massive erasure of genomic imprints. Despite this global loss of DNA methylation, early-passage 2i/L ES cells efficiently differentiate into somatic cells, and this process requires genome-wide de novo DNA methylation. However, the majority of imprinting control regions (ICRs) remain unmethylated in 2i/L-ES-cell-derived differentiated cells. Consistently, 2i/L ES cells exhibit impaired autonomous embryonic and placental development by tetraploid embryo complementation or nuclear transplantation. We identified the derivation conditions of female ES cells that display 2i/L-ES-cell-like transcriptional signatures while preserving gamete-derived DNA methylation and autonomous developmental potential. Upon prolonged culture, however, female ES cells exhibited ICR demethylation regardless of culture conditions. Our results provide insights into the derivation of female ES cells reminiscent of the inner cell mass of preimplantation embryos. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23286&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23286&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/j3wz3Nie17w&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Stimulation of functional neuronal regeneration from Müller glia in adult mice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23283</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/qq7pogCCsuw/nature23283</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Many retinal diseases lead to the loss of retinal neurons and cause visual impairment. The adult mammalian retina has little capacity for regeneration. By contrast, teleost fish functionally regenerate their retina following injury, and Müller glia (MG) are the source of regenerated neurons. The proneural transcription factor Ascl1 is upregulated in MG after retinal damage in zebrafish and is necessary for regeneration. Although Ascl1 is not expressed in mammalian MG after injury, forced expression of Ascl1 in mouse MG induces a neurogenic state in vitro and in vivo after NMDA (N-methyl-d-aspartate) damage in young mice. However, by postnatal day 16, mouse MG lose neurogenic capacity, despite Ascl1 overexpression. Loss of neurogenic capacity in mature MG is accompanied by reduced chromatin accessibility, suggesting that epigenetic factors limit regeneration. Here we show that MG-specific overexpression of Ascl1, together with a histone deacetylase inhibitor, enables adult mice to generate neurons from MG after retinal injury. The MG-derived neurons express markers of inner retinal neurons, synapse with host retinal neurons, and respond to light. Using an assay for transposase-accessible chromatin with high-throughput sequencing (ATAC–seq), we show that the histone deacetylase inhibitor promotes accessibility at key gene loci in the MG, and allows more effective reprogramming. Our results thus provide a new approach for the treatment of blinding retinal diseases. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23283&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23283&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/qq7pogCCsuw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Hypothalamic stem cells control ageing speed partly through exosomal miRNAs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23282</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/JjUMDNrU3xg/nature23282</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 It has been proposed that the hypothalamus helps to control ageing, but the mechanisms responsible remain unclear. Here we develop several mouse models in which hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells that co-express Sox2 and Bmi1 are ablated, as we observed that ageing in mice started with a substantial loss of these hypothalamic cells. Each mouse model consistently displayed acceleration of ageing-like physiological changes or a shortened lifespan. Conversely, ageing retardation and lifespan extension were achieved in mid-aged mice that were locally implanted with healthy hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells that had been genetically engineered to survive in the ageing-related hypothalamic inflammatory microenvironment. Mechanistically, hypothalamic stem/progenitor cells contributed greatly to exosomal microRNAs (miRNAs) in the cerebrospinal fluid, and these exosomal miRNAs declined during ageing, whereas central treatment with healthy hypothalamic stem/progenitor cell-secreted exosomes led to the slowing of ageing. In conclusion, ageing speed is substantially controlled by hypothalamic stem cells, partially through the release of exosomal miRNAs. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23282&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23282&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/JjUMDNrU3xg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Prolonged Mek1/2 suppression impairs the developmental potential of embryonic stem cells</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23274</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/xUhQ6yQFQ00/nature23274</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Concomitant activation of the Wnt pathway and suppression of Mapk signalling by two small molecule inhibitors (2i) in the presence of leukaemia inhibitory factor (LIF) (hereafter termed 2i/L) induces a naive state in mouse embryonic stem (ES) cells that resembles the inner cell mass (ICM) of the pre-implantation embryo. Since the ICM exists only transiently in vivo, it remains unclear how sustained propagation of naive ES cells in vitro affects their stability and functionality. Here we show that prolonged culture of male mouse ES cells in 2i/L results in irreversible epigenetic and genomic changes that impair their developmental potential. Furthermore, we find that female ES cells cultured in conventional serum plus LIF medium phenocopy male ES cells cultured in 2i/L. Mechanistically, we demonstrate that the inhibition of Mek1/2 is predominantly responsible for these effects, in part through the downregulation of DNA methyltransferases and their cofactors. Finally, we show that replacement of the Mek1/2 inhibitor with a Src inhibitor preserves the epigenetic and genomic integrity as well as the developmental potential of ES cells. Taken together, our data suggest that, although short-term suppression of Mek1/2 in ES cells helps to maintain an ICM-like epigenetic state, prolonged suppression results in irreversible changes that compromise their developmental potential. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23274&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23274&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/xUhQ6yQFQ00&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Higher-order interactions stabilize dynamics in competitive network models</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23273</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ZxFGAp7Y08E/nature23273</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Ecologists have long sought a way to explain how the remarkable biodiversity observed in nature is maintained. On the one hand, simple models of interacting competitors cannot produce the stable persistence of very large ecological communities. On the other hand, neutral models, in which species do not interact and diversity is maintained by immigration and speciation, yield unrealistically small fluctuations in population abundance, and a strong positive correlation between a species’ abundance and its age, contrary to empirical evidence. Models allowing for the robust persistence of large communities of interacting competitors are lacking. Here we show that very diverse communities could persist thanks to the stabilizing role of higher-order interactions, in which the presence of a species influences the interaction between other species. Although higher-order interactions have been studied for decades, their role in shaping ecological communities is still unclear. The inclusion of higher-order interactions in competitive network models stabilizes dynamics, making species coexistence robust to the perturbation of both population abundance and parameter values. We show that higher-order interactions have strong effects in models of closed ecological communities, as well as of open communities in which new species are constantly introduced. In our framework, higher-order interactions are completely defined by pairwise interactions, facilitating empirical parameterization and validation of our models. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23273&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23273&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ZxFGAp7Y08E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Complex cellular logic computation using ribocomputing devices</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23271</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/Im5ft398v8c/nature23271</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Synthetic biology aims to develop engineering-driven approaches to the programming of cellular functions that could yield transformative technologies. Synthetic gene circuits that combine DNA, protein, and RNA components have demonstrated a range of functions such as bistability, oscillation, feedback, and logic capabilities. However, it remains challenging to scale up these circuits owing to the limited number of designable, orthogonal, high-performance parts, the empirical and often tedious composition rules, and the requirements for substantial resources for encoding and operation. Here, we report a strategy for constructing RNA-only nanodevices to evaluate complex logic in living cells. Our ‘ribocomputing’ systems are composed of de-novo-designed parts and operate through predictable and designable base-pairing rules, allowing the effective in silico design of computing devices with prescribed configurations and functions in complex cellular environments. These devices operate at the post-transcriptional level and use an extended RNA transcript to co-localize all circuit sensing, computation, signal transduction, and output elements in the same self-assembled molecular complex, which reduces diffusion-mediated signal losses, lowers metabolic cost, and improves circuit reliability. We demonstrate that ribocomputing devices in Escherichia coli can evaluate two-input logic with a dynamic range up to 900-fold and scale them to four-input AND, six-input OR, and a complex 12-input expression (A1 AND A2 AND NOT A1*) OR (B1 AND B2 AND NOT B2*) OR (C1 AND C2) OR (D1 AND D2) OR (E1 AND E2). Successful operation of ribocomputing devices based on programmable RNA interactions suggests that systems employing the same design principles could be implemented in other host organisms or in extracellular settings. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23271&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23271&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/Im5ft398v8c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Sequencing and de novo assembly of 150 genomes from Denmark as a population reference</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23264</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/QSlVa-oC1tY/nature23264</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Hundreds of thousands of human genomes are now being sequenced to characterize genetic variation and use this information to augment association mapping studies of complex disorders and other phenotypic traits. Genetic variation is identified mainly by mapping short reads to the reference genome or by performing local assembly. However, these approaches are biased against discovery of structural variants and variation in the more complex parts of the genome. Hence, large-scale de novo assembly is needed. Here we show that it is possible to construct excellent de novo assemblies from high-coverage sequencing with mate-pair libraries extending up to 20 kilobases. We report de novo assemblies of 150 individuals (50 trios) from the GenomeDenmark project. The quality of these assemblies is similar to those obtained using the more expensive long-read technology. We use the assemblies to identify a rich set of structural variants including many novel insertions and demonstrate how this variant catalogue enables further deciphering of known association mapping signals. We leverage the assemblies to provide 100 completely resolved major histocompatibility complex haplotypes and to resolve major parts of the Y chromosome. Our study provides a regional reference genome that we expect will improve the power of future association mapping studies and hence pave the way for precision medicine initiatives, which now are being launched in many countries including Denmark. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23264&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23264&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/QSlVa-oC1tY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Ecology: Contests between species aid biodiversity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23103</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/r3mChb-0wuQ/nature23103</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A modelling approach used to investigate competition between different species provides insight into how contests that have multiple players can help to maintain biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23103&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23103&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/r3mChb-0wuQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Stem cells: The cost of perpetual youth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23102</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/NdgvXFqpuxg/nature23102</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to become nearly any cell type is restricted to eggs, sperm and primitive stem cells in very early embryos. Two studies reveal that maintaining this pluripotent state  in vitro  comes at a cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23102&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23102&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/NdgvXFqpuxg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Wilhelm et al. reply</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22294</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/l57yDkMiE7I/nature22294</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 E23 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22294&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22294&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/l57yDkMiE7I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Can we predict protein from mRNA levels?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22293</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/g-NldABHMmU/nature22293</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 E19 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22293&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22293&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/g-NldABHMmU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Good news</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547486a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/CIjlH98udwM/547486a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A global success?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 486 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547486a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547486a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/CIjlH98udwM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Imaging: History's take on the atomic forge</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403e</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/d31jTU0366U/547403e</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/d31jTU0366U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Thirty Meter Telescope: Alternative telescope site is a good back-up</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403d</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6F_kHLplC7Q/547403d</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6F_kHLplC7Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Biodiversity: Factor in species' conservation value</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403c</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/oCWs-gS0f0Y/547403c</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403c&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/oCWs-gS0f0Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Open data: support from Swiss funder</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/czS-XuUQdjg/547403b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/czS-XuUQdjg&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Open data: enforce materials sharing</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/kv43JOAQyYY/547403a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547403a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547403a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/kv43JOAQyYY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: In retrospect: Das Kapital</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547401a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/PIxwuTXtaL0/547401a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;As the world is reshaped by another industrial revolution, Gareth Stedman Jones revisits Karl Marx's opus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 401 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547401a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547401a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/PIxwuTXtaL0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Climate change: Al Gore gets inconvenient again</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547400a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/fvlBdGNDy-c/547400a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Mann views the US statesman's second film probing climate change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 400 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547400a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547400a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/fvlBdGNDy-c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Most football players who donated their brains to science had traumatic injury</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-football-players-who-donated-their-brains-science-had-traumatic-injury</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/most-football-players-who-donated-their-brains-science-had-traumatic-injury</link>
	<description>A self-selected sample of 202 deceased football players, the largest to date, finds that the majority suffered from chronic traumatic encephalopathy.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 20:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072517_AC_football-head-injury_main_free.jpg?itok=XWpnpJ_k" length="43650" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Add penis bacteria to the list of HIV risk factors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/add-penis-bacteria-list-hiv-risk-factors</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/add-penis-bacteria-list-hiv-risk-factors</link>
	<description>Certain bacteria found on the penis raise the risk of HIV infection, a new study finds.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 16:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072517_LH_HIV_main.jpg?itok=IORQNUNY" length="32363" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: How earthquake scientists eavesdrop on North Korea’s nuclear blasts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earthquakes-north-korea-nuclear-testing</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earthquakes-north-korea-nuclear-testing</link>
	<description>Researchers monitor the power and location of underground nuclear weapons testing by North Korea.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/080517_feat_seismology_main.jpg?itok=-sRAu8xa" length="56005" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: May the sting be with you: Another journal prank, too good to overlook</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51172</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/may-sting-another-journal-prank-good-overlook/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes, we know: It’s easy to publish “fake” papers in journals and expose the inherent flaws of academic publishing. We’ve covered many such stings, but there are simply too many for us to cover all.  Still, occasionally one is just too clever to ignore. On Saturday, the pseudonymous blogger Neuroskeptic announced that they had […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/may-sting-another-journal-prank-good-overlook/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;May the sting be with you: Another journal prank, too good to overlook&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 14:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Uni dings schizophrenia studies for problems with informed consent, other flaws</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51149</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/uni-dings-schizophrenia-studies-problems-informed-consent-flaws/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Psychiatry journals have retracted two papers evaluating a schizophrenia drug after a university in Japan flagged issues, such as a lack of written informed consent. The papers—published in Human Psychopharmacology: Clinical &amp;amp; Experimental in 2012 and Psychiatry and Clinical Neurosciences in 2014—examined the safety and effectiveness of an antipsychotic drug in patients with schizophrenia. According […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/25/uni-dings-schizophrenia-studies-problems-informed-consent-flaws/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Uni dings schizophrenia studies for problems with informed consent, other flaws&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: There’s a long way to go in understanding the brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/neuroscience-understanding-brain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/context/neuroscience-understanding-brain</link>
	<description>Neuroscientists offer multiple “perspectives” on how to plug gaps in current knowledge of the brain’s inner workings.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/context_nerve-cell-illustration_free.jpg?itok=YVkeYtVy" length="25200" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: CiteScore highlights top-cited journals neglected by other metrics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-highlights-top-cited-journals-neglected-by-other-metrics</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/citescore-highlights-top-cited-journals-neglected-by-other-metrics</link>
	<description>CiteScore is the only metric for more than 200 top-quality academic journals from numerous publishers</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 09:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Your face gives clues to your name, suggesting your name has affected your appearance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27296</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/25/your-face-gives-clues-to-your-name-suggesting-your-name-has-affected-your-appearance/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_27320&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot 2017-07-25 09.49.22&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-27320 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27320&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Screenshot 2017-07-25 09.49.22&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=732&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;732,674&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/25/your-face-gives-clues-to-your-name-suggesting-your-name-has-affected-your-appearance/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22/&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/screenshot-2017-07-25-09-49-22.png?w=300&amp;amp;h=276&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;Example of test material from &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2017-08698-001.html&quot;&gt;Zwebner et al&lt;/a&gt;. See footer for correct name.&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can we tell about someone from their face? Their favoured facial expressions can hint at their temperament, the weathering of their skin at their life history, their facial hair and makeup at their aesthetic taste. But now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-08698-001&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;i&gt;Attitudes and Social Cognition&lt;/i&gt; suggests that we can also intuit their names, because a person’s given name influences their facial appearance in adult life. On the face of it (sorry) this is hard to believe, but the case, made across eight studies, is based on plenty of careful evidence, and also proposes a plausible explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27296&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first of several experiments, Yonat Zwebner at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem and his team showed student participants 20 colour headshots of a person with a neutral expression and asked them to choose which of five given names they would assign to each face based on sheer intuition. The given names included the true name of the person in the photo and four alternatives. When participants picked the name that genuinely belonged to the photo’s subject, they were scored as correct. Chance performance (i.e. random guessing) would mean getting 20 per cent correct, on average, but the participants performed better, at 28 per cent. For 17 of the 20 faces they achieved greater accuracy than you’d expect based on random guessing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another study was similar but this time Zwebner and his colleagues used photos only belonging to people from an Ashkenazi Israeli ethnic background and who were in their mid-twenties, and the mix of actual and filler names were all drawn from the same ethnic population (the intention was that this would avoid potential confounds due to participants choosing the correct name because of extrapolation from the name or ethnicity). This study also threw in a control condition – participants had the same menu of names to pick from, but the photos were covered up – the idea was to check whether participants’ were being drawn to the correct names because they were for some reason simply more pickable. In fact, participants in the control condition showed no tendency towards picking the true names, whereas participants who could see the photos managed an average face-name matching accuracy of 25 per cent (again better than you’d expect if they’d just guessed at random).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In further studies, the researchers made sure they took account of the possible influence of the relative popularity of different names. They also conducted a replication in France with photos of French people and featuring French names. Whatever changes they made, the researchers found the same thing: based purely on the appearance of someone’s face, participants had an inkling of their name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same proved true when the researchers programmed a computer to match names to faces. Through machine learning processes using a training set of nearly 100,000 faces drawn from an online networking site, a computer programme learned to distinguish between true and false names of faces at better than chance levels. The data was rich enough to evaluate specific comparisons, so we know that in this dataset the algorithm found it impossible to tell from her photo whether a woman was called Emilie as opposed to Jeannie, but found it almost no trouble to tell whether another woman was called Emma rather than Veronique (in this case achieving 95 per cent accuracy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s going on? One possibility is that we give babies names that somehow reflect their physical properties, and observers are simply drawing on these same associations to guide their judgments. This would be an example of the wonderfully titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://https//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bouba/kiki_effect&quot;&gt;bouba-kiki effect&lt;/a&gt;, wherein across cultures certain sounds seem soft or round, others hard or sharp. However this seems a bit of a reach, given that at the time most babies are named, they are still pretty similar-looking (sorry parents).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, when the researchers looked for cross-cultural effects by testing Israeli students with French stimuli and vice-versa, they found none: the participants lost the ability to match names at better than chance levels. If the bouba-kiki effects was behind it, the feel of the names – independent of their cultural meaning – would be sufficient to make the associations. So &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/2017/02/27/dorian-gray-effect-name-alters-face/&quot;&gt;despite some earlier coverage&lt;/a&gt;, this isn’t a compelling explanation for the new data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zwebner and his team think it is likelier that their findings reflect some sort of self-fulfilling prophecy. Within a given culture, names carry associations – historical and celebrity figures, “types” (a Kevin versus a Brad), and cues related to class or background (contrast Tony with Tristan). Once a person is named, these associations form a filter through which all their future interactions take place – starting with parental guidance and expectations, then first encounters with schoolyard peers, career guidance counselling – and even if the filter is a subtle one, over a lifetime these effects can accumulate to impact how we act in the world, and ultimately this ends up written in our faces –  by our preference for smiles over frowns, big mugging expressions over wry understated ones, or an open relaxed visage rather than one tight-lipped and controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this explanation is correct, we’d expect to see a stronger influence of names upon those parts of the face and appearance that are more under voluntary control. Consistent with this, in one study the researchers found that removing hair style (arguably one of the aspects of our appearance over which we have most control) from the photos significant reduced participants’ ability to identify the correct names for the photos, though they still performed better than chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To investigate this more deeply, Zwebner’s team turned to their algorithm, investigating which pixels of each photo were most useful in making accurate name-matches, and using this data to create heat-maps of the faces. These clearly showed the margins of the faces (aside from hair itself) were next to useless and the nose and ears were also of limited value. The most important facial areas for correct name identification were the brows, eyes and mouth – areas that are habitually engaged in voluntary facial expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests that the effect due to given names is an extension of the Dorian Grey effect, the phenomenon where personality influences facial appearance. In terms of links between facial appearance and personality, we already know that short-tempered people tense certain facial muscles more frequently than do relaxed people, which can make their resting face appear angry, for example. Or that adolescent women who are more sociable are perceived as more attractive later in life, presumably because smile lines are construed as more attractive than a tight-set face.  The bundle of associations that make Celina’s name reflected in her face are arguably doing the same thing, but through a more circuitous route (for example, the name label leading to differential treatment that then contributes to personality, and finally onto the face), which would explain why the effects were statistically significant but not large in size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re struggling to pick the ideal appellation for your newborn, these new findings suggest that on top of everything else you have to worry about, your decision will likely influence what they look like as an adult – but only to a small extent. If you want to predict their future appearance, you won’t find the answers by gazing at their potential namesakes. But you might get a clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/2017-08698-001&quot;&gt;We look like our names: The manifestation of name stereotypes in facial appearance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2017-08698-001.html&quot;&gt;Zwebner et al, 2017&lt;/a&gt;. The correct name for this example is Dan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27296/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27296/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27296&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 08:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Australia cuts conservation protections in marine parks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22369</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/5Ci3v8G1Xvc/nature.2017.22369</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Conservationists accuse government of ignoring science-based recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22369&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22369&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/5Ci3v8G1Xvc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Metrology is key to reproducing results</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547397a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/l-YzDMPYbF8/547397a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists of all stripes must work with measurement experts so that studies can be compared, urge Martyn Sené, Ian Gilmore and Jan-Theodoor Janssen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 397 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547397a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547397a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/l-YzDMPYbF8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Budding UK innovation agency gains cash — and clout</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547390a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/jH6EQ9SFRsQ/547390a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Business-focused funding agency Innovate UK is driving British efforts to commercialize research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 390 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547390a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547390a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/jH6EQ9SFRsQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Don't run biomedical science as a business</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547381a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/2babAlGG2zo/547381a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Science should abandon its assembly-line mentality and rebuild for quality, not quantity, argues Michele Pagano.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 381 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547381a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547381a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/2babAlGG2zo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The digital native is a myth</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547380a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/x8vBDm1VUO0/547380a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The younger generation uses technology in the same ways as older people — and is no better at multitasking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 380 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547380a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547380a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/x8vBDm1VUO0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘Making Contact’ chronicles an astronomer’s struggle to find E.T.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/making-contact-chronicles-astronomers-struggles-find-aliens</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/making-contact-chronicles-astronomers-struggles-find-aliens</link>
	<description>For decades, astronomer Jill Tarter led the hunt for extraterrestrial intelligence, as detailed in a new biography.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 20:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/080517_reviews_bookshelf-astronomer-main.jpg?itok=MWth2td7" length="17775" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Following uproar, surgery journal retracts paper with male-only pronouns</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51164</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/following-uproar-surgery-journal-retracts-paper-male-pronouns/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Annals of Surgery has retracted a paper that used only male pronouns to describe surgeons following outcry from readers. The journal plans to replace the article — a recent presidential address of the European Surgical Association — with a new version with more “gender inclusive language.” The problem, said editor Keith D. Lillemoe, is that […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/following-uproar-surgery-journal-retracts-paper-male-pronouns/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Following uproar, surgery journal retracts paper with male-only pronouns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Nootropics: How Smart Can You Get on Smart Drugs?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22686</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/24/nootropics-how-smart-you-can-get-on-smart-drugs/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The use of smart drugs is becoming “trendy”. Lots of people are taking various substances regularly, many others try them from time to time. The idea of enhancing the brain’s ability, or tapping into its unused reservoir is definitely sexy, and many people are actively looking for information on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shortage of scientifically verified information is exactly the reason I’m writing this article. Although thousand of publications on “&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/18/memory-enhancement-nootropics-and-electromagnetic-stimulation/&quot;&gt;smart drugs&lt;/a&gt;”, “cognitive enhancers”, and “nootropics” etc. can be found online, the overwhelming majority of claims are unsubstantiated or unashamedly commercialized. This means that the info you come across mostly consists of descriptions of personal opinions or experiences, or compilations of facts published elsewhere, or just articles from popular media where people can write whatever they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple websites publish all kind of rubbish just to convince you to buy yet another wonderfully effective smart drug. Few people make an effort to refer to their sources of information, not to mention to present scientific and statistical data backing their claims. This is particularly enigmatic when these articles provide recipes for various drug combinations and claim the superiority of some of these combinations/compounds over the others. However, even scientific data on the subject is rather incomplete. Many studies were done using only a small number of participants, or in the absence of any reasonable controls. On their own, studies of such kind are of little, if any, value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, several systematic reviews and meta-analyses on the use of nootropics were published in the last couple of years. Systematic reviews and meta-analyses combine data from multiple individual studies, thus making the data statistically significant. This is a better way of assessing the efficacy of different drugs in the general, healthy population, and these are the publications that I will mostly use as reference points in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to prove that a smart drug is really smart?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart drugs (e.g., nootropics and cognitive enhancers) are defined as substances that improve cognitive function, particularly executive functions, memory, creativity, or motivation, in &lt;u&gt;healthy individuals&lt;/u&gt;. The last bit is important: there are many drugs that were specifically developed to enhance brain functions in people with various cognitive disorders or deficits. Such drugs won’t necessarily smarten up healthy people, and when they do, they are not necessarily safe. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/01/29/nootropics-reduce-the-severity-of-brain-trauma/&quot;&gt;Nootropics &lt;/a&gt;may come in many forms, from classical pharmaceutics in the form of pills to herbal supplements and “functional foods”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only few smart drugs that are proven to improve some aspects of cognition. Proving that a compound has the properties of a nootropic is not a simple task. There is no straightforward way of measuring whatever cognitive enhancement you may experience once the pill is taken. The drug may indeed work and visibly increase your productivity. But it may also simply improve your mood if you anticipate a positive effect. On top of this, any given drug may work for some people and not work for others. Furthermore, the use of any drug is associated with potential side effects (e.g., headaches) that might eliminate its advantages in productivity and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/12/14/decoding-creativity-its-in-the-genes/&quot;&gt;creativity&lt;/a&gt;. If the changes in productivity can be measured using some tests, creativity still remains something arguably impossible to quantify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How smart drugs work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several mechanisms that can be involved in the functioning of smart drugs. Some drugs can increase the blood flow (and thus oxygen supply) to the brain. Others can accelerate neuronal communication through increased release of certain neuromediators or through agonistic effects on the receptors of these neuromediators. Some compounds can serve as biochemical precursors of neuromediators, others may prevent oxidative damage to brain cells or provide them with a source of energy. Some of these changes can be achieved quickly making the drugs work almost instantly. Others, such as amendment/prevention of neuronal damage, manifest themselves only after prolonged use of the drug, thus making any changes in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/15/brain-training-can-we-really-enhance-our-cognitive-skills/&quot;&gt;cognitive functions&lt;/a&gt; not so fast and not so obvious (although they can still be substantial).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short overview of most popular nootropics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/11/18/memory-enhancement-nootropics-and-electromagnetic-stimulation/&quot;&gt;Amphetamines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are a class of pharmaceuticals that include &lt;strong&gt;adderall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;dextroamphetamine&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;lisdexamphetamine&lt;/strong&gt;. The drugs were developed to treat people with ADHD (attention deficit hyperactivity disorder) and this is where their effects are the most prominent. The drugs were also demonstrated to improve episodic memory, working memory, and some aspects of attention in the general population. At low doses they improve memory consolidation, recall of information, and motivation to perform tasks that require high degree of attention. &lt;strong&gt;Ritalin&lt;/strong&gt; is structurally different from amphetamines and works through different mechanisms, although produces similar effects. Both amphetamines and ritalin improve cognitive functions, albeit only at lower doses. At high doses they stimulate other neural pathways not involved in learning that effectively cancel their positive effects on cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wakefulness-promoting agents&lt;/strong&gt;, such as &lt;strong&gt;modafinil&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;armodafinil&lt;/strong&gt;, increase alertness, counteract fatigue, and increase productivity and motivation. Modafinil is praised for its ability to improve reaction time, logical reasoning, and problem-solving. The drug is clinically prescribed  for a number of conditions including sleep apnea, narcolepsy, and shift work sleep disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compounds from the &lt;strong&gt;racetam family&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;piracetam, oxiracetam&lt;/strong&gt; etc.) are more extensively studied compared than the newer nootropics. Piracetam was developed back in the 1960s and has an almost perfect safety profile. Convincingly, it was shown to improve cognitive abilities, particularly in older people and those with cognitive impairment. Although piracetam is officially recognized as a nootropic, its brain-enhancing effects in healthy people are considered to be moderate. There is a number of other derivatives from this group of drugs which, allegedly, work better. A good example is &lt;strong&gt;phenotropil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; This compound was developed in Russia where it is available as a prescription drug. It was demonstrated to have a memory enhancing effect. The drug can be used as a stimulant and enhances resistance to extreme temperatures and stress. Due to its stimulating effect, phenotropil is banned by the World Anti-Doping Agency, which means that it cannot be used by athletes intending to compete in official events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xanthines, such as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/01/26/nurturing-the-brain-part-i-caffeine/&quot;&gt;caffeine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, are some of the most commonly used compounds with nootropic effects. In particular, they increase alertness and performance levels. Caffeine is not what comes to mind when we think of nootropics, but apparently its effect is comparable to many pharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L-Theanine&lt;/strong&gt;, a chemical component of green tea, is very well studied and its effects on promoting alertness and attention are confirmed by multiple research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to nutraceuticals and herbal supplements, recent studies appear to be contradictory. Some data do support the memory-enhancing effects of such plants as &lt;em&gt;Gingko biloba&lt;/em&gt;, Asian ginseng, and &lt;em&gt;Bacopa monnieri&lt;/em&gt;, but systematic reviews do not find convincing evidence of their effectiveness. It is likely that herbal supplements may work well over longer periods of time and improve cognitive abilities, but in the short term their effects are not particularly obvious. The same applies to many vitamins, such as vitamin E and B group vitamins, as well as Omega-3 fatty acids: the evidence supporting their benefits are limited at the present time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude, only few drugs are scientifically proven to be associated with moderate cognitive enhancement effects in the healthy population. Being sceptical when assessing information on smart drugs from the internet is a good idea: lots of ridiculous rubbish is published online. Most nootropics are relatively safe, but side effects are always a possibility since the response to nootropics is highly individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spencer BC et al. (2015) The Cognition-Enhancing Effects of Psychostimulants Involve Direct Action in the Prefrontal Cortex. Biological Psychiatry 77, 940–950. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016%2Fj.biopsych.2014.09.013&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.09.013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ilieva IP et al. (2015) Prescription Stimulants’ Effects on Healthy Inhibitory Control, Working Memory, and Episodic Memory: A Meta-analysis. J Cogn Neurosci. 27, 1069-1089. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1162%2Fjocn_a_00776&quot;&gt;10.1162/jocn_a_00776&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bagot KS and Kaminer Y (2014) Efficacy of stimulants for cognitive enhancement in non-attention deficit hyperactivity disorder youth: a systematic review. Addiction 109, 547–557. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1111%2Fadd.12460&quot;&gt;10.1111/add.12460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linssen AMW et al. (2014) Cognitive effects of methylphenidate in healthy volunteers: a review of single dose studies. &lt;em&gt;Int J Neuropsychopharmacol&lt;/em&gt; 17, 961-977. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_object_identifier&quot;&gt;doi&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1017%2FS1461145713001594&quot;&gt;10.1017/S1461145713001594&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban KR and Gao WJ (2014) Performance enhancement at the cost of potential brain plasticity: neural ramifications of nootropic drugs in the healthy developing brain. Front. Syst. Neurosci.| &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2014.00038&quot;&gt;doi: 10.3389/fnsys.2014.00038&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winblad B (2005) Piracetam: a review of pharmacological properties and clinical uses. CNS Drug Rev. 11, 169-182. PMID:16007238&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zvejniece L et al. (2011) Investigation into Stereoselective Pharmacological Activity of Phenotropil. Basic &amp;amp; Clinical Pharmacology &amp;amp; Toxicology 109, 407–412. doi: 10.1111/j.1742-7843.2011.00742.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rogers PJ (2007) Caffeine, mood and mental performance in everyday life. Nutrition Bulletin 32, 84–89. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-3010.2007.00607.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camfield DA et al. (2014) Acute effects of tea constituents L-theanine, caffeine, and epigallocatechin gallate on cognitive function and mood: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev 72, 507-522. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1111/nure.12120&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/nure.12120&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Pexels-2286921/&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: NIH section chief with 19 retractions is no longer running a lab</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51156</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/nih-section-chief-19-retractions-no-longer-running-lab/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A former section chief at the National Institutes of Health who has had 19 papers retracted is no longer running a lab, Retraction Watch has learned. In the last three years, Stanley Rapoport, who is based at the U.S. National Institute on Aging (NIA), has lost 19 papers due to the misconduct of three different […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/nih-section-chief-19-retractions-no-longer-running-lab/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NIH section chief with 19 retractions is no longer running a lab&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fewer big rogue planets roam the galaxy, recount shows</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fewer-big-rogue-planets-roam-galaxy-recount-shows</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/fewer-big-rogue-planets-roam-galaxy-recount-shows</link>
	<description>Jupiter-mass planets without parent solar systems are less common than astronomers thought, a new study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/082117_AY_rogue-planet_main.jpg?itok=7-c9mFJu" length="64957" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: A Publishing Milestone to Celebrate: 200,000 PLOS Research Articles and Counting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7673</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/0EQ7vKTIN-4/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/200K-blog-post-image-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2003, PLOS published its first research article and this month we’re proud to announce that we have now published more than 200,000 research articles across our seven Open Access journals. It has been an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/history&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;amazing journey &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;to reach this milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In only 14 years of existence, PLOS has helped catalyze the rapid growth of the Open Access literature. The 200,000th article is a remarkable milestone for PLOS and for the scientific community that has supported the Open Access movement.”-Veronique Kiermer, PLOS Executive Editor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d like to take this opportunity to thank those who have helped rapidly create this large corpus of diverse, Open Access research:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nearly 1,000,000 authors who trusted PLOS to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/why-publish-with-plos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;maximize the accessibility and readership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of their research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2017/03/thank-you-from-plos/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;7,000 editorial board members and 70,000+ volunteer peer reviewers &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;each year for their contribution to making PLOS journals’ content strong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thousands of journalists who &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/press-kit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report on trusted PLOS content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online readers of our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/innovation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;organization’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, who have made &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; one of the 50 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexa.com/topsites/category/Science&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most-visited science websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, creating a global audience for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/2016-research-highlights&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS journal content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/open-access-funds&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Funders and institutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; all over the world who supported publication of this rich body of research under a model that provides unrestriced access to all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS was incorporated in 2001 as an Open Access advocacy organization and became a publisher to prove the value of Open Access, beginning with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosbiology/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in 2003 and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/&quot;&gt;e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in 2004 as open alternatives to prestigious subscription journals. In 2005, PLOS launched &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plospathogens/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Pathogens&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/ploscompbiol/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as proof of concept to show that research communities built around and across specific areas and disciplines could thrive with an Open Access model. In late December 2006, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; spearheaded the innovative editorial approach focused on evaluation of research independent of perceived impact; this editorial approach has now been adopted by journals from nearly every scientific publisher. Since its founding, &lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt; has published more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/search?filterJournals=PLoSONE&amp;amp;filterArticleTypes=Research+Article&amp;amp;q=publication_date%3A%5B2001-01-01T00%3A00%3A00Z%20TO%202017-07-19T23%3A59%3A59Z%5D&amp;amp;page=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;175,000 research articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; based on three compelling features: advancing quality science for everyone, moving publication forward in all scientific disciplines, and favoring speed to publication over subjective assessment of significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, with the support of the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, PLOS launched a fourth community journal, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;. Together with the journal’s leadership and global community, we now proudly celebrate the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ntds-10th-anniversary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;10th Anniversary of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/ntds-10th-anniversary&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PLOS NTDs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the more than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosntds/search?filterJournals=PLoSNTD&amp;amp;filterArticleTypes=Research+Article&amp;amp;q=publication_date%3A%5B2001-01-01T00%3A00%3A00Z%20TO%202017-07-19T23%3A59%3A59Z%5D&amp;amp;page=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4,500 research articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that contribute to advances in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Access continues to gain momentum but there is further work to be done. At PLOS, we are constantly looking for ways to use emerging technology and new ideas to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/2016/04/placing-authors-at-the-center-of-the-scientific-endeavor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open up scientific communication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;—to make it faster, more efficient, more connected and more useful. We look forward to the next 200,000 articles and continued involvement with the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/0EQ7vKTIN-4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Here’s a clever demonstration of how we simulate the mental experiences of story characters</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27197</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/24/heres-a-clever-demonstration-of-how-we-simulate-the-mental-experiences-of-story-characters/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-629579800.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27286&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27286&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woman, 30s, at home,reading, book, resting, one person,  bedroom&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1481718820&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Eva Katalin Kondoros&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Beautiful young woman at home&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Beautiful young woman at home&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/24/heres-a-clever-demonstration-of-how-we-simulate-the-mental-experiences-of-story-characters/beautiful-young-woman-at-home/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-629579800.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avid readers of novels know that they often take the perspective of the characters they read about. But just how far does this mental role-playing go? A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0749596X16300997?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Memory and Language&lt;/em&gt; has provided a clever demonstration of how readily we simulate the thoughts of fictional characters. Borrowing a method from research into the psychology of deliberate forgetting, the researchers at Binghamton University, USA, show that when a story character needs to focus on remembering one series of words rather than another, the reader simulates this same memory process in their own minds. The character’s mental experience becomes the reader’s mental experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27197&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experiment, Danielle Gunraj and her colleagues asked about 100 undergrads to read a vignette about Nadia and Lyle, who’d just moved from New York to North Dakota. Nadia decides to go shopping for their new place and makes a list of 15 items to buy from an emporium (the vignette then details the list of items). Half the participants then read that Nadia changed her mind and that she drew up a new list of items (again these are listed) to buy at Walmart. The other half the participants read that Nadia decided to go to both the emporium and Walmart to buy both lists of items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively, this is an implicit version of an established memory test used in research into deliberate forgetting: half the participants had been cued that Nadia needed to forget the first list and focus on remembering the second; the other participants had been cued that both lists should be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the vignette, Gunraj’s team gave the participants a surprise test of their memory for the two lists of items. They wanted to see how much they had simulated Nadia’s thought processes, depending on the version of the story they read. The key finding was that participants who read the version in which Nadia decided not to go the emporium and to only get the items at Walmart showed superior memory for the Walmart list compared with the participants who read the other story version. Although they didn’t show forgetting of the first, emporium list, it’s as if the Walmart-only participants had deliberately focused on remembering the second, Walmart list, just as their version of Nadia needed to do. “We conclude that Nadia’s memory experience influenced readers’ mental experience,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A follow-up experiment was similar but this time undergrads read one of two versions of a vignette about a Frenchman Pierre who was learning English and had to study a list of 15 English words for an exam. In one version, he realises he has studied the wrong list and must study a new list of 15 more words instead. In the other version, he suddenly realises he needs to study the new list as well as the old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, when the participants were given a surprise memory test for both the lists, their performance again depended on the story version they’d read. The participants who read the version in which Pierre realised he’d initially studied the wrong list showed superior memory for the second list as compared with the participants who read the other story version. Again, the participants seem to have simulated the memory processes of the fictional character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are intriguing effects, although reading a short vignette in a psychology lab is of course quite different from being immersed in a literary novel. However, arguably we should expect the memory simulation effects uncovered in this research to be even more powerful for engrossing novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another potential caveat relates to the task instructions. Although participants were surprised by the specific nature of the memory tests, and they weren’t given any explicit instructions to remember or forget the two lists, they were told to “read the passage from Nadia’s (or Pierre’s) perspective. Try to imagine what she is thinking and doing as you read. Furthermore, try to keep track of the details that are important to Nadia (Pierre). After reading the passage you will be asked to recall details from Nadia’s experience”. It’s not clear how much readers would have spontaneously simulated the characters’ memory processes without these instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Regardless of the exact mechanisms involved, we can conclude that readers’ mental representation was influenced by their understanding of the story character’s cognitive processes,” the researchers said. Their findings add to past research that’s shown how we automatically simulate the content of the stories we read: for instance, we are better at &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BF03194927&quot;&gt;remembering a story character’s current location compared with their past location&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/BF03196313&quot;&gt;we’re quicker to make bodily movements that resemble character’s actions&lt;/a&gt; described in written sentences, as if we simulate their described actions in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0749596X16300997?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Simulating a story character’s thoughts: Evidence from the directed forgetting task&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27197/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27197/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27197&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 12:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Work by group at Australian university faces scrutiny</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51139</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/work-group-australian-university-faces-scrutiny/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A journal is investigating research by a group in Australia, after receiving “serious allegations” regarding a 2017 paper about treating eye burns. The journal, Frontiers in Pharmacology, has issued an expression of concern (EOC) for the 2017 paper while it investigates. The notice does not specify the nature of the allegations.  Meanwhile, several other papers […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/24/work-group-australian-university-faces-scrutiny/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Work by group at Australian university faces scrutiny&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 12:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Radioactive substances leave electron ‘fingerprints’ behind</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/radioactive-substances-leave-electron-fingerprints-behind</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/radioactive-substances-leave-electron-fingerprints-behind</link>
	<description>A new method of nuclear forensics could make it harder to handle radioactive material in secret.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071917_MT_radiation-forensics_main_FREE.jpg?itok=b_rtNjMo" length="49056" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Giant radio telescope scaled back to contain costs</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22361</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Cy-oIkmtyN4/nature.2017.22361</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Crowding antennas closer together may affect the Square Kilometre Array's ability to observe the early Universe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 391 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22361&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22361&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Cy-oIkmtyN4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Channel opening and gating mechanism in AMPA-subtype glutamate receptors</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23479</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/ioavAfp-1V8/nature23479</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 AMPA-subtype ionotropic glutamate receptors mediate fast excitatory neurotransmission throughout the central nervous system. Gated by the neurotransmitter glutamate, AMPA receptors are critical for synaptic strength and dysregulation of AMPA receptor-mediated signalling is linked to numerous neurological diseases. Here, we use cryo-electron microscopy to solve the structures of AMPA receptor-auxiliary subunit complexes in the apo, antagonist and agonist-bound states and elucidate the iris-like mechanism of ion channel opening. The ion channel selectivity filter is formed by the extended portions of the re-entrant M2 loops, while the helical portions of M2 contribute to extensive hydrophobic interfaces between AMPA receptor subunits in the ion channel. We show how the permeation pathway changes upon channel opening and identify conformational changes throughout the entire AMPA receptor that accompany activation and desensitization. Our findings provide a framework for understanding gating across the family of ionotropic glutamate receptors and the role of AMPA receptors in excitatory neurotransmission. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23479&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/ioavAfp-1V8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Glutamate receptor-like channels are essential for chemotaxis and reproduction in mosses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23478</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/7CUiwVn0_9Q/nature23478</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Glutamate receptors are well characterized channels that mediate cell-to-cell communication during neurotransmission in animals. Nevertheless, information regarding their functional role in organisms without nervous systems is still limited. In plants, Glutamate Receptor-like (GLR) genes have been implicated in defence against pathogens, reproduction, control of stomata aperture and light signal transduction1–5. However, the numerous GLR genes present in angiosperm genomes (20 to 70)6 has prevented the observation of strong phenotypes in loss-of-function mutants. Here, we show that in the moss Physcomitrella patens, a basal land plant, mutation of GLR genes cause sperm failure in targeting the female reproductive organs. In addition, we show that GLR genes encode non-selective Ca2+ permeable channels that can regulate cytoplasmic Ca2+ and are needed to induce the expression of a BELL1-like transcription factor essential for zygote development. Our work reveals novel functions for GLRs in sperm chemotaxis and transcriptional regulation. Sperm chemotaxis is essential for fertilization in both animals and early land plants like bryophytes and pteridophytes. Therefore, our results are suggestive that ionotropic glutamate receptors may have been conserved throughout plant evolution to mediate cell-to-cell communication during sexual reproduction. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23478&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23478&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/7CUiwVn0_9Q&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: cGAS surveillance of micronuclei links genome instability to innate immunity</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23449</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/AlgcIhmiC88/nature23449</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 DNA is strictly compartmentalized within the nucleus to prevent autoimmunity; despite this, cyclic GMP–AMP synthase (cGAS), a cytosolic sensor of double-stranded DNA, is activated in autoinflammatory disorders and by DNA damage. Precisely how cellular DNA gains access to the cytoplasm remains to be determined. Here, we report that cGAS localizes to micronuclei arising from genome instability in a mouse model of monogenic autoinflammation, after exogenous DNA damage and spontaneously in human cancer cells. Such micronuclei occur after mis-segregation of DNA during cell division and consist of chromatin surrounded by its own nuclear membrane. Breakdown of the micronuclear envelope, a process associated with chromothripsis, leads to rapid accumulation of cGAS, providing a mechanism by which self-DNA becomes exposed to the cytosol. cGAS is activated by chromatin, and consistent with a mitotic origin, micronuclei formation and the proinflammatory response following DNA damage are cell-cycle dependent. By combining live-cell laser microdissection with single cell transcriptomics, we establish that interferon-stimulated gene expression is induced in micronucleated cells. We therefore conclude that micronuclei represent an important source of immunostimulatory DNA. As micronuclei formed from lagging chromosomes also activate this pathway, recognition of micronuclei by cGAS may act as a cell-intrinsic immune surveillance mechanism that detects a range of neoplasia-inducing processes. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23449&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23449&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/AlgcIhmiC88&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Elements of Eoarchean life trapped in mineral inclusions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23261</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/IvTz3P-RsEM/nature23261</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Metasedimentary rocks from Isua, West Greenland (over 3,700 million years old) contain 13C-depleted carbonaceous compounds, with isotopic ratios that are compatible with a biogenic origin. Metamorphic garnet crystals in these rocks contain trails of carbonaceous inclusions that are contiguous with carbon-rich sedimentary beds in the host rock, where carbon is fully graphitized. Previous studies have not been able to document other elements of life (mainly hydrogen, oxygen, nitrogen and phosphorus) structurally bound to this carbonaceous material. Here we study carbonaceous inclusions armoured within garnet porphyroblasts, by in situ infrared absorption on approximately 10−21 m3 domains within these inclusions. We show that the absorption spectra are consistent with carbon bonded to nitrogen and oxygen, and probably also to phosphate. The levels of C–H or O–H bonds were found to be low. These results are consistent with biogenic organic material isolated for billions of years and thermally matured at temperatures of around 500 °C. They therefore provide spatial characterization for potentially the oldest biogenic carbon relics in Earth’s geological record. The preservation of Eoarchean organic residues within sedimentary material corroborates earlier claims for the biogenic origins of carbon in Isua metasediments. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23261&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23261&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/IvTz3P-RsEM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This history book offers excellent images but skimps on modern science</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/history-book-offers-excellent-images-skimps-modern-science</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/history-book-offers-excellent-images-skimps-modern-science</link>
	<description>For an accessible account of mostly pre-20th century science, check out The Oxford Illustrated History of Science.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/080517_reviews_bookshelf-science-main_free.jpg?itok=uiT20DTM" length="27323" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: 10 rules for research misconduct; peer review’s black box; the rich get richer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51152</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/22/weekend-reads-10-rules-research-misconduct-peer-reviews-black-box-rich-get-richer/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured authors making a difficult decision to retract once-promising findings about gliobastoma, and sanctions for a researcher in whose lab image manipulations were found. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: “So, here we are! You’ve decided to join the dark side of Science. That’s great!” Ten Simple Rules for Scientific Fraud &amp;amp; […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/22/weekend-reads-10-rules-research-misconduct-peer-reviews-black-box-rich-get-richer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: 10 rules for research misconduct; peer review’s black box; the rich get richer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 13:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Predatory Journals Hit By 'Star Wars' Sting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8981</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8981</link>
	<description>A number of so-called scientific journals have accepted a Star Wars-themed spoof paper. The manuscript is an absurd mess of factual errors, plagiarism and movie quotes. I know because I wrote it.

Inspired by previous publishing &quot;stings&quot;, I wanted to test whether 'predatory' journals would publish an obviously absurd paper. So I created a spoof manuscript about &quot;midi-chlorians&quot; - the fictional entities which live inside cells and give Jedi their powers in Star Wars. I filled it with other refe</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 09:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Fire ants build towers with three simple rules</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/fire-ants-build-towers-three-simple-rules</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/wild-things/fire-ants-build-towers-three-simple-rules</link>
	<description>Fire ants use the same set of simple rules to produce static rafts and perpetually moving towers.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 18:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/wt_fireanttower_free.jpg?itok=Zqd0jIyE" length="16122" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Months after neuroscientist flagged errors, Nature journal corrects them — and more</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51143</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/months-neuroscientist-flagged-errors-nature-journal-corrects/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;When a neuroscientist noticed there were problems with his January 2017 paper in Nature Neuroscience, he didn’t wait for the journal to take action — instead, he published his concerns about four figures on PubMed Commons. Months later, the journal has issued formal corrections to those figures — along with several more.    In February […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/months-neuroscientist-flagged-errors-nature-journal-corrects/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Months after neuroscientist flagged errors, Nature journal corrects them — and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 14:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: “I was skeptical at first, but now I firmly believe in agile”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/i-was-skeptical-at-first-but-now-i-firmly-believe-in-agile</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/i-was-skeptical-at-first-but-now-i-firmly-believe-in-agile</link>
	<description>Two years after Newsflo joined Elsevier, its small team has been expanding its technology and influence in a big way</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 13:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Earth might once have resembled a hot, steamy doughnut</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-might-once-have-resembled-hot-steamy-doughnut</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/earth-might-once-have-resembled-hot-steamy-doughnut</link>
	<description>Newly proposed space objects called synestias are large, spinning hunks of mostly vaporized rock. They look like a jelly-filled doughnut.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 13:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/060617_AY_synestia_main.jpg?itok=-ZVMI366" length="11452" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Jumped the gun: Paper about non-finalized guidelines is retracted</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51093</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/jumped-gun-paper-non-finalized-guidelines-retracted/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Too soon? A surgeon is retracting his overview of new hernia surgery guidelines after it was published before the guidelines were finalized. The paper, published in German in the journal, Der Chirurg, was also retracted because — according to two co-authors of the new guidelines — the final version of the guidelines was supposed to […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/21/jumped-gun-paper-non-finalized-guidelines-retracted/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Jumped the gun: Paper about non-finalized guidelines is retracted&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Baby-led weaning won’t necessarily ward off extra weight</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/baby-led-weaning-obesity</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/baby-led-weaning-obesity</link>
	<description>Babies allowed to feed themselves gained similar amounts of weight as babies spoon-fed by caretakers.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071917_LS_growth-curve_weaning_main_FREE.jpg?itok=XD_Fhr_e" length="25245" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Critical thinking skills are more important than IQ for making good decisions in life</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27173</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/21/why-some-smart-people-make-foolish-decisions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-536092577.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27188&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27188&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Facepalm, retro vintage disappointed man slapping forehead with hand due to mistake, oversight or epic fail, d'oh!&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;drante&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Facepalm, retro disappointed man slapping forehead, d'oh!&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Facepalm, retro disappointed man slapping forehead, d’oh!&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-536092577.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-536092577.jpg?w=845?w=265&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-536092577.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1629,1841&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/21/why-some-smart-people-make-foolish-decisions/facepalm-retro-disappointed-man-slapping-forehead-doh/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-536092577.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To lead a good life, we need to make good decisions: manage our health and financial affairs, invest in appropriate relationships, and avoid serious lapses like falling for online scams. What equips us to do this? One candidate is IQ: after all, people who score higher on intelligence tests tend to go on to do better academically and in their careers. But many of us know intellectual titans who still make grave errors of judgment in their lives. Book-smart doesn’t necessarily make you life-smart, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1871187116300384&quot;&gt;a new article&lt;/a&gt; in the journal &lt;i&gt;Thinking Skills and Creativity&lt;/i&gt; examines the utility of IQ in navigating existence, and how another mental ability may put it in the shade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27173&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas IQ is – crudely speaking – a measure of the mental horsepower we have for handling abstract content, some researchers say that “critical thinking” – the ability to make judgments dispassionately without jumping to false conclusions – is a separate ability. To find out if critical thinking ability might be important for real-life outcomes, perhaps even more than IQ, Heather Butler of California State University and her colleagues asked 244 participants – a mix of students and adults recruited online – to complete tests, of their IQ and critical thinking skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intelligence test was fairly standard and covered memory, visual processing and quantitative reasoning. The critical thinking assessment involved participants evaluating courses of action in hypothetical scenarios and also considering the relevance of contextual information that could have a bearing on the decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a typical critical thinking question might require participants to explain whether they would want preschool to be mandatory for all children if research had shown that kids who attend preschool are more likely to excel at school (note this specific question wasn’t used in the test). Successful critical thinking would include recognising that correlation is not causation and reflecting on other possible explanations, and rating as valuable further information such as the income disparity between parents who send their children to preschool and other parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per previous research, critical thinking correlated with IQ moderately (.38), suggesting some overlap but that each test was measuring something distinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers were especially interested in how these measures correlated with scores on an inventory of real-world outcomes, on which participants indicated whether they had experienced events ranging from the mildly bad (e.g. fined late fees for a video rental) to the more severe (e.g. acquiring a sexually transmitted disease). The avoidance of these kinds of experiences gives an indirect measure of wise, effective decision making, and the data showed higher IQ individuals did do better. However, high critical thinking was even more strongly associated with these real-world outcomes (even after factoring out IQ). So it’s possible to have a modest IQ and navigate life wisely, or to have a high IQ and make clangers that leave your peers shaking their heads. It’s a question of critical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s something that can be worked on. Critical thinking isn’t about mental resources so much as a way of looking at the world and a tool-kit to use at the relevant moments. But unfortunately, as a society, we don’t give enough attention to how to foster these skills.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/A/bo10327226.html&quot;&gt;Some researchers&lt;/a&gt; are very pessimistic about the benefits of formal education for critical thinking, and although &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0034654315605917?journalCode=rera&quot;&gt;a recent meta-analysis&lt;/a&gt; has since suggested that attending college produces improvements in critical thinking, it could not identify where the skills were coming from. It should be possible to design better ways to impart and hone these skills, skills critical for the decisions that make up the stuff of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1871187116300384&quot;&gt;Predicting Real-World Outcomes: Critical Thinking Ability is a Better Predictor of Life Decisions than Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27173/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27173/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27173&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 10:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Sugar-sweetened drinks and your metabolism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9293</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/21/sugar-sweetened-drinks-and-your-metabolism/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/soft-2262307_640-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it, sugar tastes good. Added sugars account for approximately 16% of total energy intake. That’s around 6 tablespoons (91 grams) of added sugar every day. The largest source of added sugars in our diet is from sugar-sweetened drinks. This is why a large amount of research is focused on the health effects of these types of drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beneficial effects of protein-rich diets are well documented. Increasing protein intake increases satiety, increases metabolism and decreases energy intake. But what happens when we drink a sugar-sweetened beverage with our steak dinner? How does this change how our body processes and uses the nutrients from the meal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9298&quot; style=&quot;width: 315px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9298&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/room.jpg&quot; width=&quot;305&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The 12-by-10-foot metabolic chamber that participants spent 24 hours in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, we asked volunteers to spend 24 hours in a metabolic chamber on two separate occasions. The metabolic chamber is a 12-by-10-foot hermetically controlled room. This allows us to measure exactly how the body is using the nutrients from the foods. By having someone stay in a metabolic chamber, we can determine how many grams of carbohydrate, protein and fat the volunteer is using and how many calories they’re burning every minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fully understand how the volunteer used the nutrients from the meals, we measured oxygen consumption, carbon dioxide production and urinary nitrogen excretion. Nitrogen is a key component of protein and the amount excreted in urine provides an estimate of protein breakdown. Once protein utilization is known, the amount of carbohydrate and fat utilization can be correctly calculated from respiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all testing procedures, the volunteers ate the exact same foods throughout the day. During one of the visits, they ate a diet consisting of 15% protein and for the other visit they ate a diet consisting of 30% protein. At each meal, they had either a sugar-sweetened drink or an artificially sweetened drink. After each meal, we asked the participant about their hunger and desire to eat certain types of foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The body only expended 80 of the 120 kcals that was provided by the sugar-sweetened drink&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that drinking a sugar-sweetened drink with a meal significantly decreases fat use and diet-induced thermogenesis (heat production). And when we paired the sugar-sweetened drink with a protein-rich meal, the combination further decreased fat use and diet-induced thermogenesis by more than 40%. Additionally, we found that, over the course of a day, the body only expended 80 of the 120 kcals that was provided by the sugar-sweetened drink, thus creating a 40-kcal surplus independent of how much protein was in the meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results highlight the impact that consuming a sugar-sweetened drink can have on energy balance and fat use. One implication of the results is that the body’s reduced metabolic efficiency after drinking a sugar-sweetened beverage can lead to a greater tendency to make and store fat. Our findings provide further insight into the potential role of sugar-sweetened drinks in the etiology of obesity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/21/sugar-sweetened-drinks-and-your-metabolism/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sugar-sweetened drinks and your metabolism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/soft-2262307_640-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Resistance to CRISPR gene drives may arise easily</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/resistance-crispr-gene-drives-may-arise-easily</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/resistance-crispr-gene-drives-may-arise-easily</link>
	<description>New tools for pest and disease control could become useless without improvements.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 20:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072017_TI_gene-drive_main.jpg?itok=b8wtH3IS" length="25640" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Majorana fermion detected in a quantum layer cake</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/majorana-fermion-detected-quantum-layer-cake</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/majorana-fermion-detected-quantum-layer-cake</link>
	<description>Scientists found evidence of a particle that is its own antiparticle.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 19:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072017_EC_fermion_main.jpg?itok=u1ILctSv" length="16433" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Cows produce powerful HIV antibodies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cows-produce-powerful-hiv-antibodies</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cows-produce-powerful-hiv-antibodies</link>
	<description>For the first time in any animal, researchers elicit broadly neutralizing antibodies against HIV. Cows’ antibodies could help with drug development.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 18:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/072017_ac_HIVcow_free.jpg?itok=ho58PO4z" length="47618" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Elephant seals recognize rivals by the tempo of their calls</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/elephant-seals-recognize-rivals-tempo-their-calls</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/elephant-seals-recognize-rivals-tempo-their-calls</link>
	<description>The distinct sputtering-lawnmower sound of a male elephant seal’s call has a tempo that broadcasts his identity to competitors.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/072017_LH_elephant-seals_main.jpeg?itok=lVCuvtxw" length="31469" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “We do not want to create false hope”: Authors retract Cell paper they can’t replicate</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51133</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/20/not-want-create-false-hope-authors-retract-cell-paper-cant-replicate/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, researchers in Sweden had something to celebrate: They thought they had discovered a chink in the armor of the most common type of malignant brain cancer. In a 2014 Cell paper, the team — led by Patrik Ernfors at the Karolinska Institutet — reported that they had identified a small molecule […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/20/not-want-create-false-hope-authors-retract-cell-paper-cant-replicate/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“We do not want to create false hope”: Authors retract Cell paper they can’t replicate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 15:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Privacy Shield Certification Shows Our Commitment to Protecting Customer Data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1106</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2017/07/privacy-shield-certification-shows-our-commitment-to-protecting-customer-data/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Science Exchange First &amp;amp; Only R&amp;amp;D Outsourcing Platform to Receive EU-U.S. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Privacy Shield Framework Certification&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PALO ALTO CA, July 20, 2017 – Science Exchange today announced that it is the first and only R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform to receive EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification from the U.S. Department of Commerce. This certification demonstrates the company’s commitment to the protection and privacy of sensitive data shared by its customers and scientific service providers on the Science Exchange platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designed by the U.S. Department of Commerce, the European Commission and Swiss Administration, the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework provides companies with a method to conform to data protection requirements when transferring personal data from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States in support of transatlantic business. This new framework replaces the EU-U.S. Safe Harbor program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The privacy and security of data for scientific research is a top priority for our customers and service providers, and we saw this certification as an important step for Science Exchange, especially in light of recent cyberattacks that affected companies across the healthcare and biopharma industries,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “The thousands of companies that use the Science Exchange platform can be assured that we are committed to the protection of the personal and scientific data entrusted to us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To receive EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification, companies must commit to a range of data management requirements, including that they will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inform individuals about how their data is processed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain data integrity and purpose limitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure accountability for data transferred to third parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review and certify that all requirements are met on an annual basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to being the only R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform with EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification, Science Exchange is also SOC 2 compliant, which validates that the company meets standardized criteria for managing data privacy and security – a certification that is increasingly required by regulators and auditors. Science Exchange is also ISO 9001 certified, which recognizes that the company adheres to strict quality management principles and maintains a consistent quality assurance program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details about the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, the certification process, or to view a list of participating companies, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.privacyshield.gov&quot;&gt;www.privacyshield.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about our certifications ensuring data security, quality management and privacy at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/compliance&quot;&gt;www.scienceexchange.com/compliance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerry Metzdorf&lt;br /&gt;
Big Swing Communications&lt;br /&gt;
978-463-2575&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kerry@big-swing.com&quot;&gt;kerry@big-swing.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 13:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Oh dear, even people with neuroscience training believe an awful lot of brain myths</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27063</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/20/oh-dear-even-people-with-neuroscience-training-believe-an-awful-lot-of-brain-myths/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-526823188.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27154&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27154&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Concept illustration of human brain hemispheres with information about left and right brains in modern flat line art style. EPS10 vector.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;cienpies&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Left and right brain concept poster illustration&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Left and right brain concept poster illustration&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-526823188.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-526823188.jpg?w=845?w=277&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-526823188.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1663,1803&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/20/oh-dear-even-people-with-neuroscience-training-believe-an-awful-lot-of-brain-myths/left-and-right-brain-concept-poster-illustration/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-526823188.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, the film &lt;em&gt;Lucy&lt;/em&gt; came out starring Scarlett Johansson as the eponymous heroine who is implanted with drugs that allow her to use the full capacity of her brain rather than the mere 10 per cent that the rest of us supposedly use. In response I wrote an article for WIRED “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-10-brain-myth-explained-in-60-seconds/&quot;&gt;All you need to know about the 10 per cent brain myth in 60 seconds&lt;/a&gt;“. Soon afterwards I received an angry, acerbic 1,200-word email from a reader: “I am obviously not going to insist you take your article down since that isn’t my place,” she wrote, “but you should certainly not feel proud to be spreading such misinformed information to the public”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What particularly shocked me was not just the tone of the correspondence, but the fact this email, endorsing the 10 per cent brain myth, came from a Masters student in neuroscience at Yale. But perhaps this wasn’t such an odd occurrence. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01314/abstract&quot;&gt;new US survey&lt;/a&gt; published in &lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Psychology&lt;/em&gt; finds that belief in brain myths remains widespread, and moreover, that extensive education in neuroscience seems to provide little protection from such beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27063&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kelly Macdonald at the University of Houston and her colleagues, including Lauren McGrath at the University of Denver, recruited a total of 3,877 people to take a survey of brain myths hosted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://testmybrain.org&quot;&gt;Testmybrain.org&lt;/a&gt; website. This included 3,045 members of the general public, 598 teachers, and 234 people with “high neuroscience exposure” (defined as having completed many college/university courses related to the brain or neuroscience). The researchers had sent messages to neuroscience email lists and social networks to attract people with neuroscience training to take the survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey featured 32 statements about the brain, 14 of which were true (e.g. we use our brains 24 hours a day) and 18 of which were false (e.g. we only use 10 per cent of our brain). Many of the items were the same or similar to those used in &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2012.00429/full&quot;&gt;earlier surveys&lt;/a&gt; of belief in neuromyths among teachers in the UK and The Netherlands. The participants’ task was simply to indicate which statements were true and which were false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that teachers endorsed fewer brain myths than the general public, and those participants with neuroscience training endorsed fewer brain myths than teachers. And yet, all three groups still displayed high levels of brain myth endorsement, especially for what Macdonald and her colleagues identify as the classic brain myths, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2015/01/need-know-learning-styles-myth-two-minutes/&quot;&gt;Learning styles myth&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 93 per cent of the public, 76 per cent of teachers, and 78 per cent of those with neuroscience education)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologicalscience.org/media/myths/myth_17.cfm&quot;&gt;A common sign of dyslexia is seeing letters backwards&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 76 per cent of the public, 59 per cent of teachers, and 50 per cent of those with neuroscience education)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20130107-can-mozart-boost-brainpower&quot;&gt;Listening to classical music increases children’s reasoning ability&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 59 per cent of the public, 55 per cent of teachers, and 43 per cent of the neuroscience group) [&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/05/19/music-teachers-and-students-fall-for-music-related-neuromyths-german-study/&quot;&gt;more on music-related neuromyths&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nymag.com/scienceofus/2016/08/the-sugar-high-is-actually-just-a-parenting-myth.html?mid=twitter_scienceofus&quot;&gt;Children are less attentive after consuming sugar&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 59 per cent of the public, 50 per cent of teachers and 39 per cent of the neuroscience group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-myths/201206/why-the-left-brain-right-brain-myth-will-probably-never-die&quot;&gt;The left-brain right-brain myth&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 64 per cent of the public, 49 per cent of teachers and 32 per cent of the neuroscience group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/07/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-10-brain-myth-explained-in-60-seconds/&quot;&gt;10 per cent myth&lt;/a&gt; (endorsed by 36 per cent of the public, 33 per cent of teachers, and 14 per cent of those with neuroscience education – my unfriendly correspondent is not alone).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the participants with extensive exposure to neuroscience (most of whom said they had at a minimum a science or health-related university degree) endorsed just under half of the neuromyths (specifically 46 per cent, compared with 68 per cent average endorsement among the public and 56 per cent among teachers). Another clear pattern in the findings was that participants who believed one of the above myths were more likely than average to also endorse one or more of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings are worrying because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2014/12/10-ways-brain-myths-harming-us/&quot;&gt;brain myths are harmful&lt;/a&gt;: they undermine valid neuroscience findings and they encourage bogus practices in health, education and business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s going on? Why is training in neuroscience not enough to prevent many people from endorsing some of the most hackneyed brain myths? Macdonald and her colleagues note that many of the most widely endorsed myths pertain to education and the supposed application of neuroscience to improving learning. They speculate that perhaps it’s possible to study the brain-basis of dyslexia or memory, for instance, while remaining unaware of related psychological research, such as on the behavioural manifestations of dyslexia or the findings that have challenged the concept of learning styles. In other words, perhaps the issue is partly one of different levels of explanation: just because you are schooled in neuroscience doesn’t mean you are aware of psychological findings that are pertinent to education-based neuromyths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“[These findings] suggest that if educators were to take a class in neuroscience that did not specifically address neuromyths, it would be unlikely to help with dispelling the misconceptions that are most closely related to learning and education,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They added that programmes intended to combat belief in neuromyths might benefit from highlighting how many myths mistakenly imply that a single factor is responsible for, or indicative of, a given outcome (e.g. sugar causing bad behavior or letter reversals being a sign of dyslexia) when in fact many factors are usually involved in learning and cognition. Also, myth-busting programmes could emphasise how many of us seem to have a bias to find explanations more credible when they contain neuroscience references, no matter how gratuitous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting a few problems with the new survey (acknowledged by the researchers themselves), such as the fact the general public who took part were highly educated compared with the wider US population as a whole – of course this may suggest the observed levels of myth endorsement are an underestimate. Also, the neuroscience group in the survey self-reported their own experience of neuroscience so it’s not clear exactly what kind of courses they’d completed. And some might say that there’s an inherent problem with asking people to give a simple “true/false” response to statements about the brain – it leaves little room for nuance and some statements may be open to multiple interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01314/abstract&quot;&gt;Dispelling the myth: Training in education or neuroscience decreases but does not eliminate beliefs in neuromyths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; and author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/Index/Great_Myths_of_the_Brain.html&quot;&gt;Great Myths of the Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27063/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27063/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27063&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 12:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Drip, drip: UCLA investigation finds more image duplications</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51127</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/20/drip-drip-ucla-investigation-finds-image-duplications/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Image duplications and unsupported data continue to plague a network of cancer researchers that includes the former vice chancellor for research at the University of California, Los Angeles, James Economou. On July 2, the editors at Cancer Research retracted a 2011 paper that Economou published as last author, saying it suffered from image duplication and […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/20/drip-drip-ucla-investigation-finds-image-duplications/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Drip, drip: UCLA investigation finds more image duplications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New Horizons’ next target caught making a star blink</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-next-target-caught-making-star-blink</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-next-target-caught-making-star-blink</link>
	<description>The team behind the spacecraft that visited Pluto has seen its next quarry blocking the light from a distant star.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071917_LG_new-horizons_main.jpg?itok=O5wphJHm" length="27015" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Accelerating ethics review during disease outbreaks: what we can learn from West Africa’s Ebola Outbreak</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9255</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/20/accelerating-ethics-review-during-disease-outbreaks-what-we-can-learn-from-west-africas-ebola-outbreak/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Ebola-4-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zika virus, Ebola virus, and avian flu outbreaks are among the more recent and well-known international public health emergencies. It is critical to quickly control such outbreaks to minimize spreading, but often there is no standard treatment or vaccine. Therefore researchers investigating new drugs or treatments must work against the clock to discover effective treatments, without compromising ethical standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how can we ease the process of ethics approval during public health emergencies? In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedethics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12910-017-0201-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; recently published in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcmedethics.biomedcentral.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BMC Medical Ethics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, researchers Emilie Alirol &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; describe their experience with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/en/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/a&gt; ethics review during the recent Ebola virus outbreak in West Africa, providing recommendations to accelerate study approval in future health emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ebola Virus Outbreak (2013-2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2013-2016 Ebola Outbreak was the largest outbreak of Ebola virus in history, and also the most deadly. With approximately 11,300 reported deaths, this outbreak killed more people than all previous outbreaks combined. At the start of the epidemic, Ebola virus research was limited to laboratory studies and data from previous outbreaks. There was no established vaccine available, and potential vaccines were still in early development. This proved especially concerning given the high mortality rate (40-90% dependent on country) and the large scale in which the disease was spreading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9254&quot; style=&quot;width: 303px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9254&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/ebola-293x300.png&quot; width=&quot;293&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;2014 Map of Ebola outbreaks in West Africa&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons, Source: CDC&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the urgency of the outbreak, the WHO decided that use of unregistered medical interventions was acceptable, provided ethical standards were not compromised. It also allowed for a streamlined review process, with the hopes of identifying potential treatments more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations for future public health emergencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the outbreak, the WHO-ERC reviewed 24 new protocols and 22 amended protocols in total, including observational and interventional studies. In the article by Emilie Alirol &lt;em&gt;et al.,&lt;/em&gt; a number of approaches are proposed to help accelerate the study approval process, which are applicable to any future disease outbreaks, not just Ebola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found that incorrect or incomplete information was the most common hindrance of rapid ethics approval. For example, missing information on data sharing, inappropriate participant information documents, or inconsistent details like sample size. Despite time pressure, it’s recommended that documents are thoroughly reviewed to prevent unnecessary delays as these issues are avoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9276&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9276&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/ebola-5-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;CDC staff member preparing to enter Ebola treatment unit&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons; Via CDC Global&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closer collaboration between local and international researchers may also prove effective. Studies during the Ebola outbreak were often led by international researchers, as resources were limited in locally affected areas. Local researchers have beneficial knowledge of the local culture which can be used to encourage study participation and provide advice on appropriate study plans, ultimately fast-tracking the study process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template agreements and joint committees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more specific systems proposed includes development of template agreements for data and sample ownership and use. Many of the studies didn’t provide enough of this information which delayed approval. Because negotiating these agreements can be time consuming, the authors recommend developing template agreements which can be drafted from international consultations and discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also suggest forming a Joint Ethics Review Committee, as many trials require approval from multiple ethics committees. The joint committee would include members of committees from the countries or institutions relevant to the outbreak. Rather than waiting for approval from multiple committees, a joint committee would cut approval time while also providing the value of cross-trial data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9257&quot; style=&quot;width: 209px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9257&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/ebola-3-199x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Poster spread by the Sierra Leone Government during Ebola Outbreak&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Wikimedia Commons,  Sierra Leone Goverment with the help of Limkokwing University of Creative Technology&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation of pregnant women and children&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably the most difficult proposal to implement would be the inclusion of pregnant women and children in clinical trials. In previous Ebola outbreaks, mortality rates of pregnant women were about 90%, and the highest mortality rates were in children 4 years old or younger. Given the high mortality in these groups, it makes them the most likely to benefit from a health intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rates encouraged the WHO-ERC to request protocol amendments that include children and pregnant women in studies. Despite the potential benefits, pregnant women and children were not included in any of the studies, likely due to ethical and liability concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they are normally excluded from trials, children and pregnant women generally accept treatments based on data from other groups. In order to improve their clinical care during health emergencies, the authors of this article push for their inclusion during future outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for future outbreaks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue of timeliness is one of the most challenging aspects of conducting clinical research during public health emergencies. The experience of Emilie Alirol&lt;em&gt; et al. &lt;/em&gt;during the Ebola Outbreak displays many of the issues researchers face during such emergencies. They provide us with useful suggestions to accelerate the ethics approval process, and these should be taken into consideration in preparation for future outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/20/accelerating-ethics-review-during-disease-outbreaks-what-we-can-learn-from-west-africas-ebola-outbreak/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Accelerating ethics review during disease outbreaks: what we can learn from West Africa’s Ebola Outbreak&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 09:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Ebola-4-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Rapid elicitation of broadly neutralizing antibodies to HIV by immunization in cows</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23301</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/VZd_ePKhiss/nature23301</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 No immunogen to date has reliably elicited broadly neutralizing antibodies to HIV in humans or animal models. Advances in the design of immunogens (BG505 SOSIP) that antigenically mimic the HIV envelope glycoprotein (Env)1 have improved the elicitation of potent isolate-specific antibody responses in rabbits2 and macaques3, but so far failed to induce broadly neutralizing antibodies. One possible contributor to this failure is that the relevant antibody repertoires are poorly suited to target somewhat occluded conserved epitope regions on Env relative to exposed variable epitopes. To test this hypothesis, we immunized four cows with BG505 SOSIP. The antibody repertoire of cows contains long third heavy chain complementarity determining regions (HCDR3) with an ultralong subset that can reach over 70 amino acids in length4–9. Remarkably, BG505 SOSIP immunization resulted in rapid elicitation of broad and potent serum antibody responses in all four cows. Longitudinal serum analysis for one cow showed the development of neutralization breadth (20%, n = 117 cross-clade isolates) in 42 days and 96% breadth (n = 117) at 381 days. A monoclonal antibody isolated from this cow harboured an ultralong HCDR3 of 60 amino acids and neutralized 72% of cross-clade isolates (n = 117) with a potent median IC50 value of 0.028 μg ml−1. We note that breadth was elicited with a single trimer immunogen and did not require additional envelope diversity. Immunization of cows may provide an avenue to rapidly generate antibody prophylactics and therapeutics to address disease agents that have evolved to avoid human antibody responses. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23301&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23301&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/VZd_ePKhiss&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This robot grows like a plant</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/robot-grows-plant</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/robot-grows-plant</link>
	<description>A new soft robot navigates its environment by growing in a manner inspired by plants.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 21:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071917_ht_plantrobot_main.jpg?itok=9i5zv9yI" length="34451" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Is Neuroscience Underpowered? &quot;Power Failure&quot; Revisited</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8972</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8972</link>
	<description>Back in 2013, a Nature Reviews Neuroscience paper appeared called Power failure: why small sample size undermines the reliability of neuroscience. This paper got a lot of attention at the time and has since been cited a dizzying 1760 times according to Google.



'Power Failure' made waves for its stark message that most neuroscience studies are too small, leaving neuroscience lacking statistical power, the chance of detecting signal in the noise. As the authors Kate Button et al. wrote
The</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 19:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These genes may be why dogs are so friendly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-genes-may-be-why-dogs-are-so-friendly</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-genes-may-be-why-dogs-are-so-friendly</link>
	<description>Dog domestication may be the result of just a few genetic changes, including ones that made canines more interested in interacting with people.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071917_ay_friendlydogs_main.jpg?itok=qcnvFwb7" length="30554" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Humans first settled in Australia as early as 65,000 years ago</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-first-settled-australia-early-65000-years-ago</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/humans-first-settled-australia-early-65000-years-ago</link>
	<description>Australia may have said “G’day” to humankind thousands of years earlier than previously believed.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071917_MT_first-Australians_main.jpg?itok=ldiAAgCn" length="51455" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Oscillatory Thoughts: Neural Communication: Jazz, Not Symphony</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545.post-7812152806140468181</guid>
	<link>http://blog.ketyov.com/2015/05/neural-communication-jazz-not-symphony.html</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://voyteklab.com/neural-communication-jazz-not-symphony&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;New post&lt;/a&gt; up over on my (new) main blog! It's about &lt;a href=&quot;http://biologicalpsychiatryjournal.com/article/S0006-3223%2815%2900354-6/abstract&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my latest paper&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Dynamic Network Communication as a Unifying Neural Basis for Cognition, Development, Aging, and Disease.&quot; This paper was invited as part of a special issue for &lt;i&gt;Biological Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt; titled &quot;Cortical Oscillations for Cognitive/Circuit Dysfunction in Psychiatric Disorders,&quot; by the organizing editor, György Buzsáki. Although it was invited, it was still peer-reviewed as normal.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Bradley Voytek)</author>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/5648062351012720545/posts/default">Oscillatory Thoughts</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weizmann bans grad students from researcher’s lab over “serious misconduct”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51101</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/19/weizmann-bans-grad-students-researchers-lab-serious-misconduct/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Weizmann Institute in Israel has barred a biologist from mentoring graduate students, after an investigation uncovered ” a case of serious misconduct that included manipulation of data.” In a letter posted on PubPeer, President Daniel Zajfman describes some of the disciplinary measures taken against an unnamed scientist, including also retracting or correcting all affected papers. Michal Neeman, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/19/weizmann-bans-grad-students-researchers-lab-serious-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weizmann bans grad students from researcher’s lab over “serious misconduct”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: What a report into scientific misconduct reveals: The case of Frank Sauer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51075</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/19/report-scientific-misconduct-reveals-case-frank-sauer/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Oct. 3, 2011, was the beginning of the end for Frank Sauer’s tenure at the University of California, Riverside. On that day, an anonymous emailer contacted Sauer’s institution with accusations that the biochemist had cooked his research in at least eight papers over a 16-year period. Sauer was found to have doctored images in studies […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/19/report-scientific-misconduct-reveals-case-frank-sauer/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What a report into scientific misconduct reveals: The case of Frank Sauer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The incredible shrinking transistor just got smaller</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/incredible-shrinking-transistor-just-got-smaller</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/incredible-shrinking-transistor-just-got-smaller</link>
	<description>Tiniest transistor, made with carbon nanotubes, suggests computers aren’t done shrinking down.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/070717_EC_transistor_main.jpg?itok=pofsAQLo" length="29347" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: For one week these women recorded all the times they were objectified sexually</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27028</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/19/for-one-week-these-women-recorded-all-the-times-they-were-objectified-sexually/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a ranking of genuinely important YouTube videos to have gone viral, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b1XGPvbWn0A&quot;&gt;this one (see above)&lt;/a&gt; from 2014 places high: it shows over 100 instances of harassment endured by a woman wearing a hidden camera as she walked around New York City for ten hours, including comments, stares, winks and whistles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video was posted in 2014 by the domestic violence activist group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ihollaback.org&quot;&gt;Hollaback!&lt;/a&gt; to highlight the prevalence of this kind of behaviour. As individual testimony, it was powerful. But, critics could argue, it was just one woman, on just one day. This is an argument they cannot use about the results of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12152/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt;, published in the &lt;i&gt;British Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, which the researchers, led by Elise Holland at the University of Melbourne in Australia, believe is the first to capture just how common sexual harassment and “objectification” is in the daily lives of young women – and to show the possible impact on how women think about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27028&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighty-one women living in Melbourne, with an average age of 22, first completed a number of surveys, including measures of their self-esteem and personality. They were also shown examples of what the researchers considered to be different forms of objectification, including gazes and comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the women downloaded an app to their own smartphones and they had to respond to its survey prompts for a week: these came in the form of three questions, ten times a day, at random intervals between 10am and midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question was whether, since the last prompt, they’d been thinking about how they look to other people (rated on a scale from 0 to 100). Then, whether, since the last survey, they had been targeted by any sexually objectifying events; if they had, they could check boxes to indicate what type. And finally, whether they had witnessed anyone else being targeted by these kinds of behaviours; this included an extra option of “media image/video”, designed to capture sexual objectification in the media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women reported being the target of a “sexually objectifying event” on average roughly once every 2 days: 55 per cent of the events they recorded consisted of an “objectifying gaze”, while 11 per cent were cat calls or wolf whistles. Ten per cent were sexual remarks, and four per cent were “touching or fondling”. (As the researchers note, “While such severe instances of objectification may not be common everyday experiences they still occur frequently enough to have been captured in a 7-day…study with a sample of 81 women…”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants also witnessed sexual objectification of another woman on average 1.35 times a day. The inclusion of a media image/video option perhaps unsurprisingly (given the way women are often portrayed in magazines and music videos) meant that the majority – roughly two thirds, in fact – of instances of witnessing objectification of other women fell into this category. But the volunteers also recorded many occasions of other women having similar experiences to their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both being personally targeted and witnessing others being objectified was associated with a “substantial increase” in “self-objectification”, which can be defined as thinking about yourself as an object to be used, and the correlation was stronger when the individual was targeted themselves. This seemed to be true regardless of the women’s scores on the personality test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some limitations with the work. Though the researchers did show examples of the kinds of behaviours that they considered to be “objectifying”, not all women will perceive the same gaze, for example, in the same way. The paper also provided no detail on the sexual orientation of the women and the survey prompts didn’t allow them to indicate whether the person doing the objectifying was male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, while increases in participants’ levels of self-objectification were clearly associated with the recent experience of objectifying events (at each survey point, participants were first asked to report on their feelings of self-objectification and then whether they’d experienced any objectification since the last prompt – i.e. over the past hour or two), it’s theoretically possible that if some women were generally thinking more about themselves as objects to be used, they may have noticed more objectifying gazes, for example, than they would otherwise have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the study certainly does show that while the women in this study may not have experienced sexual harassment on the same scale as recorded in the 2014 video, these kinds of events – for young women in Melbourne, at least – are very common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12152/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;Sexual objectification in women’s daily lives: A smartphone ecological momentary assessment study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/EmmaELYoung&quot;&gt;@EmmaELYoung&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27028/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27028/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27028&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 08:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Type III CRISPR–Cas systems produce cyclic oligoadenylate second messengers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23467</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/m7hd0PfAYkk/nature23467</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 In many prokaryotes, type III CRISPR–Cas systems detect and degrade invasive genetic elements by an RNA-guided, RNA-targeting multisubunit interference complex. The CRISPR-associated protein Csm6 additionally contributes to interference by functioning as a standalone ribonuclease that degrades invader RNA transcripts, but the mechanism linking invader sensing to Csm6 activity is not understood. Here we show that Csm6 proteins are activated through a second messenger generated by the type III interference complex. Upon target RNA binding by the interference complex, its Cas10 subunit converts ATP into a cyclic oligoadenylate product, which allosterically activates Csm6 by binding to its CARF domain. CARF domain mutations that abolish allosteric activation inhibit Csm6 activity in vivo, and mutations in the Cas10 Palm domain phenocopy loss of Csm6. Together, these results point to an unprecedented mechanism for regulation of CRISPR interference that bears striking conceptual similarity to oligoadenylate signalling in mammalian innate immunity. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23467&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23467&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/m7hd0PfAYkk&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cysteine protease cathepsin B mediates radiation-induced bystander effects</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23284</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/5qk-6hQGCiA/nature23284</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 The radiation-induced bystander effect (RIBE) refers to a unique process in which factors released by irradiated cells or tissues exert effects on other parts of the animal not exposed to radiation, causing genomic instability, stress responses and altered apoptosis or cell proliferation. Although RIBEs have important implications for radioprotection, radiation safety and radiotherapy, the molecular identities of RIBE factors and their mechanisms of action remain poorly understood. Here we use Caenorhabditis elegans as a model in which to study RIBEs, and identify the cysteine protease CPR-4, a homologue of human cathepsin B, as the first RIBE factor in nematodes, to our knowledge. CPR-4 is secreted from animals irradiated with ultraviolet or ionizing gamma rays, and is the major factor in the conditioned medium that leads to the inhibition of cell death and increased embryonic lethality in unirradiated animals. Moreover, CPR-4 causes these effects and stress responses at unexposed sites distal to the irradiated tissue. The activity of CPR-4 is regulated by the p53 homologue CEP-1 in response to radiation, and CPR-4 seems to exert RIBEs by acting through the insulin-like growth factor receptor DAF-2. Our study provides crucial insights into RIBEs, and will facilitate the identification of additional RIBE factors and their mechanisms of action. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 458 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23284&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23284&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/5qk-6hQGCiA&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
