<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: For one week these women recorded all the times they were objectified sexually</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=27028</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/19/for-one-week-these-women-recorded-all-the-times-they-were-objectified-sexually/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://emmayoung.net/&quot;&gt;Emma Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a ranking of genuinely important YouTube videos to have gone viral, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b1XGPvbWn0A&quot;&gt;this one (see above)&lt;/a&gt; from 2014 places high: it shows over 100 instances of harassment endured by a woman wearing a hidden camera as she walked around New York City for ten hours, including comments, stares, winks and whistles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video was posted in 2014 by the domestic violence activist group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ihollaback.org&quot;&gt;Hollaback!&lt;/a&gt; to highlight the prevalence of this kind of behaviour. As individual testimony, it was powerful. But, critics could argue, it was just one woman, on just one day. This is an argument they cannot use about the results of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12152/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;new study&lt;/a&gt;, published in the &lt;i&gt;British Journal of Social Psychology&lt;/i&gt;, which the researchers, led by Elise Holland at the University of Melbourne in Australia, believe is the first to capture just how common sexual harassment and “objectification” is in the daily lives of young women – and to show the possible impact on how women think about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-27028&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighty-one women living in Melbourne, with an average age of 22, first completed a number of surveys, including measures of their self-esteem and personality. They were also shown examples of what the researchers considered to be different forms of objectification, including gazes and comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the women downloaded an app to their own smartphones and they had to respond to its survey prompts for a week: these came in the form of three questions, ten times a day, at random intervals between 10am and midnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question was whether, since the last prompt, they’d been thinking about how they look to other people (rated on a scale from 0 to 100). Then, whether, since the last survey, they had been targeted by any sexually objectifying events; if they had, they could check boxes to indicate what type. And finally, whether they had witnessed anyone else being targeted by these kinds of behaviours; this included an extra option of “media image/video”, designed to capture sexual objectification in the media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women reported being the target of a “sexually objectifying event” on average roughly once every 2 days: 55 per cent of the events they recorded consisted of an “objectifying gaze”, while 11 per cent were cat calls or wolf whistles. Ten per cent were sexual remarks, and four per cent were “touching or fondling”. (As the researchers note, “While such severe instances of objectification may not be common everyday experiences they still occur frequently enough to have been captured in a 7-day…study with a sample of 81 women…”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The participants also witnessed sexual objectification of another woman on average 1.35 times a day. The inclusion of a media image/video option perhaps unsurprisingly (given the way women are often portrayed in magazines and music videos) meant that the majority – roughly two thirds, in fact – of instances of witnessing objectification of other women fell into this category. But the volunteers also recorded many occasions of other women having similar experiences to their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both being personally targeted and witnessing others being objectified was associated with a “substantial increase” in “self-objectification”, which can be defined as thinking about yourself as an object to be used, and the correlation was stronger when the individual was targeted themselves. This seemed to be true regardless of the women’s scores on the personality test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some limitations with the work. Though the researchers did show examples of the kinds of behaviours that they considered to be “objectifying”, not all women will perceive the same gaze, for example, in the same way. The paper also provided no detail on the sexual orientation of the women and the survey prompts didn’t allow them to indicate whether the person doing the objectifying was male or female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, while increases in participants’ levels of self-objectification were clearly associated with the recent experience of objectifying events (at each survey point, participants were first asked to report on their feelings of self-objectification and then whether they’d experienced any objectification since the last prompt – i.e. over the past hour or two), it’s theoretically possible that if some women were generally thinking more about themselves as objects to be used, they may have noticed more objectifying gazes, for example, than they would otherwise have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the study certainly does show that while the women in this study may not have experienced sexual harassment on the same scale as recorded in the 2014 video, these kinds of events – for young women in Melbourne, at least – are very common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjso.12152/abstract?campaign=woletoc&quot;&gt;Sexual objectification in women’s daily lives: A smartphone ecological momentary assessment study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27028/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/27028/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=27028&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 08:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Solve Antarctica’s sea-ice puzzle</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547275a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/4ve_e7NL5Iw/547275a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;John Turner and Josefino Comiso call for a coordinated push to crack the baffling rise and fall of sea ice around Antarctica.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 275 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547275a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547275a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/4ve_e7NL5Iw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: The DeepMind debacle demands dialogue on data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547259a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/C7NORDAdK7U/547259a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Mishandling of patient information shows how governments and companies must become more worthy of trust, says Hetan Shah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 259 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547259a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547259a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/C7NORDAdK7U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Common drugs help reverse signs of fetal alcohol syndrome in rats</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-drugs-help-reverse-signs-fetal-alcohol-syndrome-rats</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/common-drugs-help-reverse-signs-fetal-alcohol-syndrome-rats</link>
	<description>A thyroid hormone and a blood sugar drug affect levels of a hormone needed for brain development, study in rats shows.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 18:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071818_LH_fetal-alcohol_main_FREE.jpg?itok=ZEsLvUje" length="21908" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Science journal flags cancer paper under investigation for image manipulation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51102</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/18/science-journal-flags-cancer-paper-investigation-image-manipulation/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Science Signaling has issued an expression of concern for a 2016 paper, citing an institutional investigation into image manipulation. According to a spokesperson for the journal, the corresponding author, Tanya Kalin, became concerned that two images in the paper had been manipulated. Kalin then notified the research integrity officer at Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center, […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/18/science-journal-flags-cancer-paper-investigation-image-manipulation/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Science journal flags cancer paper under investigation for image manipulation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: People domesticated dogs just once, ancient DNA study suggests</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/people-domesticated-dogs-just-once-ancient-dna-study-suggests</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/people-domesticated-dogs-just-once-ancient-dna-study-suggests</link>
	<description>DNA of ancient canines counters idea that dogs were domesticated twice, in Europe and Asia.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071817_TI_dog-domestication_main.jpg?itok=fWS-hxbD" length="22899" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Dog domestication happened just once, ancient DNA study suggests</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dog-domestication-happened-just-once-ancient-dna-study-suggests</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dog-domestication-happened-just-once-ancient-dna-study-suggests</link>
	<description>DNA of ancient canines counters idea that dogs were domesticated twice, in Europe and Asia.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 15:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071817_TI_dog-domestication_main.jpg?itok=fWS-hxbD" length="22899" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Ex-Wayne State scientist, ORI square off in court</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51083</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/18/ex-wayne-state-scientist-ori-square-off-court/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON, D.C — Last week, former brain scientist Christian Kreipke stared down the third set of research misconduct allegations against him since 2011. Or, possibly, according to him, it was the third iteration of the same research misconduct allegations he’s faced for years, a piling on by the most powerful of the three institutions out […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/18/ex-wayne-state-scientist-ori-square-off-court/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ex-Wayne State scientist, ORI square off in court&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Hard-core players of violent video games do not have emotionally blunted brains</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26930</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/18/hard-core-players-of-violent-video-games-do-not-have-emotionally-blunted-brains/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-591097802.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-27009&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;27009&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GERMANY - AUGUST 17:  Visitors stands in front of the \&amp;quot;Call of Duty\&amp;quot; stand at the Gamescom 2016 gaming trade fair during the media day on August 17, 2016 in Cologne, Germany. Gamescom is the world's largest digital gaming trade fair and will be open to the public from August 18-21. (Photo by Sascha Schuermann\/Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2016 Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Gamescom 2016 Media Day&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Gamescom 2016 Media Day&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-591097802.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-591097802.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-591097802.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,682&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/18/hard-core-players-of-violent-video-games-do-not-have-emotionally-blunted-brains/gamescom-2016-media-day/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-591097802.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No sooner had the American Psychological Association released their 2015 task force report supposedly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2015/08/violent-video-games.aspx&quot;&gt;confirming&lt;/a&gt; that violent video games make players aggressive than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsweek.com/apa-video-games-violence-364394&quot;&gt;the criticisms&lt;/a&gt; of the report started pouring in, of bias and bad practice. On the issue of whether violent games breed real-world aggression, there’s not much that you can say for certain except that there’s a lot of disagreement among experts. So of course, one more study is not going to settle this long-running debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what a &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9549-y?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Brain Imaging and Behaviour&lt;/em&gt; does do is provide a good test of a key argument made by the “violent games cause aggression” camp, namely that over time, excessive violent gameplay desensitises the emotional responsiveness of players. Using brain scanning to look for emotional desensitisation at a neural level, Gregor Szycik at Hannover Medical School and his colleagues in fact found no evidence that excessive players of violent video games are emotionally blunted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26930&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers conducted two studies, each of which compared 14 excessive players of violent first-person shooter games (such as Call of Duty and Battlefield) with 14 controls who never played violent games. The average age of the participants was 22 to 23 and they were all male. The violent video game players really did invest a lot of time shooting people on-screen: in the first study, they averaged 4.9 hours violent game-play per day, and in the second study they averaged 4.6 hours daily play. They’d also been playing these games since they were six years old, on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two studies were very similar: the participants lay in a brain scanner and looked at a range of emotionally positive, negative and neutral photos, most of which came from the well-used International Affective Picture System. The negative images in this series are pretty grim and include things like dead bodies or graphic, violent attacks. The positive images include cute animals, and an example of a neutral image would be a natural vista.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at emotional pictures led to larger increases in brain activity compared with neutral pictures, just as you’d expect, especially in neural regions responsible for emotional processing. But the key finding is that this effect didn’t vary by group: the violent video game players showed just as much neural sensitivity to the emotional pictures as the control participants. This was true even when the researchers relaxed the statistical parameters (to make it easier to find a group difference), when they lumped all the data together from the two studies, and when they zoomed in on the amygdala, a part of the brain that plays an important role in emotional processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our results suggest [a need] to rethink the desensitisation hypothesis,” the researchers said. They added that this does not mean there are no consequences to playing violent video games: for instance, one possibility is that playing violent games affects how players act in response to emotional stimuli, rather than how their brains initially process such stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings build on earlier research that’s shown it’s important not to make sweeping statements on this topic: for instance, the psychological effects of violent video gameplay could depend on the character you play (&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2013/11/07/effects-of-a-violent-video-game-depend-on-whether-youre-superman-or-the-joker/&quot;&gt;Superman or the Joker, for example&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ab.21487/abstract&quot;&gt;the goals of the game&lt;/a&gt;, and in some instances violent play could even lead to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2015/01/06/could-violent-video-games-make-players-more-moral-in-the-real-world/&quot;&gt;enhanced moral emotions&lt;/a&gt;. The new results also follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00174/full&quot;&gt;similar findings&lt;/a&gt; from the same research group published earlier this year using line drawings of emotional versus neutral situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-016-9549-y?wt_mc=alerts.TOCjournals&quot;&gt;Excessive users of violent video games do not show emotional desensitization: an fMRI study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: Visitors stand in front of the ‘Call of Duty’ stand at the Gamescom 2016 gaming trade fair August 17, 2016 in Cologne, Germany. (Photo by Sascha Schuermann/Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26930/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26930/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26930&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 08:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ancient genomes heat up dog domestication debate</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22320</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/hsv-IldtoI4/nature.2017.22320</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Results point to a single origin for modern canines and push back the timing by thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22320&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22320&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/hsv-IldtoI4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Climate scientists flock to France’s call</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22318</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/KtQTs5e5u9g/nature.2017.22318</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;President said ‘Make Our Planet Great Again’ — and researchers signed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 269 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22318&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22318&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/KtQTs5e5u9g&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The &quot;Eleven Dimensional&quot; Brain? Topology of Neural Networks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8964</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8964</link>
	<description>Last month, a neuroscience paper appeared that triggered a maelstrom of media hype:
The Human Brain Can Create Structures in Up to 11 Dimensions

The human brain sees the world as an 11-dimensional multiverse

Scientists find mysterious shapes and structures in the brain with up to ELEVEN dimensions 


The paper, published in Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, comes from the lab of Henry Markram, one of the world's most powerful neuroscientists. As well as being head of the Blue Br</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 20:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: NIH neuroscientist up to 19 retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51051</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/17/nih-neuroscientist-19-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The string of apparent bad luck continues for Stanley Rapoport. Rapoport, a neuroscientist based at the U.S. National Institute on Aging, has lost three more papers in three journals due to the misconduct of his co-authors. By our count, these retractions bring his tally to 19 — and tie him for 21st place on our leaderboard. […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/17/nih-neuroscientist-19-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NIH neuroscientist up to 19 retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 15:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: A taxonomic revolution? A Q&amp;A with Sandy Knapp on the impact of e-publications</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9280</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/17/taxonomic-revolution-qa-sandy-knapp-impact-e-publications/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Diversity_of_plants_image_version_edit-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright size-full wp-image-9282&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Sandy-knapp.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;Dr Sandy Knapp is Head of the Plants Division at London’s Natural History Museum, specialising in the taxonomy of the nightshade family. She is also Vice president of the Council of the International Association for Plant Taxonomy (IAPT), Editor of the journal &lt;em&gt;Phytokeys&lt;/em&gt;, and a member of the Editorial Board of &lt;em&gt;BMC Evolutionary Biology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you briefly explain the changes that were made to the rules surrounding naming of new plant species at the 2011 IBC congress?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every six years at International Botanical Congresses (IBC) a group of scientists who study algae, fungi and plants gather to review and change the rules for naming (nomenclature). The Nomenclature Section at the IBC in Melbourne six years ago made a big change to media allowed for publishing new nomenclatural acts (new names and the like) – previously if you wanted to describe a new species, for example, you would have to do it in a print journal (or book) and only once the journal was printed was the name available for others to use. In Melbourne, the assembled scientists voted to allow publication in journals and books that were only published electronically – no longer did we have to publish only in print media, or wait until the paper was printed on paper!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;no longer did we have to publish only in print media, or wait until the paper was printed on paper!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why were you personally so keen on seeing these changes made?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomy is often seen as a dusty, old-fashioned science, and clinging to print-on-paper as the publishing world itself was moving into the electronic realm only re-enforced that image. I personally felt there was a real danger that taxonomic publications would be relegated to fewer and fewer places, that were less and less accessible to most people. For me, accessibility was also important, many of the specialist publications are not available outside rich Western institutions, and taxonomy needs to be done everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversely, why were these changes seen by some taxonomists as so controversial?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, even though the publishing world was slowly (or quickly) going electronic, many people were concerned about the permanency of works that were produced only electronically. Taxonomy depends upon being able to access the literature of the past, and some felt that safeguards were not well-developed and that proper archives didn’t yet exist. There were also fears about unscrupulous folk going in and changing e-published works, and about the possible disenfranchisement of those with minimal access to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignright wp-image-9286 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1127&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/800px-Haeckel_Orchidae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long had these debates been going on in the taxonomic community? Was there a specific reason why the changes were finally passed at the 2011 congress?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first proposals to allow e-publishing what was then called the Botanical Code (it’s now the International Code of Nomenclature for algae, fungi and plants) were made to the IBC in Vienna in 2005. Although there was some support for the change, the particular way in which it was proposed was voted down. A Special Committee was then set up to further refine the changes and bring them to the Melbourne Congress. They worked for six years to make the proposal that eventually was accepted by an over-whelming majority in Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Based on your new research, what is your assessment of the early impact of these changes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, contrary to our expectations, the changes have basically had little effect on the publishing behaviour of scientists working with naming of plants. Because e-publication is now permitted as just another instance of publishing (much like it is in the publishing industry itself) taxonomists just kept on publishing in the normal way, but had a wider range of places open to them. There were not huge numbers of “rogue” journals, but conversely, the rate of species description did not speed up either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is gratifying that today, e-publication is seen as publication…. not peculiar, not outlandish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six years on, do you feel that the taxonomic community has broadly come to accept these changes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is gratifying that today, e-publication is seen as publication…. not peculiar, not outlandish. There are teething problems for sure – date of publication not on the pdf copy, no page numbers (this upsets some), or uncertainty in some journals whether the e-version is actually the final Version of record (the one that doesn’t change). But overall, the number of taxonomists publishing electronically is going up and to me this says that it is now accepted by most of us. If we all work together as a community, publishers and publishes alike, these problems will be ironed out – hopefully long before the publishing world turns its back on print-on-paper forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/17/taxonomic-revolution-qa-sandy-knapp-impact-e-publications/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;A taxonomic revolution? A Q&amp;amp;A with Sandy Knapp on the impact of e-publications&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 14:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Diversity_of_plants_image_version_edit-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Cleaning up a public health threat – the River Ganges</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9285</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/17/cleaning-up-a-public-health-threat-the-river-ganges/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/ganges-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ganga – the holy river&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, India’s National Green Tribunal issued new, strict regulations aimed at cleaning up one of the most the polluted rivers in the world – the Ganges, or Ganga in the vernacular. According to Indian mythology, the Mother Ganges is a goddess who long ago descended from the sky to resurrect the ashes of an ancient king’s ancestors. Any Hindu who dips in or drinks from her is freed from a great deal of karmic debt. Furthermore, anyone whose  remains are scattered in her escapes immediately from the cycle of reincarnation. She is also the most respectful resting place for the carcasses of cows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public health crisis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing a water source for an estimated 400 million people, the river is home to industrial waste, sewage and human and animal remains which pose significant threats to human health. Hinduism beliefs about the holiness of the water are powerful enough to neutralise any warnings of health risks, making any public health interventions even more challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week’s announcement is not the first time attempts have been made at cleaning up the river. Shortly after Narendra Modi became India’s prime minister in 2014, he pledged to lead efforts to reduce pollution by building more treatment plants and moving more than 400 tanneries away from the river. But that estimated $3 billion clean-up plan has never come to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new regulations announced last week state that no waste can be dumped within half a kilometre of the river’s edge, and that any littering of any sort will invoke an instant fine of 50,000 rupees.  No construction will be allowed within 100 meters of the river and 456 tannery units, which release effluent into the water, should be moved away from the river within the next six weeks. If they are not relocated, they will be closed down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water-borne diseases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Ganges may be considered holy, major health risks are transmitted to the human population either by direct bathing in the dirty water or by drinking. Fecal coliform counts in the water are dangerously high and disease risks include hepatitis, typhoid, cholera, amoebic dysentery and a variety of skin afflictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9291&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-9291&quot; height=&quot;235&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/Cholera_bacteria_SEM-300x235.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Scanning electron microscope image of &lt;em&gt;V. cholerae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;Wikimedia commons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2015, there were an estimated 1.3 billion people at risk for cholera in 69 countries classified as cholera-endemic, with India being among the countries with the highest number of people at risk.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs107/en/&quot;&gt;Cholera&lt;/a&gt; is an infection of the small intestine by some strains of the bacterium &lt;em&gt;Vibrio cholerae.&lt;/em&gt; During the 19th century, the disease spread across the world from its original reservoir in the Ganges delta.  It is raising its head again in India this year and experts predict the disease will only become more frequent due to the added effects of climate change. If people with cholera are treated quickly and properly, the mortality rate is less than 1%; however, for certain genetic strains of cholera, such as the one present during the 2004 outbreak in India, death can occur within a mere two hours of becoming ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/topics/dysentery/en/&quot;&gt;Dysentery&lt;/a&gt; is a type of gastroenteritis that results in diarrhea with blood. Like cholera, dysentery is spread by fecal contamination of food and water and is usually prevalent in areas with poor sanitation. Worldwide, approximately 140 million people develop dysentery each year, and about 600,000 die.  Over 60 percent of these fatalities are children under 5 years old in developing countries. There are two main types of the disease: bacillary dysentery and amebic dysentery.  The latter is carried by the river Ganges and is caused by &lt;em&gt;Entamoeba histolytica&lt;/em&gt;, an ameba.  In areas of poor sanitation, the ameba can contaminate food and water and, as they can survive for long periods outside the body, infect other humans. They can also linger on people’s hands after using the bathroom, implying that good hygiene can reduce the risk of spreading infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/diseases/typhoid/en/&quot;&gt;Typhoid&lt;/a&gt; occurs predominantly in association with poor sanitation and lack of clean drinking water.  It is a life-threatening illness caused by the bacterium &lt;em&gt;Salmonella typhi &lt;/em&gt;and can spread throughout the body, affecting many organs. It is an important public health challenge for India where it is most common, particularly among young children and especially with the spread of antimicrobial resistance. Typhoid can easily be prevented by following simple rules including proper hygiene and sanitation and persistent hand washing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, the river also led to the development of water-borne superbugs – New Delhi metallo-beta-lactamase (NDM)-1 and NDM-4 which spread at an alarming rate, leading to a warning sparked by the World Health Organization two years later. Not only is waste contaminating the river’s water and leading to disease risk but it is also assisting in the proliferation of antibiotic resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public health efforts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contaminated water causes millions of cases of these diseases every year. Results of epidemiological studies assessing the relationship between the quality of water supply and sanitation versus human health vary widely and there are severe methodological difficulties involved in undertaking such studies.  One of the main reasons for these difficulties is that the fecal-oral route includes multiple routes for infection. However, there is sufficient evidence to support the conclusion that key to controlling these diseases is improved sanitation, the provision of clean water and the installation and maintenance of proper sewage systems or treatment facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in reading more on this topic, please visit &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Public Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The journal welcomes submissions on the epidemiology and environmental correlates of infectious disease.  Related papers can be submitted to the journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.editorialmanager.com/pubh/default.aspx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/17/cleaning-up-a-public-health-threat-the-river-ganges/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cleaning up a public health threat – the River Ganges&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 14:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/07/ganges-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Diabetes researcher who sued to prevent retractions now has 13</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51037</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/17/diabetes-researcher-sued-prevent-retractions-now-13/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A diabetes researcher who sued a publisher to protect several papers from being retracted recently received his 13th, in a prestigious gastroenterology journal. Mario Saad, based at the University of Campinas in São Paulo, Brazil, has had a string of retractions over the past few years, including four in Diabetes after he lost a legal […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/17/diabetes-researcher-sued-prevent-retractions-now-13/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Diabetes researcher who sued to prevent retractions now has 13&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Scientists peek inside the mind of Maxwell’s demon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-peek-inside-mind-maxwells-demon</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-peek-inside-mind-maxwells-demon</link>
	<description>Scientists probe information retained by Maxwell’s demon.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071417_ec_Maxwell%27s-Demon_free.png?itok=zGfo5RAv" length="101396" type="image/png"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Green and sustainable chemistry: an industry in need of a story</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/green-and-sustainable-chemistry-an-industry-in-need-of-a-story</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/green-and-sustainable-chemistry-an-industry-in-need-of-a-story</link>
	<description>Industry leaders weigh in on the future of green and sustainable chemistry and how to tell the public about it</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: It’s not just lack of sleep: why pupils with an “owl” chronotype get lower grades</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26902</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/17/its-not-just-lack-of-sleep-why-pupils-with-an-owl-chronotype-get-lower-grades/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_26922&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-84464371.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26922&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26922&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/Monkey Business&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS-1Ds Mark II&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1184757060&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;148&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;400&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.025&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Student in class sleeping (selective focus)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Student in class sleeping (selective focus)&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-84464371.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-84464371.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-84464371.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/17/its-not-just-lack-of-sleep-why-pupils-with-an-owl-chronotype-get-lower-grades/student-in-class-sleeping-selective-focus/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-84464371.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;Pupils with an “owl” chronotype may be at particular disadvantage for science and maths&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By guest blogger&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive performance fluctuates throughout the day. Depending on their “chronotype” some people are sharpest in the morning (“larks”), while others generally prefer the later hours of the day (“owls”). For obvious reasons, this is mirrored in our preferred sleep routines: larks get tired in the evenings earlier and, as a consequence, also wake up earlier, while owls show the opposite pattern. Your chronotype is not something that you’re stuck with for the rest of your life, but it changes with age. In fact we’re most likely to show an owl-like chronotype during adolescence, which might at least partly explain why teenagers often stay up late and arrive at school with eyes bloodshot thanks to a hefty sleep debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if late chronotypes are so common in adolescents, why does school start so early (usually well before 9am in the UK, Netherlands and Germany)? Doesn’t that mean that many students are likely to be constantly sleep-deprived and not assessed during their biological peaks? Yes, it does! In fact, there is a lot of evidence to suggest that school kids who have a late chronotype score lower grades. But besides reduced sleep time, there are several alternative explanations for why a late chronotype could be associated with lower academic performance (such as absenteeism, for instance) as explored in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-04076-y&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Scientific Reports. &lt;/i&gt;The researchers, led by Giulia Zerbini at University of Groningen, say their findings might help us understand the chronotype/school grade link and how we can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26902&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers collected more than 40,000 individual exam grades across multiple school subjects from 523 pupils (aged 11 to 17) at various Dutch secondary schools. They also assessed the chronotype of the students with the Munich ChronoType Questionnaire (MCTQ) which asked them several questions about their sleep habits, including what time they went to bed, fell asleep and woke on school days compared with the weekend. These data also made it possible to calculate social jetlag, which is a rough measure of the misalignment between biological and social clocks. For example, imagine you are generally not sleepy until midnight but that you have a job that means you have to be in the office from 7am: you are likely to be at risk of developing social jetlag because it will be difficult for you to get enough sleep to fit in with your schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So did owls in this study get lower grades? Yes, they did. In fact, the negative association between having a late chronotype and poorer school performance was similar to the association between absenteeism from school and poorer grades! For every hour a student’s chronotype ran later, grades dropped by 0.06 (on the 0-10 Dutch grading scale). Interestingly, this effect was largely independent of sleep duration, suggesting that even when owls got enough sleep, they still performed poorly compared with larks, perhaps because of their difficulty performing at their best during certain school hours. Consistent with this, they actually achieved similar grades to larks when they took the exam in the afternoon, nearer to their own optimal time of day. A similar pattern was also seen for the association between later chronotype and having an increased risk of dismissal from class, late arrival and social jetlag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An even more interesting pattern emerged when the researchers looked at school subjects separately. A later chronotype was associated with poorer performance in science (except physics), but not in humanities/linguistic subjects (in contrast, absenteeism had universally negative associations with grades). The apparently subject-specific relevance of chronotype chimes with previous studies suggesting that chronotype and time-of-day variation in performance have the most pronounced effects in areas demanding fluid intelligence, such as mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These findings should give policy makers food for thought. For example, they reiterate the common observation that adolescents often have late chronotypes and that early school schedules do not match their needs. And it’s not simply their fault for not going to bed early enough – often, their circadian rhythm is to blame just as much! It is promising that some British schools have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/education/educationnews/10818678/School-introduces-no-mornings-policy-for-tired-teenagers.html&quot;&gt;begun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/education/8579951.stm&quot;&gt;trialling&lt;/a&gt; later start times. Even if there is no room for modification in terms of school times, at least it could be a good idea for schools to consider postponing science subjects and exams until after lunch. Of course, this won’t transform every pupil into a potential Oxbridge graduate. But, at least it might make some of them feel less tired and help them perform at their best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-04076-y&quot;&gt;Lower school performance in late chronotypes: underlying factors and mechanisms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;img_20150110_163732&quot; class=&quot; size-thumbnail wp-image-13865 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;13865&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Nexus 5&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1420907852&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.97&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;734&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.033333333333333&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;img_20150110_163732&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_20150110_163732.jpg?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_20150110_163732.jpg?w=277&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_20150110_163732.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1425,1546&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/11/17/autistic-peoples-social-difficulties-linked-to-abnormal-processing-of-touch/img_20150110_163732/&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2016/11/img_20150110_163732.jpg?w=138&amp;amp;h=150&quot; width=&quot;138&quot; /&gt;Post written for &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://psychiatrie.charite.de/fileadmin/user_upload/microsites/m_cc15/psychiatrie/Mitarbeiter/cvs/Hasselmann/CV_Hasselmann.pdf&quot;&gt;Helge Hasselmann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Helge studied psychology and clinical neurosciences. Since 2014, he is a PhD student in medical neurosciences at Charité University Hospital in Berlin, Germany, with a focus on understanding the role of the immune system in major depression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26902/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26902/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26902&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Satellite snafu masked true sea-level rise for decades</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22312</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/dHC9JoWP1aw/nature.2017.22312</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Revised tallies confirm that the rate of sea-level rise is accelerating as the Earth warms and ice sheets thaw.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 265 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22312&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22312&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/dHC9JoWP1aw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ditching diesel won’t clear the air</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547258a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/3N6MIJPw-6c/547258a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Arguments about the environmental benefits of petrol or diesel engines are outdated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 258 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547258a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547258a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/3N6MIJPw-6c&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Neurocritic: Role of the Vestibular System in the Construction of Self</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-21605329.post-9181184035917146455</guid>
	<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~3/2S9GxozGL_A/role-of-vestibular-system-in.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9okCFl-DYBE/WWqxlVj8j1I/AAAAAAAAMNQ/WQQ8L_v84HwLdKYFBoNro5Fj4UQPrMJYgCLcBGAs/s1600/obe.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;450&quot; data-original-width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9okCFl-DYBE/WWqxlVj8j1I/AAAAAAAAMNQ/WQQ8L_v84HwLdKYFBoNro5Fj4UQPrMJYgCLcBGAs/s400/obe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How do we construct a unified self-identity as a thinking and feeling person inhabiting a body, separate and unique from other entities? A “self” with the capacity for autobiographical memory and complex thought? Traditionally, the field of cognitive science has been concerned with explaining the mind in isolation from the body.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The growing field of &lt;a href=&quot;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/embodied-cognition/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;embodied cognition&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, seeks to rejoin them. One major strand has focused on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17705682&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;grounded cognition&quot;&gt;grounding&lt;/a&gt; higher-order semantics and language understanding in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11301525&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;perceptual symbol systems&quot;&gt;perceptual&lt;/a&gt; and sensory-motor representations. This view is distinct from theories of knowledge based on abstract, amodal representations divorced from sensory-motor experience. Another wing of the embodied approach is concerned with how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/nrn/journal/v3/n8/full/nrn894.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;interoception&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot; data-hveid=&quot;55&quot; data-ved=&quot;0ahUKEwj9kbT6po7VAhWHxlQKHaTPB_IQ4EUINzAB&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; the inner sense of your physical state &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot; data-hveid=&quot;55&quot; data-ved=&quot;0ahUKEwj9kbT6po7VAhWHxlQKHaTPB_IQ4EUINzAB&quot;&gt;—&lt;/span&gt; grounds your feelings and emotions in the body. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/neuro/journal/v7/n2/full/nn1176.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interoceptive awareness&lt;/a&gt; of visceral functions such as heartbeat has been related to core consciousness and awareness of self, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0149763416308053&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;body image&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A relatively neglected yet critical aspect of any grand theory of the embodied self is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scholarpedia.org/article/Vestibular_system&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vestibular system&lt;/a&gt;. The vestibular system is the set of sensory organs responsible for maintaining our balance and keeping our visual field in a stable position while our head moves around. These organs are located in the inner ear and include...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;...two &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Otolith&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;otolith&lt;/a&gt; organs (the saccule and utricle), which sense linear  acceleration (i.e., gravity and translational movements), and the three  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semicircular_canal&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;semicircular canals&lt;/a&gt;, which sense angular acceleration in three planes.  The receptor cells of the otoliths and semicircular canals send signals  through the vestibular nerve fibers to the neural structures that control eye movements, posture, and balance. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The quote above is from &lt;span class=&quot;subpages&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scholarpedia.org/article/Vestibular_system&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kathleen Cullen and Soroush Sadeghi (2008)&lt;/a&gt;, who have an excellent review on the vestibular system in &lt;i&gt;Scholarpedia&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eZcwRdUD2yM/WWu9q3u5zOI/AAAAAAAAMNc/z5YPAp30J_EoGY5wBApacvm9hZ8bg5p7wCLcBGAs/s1600/Vestibular_system.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;904&quot; data-original-width=&quot;1056&quot; height=&quot;341&quot; src=&quot;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eZcwRdUD2yM/WWu9q3u5zOI/AAAAAAAAMNc/z5YPAp30J_EoGY5wBApacvm9hZ8bg5p7wCLcBGAs/s400/Vestibular_system.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We take the vestibular system for granted until something goes wrong, like motion sickness (a mismatch of movement perceived by the vestibular and visual systems) or a rare disorder of the inner ear such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M%C3%A9ni%C3%A8re%27s_disease&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;'characterized by episodes of feeling like the world is spinning (vertigo), ringing in the ears (tinnitus), hearing loss, and a fullness in the ear'&quot;&gt;Menière’s disease&lt;/a&gt;. But how can a dysfunction of the inner ear influence our sense of self?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jnnp.bmj.com/content/77/6/760.short&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Song, Jáuregui-Renaud, and colleagues (2008)&lt;/a&gt; looked at symptoms of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depersonalization&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;depersonalization&lt;/a&gt; (a feeling of detachment from oneself) in 50 patients with peripheral vestibular disease and 121 healthy controls. The participants were given the Depersonalization/Derealization Inventory of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12112722&quot;&gt;Cox and Swinson (2002)&lt;/a&gt; to assess symptoms of &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20140313163001/http://www.dissociative-identity-disorder.net/wiki/Depersonalization_Disorder&quot; title=&quot;Depersonalization Disorder&quot;&gt;these conditions&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Depersonalization: Experiences of unreality, &lt;span class=&quot;tooltip &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip_abbr&quot;&gt;detachment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,   or being an outside observer with respect to one's thoughts, feelings,   sensations, body, or actions (e.g.,perceptual alterations, distorted   sense of time, unreal or absent self, emotional and/or physical   numbing.)&quot;  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip &quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltip_abbr&quot;&gt;Derealization&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:   &quot;Experiences of unreality or detachment with respect to surroundings   (e.g., individuals or objects are experienced as unreal, dreamlike,   foggy, lifeless, or visually distorted.&quot; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beyond the expected high frequency of dizziness, the patients were much more likely to experience feelings of Shifting Ground, Spaced Out, Body Feels Strange, and Not Being in Control of Self than were controls (see bottom half of the figure below).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cp_SGt4B6cc/WWvHMd2nQBI/AAAAAAAAMNk/uNxxYGdhtFQPZiWFkClmAuIQ7Z9SBYdGACLcBGAs/s1600/Fig%2B1_DD%2BSymptoms.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;683&quot; data-original-width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-cp_SGt4B6cc/WWvHMd2nQBI/AAAAAAAAMNk/uNxxYGdhtFQPZiWFkClmAuIQ7Z9SBYdGACLcBGAs/s400/Fig%2B1_DD%2BSymptoms.png&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The authors suggest that abnormal vestibular signals disrupt the relationship of the self to the environment, leading to strange feelings of detachment:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;tr_bq&quot;&gt;Vestibular disease causes primary symptoms of vertigo and feelings that the ground is unstable ... which are more marked in distinct, acute episodes. These immediate symptoms are, by definition, unreal experiences since the body is not spinning and the ground is not heaving, but they are readily understandable as perceptions derived directly from abnormal sensory signals. Vestibular dysfunction could also compromise more general precepts of stable relationships between the self and the environment...&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Symptoms of depersonalization/derealization can be induced experimentally in healthy people via &lt;a href=&quot;https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/003429.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;caloric stimulation&lt;/a&gt;. This procedure is used medically to check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17314478&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vestibulo-ocular reflex&lt;/a&gt;, which stabilizes the visual image while the head is moving. The test involves delivering warm or cold water into the ear canal and observing the resultant eye movements (or lack thereof).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jnnp.bmj.com/content/77/6/760.short&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Song et al. (2008)&lt;/a&gt; administered caloric stimulation to 20 of their vestibular patients and 20 controls. After stimulation, many healthy participants reported feelings of detachment/separation from their surroundings (40%), and that their body feels strange/different (50%). These were novel experiences for most. Conversely, the patients reported no such changes after stimulation because they already experience these symptoms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An even more extreme way to stimulate the vestibular system is through &lt;a href=&quot;http://naukarus.com/reliability-of-utricular-function-testing-using-a-sinusoidal-translation-profile-during-unilateral-centrifugation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unilateral centrifugation &lt;/a&gt;(i.e., spinning around in a specialized chair). NOTE: this has nothing to do with the fictional &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/58293017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Centrifuge Brain Project&lt;/a&gt;. See more about that &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2017/03/a-brain-enhancement-amusement-park.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;A brain-enhancement amusement park mockumentary&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xk88gUampX8/WWvk11jElEI/AAAAAAAAMNw/NQ2RSMKk8c8f_vg0JfUbuNZ6TvOT1nu1wCLcBGAs/s1600/Neuro%2BKinetics%2BNOTC.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;900&quot; data-original-width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xk88gUampX8/WWvk11jElEI/AAAAAAAAMNw/NQ2RSMKk8c8f_vg0JfUbuNZ6TvOT1nu1wCLcBGAs/s400/Neuro%2BKinetics%2BNOTC.jpg&quot; width=&quot;266&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neuro-kinetics.com/about.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neuro Kinetics I-Portal®-NOTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;(I don't think I'd be smiling)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A recent study subjected 100 healthy participants to unilateral centrifugation to stimulate the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Utricle_%28ear%29&quot; title=&quot;Utricle (ear)&quot;&gt;utricles&lt;/a&gt;  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://content.iospress.com/articles/journal-of-vestibular-research/ves597&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aranda-Moreno &amp;amp; Jáuregui-Renaud, 2016&lt;/a&gt;). The target of this test differs from the caloric procedure, which stimulates the semicircular canals. The utricles and the semicircular canals detect different types of motion (linear  acceleration and angular acceleration, respectively), and the authors wanted to see if unilateral centrifugation would produce the same effects as caloric stimulation. And indeed, after centrifugation, symptoms of depersonalization and derealization were reported with increased frequency &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot; data-hveid=&quot;55&quot; data-ved=&quot;0ahUKEwj9kbT6po7VAhWHxlQKHaTPB_IQ4EUINzAB&quot;&gt;— &lt;/span&gt;e.g., Surroundings seem strange and unreal; Time seems to pass very slowly; Body feels strange or different in some way (see Table below for details).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;- click on image for a larger view -&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-05-S4Df7hmY/WMszCpXNXaI/AAAAAAAAMFI/uXB0Y-qy-5UaI_oFX16cFzqUCCSMWaO7QCLcB/s1600/Depersonalization_derealization%2Bsymptoms.png&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: 0em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-05-S4Df7hmY/WMszCpXNXaI/AAAAAAAAMFI/uXB0Y-qy-5UaI_oFX16cFzqUCCSMWaO7QCLcB/s400/Depersonalization_derealization%2Bsymptoms.png&quot; width=&quot;343&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;modified from Table 2 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://content.iospress.com/articles/journal-of-vestibular-research/ves597&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Aranda-Moreno &amp;amp; Jáuregui-Renaud, 2016&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/b&gt; Frequency (Freq) and severity (score range) for each of the symptoms of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12112722&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cox and Swinson (2002)&lt;/a&gt; depersonalization/derealization inventory reported by 100 subjects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These results provide further evidence that the vestibular system contributes to the construction of the self. The sense of inhabiting one's body is assembled from many different inputs, of course. These &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0165017305000792&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can go awry&lt;/a&gt; in epilepsy, migraine, focal brain injury, psychiatric disturbances, and under extreme stress. Although rare, out-of-body experiences are more frequent in persons who suffer from dizziness due to vestibular disorders (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010945217301892&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lopez &amp;amp; Elzière, 2017&lt;/a&gt;). In these instances, the vestibular system is unable to ground the self within the body.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Aranda-Moreno C, Jáuregui-Renaud K. (2016). &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.iospress.com/articles/journal-of-vestibular-research/ves597&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Derealization during utricular stimulation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Vestibular Research&lt;/i&gt; 26(5-6):425-431.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cullen K, Sadeghi S (2008). &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.4249/scholarpedia.3013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vestibular system&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Scholarpedia&lt;/i&gt;, 3(1):3013.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lopez C, Elzière M. (2017). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010945217301892&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Out-of-body experience in vestibular disorders - A prospective study of 210 patients with dizziness.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Cortex&lt;/i&gt; Jun 8. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gs_citr&quot; id=&quot;gs_cit4&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Sang FY, Jauregui-Renaud  K, Green DA, Bronstein AM, Gresty MA. (2006). &lt;a href=&quot;http://jnnp.bmj.com/content/77/6/760.short&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Depersonalisation/derealisation symptoms in vestibular disease&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp;amp;  Psychiatry&lt;/i&gt; 77(6):760-6.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Further Reading&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/researchtopic/1235/the-vestibular-system-in-cognitive-and-memory-processes-in-mammalians#articles&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Research Topic: The Vestibular System in Cognitive and Memory Processes in Mammalians&lt;/a&gt; (collection edited by Besnard et al., 2015)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00678/full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Personality changes in patients with vestibular dysfunction&lt;/a&gt; (review by Smith &amp;amp; Darlington, 2013)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2014/06/feeling-mighty-unreal-derealization-in.html&quot;&gt;Feeling Mighty Unreal: Derealization in Kleine-Levin Syndrome&lt;/a&gt; (blog post by The Neurocritic)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neurocritic.blogspot.com/2016/03/a-detached-sense-of-self-associated.html&quot;&gt;A Detached Sense of Self Associated with Altered Neural Responses to Mirror Touch&lt;/a&gt; (blog post by The Neurocritic)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/371/1708&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Theme issue ‘Interoception beyond homeostasis: affect, cognition and mental health’&lt;/a&gt; (edited by Manos Tsakiris and Hugo D. Critchley).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13423-015-0860-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The poverty of embodied cognition&lt;/a&gt; (Goldinger et al., 2016).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.3758/s13423-016-1045-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arguments about the nature of concepts: Symbols, embodiment, and beyond&lt;/a&gt; (Mahon &amp;amp; Hickok, 2016). &lt;div class=&quot;feedflare&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:yIl2AUoC8zA&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=yIl2AUoC8zA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=JUhcmGiK9AQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:qj6IDK7rITs&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=qj6IDK7rITs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:gIN9vFwOqvQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?a=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNeurocritic?i=2S9GxozGL_A:UiJ0xKiJ87Y:F7zBnMyn0Lo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNeurocritic/~4/2S9GxozGL_A&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 23:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (The Neurocritic)</author>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/TheNeurocritic">The Neurocritic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: The RW week in review: Doing the right thing, two journals’ first retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51067</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/16/rw-week-review-right-thing-two-journals-first-retractions/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Did you miss some of this week’s posts? Here they all are, in one handy roundup: Are there foxes in Tasmania? Follow the poop Lancet retracts (and replaces) paper a year after authors report error that changes “all numbers” Lost in translation: Authors blame a language error for wrong diagnosis More notices appear for embattled […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/16/rw-week-review-right-thing-two-journals-first-retractions/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The RW week in review: Doing the right thing, two journals’ first retractions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Researchers Apologize For Writing &quot;Derpy&quot; In A Paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8956</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8956</link>
	<description>It appears that memes and science don't mix well. A pair of researchers have published an apology in a peer-reviewed journal - for using the word &quot;derpy&quot; in an earlier paper.



In April 2016, Archives of Sexual Behavior published a piece called Fighting the Derpy Science of Sexuality by Banu Subramaniam and Angela Willey.



In this paper, Subramaniam and Willey criticized studies of biological differences between human groups:
The various sciences of‘‘difference’’ - sex, gender, race,</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 14:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Six-figure publishing bonuses; Google’s scientific influence campaign</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51063</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/15/weekend-reads-six-figure-publishing-bonuses-googles-scientific-influence-campaign/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week at Retraction Watch featured the story of a group devastated to learn that they had used the wrong mice in their experiments, and the tale of how keycard swipe records gave away faked data. Here’s what was happening elsewhere: In China, “scientists who publish in the top Western journals can earn in excess of […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/15/weekend-reads-six-figure-publishing-bonuses-googles-scientific-influence-campaign/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Six-figure publishing bonuses; Google’s scientific influence campaign&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 13:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Giant mud balls roamed the early solar system</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-mud-balls-roamed-early-solar-system</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/giant-mud-balls-roamed-early-solar-system</link>
	<description>The first asteroids may have been great balls of mud, which would solve some puzzling features of meteorites.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071417_LG_mud-asteroid_main-free.jpg?itok=ipFRwm2j" length="14071" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: GM moth trial gets a green light from USDA</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gm-moth-trial-gets-green-light-usda</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gm-moth-trial-gets-green-light-usda</link>
	<description>GM diamondback moths will take wing in a New York field trial.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 17:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071417_HT_moth_main_free.jpg?itok=Gw0tdRJq" length="14073" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Water bears will survive the end of the world as we know it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/water-bears-will-survive-end-world-we-know-it</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/water-bears-will-survive-end-world-we-know-it</link>
	<description>Water bears have a till-death-do-us-part pact with the sun, study suggests.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 15:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071417_MT_tardigarde_main_free.jpg?itok=EONox1Wv" length="34462" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Volunteer researcher faked weeks’ worth of data</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51042</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/research-volunteer-faked-weeks-worth-data/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A volunteer researcher at Florida Atlantic University fabricated the results of mouse experiments over a 14-day period in June, 2016, according to a new finding issued by the U.S Office of Research Integrity (ORI). According to the ORI, Alec Mirchandani made up the results of behavioral experiments to make it seem as if he had done the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/research-volunteer-faked-weeks-worth-data/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Volunteer researcher faked weeks’ worth of data&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 15:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: New Breakthroughs in Concussion Diagnostics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22603</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/14/new-breakthroughs-in-concussion-diagnostics/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Concussion is the most common form of traumatic brain injury. While serious concussions present with overt symptoms, the diagnosis of mild concussions remains a clinical difficulty. Researchers recently developed two novel methods for the diagnosis of concussion that may aid in the identification of less severe traumatic brain injuries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/06/new-game-like-technology-helps-assess-concussions/&quot;&gt;concussion&lt;/a&gt; is a relatively common traumatic brain injury caused by a fall or blow to the head that results in a temporary impairment of brain function. Loss of consciousness is common, but contrary to popular belief, it is not a requirement for diagnosis. Typical indicators include drowsiness, dizziness, confusion, headache, and memory impairment, among other neurological symptoms. These symptoms usually persist for a few months, but some patients continue to experience cognitive and behavioral manifestations long after the initial injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detection of concussion using objective, quantitative methods remains a clinical challenge. Traditional &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/06/16/looking-inside-our-heads-brain-imaging-and-patient-adherence/&quot;&gt;brain imaging techniques&lt;/a&gt;, such as computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging, are not sensitive enough for this application. Therefore, diagnosis is usually made using non-objective methods such as patient interviews and self-assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of researchers led by Margot Taylor at Simon Fraser University have developed a n&lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004914&quot;&gt;ew method&lt;/a&gt; for detecting mild traumatic brain injuries using magnetoencephalographic (MEG) imaging. The results were published in the journal &lt;em&gt;PLOS Computational Biology&lt;/em&gt;. Taylor and colleagues are members of the Behavioral and Cognitive Neuroscience Institute and the ImageTech Lab at SFU, home to the only research-dedicated MEG scanners in western Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MEG imaging is a technique that measures the magnetic fields generated by brain activity. It has excellent spatial and temporal resolution and can identify events with millimeter and millisecond precision. MEG imaging can be used to map the interaction among various brain areas. Importantly for clinical applications, MEG imaging is completely noninvasive, and can be used in both adults and children without harmful radiation exposure, or the need to inject isotopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mild traumatic brain injury is associated with damage to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/03/14/shifting-paradigms-of-white-matter-diseases/&quot;&gt;white matter&lt;/a&gt; of the brain, made up of bundles of nerve axons that connect one brain area to another. When two brain areas are connected, they show activity pattern synchronization, referred to as oscillatory network synchrony. The researchers hypothesized that by using MEG imaging to measure network synchrony, they could identify small disruptions in the connections between brain areas that result from traumatic brain injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MEG scans were performed on patients who were diagnosed with a mild traumatic brain injury (concussion) in the prior three months, and on healthy controls. Computer analyses were performed to calculate several indices of network connectivity, and significant differences were found between patients and controls. The differences were stronger when less time had elapsed between the injury and the imaging procedure. Overall, MEG imaging was able to detect the presence of a mild concussion with 88% accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/srep39009&quot;&gt;10.1038/srep39009″&amp;gt;groundbreaking study&lt;/a&gt;, a group of researchers led by Nina Kraus and Cynthia LaBella of the Auditory Neuroscience Laboratory at Northwestern University have developed an approach for diagnosing concussion using an auditory biomarker. Their work was recently published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing of sound by the brain is a complex process that involves interaction among the cognitive, sensory, and limbic systems. Damage to any of these brain systems should therefore interrupt &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/09/22/hearing-voices-underpinnings-of-auditory-hallucinations/&quot;&gt;auditory processing&lt;/a&gt;, the researchers proposed. The question Kraus and colleagues asked was whether concussion-induced changes in sound processing would be large enough to distinguish between patients with a concussion and controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this question, the researchers measured speech-evoked frequency-following responses (FFRs) in 40 children with and without a concussion. The FFR is generated by the auditory center of the brain, and it incorporates cognitive, sensory, and reward input. Changes in the FFR have previously been associated with other clinical syndromes. Importantly, the FFR can be easily measured by placing electrodes on the scalp and delivering a sound stimulus into the ear. The FFR measurement is highly reliable and is consistent across the lifespan within an individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children who had sustained concussion were tested an average of 27 days after their injury. Neurophysiological responses were measured in terms of the magnitude, timing, accuracy, and pitch processing of the fundamental frequency of speech (F0). Children with &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/05/14/jury-still-out-on-after-effects-of-concussion/&quot;&gt;concussion&lt;/a&gt; exhibited on average a 35% smaller response to the F0 than the controls. They also showed impaired pitch coding, and smaller and slower brain responses to speech. These measures were correlated with the number of concussion symptoms reported by the patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers created a statistical model incorporating these data. Their model was able to classify subjects into concussion or control groups with 90% sensitivity and 95% specificity, suggesting that the observed changes in auditory processing are an accurate biomarker of concussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers cite the portability, reliability, and accuracy of their test as major advantages for its clinical application in diagnosing new injuries. Baseline readings could be made in athletes who participate in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/03/08/sports-concussion-new-testing-methods-are-imperative/&quot;&gt;impact sports&lt;/a&gt;, and repeat measures could be taken at the end of the season or following an injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with MEG imaging, this method provides an objective and quantitative means for diagnosing brain dysfunction after mild traumatic brain injury. These methods will be useful both for identifying patients with mild injuries, and for developing guidelines for recovery and the return to work and play following an injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimou S. and Lagopoulos J. (2014). Toward objective markers of concussion in sport: a review of white matter and neurometabolic changes in the brain after sports-related concussion. J Neurotrauma. 1;31(5):413-24. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1089/neu.2013.3050&quot;&gt;10.1089/neu.2013.3050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vakorin V.A., Doesburg S.M., Da Costa L., Jetly R., Pang E.W., Taylor M.J. (2016) Detecting Mild Traumatic Brain Injury Using Resting State Magnetoencephalographic Connectivity. PLOS Computational Biology 12(12):e1004914. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004914&quot;&gt;10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004914&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nina Kraus N., Thompson E.C., Krizman J., Cook K., White-Schwoch T., LaBella, C.R. (2016) Auditory biological marker of concussion in children. Sci Rep. 6:39009. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/srep39009&quot;&gt;10.1038/srep39009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kraus, N. and White-Schwoch, T. (2015) Unraveling the biology of auditory learning: A cognitive-sensorimotor-reward framework. Trends Cogn Sci. 19:642–654. DOI: dx.doi.org/10.1016&lt;a href=&quot;http://http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2015.08.017&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;/j.tics.2015.08.017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Couleur-1195798/&quot;&gt;Couleur&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Prevention Is the Best Medicine for Dementia</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22670</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/14/prevention-is-the-best-medicine-for-dementia/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Population aging is bringing about a substantial increase in the prevalence of neurocognitive disorders. Current projections estimate that, by 2050, more that 130 million people will be affected by dementia worldwide. As experts assemble to devise strategies to face this incoming challenge, one conclusion stands out: prevention is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of prevention is obvious: to promote good health and take action before disease onset, thereby reducing the incidence of disease. And this is obviously better than having to manage a disease and its complications, and losing &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/09/04/pursuing-happiness-doesnt-have-to-promote-depression-in-others/&quot;&gt;quality of life&lt;/a&gt; – “prevention is better than cure.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in order for preventive behaviors to be acquired, knowledge is essential – knowledge of modifiable risk factors and preemptive actions that can be adopted, and knowledge of how effective they really are. Studies addressing the benefit of lifestyle interventions for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/06/12/nsaids-prevention-or-just-delay-of-dementia/&quot;&gt;prevention of dementia&lt;/a&gt; have identified numerous modifiable risk and protective factors and have shown that change can indeed be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modifiable risk factors for cognitive impairment include lifestyle factors such as smoking, high alcohol intake, diet (saturated fats, sugar, processed foods), and poor physical activity; these then manifest in other risk factors that are already a consequence of inadequate lifestyle options, namely vascular and metabolic diseases (cerebrovascular and cardiovascular diseases, diabetes, hypertension, overweight and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/28/effect-of-obesity-on-human-brain/&quot;&gt;obesity&lt;/a&gt;, high cholesterol). In the end, it all builds up to speed up cognitive decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protective factors include opposite lifestyle choices, such as quitting smoking, moderate alcohol intake, healthier diet (&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2013/08/04/the-health-benefits-of-a-mediterranean-diet/&quot;&gt;Mediterranean diet&lt;/a&gt;, polyunsaturated fatty acids and fish-related fats, vitamins B6 and B12, folate, antioxidant vitamins (A, C and E), vitamin D, physical activity, and mentally stimulating activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, cognitive disorders are complex, multifactorial conditions – even if you lead the healthiest life, dementia may still strike you. But this should not be an excuse to let go because research shows is that preventive behaviors shift the odds in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important aspect of behavioral change is that it should be integrative. Single-domain interventions provide some benefit: physical activity and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/04/15/brain-training-can-we-really-enhance-our-cognitive-skills/&quot;&gt;cognitive training &lt;/a&gt;have been positively associated with cognitive performance in multiple studies; also, a recent meta-analysis showed that an increased consumption of fruit and vegetables reduces the risk of cognitive impairment and dementia. But multi-domain interventions, in which multiple risk factors are targeted simultaneously are more likely to deliver better results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a 2015 Finnish study assessed the effect of a 2-year multimodal intervention in adults aged 60-77 years at risk of cognitive decline but without pronounced cognitive impairment. Four intervention targets were included: diet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/07/19/high-intensity-interval-training-and-brain-health/&quot;&gt;exercise&lt;/a&gt;, cognitive training, and vascular risk. The program’s design included a diet with high consumption of fruit and vegetables, consumption of wholegrain cereal products and low-fat milk and meat products, low sucrose intake, use of vegetable margarine and rapeseed oil instead of butter, and fish consumption at least two portions per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical exercise training program included progressive muscle strength training, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/03/11/exercise-boosts-brain-power/&quot;&gt;aerobic exercise&lt;/a&gt;, and exercises to improve postural balance. Cognitive training consisted of computer-based training targeting executive processes, working memory, episodic memory, and mental speed. Metabolic and vascular risk factors were monitored throughout the study. Social activities were also stimulated through the numerous group meetings of all intervention components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study showed that simultaneous changes in multiple risk factors, even of small magnitude, had beneficial effects on the risk of cognitive decline, on overall cognition, complex memory tasks, executive functioning and processing speed, and on also BMI, dietary habits, and physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a timely prevention seems fundamental – these lifestyle interventions may not be as effective once cognitive impairment is manifest. A recent study evaluated the impact of a 3-year &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/16/nurturing-the-brain-part-7-omega-3-fatty-acids/&quot;&gt;omega-3 fatty acid&lt;/a&gt; supplementation with or without multi-domain lifestyle interventions on cognitive function in adults aged 70 years or older. These adults already had symptoms of cognitive impairment: either memory complaints, limitations in one instrumental daily living activity, or slow gait speed. The multi-domain intervention included cognitive training, physical activity, nutrition, and management of cardiovascular risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, neither the omega-3 supplementation alone, nor the combination with the lifestyle interventions were able to reduce cognitive decline. Also, the adherence to lifestyle interventions over time was lower in this study when compared to other studies with younger seniors, with no clinical manifestations of dementia onset. But still, those with increased risk of dementia were the ones who benefited the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early prevention is probably the best strategy. Instead of trying to prevent dementia later in life, focusing on preventing earlier, milder, and more common forms of cognitive impairment may be a better strategy that may end up also preventing cardiovascular and metabolic diseases and, ultimately, dementia. Because they’re all fruits from the same tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrieu S, et al (2017). Effect of long-term omega 3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation with or without multidomain intervention on cognitive function in elderly adults with memory complaints (MAPT): a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol, 16(5):377-389. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/laneur/article/PIIS1474-4422(17)30040-6/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30040-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiang X, et al (2017). Increased Consumption of Fruit and Vegetables Is Related to a Reduced Risk of Cognitive Impairment and Dementia: Meta-Analysis. Front Aging Neurosci, 9:18. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00018/full&quot;&gt;10.3389/fnagi.2017.00018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kivipelto M, et al (2017). Can lifestyle changes prevent cognitive impairment? Lancet Neurol, 16(5):338-339. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/laneur/article/PIIS1474-4422(17)30080-7/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30080-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ngandu T, et al (2015). A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet, 385(9984):2255-63. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)60461-5/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60461-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shah H, et al (2016). Research priorities to reduce the global burden of dementia by 2025. Lancet Neurol, 15(12):1285-1294. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/laneur/article/PIIS1474-4422(16)30235-6/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30235-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solomon A, et al (2016). Advances in the prevention of Alzheimer’s disease and dementia. J Intern Med, 275(3):229-50. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/joim.12178/abstract&quot;&gt;10.1111/joim.12178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Couleur-1195798/&quot;&gt;Couleur&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 15:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Want to appeal a journal’s rejection? Sure — that’ll be $700</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51028</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/want-appeal-journals-rejection-sure-thatll-700/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Different journals follow different editorial policies — but we’ve never seen any charge money to authors who want to appeal an editorial decision. Until now. Recently, a criminal justice researcher sent us links to multiple journals that charge appeal fees. For instance, the Journal of Accounting Research says authors must pay $500 for each submission — […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/want-appeal-journals-rejection-sure-thatll-700/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Want to appeal a journal’s rejection? Sure — that’ll be $700&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Leibniz Prize belatedly awarded to scientist cleared of misconduct</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51013</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/leibniz-prize-belatedly-awarded-scientist-cleared-misconduct/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Just before the March ceremony to bestow the coveted Leibniz Prize, the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG, German Research Foundation) received some disturbing allegations. An anonymous tipster accused one of the 10 scientists slotted to receive the award, materials scientist Britta Nestler, of misconduct. So the DFG held the ceremony on March 15, but suspended Nestler’s award. Four […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/14/leibniz-prize-belatedly-awarded-scientist-cleared-misconduct/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Leibniz Prize belatedly awarded to scientist cleared of misconduct&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Copper in Ötzi the Iceman’s ax came from surprisingly far away</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/copper-otzi-icemans-ax-came-surprisingly-far-away</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/copper-otzi-icemans-ax-came-surprisingly-far-away</link>
	<description>Copper for the ancient Iceman’s blade traveled about 500 kilometers to his northern Italian home region.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071217_BB_otzi-ax_main.jpg?itok=k-omqDNS" length="14860" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Anxious about a speech? Alcohol may calm your nerves but will harm your performance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26806</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/14/anxious-about-a-speech-alcohol-may-calm-your-nerves-but-will-harm-your-performance/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-670407788.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26894&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26894&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 600D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Black and white silhouette of a young man in depression with a glass of cognac on his forehead on an isolated background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1491586926&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;silhouette of a man with a glass of cognac on his forehead&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;silhouette of a man with a glass of cognac on his forehead&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-670407788.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-670407788.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-670407788.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/14/anxious-about-a-speech-alcohol-may-calm-your-nerves-but-will-harm-your-performance/silhouette-of-a-man-with-a-glass-of-cognac-on-his-forehead/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-670407788.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confess, I’ve tried having an alcoholic drink before giving a public speech, telling myself that it will take the edge off my nerves. But I’m going to think twice before doing so again: a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796717300864&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Behaviour Research and Therapy&lt;/em&gt; carefully monitored the effects of moderate alcohol intake on the speech-giving performance of socially anxious and control participants and while the alcohol made the nervous folk feel more relaxed, it actually harmed their performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26806&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephan Stevens and his colleagues recruited 99 young adults who met the criteria for social anxiety disorder and 78 non-anxious controls, and then allocated them randomly to one of three conditions: an alcohol group drank three vodka orange juices with the strength adjusted to their body weight to ensure they reached a blood alcohol concentration of 0.07 per cent (for comparison, the drink drive limit in England and Wales and Northern Ireland is 0.08, ditto for the USA, while it’s 0.05 in Scotland); a placebo group who thought the orange juice they were drinking had vodka in it; and a baseline group who knew they were drinking pure orange juice. The participants reported how anxious they were feeling before, during and after delivering a three-minute speech on the death penalty in front of an audience of two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The socially anxious participants who drank alcohol felt less nervous during the speech and afterwards, as compared with anxious participants in the placebo group and in the baseline pure-orange group. This gives an indication of why alcohol can become a crutch for so many anxious people with rates of problem drinking being much higher than average among people with anxiety diagnoses. Looking on the bright side, given that excessive anxiety can hamper performance, you’d think the calming effects of the alcohol might have aided the performance of the socially anxious participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s not what the researchers found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drinking alcohol actually led to socially anxious participants’ speeches being rated worse by two scorers who didn’t know which participants had a social anxiety diagnosis, nor who had drunk alcohol. The scorers also gave poor ratings to the speeches given by non-anxious control participants who’d drunk alcohol (for this group, there was no calming effect of alcohol, perhaps because they didn’t find the speech particularly nerve-wracking anyway). These findings suggest that even a couple of drinks is intoxicating enough to interfere with the mental processes needed to deliver an effective speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the socially anxious participants in the placebo condition, they felt less nervous than the baseline group who knew they’d drunk pure orange juice, but more nervous than alcohol group, suggesting that the calming effects of alcohol are partly pharmacological and partly to do with expectations. Participants in the placebo condition also gave worse speeches than those in the baseline condition, but not as poor as those in the alcohol condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stevens and his colleagues said the performance-harming effect of alcohol could lead to a vicious circle: anxious people drink alcohol to calm their nerves, but it interferes with their speech-giving performance, so they get more negative feedback than they would have done sober, and then they’re even more nervous about the next time they have to give a speech, which only makes them want to drink again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers noted that alcohol might have different effects on the social performance of anxious participants in different kinds of contexts, such as chatting at a party or at a meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796717300864&quot;&gt;Feeling safe but appearing anxious: Differential effects of alcohol on anxiety and social performance in individuals with social anxiety disorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26806/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26806/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26806&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 08:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: European Commission urges logging ban in ancient Białowieża Forest</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22309</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/n-okLm9LYhY/nature.2017.22309</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Europe’s highest court will rule on Poland's policy that encourages tree-felling in biodiversity hotspot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 267 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22309&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22309&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/n-okLm9LYhY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: New Antarctic iceberg echoes old problem</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547257a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/ikVPehqgAZU/547257a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The break in the Larsen C ice shelf highlights the vulnerable nature of other Antarctic environments and the impact people are having on the continent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 257 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547257a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547257a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/ikVPehqgAZU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PLOS Neuroscience Community: The role of neurabins in affective disorders</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19384</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/wQlFr0eCo3k/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2017/07/Affective-disorders-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Affective disorders, a set of neuropsychiatric diseases also known as mood disorders, include depression and anxiety. These disorders are emerging as a major public health challenge and, despite efforts in the last two decades, the biological mechanisms underlying such diseases remain elusive and poorly understood. Indeed, altered synaptic functions as well as aberrant connectivity and plasticity have been proposed as critical players in the etiology of affective disorders. Importantly, disruption of synaptic proteins often occurs in these pathological conditions (&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1113/jphysiol.2008.167742/abstract&quot;&gt;Luscher and Isaac, 2009&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neurabins and affective disorders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0180638&quot;&gt;PLOS One article&lt;/a&gt;, Wu and colleagues (University of Alabama at Birmingham) decided to investigate the potential role of two synaptic proteins: neurabin and spinophilin. These two proteins, also known as neurabin I and II, are homologous scaffold proteins located at the synaptic level. However, a slight difference in their synaptic location exists. In fact, while neurabin has been shown to be located at both pre- and post-synaptic levels, the other homologue protein spinophillin is primarily located at the post-synaptic site, more specifically in dendritic spines. Evidence suggests that both scaffold proteins are involved in cellular processes such as spinogenesis, dendritic spine maturation and cytoskeletal regulation. At the molecular level, neurabin and spinophilin regulate AMPA receptor trafficking, a key phenomenon able to affect fast excitatory synaptic transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using knock-out (KO) animal models for neurabin and spinophilin, Wu and colleagues aimed to understand their contribution in anxiety- and depression-related behaviors. “&lt;em&gt;Our data reveal that, despite the structural similarities between neurabin and spinophilin, and their overlapping function in regulating the synaptic cytoskeleton, inactivation of each gene caused distinct behavioral phenotypes,&lt;/em&gt;” report the authors. Because aging is a physiological variable able to constantly reshape synapses and their molecular machineries, neurabin- and spinophilin-deficient mice were studied at different ages: young (3-5 months old) and middle-aged (11-13 months old) adults. To investigate the consequences of neurabin and/or spinophilin deficiency, Wu et al. used well-established behavioral paradigms known to reveal anxiety- and depression-like phenotypes, notably the elevated zero maze (anxiety) and the forced swim test (behavioral despair, depression).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anxiety- and depression-like phenotype in neurabin-deficient mice. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel and stressful environments evoke conflicts in rodents between exploratory drive and fear/defensive behavior. When allowed to make a choice between two novel areas, closed areas are preferred. Because of the elevated nature of the platform in the elevated zero maze, rodents tend to spend more time in the closed regions than in the open ones. Interestingly, genetic ablation of neurabin, but not spinophilin, in young adult mice induced an anxiolytic-like effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioral despair, a depression-like phenotype, was assessed using the forced swim test (FST). The FST has been described as rendering a situation in which &lt;em&gt;behavioral despair&lt;/em&gt; is induced; that is, the animal loses hope to escape the stressful environment. In the FST mice are placed in an inescapable transparent tank that is filled with water and their mobility or immobility is measured. The lower the mobility (higher the immobility), the higher the despair. Surprisingly, a differential regulation of depression-like behavior was observed in neurabin KO and spinophilin KO mice. In fact, while spinophilin-deficient mice displayed a significantly increased immobility time (increased behavioral despair) during the first day of FST, neurabin-deficient mice showed a reduction of such behavior, thus suggesting a reduction of depression-like phenotype. “&lt;em&gt;These data suggest that loss of neurabin leads to reduced depression-like behavior in young adult mice, and that neurabin and spinophilin play different roles in regulating depression-like behavior&lt;/em&gt;”, say Qin Wang, the senior author of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neurabins, aging and affective disorders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about aged mice? As mentioned above, aging shapes synaptic functions. Thus, Wu and co-authors decided to perform the same behavioral investigations in middle-aged mice. Unexpectedly, middle-aged KO mice behaved differently compared to young adults. In fact, middle-aged spinophilin KO mice were less anxious, whereas the anxiolytic effect of genetic neurabin loss observed in the younger mice was absent in the older individuals. A similar scenario was observed during the characterization of depression-like behavior in middle-aged mice: loss of spinophilin imparted an apparent protective effect in terms of the depression-like behavior of swimming-induced learned helplessness at this age, whereas neurabin-deficient mice looked normal. It is worth mentioning that while neurabin KO mice display deficient long-term potentiation (LTP) but normal long-term depression (LTD), spinophilin KO mice show impaired LTD but normal LTP (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16600521&quot;&gt;Allen et al., 2006&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Our data&lt;/em&gt;”, conclude the authors, “&lt;em&gt;indicate that these two homologous proteins play important, yet distinct, roles in the regulation of anxiety- and depression-like behaviors, as well overall activity level, in an age-dependent manner. Our study therefore provides new insights into the complex neurobiology of affective disorders.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genetics and caveats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this study may help to dissect the molecular and functional mechanisms underlying affective disorders, several caveats arise from the genetic strategy used in the study. In particular, complete deletion of a gene (neurabin, spinophilin, or other) may trigger maladaptive and compensatory modifications which may lead to erroneous interpretations. In addition, developmental arrangements may occur, thus leading to abnormal phenotypes. Indeed, strategies using conditional, tissue- and cell type-specific engineered mice must be encouraged in order to clearly establish functional roles of specific molecular actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Peppe-BW&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-17882 alignleft&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2015/10/Peppe-BW-238x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;117&quot; /&gt;Giuseppe Gangarossa &lt;/b&gt;received his PhD in Biomedical Sciences, specialty Neuroscience, from the University of Bologna. He has been a visiting fellow at the Karolinska Institutet (Sotckholm, Sweden), the French Inserm (Montpellier, France) and the Collège de France (Paris, France). Giuseppe is currently Assistant Professor of Physiology at the University Paris Diderot. His main research topic is dopamine-related brain disorders. You can follow him on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peppeganga?lang=en&quot;&gt;@PeppeGanga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/wQlFr0eCo3k&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 20:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro">PLOS Neuroscience Community</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: &quot;Brain Training&quot; Doesn't Work?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8948</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8948</link>
	<description>Lumosity &quot;brain training&quot; games have no beneficial effects on cognition, according to a paper just published in the Journal of Neuroscience.



According to the authors, led by UPenn psychologist Joseph W. Kable, Lumosity &quot;appears to have no benefits in healthy young adults above those of standard video games.&quot;

In the study, 128 young adults were randomly assigned to either 10 weeks of Lumosity training, or a control condition: 10 weeks of playing normal, non-brain-based online videogames</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 19:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: These bacteria may egg on colon cancer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-bacteria-may-egg-colon-cancer</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/these-bacteria-may-egg-colon-cancer</link>
	<description>Streptococcus gallolyticus may goad colon cancer growth.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 18:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071317_TI_bacteria-cancer_main.jpg?itok=GGTRgt-n" length="16653" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Ravens pass tests of planning ahead in unnatural tasks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ravens-pass-tests-planning-ahead-unnatural-tasks</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ravens-pass-tests-planning-ahead-unnatural-tasks</link>
	<description>Clever birds may have evolved their own broad powers of apelike thinking about the future.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 18:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071317_SM_raven_main.jpg?itok=l8xKapIq" length="23919" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Brain activity helps build an alpha male</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-activity-helps-build-alpha-male</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/brain-activity-helps-build-alpha-male</link>
	<description>In mice, nerve cells in the prefrontal cortex influence whether an individual is dominant or submissive.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071317_LH_alpha-mouse_main_FREE_REV.jpg?itok=4Zh5RHqr" length="19196" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Authors say patient threatened legal action after being subject of scholarly paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50989</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/13/authors-say-patient-threatened-legal-action-subject-scholarly-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A patient appears to have had a change of heart about being featured in a case report. The patient cannot be identified in the paper published in Journal of Gastrointestinal and Liver Diseases. However, according to the retraction notice, she threatened to sue if the authors did not withdraw it. After receiving the threat, the […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/13/authors-say-patient-threatened-legal-action-subject-scholarly-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Authors say patient threatened legal action after being subject of scholarly paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Nature Chemistry issues its first retraction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50997</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/13/nature-chemistry-issues-first-retraction/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in its eight-year history, Nature Chemistry has retracted a paper, citing “data integrity issues.” The 2010 paper, which explored how various iron-based molecules interact with water and ethanol, was withdrawn after the authors uncovered possible duplication in two images. According to the retraction notice, the authors could not provide the raw […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/13/nature-chemistry-issues-first-retraction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nature Chemistry issues its first retraction&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: The Correlation between EEG Signals as Measured in Different Positions on Scalp Varying with Distance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2017-07-13:/2017/07/13/the-correlation-between-eeg-signals-as-measured-in-different-positions-on-scalp-varying-with-distance.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2017/07/13/the-correlation-between-eeg-signals-as-measured-in-different-positions-on-scalp-varying-with-distance.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Biomedical signals such as electroencephalogram (EEG) are the time varying signal, and different position of electrodes give different time varying signals. There might be a correlation between these signals. It is likely that the correlation is related to the actual position of electrodes. In this paper, we show that correlation is related to the physical distance between electrodes as measured. This finding is independent of participants and brain hemisphere. Our results indicate that the EEG signal is not transmitted via neurons but through white matter in a brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 14/07/2017 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 11:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Eight important neuropsychological syndromes you’ve probably never heard of</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26652</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/13/eight-important-neuropsychological-syndromes-youve-probably-never-heard-of/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-615292182.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26801&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26801&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Corbis via Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A woodcut illustration from Andreas Vesalius' 1543 treatise on anatomy, De Humani Corporis Fabrica. (Photo by \u00a9 CORBIS\/Corbis via Getty Images)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Woodcut Illustration of the Cerebrum by Andreas Vesalius&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Woodcut Illustration of the Cerebrum by Andreas Vesalius&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-615292182.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-615292182.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-615292182.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1024,743&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/13/eight-important-neuropsychological-syndromes-youve-probably-never-heard-of/woodcut-illustration-of-the-cerebrum-by-andreas-vesalius/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-615292182.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studying people who have brain damage or illness has been hugely important to progress in psychology. The approach is akin to reverse engineering: study how things go wrong when particular regions of the brain are compromised and it provides useful clues as to how those regions usually contribute to healthy mental function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, some neuropsychological conditions, such as Broca’s aphasia (speech deficits), prosopagnosia (a difficulty recognising faces, also known somewhat misleadingly as “face blindness”) and Alien Hand syndrome (a limb seeming to act of its own volition) have become extremely well-known – at least in psychological circles – and extensively studied. However, others are virtually unheard of, even though their importance to our understanding of the brain is significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuropsychologist Alfredo Ardila at Florida International University has just published &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-28540-001/&quot;&gt;in the journal &lt;em&gt;Psychology and Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; an overview of four of these little-known conditions, “so rare that they are not even mentioned in basic neuropsychology textbooks”: Central achromatopsia, Bálint’s syndrome, Pure-word deafness, and aphasia of the supplementary area. This follows &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/acn/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/arclin/acw021&quot;&gt;a paper he published last year&lt;/a&gt; covering four other rare but important neuropsychological syndromes: Somatoparaphrenia, Akinetopsia, Reduplicative Paramnesia, Autotopagnosia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In neuropsychology … there are some unusual syndromes that are found very sporadically,” he writes. “But their rarity does not diminish their importance in the fundamental understanding about the brain organisation of cognition, as well as in clinical analysis of patients with brain pathologies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a brief breakdown of what Ardila has to say about these rare conditions and why they’re important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26652&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Akinetopsia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Imagine if someone pressed pause on your view of the world: that may be what’s it’s like for patients with akinetopsia, who are unable to see movement, even though they can perceive the sound of motion. The syndrome is associated with damage to a specific region of the brain’s visual cortex (area V5) and it can be induced in healthy volunteers by using transcranial magnetic stimulation to induce a “virtual lesion” in that same brain region. Akinetopsia is extremely rare but may be associated with the &lt;em&gt;Zeitraffer&lt;/em&gt; phenomenon, which is when patients perceive the speed of moving objects as noticeably slowed down. “The description of akinetopsia represents a crucial step in the comprehension of how motion perception is organized in the brain,” notes Ardila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aphasia of the Supplementary Motor Area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In this condition, patients have a particular problem speaking spontaneously. They can repeat things back when asked, and name things when prompted, but they don’t seem to be able to initiate speech. The region of the brain that’s affected – the Supplementary Motor Area (SMA) – is involved in preparing and initiating movements, especially sequences of movements, and it’s thought this form of aphasia (arising from damage to the SMA) is due to problems with planning the movements required for spontaneous speech, rather than a language problem per se. Language comprehension is mostly unaffected. “Aphasia of the SMA illustrates the complex overlap between language and motor processes, which has contributed positively to further our understanding about brain representation of linguistic processes,” Ardila said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autotopagnosia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the inability to locate and identify parts of one’s body even though the ability to locate and name the parts of objects, plants or animals is unaffected. The condition can be seen as an impairment in updating the body schema – the brain’s representation of the body and where it is located in space – combined with a naming impairment, suggesting that language deficits are involved. The condition is usually associated with damage to the rear of the parietal cortex (near the crown of the head) in the left hemisphere. “Although autotopagnosia was described over a century ago, research has been limited,” says Ardila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bálint’s syndrome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also first described over a century ago, people with this condition often behave as if they are blind. Associated with damage or pathology to the parietal and occipital lobes, this syndrome is really a complex involving three sub-syndromes: simultanagnosia which is the inability to perceive an entire scene, even while being able to see individual elements within it; optic ataxia, which is a problem reaching to specific objects even though the patient has no muscular or motor problems per se; and gaze apraxia, which describes the way the patient will struggle to move their eyes voluntarily or to keep fixated on an object. Ardila says “this is one of the clinical syndromes which has most contributed to the understanding of visual and spatial perception.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Achromatopsia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the loss of the ability to perceive colours caused entirely by damage to parts of the brain, usually in the occipital or temporal lobe (located near the back and sides of the head), rather than to any problem with the eyes. It can co-occur with other conditions such as prosopagnosia, but importantly the ability to imagine or visualise colours is preserved. “Evidently this syndrome is crucial to understand the brain organisation of visual perception, particularly colour perception,” writes Ardila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pure-word Deafness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Patients with this condition display a profound problem understanding spoken language, even though their ability to read and to speak is completely unaffected. Patients describe speech sounding as if it is a barely audible whisper or as if it is a foreign language. Unlike  other conditions that affect language comprehension, such as Wernicke’s aphasia, pure-word deafness is considered a purely perceptual impairment and consistent with this, it is often associated with lesions to auditory processing regions in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduplicative Paramnesias&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This extraordinary condition leads patients to believe that a particular place, such as their home or even an entire city, has been duplicated and is located in two places at once. Less often, patients may express the same belief about a person, a particular object or a body part. Forms of reduplicative paramnesia have some similarities with other delusional syndromes to do with identity, such as &lt;em&gt;capgras syndrome&lt;/em&gt; in which the patient believes one or more of their relatives or friends have been replaced with imposters; &lt;em&gt;Frégoli syndrome&lt;/em&gt;, the belief that someone, usually a perceived stalker, is repeatedly changing their appearance; and &lt;em&gt;intermetamorphosis – &lt;/em&gt;the belief that someone has transformed into another person. The evidence suggests that reduplicative paramnesias for place are often associated with damage to the right hemisphere of the brain, and are perhaps more likely due to this organic damage, whereas Ardila proposes that the other delusional identity syndromes may more often have a psychological cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Somatoparaphrenia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First described in 1942, patients with this syndrome deny owning one or more of their limbs on the opposite side of their body to where they have damage in their brains. The syndrome tends to co-occur with another syndrome known as anosognosia, which is a denial of an impairment, such as paralysis to a limb. Somatoparaphrenia can also be seen as a more extreme version of &lt;em&gt;hemiasomatognosia&lt;/em&gt;, which is a lack of awareness of one’s own limb(s). Curiously, patients with somatoparaphrenia may recognise an affected limb as theirs when they see it in a mirror. Ardila says the condition, which has been associated with lesions to multiple regions in the brain, is little understood and may partly be a psychiatric condition (a form of delusion) as well as neurological. “In this regard, the analysis of somatoparaphrenia may contribute to further our understanding about the neurological bases of psychosis,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/acn/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/arclin/acw021&quot;&gt;Some Unusual Neuropsychological Syndromes: Somatoparaphrenia, Akinetopsia, Reduplicative Paramnesia, Autotopagnosia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/psycinfo/2017-28540-001/&quot;&gt;Some Rare Neuropsychological Syndromes: Central Achromatopsia, Bálint’s Syndrome, Pure Word-Deafness, Supplementary Motor Area Aphasia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image: A woodcut illustration from Andreas Vesalius’ 1543 treatise on anatomy, De Humani Corporis Fabrica. (Photo by © CORBIS/Corbis via Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26652/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26652/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26652&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 11:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Google no more: How radiologists are shifting to specialized databases</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/google-no-more-how-radiologists-are-shifting-to-specialized-databases</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/google-no-more-how-radiologists-are-shifting-to-specialized-databases</link>
	<description>Radiologists at a leading hospital in Taiwan are discovering the benefits of tools personalized to their profession</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 10:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Rising temps may mean fewer passengers on airplane flights</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rising-temps-may-mean-fewer-passengers-airplane-flights</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/rising-temps-may-mean-fewer-passengers-airplane-flights</link>
	<description>Global warming could force airplanes to carry a lighter load — and fewer passengers —on each flight.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_MT_airplane_main_FREE.jpg?itok=MsefCxZf" length="16177" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 reasons CHORUS is gaining traction</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-reasons-chorus-is-gaining-traction</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-reasons-chorus-is-gaining-traction</link>
	<description>Elsevier has made over 3,000 manuscripts available to US partner funding agencies through the CHORUS public access service</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 09:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: CRISPR adds storing movies to its feats of molecular biology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/crispr-adds-storing-movies-its-feats-molecular-biology</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/crispr-adds-storing-movies-its-feats-molecular-biology</link>
	<description>Video and images could be stored in living bacteria with a little help from the iconic gene editor, CRISPR.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 23:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/0711217_ht_crisprvideo_free.jpg?itok=du5NneYi" length="35596" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Nature retracts paper by stem cell scientist appealing her dismissal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=51000</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/nature-retracts-paper-stem-cell-scientist-appealing-dismissal/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A once-rising star in stem cell biology — who recently lost both her job and a sizable grant — has had a fourth paper retracted. The notice — issued by Nature for a 2006 letter — cites duplicated images, and a lack of raw data to verify the findings. First author Susana Gonzalez — who […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/nature-retracts-paper-stem-cell-scientist-appealing-dismissal/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Nature retracts paper by stem cell scientist appealing her dismissal&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here are Juno’s first close-ups of Jupiter’s Great Red Spot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-first-pictures-jupiter-great-red-spot</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/juno-first-pictures-jupiter-great-red-spot</link>
	<description>The Juno spacecraft swooped just 9,000 kilometers above Jupiter’s Great Red Spot on July 10. Here are the first pictures.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 17:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_JupiterRedSpot-raw_composite_free.jpg?itok=_qtQItFt" length="16185" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Delaware-sized iceberg breaks off Antarctic ice shelf</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/delaware-sized-iceberg-breaks-antarctic-ice-shelf</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/delaware-sized-iceberg-breaks-antarctic-ice-shelf</link>
	<description>An iceberg about the size of Delaware splintered from the Larsen C ice shelf in one of the largest calving events ever recorded.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071217_AY_larsen-c-_main.jpg?itok=d2p06B_7" length="14975" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Are Sleep Apps Effective Tools For Behavioral Change?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22659</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/12/are-sleep-apps-effective-tools-for-behavioral-change/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Smartphones are technological Swiss Army knives – easy to carry and, thanks to apps, able to do almost anything. All you need is a smartphone and an internet connection to unfold a thousand tools. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps make communication, traveling, working, and entertainment easier. And they can also allow us to monitor and manage our health, fitness and lifestyle, or even improve them. There are thousands of health and lifestyle apps – for exercise, for nutrition, for weight loss, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/08/07/top-meditation-apps/&quot;&gt;meditation&lt;/a&gt;, for overall health, for sleep… Their use is on the rise and they have shown great potential in effectively promoting self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology may actually revolutionize how we take care of ourselves. It can successfully influence behavior and this is empowering in the sense that it offers an opportunity to self-manage our health routines. Apps can be a great aid for lifestyle interventions – they allow us to monitor our behavior and our progress, they can motivate us, give positive reinforcement, and set goals for continued enhancement. A well-designed app, built on scientific background may offer valuable help to behavioral health and lifestyle interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But among the sea of apps, one wonders how many are really effective and how many present evidence-based content and behavioral theory-based interventions. Although it is not clear whether evidence- and theory-based interventions are indispensable for the efficacy of an app, they are known to be effective in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/03/22/changing-the-error-of-our-ways/&quot;&gt;changing behavior&lt;/a&gt;, being, most likely, a predictor of efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional theory-based behavioral modification strategies state that behavioral change can be most successfully achieved when multiple strategic approaches and behavioral constructs are combined; these include informational strategies (creating knowledge); cognitive strategies, such as perceived benefits, barriers and risks; behavioral strategies, such as self-monitoring, realistic goal-setting, self-reward, relapse prevention; emotion-focused strategies, such as stress and negative affect management; and therapeutic interventions such as skill-building, for example. Apps that include such features have been proven more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, app developers are naturally focused on keeping users engaged. Therefore, many app features may tend to favor usability. Also, it is likely that app development may be preferentially aligned with more contemporary &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/10/01/sleep-deprivation-behavior-and-the-young/&quot;&gt;behavioral models&lt;/a&gt;. These postulate that technology can be designed to change user attitudes and behaviors through persuasion and social influence (Persuasive Technology Theory), and that when technology increases motivation and capacity to change, triggers to change behavior are more likely to work (Fogg Behavioral Model).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a reliance on either traditional or contemporary behavioral models does not seem to be the case for most health, fitness and lifestyle apps: a 2011 review revealed that most had insufficient evidence-based content; a 2012 analysis showed a general lack of theory-based strategies; a 2013 study of exercise apps found that, overall, the apps contained few features based on behavioral change theory; another 2013 study reached the same conclusion for weight management apps; a 2015 study reported similar findings for alcohol reduction apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/15/why-do-we-need-to-sleep/&quot;&gt;sleep&lt;/a&gt; apps? They are one of the most popular type of lifestyle and health apps, which comes as no surprise – sleep disorders affect millions of people and this creates a huge demand for interventional strategies. But sleep apps are particular in the sense that interventional constructs need to go way beyond motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a new study aimed at determining whether sleep apps follow evidenced-based guidelines or are grounded in behavioral change or persuasive technology theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study included the most downloaded and reviewed sleep apps for both iOS and Android. From the 369 apps found using the term “sleep” (in September 2015), 35 apps met the authors’ inclusion criteria. They scored them based on the presence of behavioral and persuasive technology constructs and correlated these scores with the average user rating for each app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average behavioral construct score was 34%, whereas the average persuasive technology score was 42%, which is not impressive. Realistic goal setting (86%), &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/10/04/ill-do-it-later-brain-connectivity-predicts-procrastination/&quot;&gt;time management&lt;/a&gt; (77%), and self-monitoring (66%) were the behavioral constructs most commonly included in sleep apps; factors that contributed most to the apps’ persuasiveness were the user interface (94%), provision of positive feedback (54%), and social praise (40%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the authors found a positive association between the presence of behavioral constructs and the apps’ popularity and ratings, showing that a good scientific design is an indication of probable success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also indicates that, since there is still a relatively poor inclusion of theory-based constructs, there is room to grow. Building strong evidence-based apps is likely to result in a real opportunity for effective behavioral intervention and be beneficial to the management of sleep disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(An important side note: one obvious limitation of using &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/02/22/what-do-smartphones-do-to-the-brain/&quot;&gt;smartphone&lt;/a&gt; apps for sleep management is the well-known negative impact of LED devices on the circadian rhythm and, consequently, on sleep. Something that should be kept in mind while designing a sleep app is the possibility on minimizing one’s interaction with our phone before bedtime.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azar KM, et al (2013). Mobile applications for weight management: theory-based content analysis. Am J Prev Med, 45(5):583-9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ajpmonline.org/article/S0749-3797(13)00431-5/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.amepre.2013.07.005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breton E, et al (2011). Weight loss—there is an app for that! But does it adhere to evidence-informed practices? Transl Behav Med, 1(4):523–9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs13142-011-0076-5&quot;&gt;10.1007/s13142-011-0076-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cowan LT, et al (2013). Apps of steel: are exercise apps providing consumers with realistic expectations?: a content analysis of exercise apps for presence of behavior change theory. Health Educ Behav, 40(2):133–9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1090198112452126&quot;&gt;10.1177/1090198112452126&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crane D, et al (2015). Behavior change techniques in popular alcohol reduction apps: content analysis. J Med Internet Res, 17(5):e118. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jmir.org/2015/5/e118/&quot;&gt;10.2196/jmir.4060&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fogg BJ (2003). Persuasive technology: using computers to change what we think and do (interactive technologies). Morgan Kaufmann, San Francisco. ISBN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/book/9781558606432&quot;&gt;978-1-55860-643-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glanz K, et al (2008). Theory, research, and practice in health behavior and health education. In Glanz K, Rimer B &amp;amp; Viswanath K, Health behavior and health education: Theory, research, and practice (4th ed., pp. 23-40). San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass. ISBN: &lt;a href=&quot;http://eu.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-0470396296,subjectCd-PS72.html&quot;&gt;978-0-470-39629-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grigsby-Toussainta DS, et al (2017). Sleep apps and behavioral constructs: A content analysis. Prev Med Rep, 6: 126–129. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211335517300360&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.pmedr.2017.02.018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higgins JP (2016). Smartphone Applications for Patients’ Health and Fitness. Am J Med, 129(1):11-9. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amjmed.com/article/S0002-9343(15)00537-9/fulltext&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.amjmed.2015.05.038&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/1haboeri-1922784/&quot;&gt;1haboeri&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: “We were devastated:” Authors retract paper after realizing they had used the wrong mice</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50981</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/devastated-authors-retract-paper-realizing-used-wrong-mice/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Longtime readers of Retraction Watch may recall a 2011 post about a research team that retracted a paper after realizing that they had ordered the wrong mice. Maureen Gannon and Raymond Pasek of Vanderbilt University contacted us earlier this week to alert us to a similar case: Their retraction, earlier this month, of a 2016 paper […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/devastated-authors-retract-paper-realizing-used-wrong-mice/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;“We were devastated:” Authors retract paper after realizing they had used the wrong mice&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 15:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Oscillatory Thoughts: New Voytek Lab paper by Richard Gao!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-5648062351012720545.post-8896253189315086132</guid>
	<link>http://blog.ketyov.com/2015/08/new-voytek-lab-paper-by-richard-gao.html</link>
	<description>&lt;span&gt;Voytek Lab Cognitive Science PhD student, Richard Gao, wrote a detailed piece about his new &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;paper, &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Interpreting the Electrophysiological Power Spectrum,” published in the peer-reviewed, student-focused “NeuroForum” mini-review section for the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Neurophysiology&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: Calibri; font-size: 13.1999998092651px; line-height: 14.7839994430542px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://voyteklab.com/interpreting-the-electrophysiological-power-spectrum/&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white; color: #a19c7c; font-family: Calibri; font-size: 13.1999998092651px; line-height: 14.7839994430542px; text-decoration: none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;float: left; padding: 5px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;ResearchBlogging.org&quot; src=&quot;http://www.researchblogging.org/public/citation_icons/rb2_large_gray.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Z3988&quot; title=&quot;ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;amp;rft.jtitle=Journal+of+Neurophysiology&amp;amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1152%2Fjn.00722.2015&amp;amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;amp;rft.atitle=Interpreting+the+Electrophysiological+Power+Spectrum&amp;amp;rft.issn=0022-3077&amp;amp;rft.date=2015&amp;amp;rft.volume=&amp;amp;rft.issue=&amp;amp;rft.spage=0&amp;amp;rft.epage=&amp;amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fjn.physiology.org%2Flookup%2Fdoi%2F10.1152%2Fjn.00722.2015&amp;amp;rft.au=Gao%2C+R.&amp;amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Neuroscience&quot;&gt;Gao, R. (2015). Interpreting the Electrophysiological Power Spectrum &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Journal of Neurophysiology&lt;/span&gt; DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1152/jn.00722.2015&quot; rev=&quot;review&quot;&gt;10.1152/jn.00722.2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 14:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Bradley Voytek)</author>
  <source url="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/5648062351012720545/posts/default">Oscillatory Thoughts</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Ankur Sinha: Bringing together Gitter, IRC, and Slack channels in one place on Riot</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:ankursinha.in,2017-07-12:/blog/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</guid>
	<link>http://ankursinha.in/blog/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;let-s-not-let-our-choice-of-platform-limit-us&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's not let our choice of platform limit us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are usually multiple platforms that provide similar functions. For instance, one can pick between &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitlab.com&quot;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://bitbucket.com&quot;&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt; for collaborative development interfaces, and one certainly should have the freedom to do so. Similarly, one can use different operating systems, web browsers, phones, etc etc etc. But, one must remember is that for a lot of us, these are simply means to an end - not the end themselves. They are tools that facilitate the completion of our goals. Different individuals or teams preferring different platforms should not hamper collaboration under any circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to communcation, different teams use different platforms. Some prefer e-mails - either private or using a mailing list. E-mails work well, but they're often overkill for simpler tasks. They're also not the best mode for quick collaborative development. This is where real-time chat comes in. Most open source communities maintain both mailing lists and chat infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to chat platforms too, there are multiple options. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; are designed to handle large communities and are therefore, usually preferred by open source communities. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; seems to be preferred by smaller teams. There are others - &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://mattermost.com&quot;&gt;Mattermost&lt;/a&gt;, for example, but I haven't much experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I've found people wary of hopping on to a different platform simply because it's too much work to set up yet another client that one must then also monitor. While this is understandable, it then has what I consider quite a major downside - limited communication amongst groups that are on different platforms. Fortunately, most platforms support bridges which lets the user connect them with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;riot-bringing-it-all-together-in-once-place&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riot - bringing it all together in once place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Using riot to access IRC, Slack, and Gitter&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; is an Open source platform that uses the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://matrix.org/&quot;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; protocol. It's similar to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, but it's a lot more usable. and what is better, one can integrate &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im&quot;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - so one can interact with users over all these platforms in one place. For example, the image below shows &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im/app/#/room/%23neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org&quot;&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; room  that I've set up on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. But, I've also gone ahead and connected this room to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby&quot;&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby room on Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby&quot;&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby channel on IRC&lt;/a&gt;. So, everyone on any of these platforms can communicate with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Neuroscience-Central/Lobby on Riot integrated with the same room on Gitter.&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the integrations is rather easy too. One needs to go to the integrations tab and set them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Integrations on Riot&quot; class=&quot;text-center img-responsive pagination-centered&quot; src=&quot;http://ankursinha.in/blog/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im/desktop.html&quot;&gt;desktop clients&lt;/a&gt; available for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; too. (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/taw/Riot/&quot;&gt;Here's a COPR for Fedora&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/17/5/introducing-riot-IRC&quot;&gt;Here's a great post on opensource.com&lt;/a&gt; discussing &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you're an admin looking to set up a new chat channel - consider setting up on different platforms and integrating them with &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://riot.im&quot;&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - it'll make things a lot easier for your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 12:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://ankursinha.in/blog/feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml">ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Author “shocked” after top math journal retracts paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50973</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/author-shocked-top-math-journal-retracts-paper/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most prestigious mathematics journals has issued what appears to be its first retraction. The Annals of Mathematics recently withdrew a 2001 paper exploring the properties of certain symmetrical spaces. What prompted this retraction? And why did it occur 16 years after the paper was published? The retraction notice for “Invariant differential […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/12/author-shocked-top-math-journal-retracts-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Author “shocked” after top math journal retracts paper&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Teeny-weeny star vies for title of smallest known</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/teeny-weeny-star-vies-title-smallest-known</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/teeny-weeny-star-vies-title-smallest-known</link>
	<description>A Saturn-sized star is one of the smallest yet discovered.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071217_EC_star-ticker_main.jpg?itok=ybKnq8Bw" length="17818" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Romain Brette: What is computational neuroscience? (XXVII) The paradox of the efficient code and the neural Tower of Babel</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://romainbrette.fr/?p=1427</guid>
	<link>http://romainbrette.fr/what-is-computational-neuroscience-xxvii-the-paradox-of-the-efficient-code-and-the-neural-tower-of-babel/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A pervasive metaphor in neuroscience is the idea that neurons “encode” stuff: some neurons encode pain; others encode the location of a sound; maybe a population of neurons encode some other property of objects. What does this mean? In essence, that there is a correspondence between some objective property and neural activity: when I feel pain, this neuron spikes; or, the image I see is “represented” in the firing of visual cortical neurons. The mapping between the objective properties and neural activity is the “code”. How insightful is this metaphor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An encoded message is understandable to the extent that the reader knows the code. But the problem with applying this metaphor to the brain is only the encoded message is communicated, not the code, and not the original message. Mathematically, original message = encoded message + code, but only one term is communicated. This could still work if there were a universal code that we could assume all neurons can read, the “language of neurons”, or if somehow some information about the code could be gathered from the encoded messages themselves. Unfortunately, this is in contradiction with the main paradigm in neural coding theory, “efficient coding”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient coding hypothesis stipulates that neurons encode signals into spike trains in an efficient way, that is, it uses a code such that all redundancy is removed from the original message while preserving information, in the sense that the encoded message can be mapped back to the original message (Barlow, 1961; Simoncelli, 2003). This implies that with a perfectly efficient code, encoded messages are undistinguishable from random. Since the code is determined on the statistics of the inputs and only the encoded messages are communicated, a code is efficient to the extent that it is not understandable by the receiver. This is the paradox of the efficient code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the neural coding metaphor, the code is private and specific to each neuron. If we follow this metaphor, this means that all neurons speak a different language, a language that allows expressing concepts very concisely but that no one else can understand. Thus, according to the coding metaphor, the brain is a Tower of Babel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can this work?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://romainbrette.fr/feed/">Romain Brette</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Non-White or female bosses who push diversity are judged negatively by their peers and managers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26633</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/12/non-white-or-female-bosses-who-push-diversity-are-judged-negatively-by-their-peers-and-managers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&quot; class=&quot; size-medium wp-image-26648 alignleft&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26648&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Detailed illustration of diverse business people in different positions in flat style on white background.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Business team and teamwork concept. Set of detailed illustration of businesswomen standing in different positions in flat style on white background. Diverse nationalities and dress styles. Vector illustration&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=263&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;1851,1620&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/12/non-white-or-female-bosses-who-push-diversity-are-judged-negatively-by-their-peers-and-managers/business-team-and-teamwork-concept-set-of-detailed-illustration-of-businesswomen-standing-in-different-positions-in-flat-style-on-white-background-diverse-nationalities-and-dress-styles-vector-illu/&quot; height=&quot;263&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-692614204.jpg?w=300&amp;amp;h=263&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first cohort of women leaders began pushing up against the glass ceiling, many hoped it would shatter… but it only cracked. Today fewer than 10 per cent of Fortune 500 companies are led by people from ethnic minority groups and women combined, and although the reasons are manifold, blame has been laid at the feet of the early pioneers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accusation is that successful people from underrepresented groups act as gatekeepers, keeping out others to maintain their special status and to identify with the dominant majority (the most famous example being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2010/11/11/queen-bees-are-the-consequence-not-the-cause-of-sexist-work-places/&quot;&gt;Queen Bee syndrome&lt;/a&gt; where a female boss undermines other women). But &lt;a href=&quot;http://amj.aom.org/content/60/2/771.abstract?etoc&quot;&gt;new research&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;i&gt;Academy of Management Journal&lt;/i&gt; suggests a different and very understandable reason that minority members are cautious to show enthusiasm for increasing diversity – because they know it could spell disaster for their own career if they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26633&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international team headed by David Hekman of the University of Colorado recruited 350 American executives from a range of organisations: one in ten of them were non-White and about 30 per cent were women. The executives’ bosses and roughly three of their peers rated them in terms of their competence and performance, including readiness to be promoted, and their diversity-valuing behaviour, an example being “values working with a diverse group of people”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last measure of “promoting diversity” is considered important in most major organisations, as it can provide better coverage of customer needs and can facilitate different ways of thinking. Overall, the findings from the current study were consistent with this: participants who were rated higher for diversity-valuing behaviour were also rated higher for performance and competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was an important exception. For female and non-White executives, the more they valued diversity, the worse they were rated for performance and competence. And the non-White leaders who received very high performance ratings (higher even than the White majority) showed the least interest in diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors argue that this points to an attitudinal bias, whereby most senior staff generally see diversity-promoting behaviour as benign or even worthwhile… except when it comes from minorities, in which case, it triggers concerns of nepotism or of opposition to the interests of the majority and a desire to undermine the status quo. In turn, these concerns may reinforce the minority status of the individual, making stereotypic negative judgments more salient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test this explanation, Hekman’s team conducted an experiment: 300 participants recruited from an online database were asked to review a hiring manager’s decision to take on a new Vice President for their organisation, and rate that manager’s competence accordingly. Participants saw photos of the new VP and the hiring manager and they read a transcript of the conversation about the hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a female or non-White hiring manager took on a female or minority VP and mentioned improving diversity as a motive, the participants gave them poor ratings, a cost that was not incurred by White male hiring managers making the same decision. This seems to back up the researchers’ theory that minority managers are perceived negatively when they actively promote diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, there are selfish incentives for successful members of minority groups to identify with the higher-status in-group, to be included and welcomed and feel like a member of the elite in good standing. This research suggests that there may also be valid reasons for minority leaders to fear making a show of helping other minority individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hekman’s team discuss a few possible ways to tackle this, and suggest an intriguing approach: to reward any organisational member that hires someone demographically different from them. This rule would apply to everyone, with a sound logic – what might you learn from a second-in-command with a different background to you? – and in practice, its application would increase minority numbers by virtue of the sheer numbers of majority group members seeking out someone different. Whatever the exact approach, one takeaway from this is that it is going to be harder for minorities to promote diversity in organisations, because their motives are going to be taken as suspect. So White men who care about diversity should step up and make the case for it. They are relatively insulated, whereas for others, the case may be simply too costly to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://amj.aom.org/content/60/2/771.abstract?etoc&quot;&gt;Does Diversity-Valuing Behavior Result in Diminished Performance Ratings for Non-White and Female Leaders?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26633/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26633/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26633&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 09:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Transparency — the key to trust in peer review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transparency-the-key-to-trust-in-peer-review</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/transparency-the-key-to-trust-in-peer-review</link>
	<description>What authors and reviewers want, according to research (and how we’re making it happen)</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 08:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: PLOS Supports Net Neutrality to Ensure Global Access to the Scientific Literature</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=7653</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/KCjLjKQr-s0/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/net-neutrality-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;PLOS works to remove barriers to public access of scientific research. Typically, these barriers are considered in terms of copyrights and journal subscriptions, but unfettered access to network infrastructure also contributes to supporting readers’ access to scientific literature. In simple terms, unencumbered dissemination of scientific research depends on a fair Internet. The provision of a fair and open Internet lies in the hands of Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and government agencies that regulate these providers. PLOS supported the July 12, 2017 Day of Action in the United States, led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Battle for the Net&lt;/a&gt;, aimed at publicizing the issues surrounding Open Internet Rules and their critical role in maintaining Internet freedoms as currently in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2015, the US Federal Communication Commission (FCC) reclassified broadband providers as common carriers rather than information providers under Title II of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_Act_of_1934&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Communications Act of 1934&lt;/a&gt;, the law that continues to regulate modern communication modes such as the Internet. This gave the FCC authority to ensure that established, large corporations including AT&amp;amp;T, Comcast and Verizon can’t block, slow (throttle) or otherwise interfere with Internet traffic. Innovations in online businesses and services, including those of PLOS, have thrived under Title II regulations. Importantly, these regulations in the US provide each and every user of the Internet a guarantee that ISPs and government regulators treat all data on the Internet the same, without discriminating against or charging differentially by user, content, website, platform, application, type of equipment or mode of communication (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_neutrality&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;These protections are known as net neutrality; scientists and those working to support the scientific endeavor rely on net neutrality for unprejudiced access to databases, the literature and information services.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Allowing ISPs to sort traffic based on content, sender and receiver opens the door for corporate and government censorship which would greatly hinder access to scientific information around the globe.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect against this type of restriction in information flow, the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/policies/open-internet-net-neutrality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EU-wide Net Neutrality rules&lt;/a&gt; were adopted in October 2015 with public guidelines released by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://berec.europa.eu/eng/netneutrality/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Body of European Regulators for Electronic Communications&lt;/a&gt; in late 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the US, the current FCC Commissioner wants to weaken these protections and this could have consequences for all scientists, not just those in the US: a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ccess to information around the world could become pay to play without these protections. &lt;/strong&gt;Services provided by publishers such as PLOS and other providers could be restricted for all our users around the world, unless we pay for priority access to our content. This will affect any Internet traffic that routes through the US, from services relying on servers located in the US to requests that are routed through the US. For instance, most of the Domain Name Server (DNS) requests for South America, Central America and the Carribbean are routed by servers located in Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-7655&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2017/07/NetNeutPopUp-234x300.jpg&quot; width=&quot;234&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 12, 2017, was a Day of Action in support of a fair and open Internet. Visitors to the PLOS.org homepage (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plos.org/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.plos.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and active PLOS staff blogs (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Official PLOS Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/everyone/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;EveryONE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/biologue/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Biologue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Speaking of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/collections/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Channels and Collections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/tech/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plospodcasts/?utm_source=plos&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=plos-1707-netneut&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PLOS Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) saw a message of explanation and letter of support for net neutrality in the form of a pop up window. This message appeared only on July 12, once per site, per device. Visitors to these web pages could choose to either immediately close the pop up by clicking on the x in the upper right or fill in the four boxes to send a message to the FCC in support of its current Open Internet Rules and the efforts to dissuade FCC Chairman Ajit Varadaraj Pai from his plan to roll back these rules. Public comment continues for an additional 60 days following the Day of Action. Form letters or personalized comments may be sent directly from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.battleforthenet.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS purposefully did not place this notice on any journal content or information pages, so that access to our content was not impeded in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about net neutrality around the globe, visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisisnetneutrality.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.thisisnetneutrality.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;; to learn more about the Day of Action visit &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.battleforthenet.com/july12/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was edited slightly on July 13, 2017 to indicate past tense for the Day of Action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/KCjLjKQr-s0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 05:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: US lawmakers seek $1.1-billion boost for the NIH</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22307</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/wk3zxLsNW8U/nature.2017.22307</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Legislation introduced in the House of Representatives also rejects a White House plan to cut 'indirect cost' payments to research institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 268 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22307&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22307&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/wk3zxLsNW8U&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Engineered cell therapy for cancer gets thumbs up from FDA advisers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22304</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/NwhSvawuDxM/nature.2017.22304</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Treatment shows promise in young people with leukaemia, but safety risks abound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 270 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22304&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22304&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/NwhSvawuDxM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Ant colonies flow like fluid to build tall towers</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22290</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/KHrGNwM_L88/nature.2017.22290</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Insects' structural secrets offer model for designing swarm robots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22290&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22290&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/KHrGNwM_L88&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Lights, camera, CRISPR: Biologists use gene editing to store movies in DNA</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22288</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/MKh7wou4GIM/nature.2017.22288</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Technique demonstrated in  E. coli  suggests ways to record key events in a cell's life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature News   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/nature.2017.22288&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature.2017.22288&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/MKh7wou4GIM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Stop Alzheimer’s before it starts</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547153a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/X1XJeuppvRw/547153a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The hunt for treatments to halt Alzheimer’s disease has been frustrating; it is time to trial preventive drugs, urge Eric McDade and Randall J. Bateman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 153 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547153a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547153a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/X1XJeuppvRw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: How poverty affects the brain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547150a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/i2hurX6ov6Y/547150a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An unprecedented study in Bangladesh could reveal how malnutrition, poor sanitation and other challenges make their mark on child development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 150 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547150a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547150a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/i2hurX6ov6Y&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Tricks to mute quantum noise aid hunt for gravitational waves</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547148a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/Y4nOuz0W0D8/547148a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Physicists find ways to make LIGO and other gravitational-wave detectors even more sensitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 148 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547148a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547148a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/Y4nOuz0W0D8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Panda diplomats, smuggled relics and a nuclear-weapons treaty</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547142a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/uU9NWGxvRRY/547142a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The week in science: 7–13 July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547142a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547142a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/uU9NWGxvRRY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: New US public-health chief is a champion for women and children</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547137b</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/1b7HnJIUG5E/547137b</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In sharp contrast to President Trump, Brenda Fitzgerald has put maternal and child health at the heart of her policies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 137 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/doifinder/10.1038/547137b&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547137b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/1b7HnJIUG5E&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Allelic reprogramming of 3D chromatin architecture during early mammalian development</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23263</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/7d_yqwTlECQ/nature23263</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 In mammals, chromatin organization undergoes drastic reprogramming after fertilization. However, the three-dimensional structure of chromatin and its reprogramming in preimplantation development remain poorly understood. Here, by developing a low-input Hi-C (genome-wide chromosome conformation capture) approach, we examined the reprogramming of chromatin organization during early development in mice. We found that oocytes in metaphase II show homogeneous chromatin folding that lacks detectable topologically associating domains (TADs) and chromatin compartments. Strikingly, chromatin shows greatly diminished higher-order structure after fertilization. Unexpectedly, the subsequent establishment of chromatin organization is a prolonged process that extends through preimplantation development, as characterized by slow consolidation of TADs and segregation of chromatin compartments. The two sets of parental chromosomes are spatially separated from each other and display distinct compartmentalization in zygotes. Such allele separation and allelic compartmentalization can be found as late as the 8-cell stage. Finally, we show that chromatin compaction in preimplantation embryos can partially proceed in the absence of zygotic transcription and is a multi-level hierarchical process. Taken together, our data suggest that chromatin may exist in a markedly relaxed state after fertilization, followed by progressive maturation of higher-order chromatin architecture during early development. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 232 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23263&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23263&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/7d_yqwTlECQ&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Neurobiology: Synapses get together for vision</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23098</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/NhZRiAqMcuI/nature23098</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A sophisticated analysis in mice of how inputs to neurons from other neurons are distributed across individual cells of the brain's visual cortex provides information about how mammalian vision is processed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23098&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23098&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/NhZRiAqMcuI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Immunology: Nervous crosstalk to make antibodies</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23097</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/zWg3bk3WILI/nature23097</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Immune cells called T cells help immune-system B cells mature to produce antibodies. This entails signalling between cells using the molecule dopamine — a surprising immunological role for this neurotransmitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23097&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23097&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/zWg3bk3WILI&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Biomechanics: How fish feel the flow</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23096</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/tjJqWZAx_hw/nature23096</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hair-like sensors are suspected to aid fish navigation in complex environments. Laboratory experiments and computational simulations reveal how these sensors can detect water flow to direct the swimming responses of fish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23096&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23096&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/tjJqWZAx_hw&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Synaptic organization of visual space in primary visual cortex</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23019</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/WAADPwSSZ00/nature23019</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 How a sensory stimulus is processed and perceived depends on the surrounding sensory scene. In the visual cortex, contextual signals can be conveyed by an extensive network of intra- and inter-areal excitatory connections that link neurons representing stimulus features separated in visual space. However, the connectional logic of visual contextual inputs remains unknown; it is not clear what information individual neurons receive from different parts of the visual field, nor how this input relates to the visual features that a neuron encodes, defined by its spatial receptive field. Here we determine the organization of excitatory synaptic inputs responding to different locations in the visual scene by mapping spatial receptive fields in dendritic spines of mouse visual cortex neurons using two-photon calcium imaging. We find that neurons receive functionally diverse inputs from extended regions of visual space. Inputs representing similar visual features from the same location in visual space are more likely to cluster on neighbouring spines. Inputs from visual field regions beyond the receptive field of the postsynaptic neuron often synapse on higher-order dendritic branches. These putative long-range inputs are more frequent and more likely to share the preference for oriented edges with the postsynaptic neuron when the receptive field of the input is spatially displaced along the axis of the receptive field orientation of the postsynaptic neuron. Therefore, the connectivity between neurons with displaced receptive fields obeys a specific rule, whereby they connect preferentially when their receptive fields are co-oriented and co-axially aligned. This organization of synaptic connectivity is ideally suited for the amplification of elongated edges, which are enriched in the visual environment, and thus provides a potential substrate for contour integration and object grouping. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23019&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/WAADPwSSZ00&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: CRISPR–Cas encoding of a digital movie into the genomes of a population of living bacteria</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23017</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/G7EJ3oRpoyM/nature23017</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 DNA is an excellent medium for archiving data. Recent efforts have illustrated the potential for information storage in DNA using synthesized oligonucleotides assembled in vitro. A relatively unexplored avenue of information storage in DNA is the ability to write information into the genome of a living cell by the addition of nucleotides over time. Using the Cas1–Cas2 integrase, the CRISPR–Cas microbial immune system stores the nucleotide content of invading viruses to confer adaptive immunity. When harnessed, this system has the potential to write arbitrary information into the genome. Here we use the CRISPR–Cas system to encode the pixel values of black and white images and a short movie into the genomes of a population of living bacteria. In doing so, we push the technical limits of this information storage system and optimize strategies to minimize those limitations. We also uncover underlying principles of the CRISPR–Cas adaptation system, including sequence determinants of spacer acquisition that are relevant for understanding both the basic biology of bacterial adaptation and its technological applications. This work demonstrates that this system can capture and stably store practical amounts of real data within the genomes of populations of living cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23017&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/G7EJ3oRpoyM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Cholangiocytes act as facultative liver stem cells during impaired hepatocyte regeneration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23015</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/T2gzkgrg6ZU/nature23015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 After liver injury, regeneration occurs through self-replication of hepatocytes. In severe liver injury, hepatocyte proliferation is impaired—a feature of human chronic liver disease. It is unclear whether other liver cell types can regenerate hepatocytes. Here we use two independent systems to impair hepatocyte proliferation during liver injury to evaluate the contribution of non-hepatocytes to parenchymal regeneration. First, loss of β1-integrin in hepatocytes with liver injury triggered a ductular reaction of cholangiocyte origin, with approximately 25% of hepatocytes being derived from a non-hepatocyte origin. Second, cholangiocytes were lineage traced with concurrent inhibition of hepatocyte proliferation by β1-integrin knockdown or p21 overexpression, resulting in the significant emergence of cholangiocyte-derived hepatocytes. We describe a model of combined liver injury and inhibition of hepatocyte proliferation that causes physiologically significant levels of regeneration of functional hepatocytes from biliary cells. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23015&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/T2gzkgrg6ZU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: A novel mechanism for mechanosensory-based rheotaxis in larval zebrafish</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23014</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/-16dHu_-2oc/nature23014</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 When flying or swimming, animals must adjust their own movement to compensate for displacements induced by the flow of the surrounding air or water. These flow-induced displacements can most easily be detected as visual whole-field motion with respect to the animal’s frame of reference. Despite this, many aquatic animals consistently orient and swim against oncoming flows (a behaviour known as rheotaxis) even in the absence of visual cues. How animals achieve this task, and its underlying sensory basis, is still unknown. Here we show that, in the absence of visual information, larval zebrafish (Danio rerio) perform rheotaxis by using flow velocity gradients as navigational cues. We present behavioural data that support a novel algorithm based on such local velocity gradients that fish use to avoid getting dragged by flowing water. Specifically, we show that fish use their mechanosensory lateral line to first sense the curl (or vorticity) of the local velocity vector field to detect the presence of flow and, second, to measure its temporal change after swim bouts to deduce flow direction. These results reveal an elegant navigational strategy based on the sensing of flow velocity gradients and provide a comprehensive behavioural algorithm, also applicable for robotic design, that generalizes to a wide range of animal behaviours in moving fluids. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23014&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/-16dHu_-2oc&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: TFH-derived dopamine accelerates productive synapses in germinal centres</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23013</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/wUJN7VonS48/nature23013</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Protective high-affinity antibody responses depend on competitive selection of B cells carrying somatically mutated B-cell receptors by follicular helper T (TFH) cells in germinal centres. The rapid T–B-cell interactions that occur during this process are reminiscent of neural synaptic transmission pathways. Here we show that a proportion of human TFH cells contain dense-core granules marked by chromogranin B, which are normally found in neuronal presynaptic terminals storing catecholamines such as dopamine. TFH cells produce high amounts of dopamine and release it upon cognate interaction with B cells. Dopamine causes rapid translocation of intracellular ICOSL (inducible T-cell co-stimulator ligand, also known as ICOSLG) to the B-cell surface, which enhances accumulation of CD40L and chromogranin B granules at the human TFH cell synapse and increases the synapse area. Mathematical modelling suggests that faster dopamine-induced T–B-cell interactions increase total germinal centre output and accelerate it by days. Delivery of neurotransmitters across the T–B-cell synapse may be advantageous in the face of infection. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23013&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/wUJN7VonS48&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Open and closed structures reveal allostery and pliability in the HIV-1 envelope spike</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23010</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/hKUHz9VJN58/nature23010</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 For many enveloped viruses, binding to a receptor(s) on a host cell acts as the first step in a series of events culminating in fusion with the host cell membrane and transfer of genetic material for replication. The envelope glycoprotein (Env) trimer on the surface of HIV is responsible for receptor binding and fusion. Although Env can tolerate a high degree of mutation in five variable regions (V1–V5), and also at N-linked glycosylation sites that contribute roughly half the mass of Env, the functional sites for recognition of receptor CD4 and co-receptor CXCR4/CCR5 are conserved and essential for viral fitness. Soluble SOSIP Env trimers are structural and antigenic mimics of the pre-fusion native, surface-presented Env, and are targets of broadly neutralizing antibodies. Thus, they are attractive immunogens for vaccine development. Here we present high-resolution cryo-electron microscopy structures of subtype B B41 SOSIP Env trimers in complex with CD4 and antibody 17b, or with antibody b12, at resolutions of 3.7 Å and 3.6 Å, respectively. We compare these to cryo-electron microscopy reconstructions of B41 SOSIP Env trimers with no ligand or in complex with either CD4 or the CD4-binding-site antibody PGV04 at 5.6 Å, 5.2 Å and 7.4 Å resolution, respectively. Consequently, we present the most complete description yet, to our knowledge, of the CD4–17b-induced intermediate and provide the molecular basis of the receptor-binding-induced conformational change required for HIV-1 entry into host cells. Both CD4 and b12 induce large, previously uncharacterized conformational rearrangements in the gp41 subunits, and the fusion peptide becomes buried in a newly formed pocket. These structures provide key details on the biological function of the type I viral fusion machine from HIV-1 as well as new templates for inhibitor design. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature23010&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature23010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/hKUHz9VJN58&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Infant viewing of social scenes is under genetic control and is atypical in autism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22999</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/_2R5fah2yZM/nature22999</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;
 Long before infants reach, crawl or walk, they explore the world by looking: they look to learn and to engage, giving preferential attention to social stimuli, including faces, face-like stimuli and biological motion. This capacity—social visual engagement—shapes typical infant development from birth and is pathognomonically impaired in children affected by autism. Here we show that variation in viewing of social scenes, including levels of preferential attention and the timing, direction and targeting of individual eye movements, is strongly influenced by genetic factors, with effects directly traceable to the active seeking of social information. In a series of eye-tracking experiments conducted with 338 toddlers, including 166 epidemiologically ascertained twins (enrolled by representative sampling from the general population), 88 non-twins with autism and 84 singleton controls, we find high monozygotic twin–twin concordance (0.91) and relatively low dizygotic concordance (0.35). Moreover, the characteristics that are the most highly heritable, preferential attention to eye and mouth regions of the face, are also those that are differentially decreased in children with autism (χ2 = 64.03, P &amp;lt; 0.0001). These results implicate social visual engagement as a neurodevelopmental endophenotype not only for autism, but also for population-wide variation in social-information seeking. In addition, these results reveal a means of human biological niche construction, with phenotypic differences emerging from the interaction of individual genotypes with early life experience. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature   &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nature22999&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/nature22999&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/_2R5fah2yZM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Legs-11</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547252a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/bpk2Ju44_x4/547252a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Meet the home help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 252 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547252a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547252a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/bpk2Ju44_x4&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature Biological Sciences Research: Bioengineering: Bile ducts regenerated</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547171a</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~3/6Kj0Nexp3AM/547171a</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The development of a protocol for isolating and expanding the cell population that lines bile ducts has enabled the  in vitro  generation of bioengineered ducts. These can replace native bile ducts when transplanted into mice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 171 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547171a&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547171a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch/~4/6Kj0Nexp3AM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureBiologicalSciencesResearch">Nature Biological Sciences Research</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Gene editing: CRISPR book review — Doudna responds</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162e</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/6EYej_GRPjY/547162e</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162e&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/6EYej_GRPjY&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Nature News &amp; Comment: Taxonomy: refine rather than stabilize</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162d</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.nature.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~3/pt_WFq9fNxM/547162d</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nature 547 162 &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/547162d&quot;&gt;doi: 10.1038/547162d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NatureNewsComment/~4/pt_WFq9fNxM&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.nature.com/NatureNewsComment">Nature News &amp;amp; Comment</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Whales feast when hatcheries release salmon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/whales-feast-when-hatcheries-release-salmon</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/whales-feast-when-hatcheries-release-salmon</link>
	<description>Whales: “They’re 40 feet long and they’re feeding on fish that are the size of my finger.”</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 23:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071117_SM_whale_main_free.jpg?itok=Gpo4XHBH" length="37417" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The most distant star ever spotted is 9 billion light-years away</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/most-distant-star-ever-spotted-9-billion-light-years-away</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/most-distant-star-ever-spotted-9-billion-light-years-away</link>
	<description>A bright blue star sends its light from two-thirds of the way across the universe, thanks to a chance alignment with a galaxy cluster.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 20:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/blogposts/071117_LG_distant-star_main.jpg?itok=_4v0yFu9" length="29006" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: More notices appear for embattled Cornell food researcher</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50968</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/notices-appear-embattled-cornell-food-researcher/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Journals have posted two corrections alongside papers by Brian Wansink, a food researcher whose work has lately come under fire. One of the corrected papers was among the initial batch that raised eyebrows last year; after Wansink praised the productivity of one of his researchers, critics suggested four papers contained critical flaws. The questions about […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/notices-appear-embattled-cornell-food-researcher/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;More notices appear for embattled Cornell food researcher&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 16:22:11 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lost in translation: Authors blame a language error for wrong diagnosis</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50965</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/lost-translation-authors-blame-language-error-wrong-diagnosis/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A patient’s “unusual” brain cyst excited several researchers in China so much they published a paper about it in a major journal. Soon a reader identified a glaring mistake: the authors had described the cause of the cyst incorrectly.   A month after the paper appeared online in November 2016, the reader — a neurologist […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/11/lost-translation-authors-blame-language-error-wrong-diagnosis/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lost in translation: Authors blame a language error for wrong diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 13:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Forging Connections: The weather and the brain – using new methods to understand developmental disorders</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/?p=459</guid>
	<link>https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The latest article was written by our brilliant lab member Danyal Akarca. It describes some of his MPhil research which aims to explore transient brain networks in individuals with a particular type of genetic mutation. Dan finished his degree in Pre-Clinical Medicine before joining our lab and has since been fascinated by the intersection of genetic disorders and the dynamics of brain networks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brain is a complex dynamic system. It can be very difficult to understand how specific differences within that system can be associated with the cognitive and behavioural difficulties that some children experience. This is because even if we group children together on the basis that they all have a particular developmental disorder, that group of children will likely have a heterogeneous aetiology. That is, even though they all fall into the same category, there may be a wide variety of different underlying brain causes. This makes these disorders notoriously difficult to study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developmental disorders that have a known genetic cause can be very useful for understanding these brain-cognition relationships, because by definition they all have the same causal mechanism (i.e. the same gene is responsible for the difficulties that each child experiences). We have been studying a language disorder caused by a mutation to a gene called &lt;em&gt;ZDHHC9&lt;/em&gt;. These children have broader cognitive difficulties, and more specific difficulties with speech production, alongside a form of childhood epilepsy called rolandic epilepsy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our lab, we have explored how brain structure is organised differently in &lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2016/06/08/a-single-gene-disorder-affects-brain-organisation/&quot;&gt;individuals with this mutation,&lt;/a&gt; relative to typically developing controls. Since then our attention has turned to applying new analysis methods to explore differences in dynamic brain function. We have done this by directly recording magnetic fields generated by the activity of neurons, through a device known as a magnetoencephalography (MEG) scanner. The scanner uses magnetic fields generated by the brain to infer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetoencephalography&quot;&gt;electrical activity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical way that MEG data is interpreted, is by comparing how electrical activity within the brain changes in response to a stimulus. These changes can take many forms, including how well synchronised different brain areas are, or the how size of the magnetic response differs across individuals. However, in our current work, we are trying to explore how the brain configures itself within different networks, in a dynamic fashion. This is especially interesting to us, because we think that the ZDHHC9 gene has an impact on the excitability of neurons in particular parts of the brain, specifically in those areas that are associated with language. These changes in network dynamics might be linked to the kinds of cognitive difficulties that these individuals have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used an analysis method called &lt;em&gt;“Group Level Exploratory Analysis of Networks” &lt;/em&gt;– or GLEAN for short – and has recently been developed at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2sJbg72&quot;&gt;Oxford centre for Human Brain Activity&lt;/a&gt;. The concept behind GLEAN is that the brain changes between different patterns of activation in a fashion that is probabilistic. This is much like the concept of the weather – just as the weather can change from day to day in some probabilistic way, so too may the brain change in its activation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-509 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;509&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;480,345&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e/&quot; height=&quot;247&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/2a6556de3969141b8006024f2d14873e-e1499771876691.png?w=344&amp;amp;h=247&quot; width=&quot;344&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis method not only allows us to observe what regions of the brain are active when the participants are in the MEG scanner. It also allows us to see the probabilistic way in which they can change between each other. For example, just as it is more likely to transition from rain one day to cloudiness the next day, relative to say rain to blistering sun, we find that brain activation patterns can be described in a very similar way over sub-second timescales. We can characterise those dynamic transitions in lots of different ways, such as how long you stay in a specific brain state or how long does it take to return to a state once you’ve transitioned away. (A more theoretical account of this can be found in another recent blog post in our Methods section – “&lt;a href=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2016/06/03/the-resting-brain-that-never-rests/&quot;&gt;The resting brain… that never rests&lt;/a&gt;”.) We have found that a number networks differ between individuals with the mutation and our control subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Picture1&quot; class=&quot;  wp-image-529 aligncenter&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;529&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Picture1&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208?w=474&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;944,373&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/2017/07/11/the-weather-and-the-brain-new-method-for-meg-analysis/picture1-2/&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;https://forgingconnectionsblog.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/picture1.png?w=526&amp;amp;h=208&quot; width=&quot;526&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(These are two brain networks that show the most differences in activation – largely in the parietal and frontotemporal regions of the brain.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, these networks strongly overlap with areas of the brain that are known to express the gene (we found this out by using data from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brain-map.org/&quot;&gt;Allen Atlas&lt;/a&gt;). This is the first time that we know of that researchers have been able to link a particular gene, to differences dynamic electrical brain networks, to a particular pattern of cognitive difficulties. And we are really excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/459/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/459/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=78489663&amp;amp;post=459&amp;amp;subd=forgingconnectionsblog&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 11:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forgingconnectionsblog.wordpress.com/feed/">Forging connections between neuroscience, cognition and the wider world.</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: Adaptive reuse of buildings in the healthcare industry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=9223</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/11/adaptive-reuse-of-buildings-in-the-healthcare-industry/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Before-WK-1-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abandoned buildings are a common and unfortunate sight in communities, emerging for myriad reasons ranging from progress, which compels establishments to relocate to better serve clients, to misfortune, which prompts businesses to cease operations at particular locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;While many overlook dilapidated buildings altogether . . . others see opportunities for, of all things, enhancing the depth and breadth of healthcare services in communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their idled states, these buildings often fall into disrepair, diminishing scenic beauty and even posing threats to health and safety as abandoned structures are vulnerable to criminal and environmental elements. While many overlook dilapidated buildings altogether, considering them to be well suited only for the wrecking ball, others see opportunities for, of all things, enhancing the depth and breadth of healthcare services in communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Willis-Knighton Health System and adaptive reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shreveport, Louisiana-based Willis-Knighton Health System has extensive adaptive reuse experience and credits the practice with facilitating expansion initiatives which have improved access to care in the community. The system decided to tap into the unrealized potential of abandoned buildings beginning in the 1970s as a means of acquiring space economically as it expanded its presence in the market. Its initial repurposing endeavors proved economical and effective, compelling subsequent pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, Willis-Knighton Health System has successfully accomplished over 20 adaptive reuse projects. Its most recently completed initiative involved repurposing the former Doctors’ Hospital of Shreveport, a 150,000 square foot building that ceased operations in 2010 and quickly became a prominent blight overlooking the heart of downtown Shreveport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building, reintroduced in 2017 as the WK Rehabilitation Institute, is virtually indistinguishable from brand new construction and features an entirely revised facade, all-new interior elements, and an enhanced layout which facilitates access. The building cost $26 million (acquisition plus renovations), a bargain price, especially when considering that equivalent new construction would total $44.5 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; id=&quot;attachment_9226&quot; style=&quot;width: 2410px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9226 size-full&quot; height=&quot;1590&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/After-WK.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2400&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;The WK Rehabilitation Institute, repurposed from Doctors’ Hospital. © Willis-Knighton Health System.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunities associated with adaptive reuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential possessed by adaptive reuse to deliver significant financial savings unavailable through equivalent new construction projects is perhaps its most notable benefit. In fact, this attribute is cited as the primary motivation for its pursuit, and in each of Willis-Knighton Health System’s experiences, cost advantages over equivalent new construction scenarios were observed. This point certainly shouldn’t be lost on those serving in the healthcare industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The physical space required by physicians, nurses, administrators, and others to carry out their many duties often represents a significant expenditure, consuming financial resources which otherwise could be directed toward patient care. Economies achieved on this front permit more resources to be directed toward mission fulfillment activities and adaptive reuse offers a prudent method for realizing such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond financial advantages, adaptive reuse offers opportunities for healthcare entities to bolster community renewal initiatives by returning to service formerly inactive properties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond financial advantages, adaptive reuse offers opportunities for healthcare entities to bolster community renewal initiatives by returning to service formerly inactive properties. Further, the practice is environmentally friendly, as repurposing abandoned buildings conserves resources and averts demolition, reducing the burden on landfills which otherwise would have to accommodate the waste. Adaptive reuse also has the potential to bring highly-prized locations in communities back into consideration in circumstances where relocations or closures present optimally situated availabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, adaptive reuse offers a unique and mutually beneficial method for addressing the spatial expansion needs of healthcare institutions, providing those serving in hospitals, medical clinics, and other care providing facilities with an option to consider beyond traditional renovation and new construction pathways. The practice by its very nature coincides nicely with the community-minded, altruistic missions typically espoused by healthcare establishments, affording an exceptional strategic fit when proper circumstances present themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional insights on the practice of adaptive reuse, including descriptions of opportunities and obstacles, case presentations profiling several of Willis-Knighton Health System’s repurposing initiatives, and a detailed operational framework, consult the associated article featured in BMC Health Services Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2017/07/11/adaptive-reuse-of-buildings-in-the-healthcare-industry/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Adaptive reuse of buildings in the healthcare industry&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2017/06/Before-WK-1-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Sexual offending by women is surprisingly common, claims US study</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=26502</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/11/sexual-offending-by-women-is-surprisingly-common-claims-us-study/</link>
	<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignnone&quot; data-shortcode=&quot;caption&quot; id=&quot;attachment_26631&quot; style=&quot;width: 2121px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-535192499.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-26631&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;26631&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 650D&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed on white background&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1422464045&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Chris_Tefme&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;35&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00625&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Silhouette of woman in dress with arms crossed&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2121,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2017/07/11/sexual-offending-by-women-is-surprisingly-common-claims-us-study/silhouette-of-woman-in-dress-with-arms-crossed/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2017/07/gettyimages-535192499.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;“Attention to female sexual perpetration serves important feminist goals,” the researchers said&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christianjarrett.com/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A team of US researchers led by Lara Stemple at the UCLA School of Law has analysed data from several large federal crime victimisation surveys and they say their findings show that sexual offences by women against male and female victims are surprisingly common. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178916301446?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Writing in &lt;em&gt;Aggression and Violent Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; the researchers stress that they are in no way intending to minimise the human cost of sexual violence perpetrated by men. But they say their results are “sufficiently robust so as to compel a rethinking of long-held stereotypes about sexual victimisation and gender”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-26502&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stemple’s team begin by pointing to data from the Center For Disease Control’s Survey of thousands of people for the “National Intimate Partner Violence and Sexual Violence”. In 2011, for example, this survey showed that equal numbers of men and women reported being forced into non-consensual sex (either raped themselves or forced to penetrate someone else). Extrapolated to the US as a whole, this would represent 1.9 million victims among each sex during the preceding 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are similar findings for sex of victim in the 2010 survey, the researchers said, and that year, the survey also included detail on the sex of offender. To illustrate the prevalence of female offending, the researchers highlighted the number of men who reported being forced by a woman to penetrate her. The survey estimated that nearly 4.5 million men in the US had at some time in their lives been forced to penetrate another person, and crucially, that in 79.2 per cent of cases the perpetrator forcing the sexual act was a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another survey the researchers looked at was the National Crime Victimisation Survey, pooling the data from 2010 to 2013. This showed that female perpetrators (without a male accomplice) were reported in 28 per cent of rape or sexual assault cases against men and 4.1 per cent of such cases against female victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from prisons collected by the Bureau of Justice Statistics is equally surprising. Among female prisoners who have been the victims of sexual offences during their incarceration, they far more often report the offender to be another female inmate than a male member of staff. Indeed, contrary to stereotypes, another survey found that women prison inmates were more than three times as likely to be sexually victimised by another women inmate as compared with male prisoners’ risk of sexual victimisation by another male prisoner (bi-sexual women were at highest risk). For boys and men who are incarcerated, the prison data also show that they are overwhelmingly more likely to be sexually victimised by female staff than male staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National surveys by the U.S. Census Bureau are also revealing. A 2012 study asked respondents whether they had ever forced someone to have sex against their will: of those who said they had, 43.6 per cent were female (compared with 56.4 per cent of men).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stemple’s team also considered data from college samples. Most recently, a 2014 study of 284 men and boys in college found that 43 reported having been sexually coerced, mostly unwanted sexual intercourse, with 95 per cent of the perpetrators reported as being female. An earlier survey obtained anecdotal descriptions of sexual violence from perpetrators. One woman described how she “locked the room door that we were in. I kissed and touched him. I removed his shirt and unzipped his pants. He asked me stop. I didn’t. Then I sat on top of him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, the researchers say that the data challenge the one-dimensional stereotype of women as only passive and harmless. Facing up to the reality of the prevalence of female sex offences actually serves feminist goals, they argue, citing another scholar who wrote that to be fully recognised, women must be “heard in all possible forms, whether in compassion, in protest or in violence”. The results also challenge stereotypes about men, they added, such as that they have “an insatiable desire for sex”, and they challenge rape myths such as that it is impossible for “a big strong man to be raped by a woman” (which the majority of students endorsed as true in a recent survey).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, it is only by recognising the reality of female sexual offending that the needs of those who offend can be properly addressed. “Female perpetration [of sexual aggression] is frequently intertwined with women’s past experience of their own victimisation”, the researchers said. For instance, evidence suggests that female offenders “have often experienced severe childhood sexual abuse themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the “culture of denial” about female sexual offending means that most female offenders are not convicted, and when they are, they receive lighter sentences, Stemple and her colleagues said. Male victims may feel pressure to interpret their victimisation experiences in a way consistent with masculine ideals, “such as the idea that men should relish any available opportunity for sex.” Meanwhile, “heterosexist” assumptions (that sexual violence is only ever perpetrated by men, usually against women) mean that lesbian and bisexual victims of female sexual aggression are “invisible to professionals”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also commonly assumed that female offenders nearly always co-offend with a male accomplice, the researchers noted, but while it is true that co-offending is more common among female offenders, data suggest they are still more likely to abuse alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We call for feminist approaches – expansively interpreted – to challenge these stereotypes, making room to consider women who are abusive, power seeking, and sexually aggressive, while taking into account the troubled background many such women possess,” the researchers concluded. “Those victimised by women are doubly harmed when we fail to treat their abuse as worthy of concern.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178916301446?_rdoc=1&amp;amp;_fmt=high&amp;amp;_origin=gateway&amp;amp;_docanchor=&amp;amp;md5=b8429449ccfc9c30159a5f9aeaa92ffb&amp;amp;dgcid=raven_sd_via_email&quot;&gt;Sexual victimization perpetrated by women: Federal data reveal surprising prevalence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26502/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/researchdigest.wordpress.com/26502/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=digest.bps.org.uk&amp;amp;blog=114693443&amp;amp;post=26502&amp;amp;subd=researchdigest&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 09:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The fight against gonorrhea gets a potential new weapon: a vaccine</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gonorrhea-std-meningitis-vaccine</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/gonorrhea-std-meningitis-vaccine</link>
	<description>A vaccine used in New Zealand to curb meningitis also appeared to drop gonorrhea infections, results that hint at a way to make a gonorrhea vaccine.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 22:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071017_ls_gonorrhea_main.jpg?itok=NoQ1RAis" length="34967" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Just one night of poor sleep can boost Alzheimer’s proteins</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/just-one-night-poor-sleep-can-boost-alzheimers-beta-proteins</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/just-one-night-poor-sleep-can-boost-alzheimers-beta-proteins</link>
	<description>Deep sleep may prevent the buildup of Alzheimer’s proteins.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 20:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2017/07/main/articles/071117_TI_alzheimers_sleep_main_FREE.jpg?itok=dFs-AsgJ" length="18205" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: Political Neuroscience: &quot;Growth Mindsets&quot; and Disability</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8936</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=8936</link>
	<description>On Twitter, I learned that the British government is citing neuroscience studies as part of a new welfare initiative.



The &quot;Health and Work Conversation&quot; (HWC) is a newly-introduced procedure for welfare claimants receiving support because sickness or disability impairs their ability to work. The one hour &quot;conversation&quot; is mandatory in most cases and it seems intended to encourage people to seek whatever work they are able to do.

A Freedom of Information Act request has revealed documen</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 20:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Lancet retracts (and replaces) paper a year after authors report error that changes “all numbers”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=50957</guid>
	<link>http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/lancet-retracts-replaces-paper-year-authors-report-error-changes-numbers/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In March 2016, researchers in Switzerland and Canada published a meta-analysis in The Lancet, exploring the optimal painkiller and dose for treating pain in knee and hip osteoarthritis. Soon after, the authors were informed of an error that would change “all numbers” in a paper that may influence clinical practice. The authors contacted The Lancet […]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com/2017/07/10/lancet-retracts-replaces-paper-year-authors-report-error-changes-numbers/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Lancet retracts (and replaces) paper a year after authors report error that changes “all numbers”&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://retractionwatch.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Retraction Watch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: HIV Reservoirs: Does The Virus Hide in the Brain?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=22605</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2017/07/10/hiv-reservoirs-does-the-virus-hide-in-the-brain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Treatment advances over the last several decades have dramatically extended the lifespan of patients with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). However, a continuing problem in HIV treatment is the ability of the virus to remain dormant in a small number of cells throughout the body, including some areas of the brain. Researchers at the University of Montreal in Canada recently discovered a way to locate and destroy hidden HIV viral particles, a finding that could eventually lead to a complete cure for the disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIV currently affects an estimated 36.7 million people worldwide, and infects 2.1 million new individuals each year. HIV infection targets a group of immune cells called CD4+ T cells. These cells are responsible for recognizing and attacking harmful bacteria and viruses that enter the body. When a large proportion of these cells are destroyed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/05/08/hiv-medications-linked-to-increase-in-alzheimers-disease-protein/&quot;&gt;HIV&lt;/a&gt;, the body can no longer defend against infections and other diseases. This stage is called acquired immunodeficiency syndrome, or AIDS, and frequently results in premature death due to opportunistic infections and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present treatments for HIV include reverse transcriptase inhibitors and &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2017/05/08/hiv-medications-linked-to-increase-in-alzheimers-disease-protein/&quot;&gt;protease inhibitors&lt;/a&gt;, among several others. These drugs work by targeting the enzymes that convert viral RNA into DNA and produce mature viral particles. These drugs are highly effective and have drastically increased the life expectancy of patients. However, a complete cure for HIV has remained elusive because of the ability of the virus to remain in so-called reservoirs in the body. If a patient in remission forgoes their medication, the virus can become re-activated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers from several universities, led by Daniel Kauffman of the University of Montreal, recently discovered a way to identify and potentially destroy HIV reservoirs. Their findings are published in the journal &lt;em&gt;Cell Host and Microbe&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the researchers sought a new way to identify HIV-infected CD4+ T cells using a method called flow-FISH, which combines two techniques for identifying proteins and nucleotides in cells. Flow cytometry uses a machine to sort and identify cell subpopulations based on surface protein markers, but it is not sensitive or specific enough to identify HIV-infected cells. Fluorescence in situ hybridization, or FISH, uses fluorescent probes directed against specific nucleotide sequences to identify DNA or RNA in a cell with local and temporal specificity. Flow-FISH was used to detect the mRNA of two specific &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2012/09/08/does-hiv-make-the-brain-old-before-its-time/&quot;&gt;HIV genes&lt;/a&gt; in CD4+ T cells, &lt;em&gt;gag &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;pol&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this method, the researchers were able to detect virus-containing cells at concentrations as low as 0.5–1 per million CD4+ T cells. This assay was combined with polychromatic flow cytometry, which analyzes multiple cell surface markers simultaneously. Together, these techniques allowed the researchers to quantify and identify the characteristics of HIV-infected cells in patient blood samples. HIV-infected CD4+ T-cells showed an increase in markers of “&lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2010/12/12/preventing-hiv-before-exposure/&quot;&gt;immune exhaustion&lt;/a&gt;” (PD-1, CTLA-4, and TIGIT), which occurs when T cells have been chronically activated and are no longer responsive. They also were able to estimate the size of the viral reservoir, which was on average 3.56 cells per million CD4+ T cells, but a wide variation was observed among patients on anti-viral therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next part of the study, two latency-reversal agents (LRA) were tested on cells from HIV-infected patients. LRAs are used in a “shock and kill” technique that activates dormant viral particles in the body, allowing them to be eradicated by antiretroviral agents. Bryostatin modulates protein kinase C, an enzyme involved in cell signaling pathways, and is currently being tested for use as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/04/01/new_anti_cancer_drug_for_aggressive_brain_tumors/&quot;&gt;anti-cancer&lt;/a&gt;, anti-HIV, and memory-enhancing agent. Ingenol is a plant-derived drug with several proposed mechanism of action that include protein kinase C activation, which leads to the activation of immune cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers determined that bryostatin and ingenol differed in their ability to activate two subpopulations of CD4+ T cells. Ingenol activated central memory cells, which persist for several years in patients, whereas bryostatin was not as effective against this T-cell subpopulation. This finding suggested that ingenol may be a more effective treatment for latent HIV. While both drugs were capable of killing the HIV virus &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt;, their effectiveness in the body remains unclear. The researchers suggest that their viral detection method will be useful for assessing the effectiveness of LRAs in clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method of reactivating latent HIV provides hope for one day eradicating the virus, but it is not without the potential for side effects. Researchers at Johns Hopkins University recently tested the effect of viral reactivation by LRAs in monkeys with simian immunodeficiency virus (SIV), the correlate of HIV in monkeys. They found that the drug caused a harmful form of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/05/28/lack-of-sleep-affects-performance-and-damages-brain-cells/&quot;&gt;brain inflammation&lt;/a&gt;. The researchers suspect that this side effects was caused by the existence of HIV reservoirs in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIV-infected monkeys were treated with a cocktail of antiretroviral agents (tenofovir, darunavir, ritonavir, and the integrase inhibitor L-870812). Following 400 days on this regimen, viral suppression was confirmed by measuring SIV in plasma. Then two of the monkeys were treated for ten days with the latency-reversing agents ingenol-B and vorinostat. Vorinostat is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2015/11/08/best-and-worst-of-neuroscience-and-neurology-october-2015/&quot;&gt;histone deacetylase&lt;/a&gt; inhibitor that works by changing the expression of genes involved in cell differentiation. The animals continued on the antiretroviral drug cocktail during the treatment with LRAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the treated monkeys remained healthy under this treatment regimen. However, the second monkey developed symptoms of brain inflammation, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/02/08/winter-depression-new-discoveries-in-treatment-of-seasonal-affective-disorder/&quot;&gt;lethargy&lt;/a&gt; and lack of appetite. Active SIV and markers of inflammation were detected in the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), the fluid that surrounds the brain and spinal cord. After the animal was euthanized due to the illness, they removed the brain for examination. They were careful to first remove the monkey’s blood to ensure that the brain tissue wasn’t contaminated by infected blood cells. They found that SIV was present in a part of the brain called the occipital cortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery that viral reactivation can cause brain inflammation, possibly by reactivating brain reservoirs of the virus, is a potential drawback for using LRAs to treat latent HIV in humans. Reassuringly, this side effect occurred in only one of the two animals, so these findings are still preliminary. Further, while there are innate differences between SIV and HIV, clinical trials of LRA in humans with HIV must be carried out with caution. Monitoring the CSF for evidence of viral reactivation in the brain should accompany LRA treatment to prevent such side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lugli E., Troiano L, Cossarizza A. (2009) Investigating T cells by polychromatic flow cytometry. Methods Mol Biol. 514:47-63. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1007/978-1-60327-527-9_5&quot;&gt;10.1007/978-1-60327-527-9_5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherry, J.E. and Kurachi M. (2015) Molecular and cellular insights into T cell exhaustion. Nature Reviews Immunology 15:486–499. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/nri3862&quot;&gt;10.1038/nri3862&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorenzo-Redondo R., Fryer H.R., Bedford T., Kim E.Y., Archer J., Kosakovsky Pond S.L., et al. (2016) Persistent HIV-1 replication maintains the tissue reservoir during therapy. Nature 530:51–56. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://10.1038/nature16933&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;10.1038/nature16933&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gama L., Abreu C.M., Shirk E.N., Price S.L., Li M., Laird G.M. et al. (2017) Reactivation of simian immunodeficiency virus reservoirs in the brain of virally suppressed macaques. AIDS. Jan 2;31(1):5-14. DOI: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1097/QAD.0000000000001267&quot;&gt;10.1097/QAD.0000000000001267&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/typographyimages-3575871/&quot;&gt;typographyimages&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Sharing knowledge to uncover cancer cells’ secret disguises</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/sharing-knowledge-to-uncover-cancer-cells-secret-disguises</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/sharing-knowledge-to-uncover-cancer-cells-secret-disguises</link>
	<description>How we used epigenetics to map the switches that help uterine cancer cells hide and spread</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
