<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Neuroscientists</title>
	<link>https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Neuroscientists - https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>

<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Ensuring science is available to everybody</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.nationmultimedia.com/detail/opinion/30347521</guid>
	<link>http://www.nationmultimedia.com/detail/opinion/30347521</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Recently, the Philippines’ Department of Science and Technology (DOST) made a welcome announcement on Facebook: The Philippine Journal of Science has been made an open-access journal, meaning anyone can read and download its articles for  free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a significant first, because the journal, founded in 1906, is the oldest scientific peer-reviewed publication in the country, featuring articles on the natural sciences, engineering, mathematics and social sciences.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This heavy element has a football-shaped atomic nucleus</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heavy-element-has-football-shaped-atomic-nucleus</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/heavy-element-has-football-shaped-atomic-nucleus</link>
	<description>Three nobelium isotopes have oblong nuclei, and some sport a ‘bubble’ center.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/061218_ec_nobelium_feat_free.jpg?itok=uy-MsXHs" length="10302" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Why Africa needs new solutions to its education challenges | Passnownow.com</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://passnownow.com/africa-needs-new-solutions-education-challenges/</guid>
	<link>https://passnownow.com/africa-needs-new-solutions-education-challenges/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The advent of Open Educational Resources (OER), free content which can be adapted for different contexts and reproduced without paying licence fees, offers tremendous potential across the continent.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OER’s – Emerging Tecnology – Miss Monica</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://missmonicascudder.wordpress.com/2018/06/11/oers-open-educational-resources/</guid>
	<link>https://missmonicascudder.wordpress.com/2018/06/11/oers-open-educational-resources/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The emerging technology that I chose to research, presented by the 2017 Horizon report for higher education and according to NMC 2017 Horizon Report for Higher Education is: open educational resources, also known as: OER.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Cape Peninsula University of Technology (via Public) / Time to create your own learning resources</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.publicnow.com/view/B5315E3793AD3EDBCFDA73E468BB7AACE851E6A8</guid>
	<link>http://www.publicnow.com/view/B5315E3793AD3EDBCFDA73E468BB7AACE851E6A8</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Lecturers interested in developing Open Educational Resources at CPUT could soon have the benefit of a R10 000 grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Innovative Educational Technology (CIET) has sent out an open call for grant proposals to create innovative resources.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: States Stepping Up Role in Reviewing Digital Resources, Analysis Finds - Market Brief</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://marketbrief.edweek.org/marketplace-k-12/states-stepping-role-reviewing-digital-resources-review-finds/</guid>
	<link>https://marketbrief.edweek.org/marketplace-k-12/states-stepping-role-reviewing-digital-resources-review-finds/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;In some cases, the rise of open educational resources–materials created on licenses that allow them to be freely shared and altered–have compelled states to set policies to help local districts review them.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OpenCon 2018 Announced -- Exclusive Discount for SPARC Members</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://mailchi.mp/ee1e21895208/opencon-2018-announced-exclusive-discount-for-sparc-members?e=7581b2b4f1</guid>
	<link>https://mailchi.mp/ee1e21895208/opencon-2018-announced-exclusive-discount-for-sparc-members?e=7581b2b4f1</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;SPARC has just announced that OpenCon 2018—the flagship global meeting of the OpenCon community—will be take place on November 2-4 in Toronto, where it will be hosted in partnership with York University, Ryerson University, and the University of Toronto. We hope you will consider sponsoring a representative from your campus to attend!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;You can view the full announcement, with more details about OpenCon and the 2018 global meeting, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opencon2017.org/opencon_2018_announced&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a benefit of membership, SPARC members will receive an exclusive $250 discount on sponsored scholarships to OpenCon. These sponsored scholarships, limited to 40 from each continent, guarantee a place at the meeting for a representative of your institution that you select and include the cost of conference registration, shared accommodations, and airfare which SPARC will book on behalf of your selected participant. For 2018, these scholarships are $2,250 for North American SPARC members ($2,500 for non-members). For Canadian members, the CAD price will be pegged at an exchange rate of $1.25 CAD/USD (unless the exchange rate drops below this level), making the cost CAD $2,812 for SPARC members and CAD $3,150 for non-members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;One of these scholarships can be held with an expression of interest, and selected scholarships will be limited to two per institution. To reserve a scholarship or find more information, please click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opencon2017.org/sponsor_selected-travel-scholarship&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Wiley Reports Fourth Quarter and Fiscal Year 2018 Results | Business Wire</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180612005525/en/Wiley-Reports-Fourth-Quarter-Fiscal-Year-2018</guid>
	<link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180612005525/en/Wiley-Reports-Fourth-Quarter-Fiscal-Year-2018</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Revenue increased due to growth in Research (+10% reported, +5% constant currency) and Solutions (+6% reported, +2% constant currency), which more than offset a decline in Publishing (-2% reported, -5% constant currency).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research growth was driven by Open Access (+59% reported, +51% constant currency) and Journal Subscriptions (+7% reported, +2% constant currency).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OpenCon 2018 to be Held in Toronto, Canada on November 2-4; Applications Open June 12 - SPARC</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://sparcopen.org/news/2018/opencon-2018-announcement/</guid>
	<link>https://sparcopen.org/news/2018/opencon-2018-announcement/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;SPARC and the Right to Research Coalition, in partnership with York University, Ryerson University, and the University of Toronto, are excited to announce that OpenCon 2018—the flagship global meeting of the OpenCon community—will take place on November 2-4 in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting the default to open for research and education is fundamentally about people and the decisions they make. The culture of research and education emerges from the countless individual decisions made by millions of researchers and educators each day—at different types of institutions, within different disciplines, and in every country. OpenCon is a platform for catalyzing change in this culture, at scale and in context. OpenCon’s programs work to develop, activate, and connect a global community of next generation leaders who are driving the culture shift toward open locally, nationally, and internationally. OpenCon creates this community through its flagship global meeting, satellite events hosted around the world, and regular community calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenCon’s flagship global meeting helps drive this culture change by bringing together the most energetic, engaged students and early career academic professionals. Participants learn about Open Access, Open Education, and Open Data, develop critical skills, find collaborators, and catalyze action toward a more open system for sharing the world’s information—from scholarly and scientific research, to educational materials, to digital research data. OpenCon 2018’s three-day program will begin with two days of panels and interactive workshops that place an emphasis on highlighting diverse, early career voices from every continent. The third day will feature an all-day “do-a-thon,” where participants have the opportunity to craft new campaigns, lay the foundations for new resources, and form collaborations that will continue long after the November conference is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenCon strives to ensure that diversity, equity, and inclusion are both foundational to the community’s efforts to open up research and education and priorities for continual improvement. OpenCon seeks to be as globally inclusive as possible and to advocate for a future that is not only open but also equitable and co-designed with diverse stakeholders—especially those from marginalized groups. In 2017, OpenCon released a report on diversity, equity, and inclusion that contains lessons learned, suggestions for conference organizers, and a self-analysis with relevant data. That report can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://sparcopen.github.io/opencon-dei-report&quot;&gt;https://sparcopen.github.io/opencon-dei-report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendance at the meeting is by application only, and the majority of past participants have received full or partial travel scholarships. Each year, most participants are first-time attendees and are selected from a pool of thousands of qualified candidates through a community-run review process based on the likelihood that their participation will translate into impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications to attend OpenCon 2018 in Toronto will open on June 12th. For more information about the conference and to sign up for updates—including a reminder when applications open—visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opencon2018.org/updates&quot;&gt;opencon2018.org/updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OpenCon 2018 to be Held in Toronto, Canada on November 2-4; - OpenCon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opencon2018.org/opencon_2018_announced</guid>
	<link>https://www.opencon2018.org/opencon_2018_announced</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;SPARC and the Right to Research Coalition, in partnership with York University, Ryerson University, and the University of Toronto, are excited to announce that OpenCon 2018—the flagship global meeting of the OpenCon community—will take place on November 2-4 in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting the default to open for research and education is fundamentally about people and the decisions they make. The culture of research and education emerges from the countless individual decisions made by millions of researchers and educators each day—at different types of institutions, within different disciplines, and in every country. OpenCon is a platform for catalyzing change in this culture, at scale and in context. OpenCon’s programs work to develop, activate, and connect a global community of next generation leaders who are driving the culture shift toward open locally, nationally, and internationally. OpenCon creates this community through its flagship global meeting, satellite events hosted around the world, and regular community calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: NYC open data winners announced - Smart Cities World</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.smartcitiesworld.net/news/news/nyc-open-data-winners-announced-3005</guid>
	<link>https://www.smartcitiesworld.net/news/news/nyc-open-data-winners-announced-3005</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;New York City’s Open Data team has named the winners of its first annual city-wide competition where participants were challenged to use the city’s 2,000+ open datasets to come up with solutions to existing problems.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open and Shut?: The OA Interviews: Taylor &amp; Francis' Deborah Kahn discusses Dove Medical Press</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7961882.post-2195350375857806932</guid>
	<link>https://poynder.blogspot.com/2018/06/the-oa-interviews-taylor-francis.html</link>
	<description>&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoNormal&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The open access publisher Dove Medical Press has a controversial past and I have written about the company on a number of occasions (&lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2008/11/open-access-interviews-dove-medical.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-linked-to-alabama-shooting.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2016/02/why-i-wont-be-doing-that-video.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2017/07/on-sponsorship-transparency-scholarly.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;table cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xKYVoxqnpn0/Wx_OcJHaw9I/AAAAAAAAdVg/aZquOe3byWkSVJhEy5PVi53aqxv4mCNlwCLcBGAs/s1600/Kahn.jpg&quot; style=&quot;clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; data-original-height=&quot;448&quot; data-original-width=&quot;336&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xKYVoxqnpn0/Wx_OcJHaw9I/AAAAAAAAdVg/aZquOe3byWkSVJhEy5PVi53aqxv4mCNlwCLcBGAs/s200/Kahn.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Deborah Kahn&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;When Dove was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebookseller.com/news/taylor-francis-buys-open-access-journal-publisher-dove-medical-644721&quot;&gt;acquired&lt;/a&gt; by Taylor &amp;amp; Francis last September it was assumed (by me at least) that controversy had become a thing of the past for the publisher.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Seven months after the purchase, however, a medical technology company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://minervasurgical.com/&quot;&gt;Minerva Surgical&lt;/a&gt; took the unusual step of publishing a &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/minerva-surgical-requests-immediate-retraction-of-misleading-intl-journal-of-womens-health-publication-that-compares-novasure-to-minerva-sponsored-by-hologic-300637791.html&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; alleging that &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/I1I7CrkEYwi8nAVEQSwP-n3?domain=dovepress.com&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; published in Dove’s &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;International Journal of Women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;’&lt;/i&gt;s Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt; makes “material misleading statements” about the nature of a study funded by a rival in “clear violation of the COPE guidelines.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result, Minerva said, the paper should be retracted immediately.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;To discuss this latest incident, Dove’s background, and some of the “historical issues” the publisher has faced, Taylor &amp;amp; Francis’ Director, Medicine and Open Access, agreed to do a Q&amp;amp;A with me, which I publish below.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of the latest controversy Kahn says, “our investigations show that the peer review was carried out to high standards and that the journal behaved well, and the authors responses have satisfied us that the complaints are unfounded.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;On the historical issues, she adds, the naysayers were wrong to have doubted Dove’s probity. “We went through very detailed due diligence, carrying out an extremely thorough process, when we acquired Dove Medical Press. We were satisfied that, after some historical issues, improvements had been made to their peer review process working with the OASPA membership team … Eight months on from our acquisition, Dove are performing well in all areas, we remain confident that we got value for money, and are delighted that they are part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;There are one or two places in the Q&amp;amp;A where readers may feel there is a little repetition. If so, this is because the interview was done by email in a staged way. I have, however, not edited the text as I am keen to publish Kahn’s answers exactly as she emailed them to me. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;The Q&amp;amp;A begins …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: I am wondering why Taylor &amp;amp; Francis (T&amp;amp;F) decided to buy Dove Medical Press? I have seen the short &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.taylorandfrancisgroup.com/dove-medical-press-joins-taylor-francis-group/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; published at the time, which talks of Dove journals having Impact Factors (and of T&amp;amp;F wanting to expand in OA and medical journals) but I am also aware that the perception in the market is that (as this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/U80xCjRvnlfnGj58ot4-9e3?domain=statnews.com&quot;&gt;puts it&lt;/a&gt;), titles from Dove “tend to rank poorly on impact factor”. Can you say more about why T&amp;amp;F chose to buy Dove? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Open Access and Medical publishing are both strategically important areas of investment and growth for Taylor &amp;amp; Francis. So we were delighted when we were able to enter into discussions with Dove Medical Press, as they fit so well with our plans. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove Medical Press is a small and entrepreneurial company, with staff based in Auckland and Macclesfield, all of whom are committed to excellent service to authors, and high-quality peer review. They publish around 100 journals, of which 12 have impact factors ranging from 1.7 to 7 –  almost all of them placed within the top two quartiles of the Journal Citation Report. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Two more titles are set to receive Impact Factors in the next release of the JCR. The vast majority of the rest of the journals are indexed in the DOAJ, PubMed and the Emerging Sources Citation Index (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mjl.clarivate.com/cgi-bin/jrnlst/jlresults.cgi?PC=EX&quot;&gt;ESCI&lt;/a&gt;). All of these indexes perform in-depth checks on the quality and integrity of the contents of journals before accepting them for indexing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We chose to buy Dove because we were impressed by the quality of their content, the quality of their peer review, their focus on author experience, and their loyal author following, with a high percentage of repeat authors. We rated it a very good business in its own right and knew that we would learn from them as we continued to develop our own open access offerings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: How much did T&amp;amp;F pay for Dove?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; This wasn’t disclosed at the time of acquisition. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://informa.com/media/press-releases-news/latest-news/informa-extends-open-access-position-and-capability-with-addition-of-dove-medical-press/&quot;&gt;press statement&lt;/a&gt; released by Informa, our parent company. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Yes, I saw that, but I was hoping you could tell me anyway? Frankly, I don’t understand why this information needs to be secret, although I suppose it fits with the secrecy that has always surrounded Dove. When I interviewed Dove’s Tim Hill in 2008 he refused to tell me who the owners of Dove were and denied that (despite what some believed) there was any connection between Libertas Academica (LA) and Dove, or with him (aside from the fact that the owner of LA was his son). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Then, when in 2010 I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2016/02/why-i-wont-be-doing-that-video.html&quot;&gt;emailed him&lt;/a&gt; to point out that New Zealand Companies House records that he had one time been the sole director and shareholder of LA, and had in fact  been a director of LA when he told me in 2008 that there was no connection, he responded, “Henceforth I will not be providing you with any comment or information on any subject.” In 2016, I tried to make contact with Dove directors Graeme Peterson and Kevin Toale, neither of whom responded. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Can you tell me why there has always been this kind of secrecy surrounding Dove? OA advocates argue that scholarly publishing is primarily funded by the taxpayer and so should be transparent both in process and financing. There is now also a widespread belief that there should be even greater transparency with regard to medical research, and those who publish it, not least because it is felt that pay-to-publish OA has made it easier for pharmaceutical and medical device companies to use scholarly papers as marketing tools. Do you agree that there are dangers here and that greater transparency is essential? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; I do believe that there should be transparency in all scholarly publishing, both in traditional subscription and open access publishing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/&quot;&gt;COPE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/&quot;&gt;OASPA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wame.org/&quot;&gt;WAME&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/&quot;&gt;DOAJ&lt;/a&gt; have collaborated to identify &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/resources/guidelines-new/principles-transparency-and-best-practice-scholarly-publishing&quot;&gt;Principles of Transparency and Best Practice in Scholarly Publishing&lt;/a&gt;, and these principles form part of the criteria on which membership applications to those organizations are evaluated. All Dove journals are &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/2JeQrsr&quot;&gt;included in the DOAJ&lt;/a&gt; and have “&lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/faq#thetick&quot;&gt;the tick&lt;/a&gt;”, which means they have met the high level of compliance to these criteria. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;All Dove journals are also members of COPE and have met their membership criteria also.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;I don’t think that there has been secrecy around Dove Medical Press. Information about the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.companieshouse.gov.uk/company/04967656&quot;&gt;has been available from Companies House&lt;/a&gt; since they came into existence in 2003. Nothing in our due diligence suggested anything to the contrary. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Tim Hill (from Dove) is Tom Hill’s father, and he may have helped his son establish Libertas Academica in the first instance. However, Tim Hill was not involved in the direction or any of the operations of Libertas Academica. No current Dove staff have ever worked with or as part of Libertas Academica, nor do the two companies share any operations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Dove is registered in the UK but, as I understand it, the company actually operates out of New Zealand. Did that present any particular issues during the negotiation process? Does it present any difficulties today?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Dove has offices in both Macclesfield and Auckland with 1/3 of the staff in the UK and 2/3 in New Zealand. These two locations are actually a real advantage, as it means we can offer global coverage and 24-hour customer service. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Apart from a few late night and early morning meetings for people in both locations, there are few disadvantages, and as a bonus I have been very much enjoying getting to know Auckland, and reacquainting myself with Macclesfield which is close to where I grew up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Founders and directors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Dove had quite a number of directors. Who did T&amp;amp;F deal with when negotiating the purchase? Was Dove’s MD involved in the negotiations? Apart from the company’s directors (who I believe have all left), have most Dove staff remained with the company? Has the Dove Press Publisher remained?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Dove had three founders all of whom were involved in the negotiations. They have left the business, but almost all of the staff have remained. Dove has a very loyal staff, and it seems has much lower staff turnover than other publishing companies I have worked in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Unfortunately, you didn’t answer my question about the Dove Press Publisher Tim Hill. Is he still with the company? You also did not say whether the Dove MD Graeme Peterson was involved in the negotiations. I would be grateful if you could address these questions? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; The founders of the company were Philip Smith, Kevin Toale and Tim Hill, all of whom have left the company, and with whom we negotiated. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Philip Smith was Managing Director of Dove. Graeme Peterson has never been the Managing Director of Dove. When he became a Director of Dove, he was (and still is) Managing Director of Prime Global (previously Prime Medica). The Companies House listing clearly shows that he was Company Secretary and Director of Dove from 2004 to 2017. His listing shows his occupation as Managing Director, but this was of Prime Global not of Dove.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: You talk of three founders of Dove. When I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2008/11/open-access-interviews-dove-medical.html&quot;&gt;spoke to&lt;/a&gt; Tim Hill in 2008, he told me the company was founded by “a group of former publishing executives, mostly from ADIS International” and that it was owned by “six private individuals”. Companies House records show there were four directors of the company – Graeme Peterson, Philip Smith, Kevin Toale and John Stolz. The shareholders included Peterson, Smith, Toale, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/william-dolben-96b526/&quot;&gt;William Dolben&lt;/a&gt; (CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.contentednet.com/corporate/content/solutions&quot;&gt;ContentEd&lt;/a&gt;, which offers “a complete publishing service for the pharmaceutical industry”), a company called JSI Communications (a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jsi.co.uk/&quot;&gt;medical communications company&lt;/a&gt; owned by John Stolz, who &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsgroups.derkeiler.com/Archive/Comp/comp.sys.mac.misc/2005-09/msg00037.html&quot;&gt;appears&lt;/a&gt; also to have also acted as a Dove commissioning editor) and the T&amp;amp;A Hill Family Trust (which I assume is connected with Tim Hill). Who were the three founders you talked to?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;As I said above, the company was founded by Kevin Toale, Philip Smith and Tim Hill. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;RP: Was T&amp;amp;F aware at the time it made a bid for Dove how controversial the company was? For instance, Dove was one of the first OA publishers to attract criticism for spamming authors (and was &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/-89XCkRwomfOXnW92SxTN6x?domain=gunther-eysenbach.blogspot.co.uk&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;dubbed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; a “black sheep” by Gunther Eysenbach); it has featured on Retraction Watch fairly regularly; it was at one time on Jeffrey Beall’s list of “Potential, possible, or probable predatory scholarly open-access publishers”; it was caught in the &lt;/i&gt;Science&lt;i&gt; open access &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/6eXJCmZ2EotjP5JzyFPaUzP?domain=science.sciencemag.org&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;sting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; (for which it had its &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/RZdxCn5Yzpc73GOv9C5KQYw?domain=oaspa.org&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;membership of OASPA terminated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;); it got mixed up in the &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/qRp7Co2vOqfrPXqE2t8TftA?domain=poynder.blogspot.co.uk&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Dr Amy Bishop incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;; and one of its peer reviewers &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/bz-FCpYRz0unOzMm4tEpNuO?domain=retractionwatch.com&quot; style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;roundly condemned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; its publishing platform, saying that it did not even allow reviewers to reject papers. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Did any of this concern T&amp;amp;F during the negotiation process? If so, why did it go ahead with the purchase? What exactly does T&amp;amp;F do in terms of due diligence before it acquires another company? Did it go through this process in the case of Dove?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; We went through very detailed due diligence, carrying out an extremely thorough process, when we acquired Dove Medical Press. We were satisfied that, after some historical issues, improvements had been made to their peer review process working with the OASPA membership team. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/dove-medical-press-reinstated-as-oaspa-members/&quot;&gt;led to their OASPA membership being reinstated&lt;/a&gt;, resulted in an extremely robust peer review process described in detail in their peer review schematic on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/editorial_policies.php?content_id=3526&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In fact, some of the additional checks they have added since that schematic was published go way beyond what most publishers do in their peer review process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In addition to the usual ethical checks which quality medical journals perform, these include: checking the affiliations of all authors and checking retractionwatch.com to identify whether any of the authors have been involved in unethical practices; manuscripts being checked for duplicate submission or publication and run through the SciDetect software; and IP address checks to make sure that there is no COI between author, reviewer and Editor. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Due diligence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Publishing a schematic is surely a good idea. What is key, of course, is routinely following that process. But you didn’t answer my question: what exactly does T&amp;amp;F do in the way of due diligence before it acquires another company?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; All papers submitted to Dove go through the same rigorous process which, as I said, is more rigorous than that on the schematic and than many I have seen in other publishers. Any implication that this is not routinely followed is unfounded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as due diligence is concerned, as part of Informa, all acquisitions by Taylor &amp;amp; Francis go through a very detailed and thorough due diligence. Cross-functional teams of experts from Finance, Legal, Tax, Treasury and Communications meet weekly with the business leads to analyse and assess the risks and considerations concerning any acquisition and follow a detailed process. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No acquisition is complete until all questions are answered in detail, and there has been a thorough review by Informa’s senior management. This process was followed with this acquisition. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On Dove’s membership of OASPA: I think it would be fair to say that this has been more of an on-off affair than the above might imply. The timeline is this: Dove joined OASPA in late 2009; Dove withdrew from OASPA on 7th April 2010; Dove applied to join again in May 2012; Dove was re-accepted on 12th July 2012; Dove’s membership was terminated by OASPA on 5th November 2013. Dove reapplied in June 2015 and was accepted on 23rd September 2015.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;What is not clear is why Dove withdrew from OASPA in 2010. What we do know is that it occurred in the wake of the Amy Bishop affair, in which publicity was given to a controversial paper authored by her and published by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/international-journal-of-general-medicine-journal&quot;&gt;Dove’s International Journal of General Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;. Controversially, Bishop added the names of her minor children as co-authors of the paper. At the time (February 2010) I &lt;a href=&quot;https://poynder.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-linked-to-alabama-shooting.html&quot;&gt;wrote an article&lt;/a&gt; about the incident in which I raised the issue of ownership and transparency, and quoted Peter Suber saying, “I am deeply suspicious of publishers who are unwilling to disclose their owners. We need that kind of transparency to be able to investigate whether the owners have financial interests, e.g. with pharma companies, that might compromise the integrity of their journals.” When I asked OASPA for the reason Dove had withdrawn I was told, “We had a few exchanges by email following your article and they then withdrew their membership. I asked them if they could give me a reason but they gave none.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Here it is worth noting that co-founder of OASPA Gunther Eysenbach &lt;a href=&quot;https://oaspa.org/response-to-the-recent-article-in-science/#comment-5201&quot;&gt;has repeatedly alleged&lt;/a&gt; that Dove engages in “questionable publishing practices”. And at the time when OASPA terminated Dove’s membership in 2013 he referred back to the Amy Bishop paper and said that it had disappeared from its website without “any proper retraction notice/process”. (The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/effects-of-selective-serotonin-reuptake-inhibitors-on-motor-neuron-sur-peer-reviewed-article-IJGM&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; appears to have been reposted later, again with no indication of its disappearance and reappearance). This will all be part and parcel of what you call Dove’s “historical issues”, but did none of this really give T&amp;amp;F any pause for thought? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; I have already discussed the very detailed due diligence we went through which satisfied us that there are no issues that should concern us with their operations. And in working closely with Dove in the eight months since the acquisition, I have been impressed by their high standards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is absolutely no evidence of any misconduct on Dove’s part, and despite persistent attempts to find some over the years, it doesn’t seem that you have evidence of any wrongdoing either. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is clear that in the two cases you mention, Bishop and Bohannon, authors who set out to deceive the system managed to do so. This showed up some inadequacies in the peer review processes of those journals. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a result of the Bohannon sting in 2013 and their OASPA membership being terminated, Dove worked closely with OASPA to improve their editorial processes and the OASPA Membership Committee were satisfied with those improvements. As I mentioned earlier, Dove also continue to enhance those processes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: While we are on the historical issues, in 2011 I was contacted by a US-based publisher who said that Dove had on two occasions launched a journal “identical or nearly identical” to this publisher’s own journals. The publisher added that only after a great deal of pressure from them did Dove change the titles of the two copycat journals. The publisher also pointed out that nine of Dove’s journals had the same EiC, many of which journals were unrelated to that EiC’s specialism. I do not know if this is still the case, but can you confirm that Taylor &amp;amp; Francis would not sanction such things? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; None of the current Dove senior management know anything about this allegation. Dove do have Editors-in-Chief who edit more than one journal, but only in their own specialist area and never more than two or three. Taylor &amp;amp; Francis also have some Editors-in-Chief editing multiple journals, but again only in their specific subject field.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;New controversy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: As you note, many of these things may be historical issues. However, it seems that the controversy over Dove continues after the acquisition. Seven months after T&amp;amp;F purchased Dove, for instance, its &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/W64GCqxV2vt8kO0ZYSw9okT?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;International Journal of Women's Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; published &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/I1I7CrkEYwi8nAVEQSwP-n3?domain=dovepress.com&quot;&gt;a paper&lt;/a&gt; that has attracted some worrying criticism – as reported recently by STAT. The paper in question compared patient satisfaction with two competing devices for endometrial ablation, and concluded that the product developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/yfJsCv2YjAf7LWNxwCNJUzh?domain=minervasurgical.com&quot;&gt;Minerva Surgical&lt;/a&gt; was inferior to the competing product developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/RbqrCwpEkBHGVL8Klin2NQY?domain=hologic.com&quot;&gt;Hologic&lt;/a&gt; (which funded the study). On April 26th Minerva published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/weEmCxkVlDi1RJMkEU6eZLm?domain=prnewswire.com&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; alleging that the Dove article makes “material misleading statements” about the nature of the study and that this is “a clear violation of the COPE guidelines”. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Writing in STAT, Adam Marcus and Ivan Oransky say, “We can’t judge the essence of Minerva’s claims, although some — particularly that paid personnel for a device maker biased the selection process for patients in the trial — are quite troubling and would constitute grounds for retraction.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;When I raised this on Twitter, T&amp;amp;F &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/D8IeCyP6mEtr2NXZOtmXtBv?domain=twitter.com&quot;&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; that it was “currently working with the editor-in-chief to look into the concerns surrounding this paper”. But in light of Dove’s history does it not cause you some concern that this has occurred not long after the acquisition?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; It is an unfortunate fact of life that all publishers are having to field more and more disputes between academics and researchers. It is keeping COPE very busy, and there are few journals or publishers who have avoided being featured on Retraction Watch’s pages. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the case of the &lt;i&gt;International Journal of Women’s Health&lt;/i&gt; paper our investigations show that the peer review was carried out to high standards and that the journal behaved well, and the authors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; responses have satisfied us that the complaints are unfounded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As per ethical guidelines, we have offered the complainant the chance to write a Letter to the Editor with his concerns, which we would publish along with a response from the authors. However, he has not chosen to do so as yet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Can I just check what you are saying: you see nothing untoward or unusual in a publisher appearing fairly frequently on Retraction Watch? And are you implying that the cases COPE deals with are generally the result of disputes between academics and researchers, not of misconduct, faulty peer review or conflicts of interest?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; Actually, I don’t. The fact that publishers are amending the scholarly record when they find that there are errors in the literature is a healthy thing. I would be worried if a publisher never retracted anything. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/why-high-profile-journals-have-more-retractions-1.15951&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; in Nature shows that journals with higher impact factors have higher levels of retractions, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/why-high-profile-journals-have-more-retractions-1.15951&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; suggests that higher levels of retractions may in fact be a good thing. In fact, this second paper finds that the rising number of retractions is most likely to be caused by a growing propensity to retract flawed and fraudulent papers, and there is little evidence of an increase in the prevalence of misconduct. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;And no, you are misinterpreting my previous comment. The cases COPE see fall into nine areas, as outlined in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicationethics.org/core-practices&quot;&gt;core practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On the issue of COIs: My understanding is that the MD of Dove was also the MD of a Medical Education and Communication Companies (MECC), and so presumably was engaged in publication planning. As I noted above, two of the other shareholders appear to have been running MECCs and/or providing publication services for pharmaceutical companies. Do you think that being a shareholder and/or MD of a medical publisher while also being the shareholder and MD or owner of a MECC might raise conflict of interest issues?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; This is a misunderstanding on your part. The MD of Dove was Philip Smith who did not run any other company. As for the shareholders, shareholders in any organization will have a number of interests. None of the shareholders you refer to played an active role in the organization or its operations. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;COIs?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: In March 2017 Dove &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prweb.com/releases/dove-press/nanomedicine-academy/prweb14143325.htm&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it was sponsoring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.northeastern.edu/nanomedicineacademy/&quot;&gt;The Nanomedicine Academy of Minority Serving Institutions at Northeastern University&lt;/a&gt;. The Director and co-founder of this Academy is listed as being on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/journal-editor-international-journal-of-nanomedicine-eic5&quot;&gt;editorial board&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/international-journal-of-nanomedicine-journal&quot;&gt;The International Journal of Nanomedicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;, which is a Dove journal and has an impact factor of 4.300. Its website also says that it is indexed in PubMed and Medline. As such, it would seem to be one of the journals that attracted T&amp;amp;F to Dove (In fact, it was singled out for mention in the Informa &lt;a href=&quot;https://informa.com/media/press-releases-news/latest-news/informa-extends-open-access-position-and-capability-with-addition-of-dove-medical-press/&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; you cited earlier). The EiC of the journal is the other &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.che.neu.edu/news/faculty/368?page=8&quot;&gt;co-founder&lt;/a&gt; of the Nanomedicine Academy, and appears to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/search_results.php?search_word=%22thomas+j+webster%22&quot;&gt;published over 100 papers&lt;/a&gt; with Dove, almost exclusively (if not exclusively) in his own journal (two of the papers seem to have been co-authored with the Director of The Academy). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;I must assume that T&amp;amp;F would have established this during the due diligence process it undertook, and so is comfortable with the arrangement. But I cannot help but think that some would feel it raises conflict of interest issues. What would you say to those who might be concerned about it? Or am I simply misunderstanding the situation and how these things work?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Journals and Publishers often sponsor conferences and educational courses of various types. I think that if you look at the Academy, you will see that it is an academic partnership dedicated to providing education in nanomedicine to minority populations. This sounds like a great educational initiative, and I cannot see any COI from a Publisher donating to an initiative of this kind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;As far as the Editor publishing in his own journal is concerned, COPE guidelines do not preclude editors submitting to their own journals. They do expect journals to “have a procedure for handling submissions from editors or members of the editorial board that will ensure that the peer review is handled independently of the author/editor”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dovepress.com/editorial_policies.php?content_id=3523&quot;&gt;clear guidance&lt;/a&gt; on Editors publishing in their own journals whereby “Editors-in-Chief must declare any financial and/or personal conflict of interest for each submitted manuscript, and decisions on manuscripts in which they have a conflict of interest will be made by another editor”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No Dove Editor is involved in the peer review of a paper that they are author on, and this is the case with the papers published by this editor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: After SAGE bought Dove’s sister company Libertas Academica it had to &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/ImX0CzpBnGHMwRg6WCLIc6L?domain=plus.google.com&quot;&gt;conclude&lt;/a&gt; that following “detailed review” it was unlikely that many of LA’s journals would be successful over the long-term. As a result, it shuttered over ¼ of those it had acquired. I wonder if Dove might have to do the same. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;On Twitter T&amp;amp;F &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-us.mimecast.com/s/D8IeCyP6mEtr2NXZOtmXtBv?domain=twitter.com&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; “When any list joins T&amp;amp;F we go through an integration phase where we check on all processes and standards and integrate / amalgamate the best of what both orgs do. This is a process that has happened with Dove and is on-going.” Do you anticipate having to close many Dove journals? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; As I said earlier, Libertas Academica had no connection with Dove and was not a sister company so there is no comparison between the two companies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;It is good publishing practice to regularly review the journals portfolio, and make changes accordingly. Dove had done this review prior to become part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis and had decided to cease the publication of some journals which were not receiving enough quality submissions to sustain them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;We reviewed this list together and agreed with their plans. Some of these journals were closed prior to the acquisition but not all had gone through the process by that point, so some are currently being closed. At the end of this process 92 journals will remain. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: large;&quot;&gt;Journal closures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: We may disagree over the definition of a sister company, but as noted earlier, the former MD of Libertas Academica is the son of Tim Hill. And according to New Zealand Companies House it was Tim Hill who registered LA, and he was listed as a shareholder until at least 2009. Does that not suggest to you that the companies were connected?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;  Please see my previous response on this. No Dove staff, now and previously, have ever been involved in the direction or operations of Libertas Academica.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: On the issue of journal closures, Wikipedia reports that in 2013 Dove published 131 journals. Unless I am miscounting, the Dove website currently lists 136 journals. This would seem to suggest that 44 (32%) of them are due to be closed – which is a higher percentage than were closed at LA. Is it normal for such a high percentage of journals to be closed after an acquisition? Is T&amp;amp;F still confident that it got value for money in buying Dove?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;DK: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dove Press has launched 136 journals in the last 14 years. Some of these were not successful and were closed. It is not uncommon for this to be the case, and for publishers to close journals which are not thriving. When we acquired Dove they were publishing 109 journals, and we were aware of and agreed with their plans to close 17 of them. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eight months on from our acquisition, Dove are performing well in all areas, we remain confident that we got value for money, and are delighted that they are part of Taylor &amp;amp; Francis Group.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;RP: Thank you for answering my questions. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;MsoPlainText&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
	<author>noreply@blogger.com (Richard Poynder)</author>
  <source url="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/7961882/posts/default">Open and Shut?</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: OpenStreetMap Should Be a Priority for the Open Source Community | Linux Journal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/openstreetmap-should-be-priority-open-source-community</guid>
	<link>https://www.linuxjournal.com/content/openstreetmap-should-be-priority-open-source-community</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The good news is that OpenStreetMap provides exactly the right foundation for creating those open map-based services, which is why supporting it must become a priority for the Open Source world.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Job Application for Research Scientist at Wikimedia Foundation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://boards.greenhouse.io/wikimedia/jobs/1173279?gh_src=a41847991</guid>
	<link>https://boards.greenhouse.io/wikimedia/jobs/1173279?gh_src=a41847991</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;As a research scientist at the Wikimedia Foundation, you will work with researchers, software engineers, designers, and volunteers to design, test and evaluate new technologies. You will produce empirical insights to inform the organization’s and the movement’s efforts towards our strategic direction—to become the platform that serves open knowledge to the world and to empower all people to access and contribute to free knowledge. You will turn research questions into publicly shared, reproducible knowledge and work with a team that is strongly committed to principles of transparency, privacy and collaboration. You will use and develop free and open source technology and collaborate with researchers in the industry and academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a research scientist with our team, you will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Conduct research involving experimental design, labeled data collection, large-scale data analysis and data mining, statistical modeling as well as the application and online/offline evaluation of machine learning methods&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the design, execution, and communication of research projects&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Discuss, document and share the process and results of your research publicly&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Actively engage in a collaborative, consensus-oriented environment and as part of a globally-distributed organization&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: BMC Biomedical Engineering: the BMC series expands into engineering! - Research in progress blog</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcblog/2018/06/12/bmc-biomedical-engineering-the-bmc-series-expands-into-engineering/</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcblog/2018/06/12/bmc-biomedical-engineering-the-bmc-series-expands-into-engineering/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am delighted to announce that BMC Biomedical Engineering, a new open access, peer-reviewed journal is now open for submissions and with it the BMC series enters for the first time a new subject area: engineering.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: BMC enters the world of chemical engineering - Research in progress blog</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcblog/2018/06/12/bmc-enters-the-world-of-chemical-engineering/</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcblog/2018/06/12/bmc-enters-the-world-of-chemical-engineering/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;As part of Springer Nature’s dedication to advancing discovery, BMC is expanding its scope beyond biology and medicine into the physical sciences and engineering. BMC Chemical Engineering is a new, open access, peer reviewed, community journal in chemical engineering.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open science &amp; the Humanities, Barcelona 21 June – Archaeological Networks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://archaeologicalnetworks.wordpress.com/2018/06/11/open-science-the-humanities-barcelona-21-june/</guid>
	<link>https://archaeologicalnetworks.wordpress.com/2018/06/11/open-science-the-humanities-barcelona-21-june/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Open science &amp;amp; the Humanities, Barcelona 21 June&quot;...&quot;On 21 June there will be a free conference on the topic in Barcelona that promises to provoke some excellent discussion and could be a catalyst for change. Hope to see you there!&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In her short life, mathematician Emmy Noether changed the face of physics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/emmy-noether-theorem-legacy-physics-math</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/emmy-noether-theorem-legacy-physics-math</link>
	<description>A century after she published a groundbreaking mathematical theory, Emmy Noether gets her due.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/062318_noether_opener_opt1.jpg?itok=yAtcz1_e" length="36706" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Toute une bibliothèque de livres de sciences politiques en Open Access</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.actualitte.com/article/patrimoine-education/toute-une-bibliotheque-de-livres-de-sciences-politiques-en-open-access/89312</guid>
	<link>https://www.actualitte.com/article/patrimoine-education/toute-une-bibliotheque-de-livres-de-sciences-politiques-en-open-access/89312</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): A whole library of political science books in Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Le projet réunit quatre partenaires d’envergure, autour d’un modèle de publication en Open Access.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Translation (Google): &quot;The project brings together four major partners around an open access publishing model.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft signs up as a sustainable funder – News Service</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.doaj.org/2018/06/11/deutsche-forschungsgemeinschaft-signs-up-as-a-sustainable-funder/</guid>
	<link>https://blog.doaj.org/2018/06/11/deutsche-forschungsgemeinschaft-signs-up-as-a-sustainable-funder/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;DOAJ is extremely pleased to welcome Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft to the growing list of organisations who have committed funds, via SCOSS, to support DOAJ on its way to a sustainable form of funding and future. DFG has demonstrated a commitment to open access for years and as such, we are very proud to receive their support.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: California Can Lead the Way in Open Access | Electronic Frontier Foundation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/06/california-can-lead-way-open-access</guid>
	<link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2018/06/california-can-lead-way-open-access</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Under A.B. 2192, all peer-reviewed, scientific research funded by the state of California would be made available to the public no later than a year after publication. Under current law, research funded by the California Department of Public Health is covered by an open access law, but that provision is set to expire in 2020. A.B. 2192 would extend it indefinitely and expand it to cover research funded by any state agency.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Open Data Projects | NISO website</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.niso.org/events/2018/06/open-data-projects</guid>
	<link>https://www.niso.org/events/2018/06/open-data-projects</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Projects that are built on top of multiple open data sets are beginning to be more visible to the public. This virtual conference will serve as an expansive tour of a variety of open data projects from academia, local government, and other sectors.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Open Access Tracking Project: Top universities’ journal subscriptions ‘average £4 million’ | Times Higher Education (THE)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timeshighereducation.com/news/top-universities-journal-subscriptions-average-4-million-pounds</guid>
	<link>https://www.timeshighereducation.com/news/top-universities-journal-subscriptions-average-4-million-pounds</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;The data emerge at a time of peak discontent with the rising costs of journals and the slow progress towards open access among the academic community.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://tagteam.harvard.edu/remix/oatp/items.rss">OATP primary</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Open science: 4 ways Elsevier is contributing to a more inclusive world of research</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-4-ways-elsevier-is-contributing-to-a-more-inclusive-world-of-research</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/open-science-4-ways-elsevier-is-contributing-to-a-more-inclusive-world-of-research</link>
	<description>We’re giving researchers more options to share more kinds of information</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Philosophers, meet the plagiarism police. His name is Michael Dougherty.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66539</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/12/philosophers-meet-the-plagiarism-police-michael-dougherty/</link>
	<description>Some researchers spot an issue with a paper, groan inwardly, and move on. Not Michael Dougherty. Over the years, the philosophy professor at Ohio Dominican University has sent us several tips about plagiarized papers, which have led to numerous editorial notices — including a correction to a more than 30-year-old paper written by a cat, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/12/philosophers-meet-the-plagiarism-police-michael-dougherty/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Philosophers, meet the plagiarism police. His name is Michael Dougherty.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: 4 ways we’re making science more collaborative</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-ways-were-making-science-more-collaborative</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/4-ways-were-making-science-more-collaborative</link>
	<description>We’re sharing resources and data to tackle critical challenges in society</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 11:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Sunshine is making Deepwater Horizon oil stick around</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sunshine-making-deepwater-horizon-oil-stick-around</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sunshine-making-deepwater-horizon-oil-stick-around</link>
	<description>Sunlight created oxygen-rich oil by-products that are still hanging around eight years after the Deepwater Horizon spill.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060818_LH_oil-spill_feat.jpg?itok=oaEZpuFi" length="38564" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Yourbrainhealth: Pink or blue brains in the womb?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5544</guid>
	<link>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/pink-or-blue-brains-in-the-womb/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-full wp-image-5545 aligncenter&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/pregnant-2763931_1920.jpg&quot; width=&quot;986&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt from the Introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/book/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness&lt;/a&gt;. Also published in the UK and Ireland as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orionbooks.co.uk/books/detail.page?isbn=9781409173199&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Demystifying the Female Brain. A neuroscientist explores health, hormones and happiness.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mother Nature is selfish. Her one and only goal is for us to have sex to make babies. To ensure dating and mating occurs, the parts of our brain that control reproduction, in particular, the hypothalamus, become ‘masculinised’ or ‘feminised’ to match our male or female gonads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sex hormones organise the prenatal brain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hormones influence how these reproductive brain circuits grow and respond. Prenatal life is the first of two life phases when the brain is super sensitive to sex hormones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We call this early period of hormone exposure the &lt;em&gt;organisational&lt;/em&gt; period, as it organises or programs the brain to respond to hormones in adulthood. Many sex differences that do exist are developmentally organised and then &lt;em&gt;activated,&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;revealed&lt;/em&gt;, by the action of hormones at puberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is the female brain the ‘default’ option?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the prenatal period, the dominating influence is that of testosterone produced by foetal testes. Testosterone helps to ensure that the reproductive regions of the brain in males becomes masculinised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, and in the &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: normal !msorm;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;absence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; of testosterone, brain regions involved in reproductive behaviours in females become feminised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, in the &lt;em&gt;absence&lt;/em&gt; of a Y chromosome, the default developmental option is for the foetus to become a female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Default’ is a term some people find a little dismissive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help unravel the complexities of male versus female prenatal brain development, I called Margaret McCarthy, a professor of neuroscience who studies the effects of hormones on brain development at the University of Maryland School of Medicine. McCarthy is one of the pioneers in the field and conducted some of the first studies on how sex hormones organise the developing brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Default does not mean passive!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCarthy said to me in a tone of voice that had me quickly convinced she’s made that statement more than once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Try using the developing mammalian brain is &lt;em&gt;destined &lt;/em&gt;for a female phenotype, instead.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;absence&lt;/em&gt; of a Y chromosome, all embryos are &lt;em&gt;destined&lt;/em&gt; to become female.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is the role of oestrogen in female brain development?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering, if testosterone ‘masculinises’ the unborn baby boy, what role does oestrogen from foetal ovaries play in ‘feminising’ the unborn baby girl?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, foetal oestrogen plays no role at all. Female embryos do not require ovarian hormones to become feminised (remember, they’re &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: normal !msorm;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;destined &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;to become female). Oestrogen’s role in the developing female brain is thus a by-product of its &lt;em&gt;absence&lt;/em&gt;, rather than presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unborn babies’ brains are also shielded from the influence of maternal oestrogens (made by their mother and the placenta) by a molecule called alpha-fetoprotein, which is made in the liver of an unborn baby. It binds to oestrogen in the bloodstream and prevents maternal oestrogen crossing into the baby’s brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiously, oestrogen is involved in organising the architecture of the &lt;em&gt;male &lt;/em&gt;brain. Testosterone easily passes into unborn baby boy’s brains where it is converted to oestradiol by an enzyme called aromatase. It is now well established the ‘female’ hormone oestradiol is responsible for ‘masculinising’ the male brain in utero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mother Nature is selfish. And she also has a sense of humour.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from Chapter One of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Later in the chapter, I explain why &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; sex differences in achievement in maths, interest in technology subjects or ability in the sciences cannot be attributed to the presence (or absence) of testosterone in the womb. In sum: the role of hormones can enhanced or entirely eliminated by how girls and boys are raised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hachette.com.au/dr-sarah-mckay/female-brain-book&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Find out how to get your copy here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/pink-or-blue-brains-in-the-womb/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pink or blue brains in the womb?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 05:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/">Your Brain Health</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Opportunity rover waits out a huge dust storm on Mars</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/opportunity-rover-waits-out-huge-dust-storm-mars</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/opportunity-rover-waits-out-huge-dust-storm-mars</link>
	<description>NASA’s Opportunity rover is in low-power mode to preserve battery life while a vast dust storm blankets part of the Red Planet.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 21:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/061118_lhg_opportunity_feat_free.jpg?itok=PwtA6_MI" length="32822" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Q&amp;A: Does gender matter in software engineering?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-does-gender-matter-in-software-engineering</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/q-and-a-does-gender-matter-in-software-engineering</link>
	<description>Beth Dickerson, Software Engineer for Elsevier’s Clinical Solutions team, talks about her work and what it takes to advance in technology</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 14:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Does Depression Accelerate Aging?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23735</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/11/does-depression-accelerate-aging/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;A clear association between depression, especially the major depressive disorder, oxidative stress, and accelerated aging is supported by research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression, major depressive disorder more specifically, is one of the most striking problems of modern society. Millions of people worldwide suffer from depression, with many patients not experiencing relief from symptoms. Depression is associated with increased mortality from age-related conditions, such as cardiovascular disease and cancer. Researchers have suggested that depression is associated with increased oxidative stress and a disturbed immune response, which may accelerate aging and increase susceptibility to age-related disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the proven indicators of cellular aging is the length of telomeres. Telomeres are nucleoprotein complexes that cap the end of chromosomal DNA and serve to protect chromosomal integrity. They become shorter with each round of replication and cell division, meaning that normally they become shorter with age. When telomeres reach a critically short length, the cells undergo apoptosis, i.e., programmed death. Leukocyte telomere length has been typically used in clinical studies as a marker of cellular aging. They shortening accelerates in the cells subjected to oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple studies, including some meta-analysis, have questioned the association between leukocyte telomere length and major depressive disorder. For instance, one meta-analysis compared the length of telomeres between depressed and healthy individuals and found significantly shorter telomeres in groups with depression. A very recent prospective study including over 100 participants aged from 18 to 70 with or without major depressive disorder assessed telomere length at baseline and at two years follow-up. The authors concluded that individuals with major depressive disorder at baseline had significantly larger shortening of telomeres over the period of 2 years, supporting the association between depression and accelerated aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major depressive disorder is typically classified as a mental illness, but its pathology is evident in cells throughout the body. According to some researchers, several biological mediators are deregulated in this disorder that contribute to accelerated aging. These changes affect levels of genetic and epigenetic mediators (i.e., the variants of genes), and biochemical mediators such as glucocorticoids and neurosteroids. This can alter immune functions, oxidative processes, and levels of factors regulating the metabolism of glucose and production of insulin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that deregulation of some of these biological mediators leads to oxidative stress, which seems to be highly correlated with the aging process. Oxidative damage occurs when the body can’t cope with psychological and physical stressors. In other words, oxidative stress refers to the excessive production of free radicals that cannot be completely neutralized by the body’s antioxidative mechanisms. Elevated markers of oxidative stress, along with  decreased antioxidant capacity, have been reported in subjects with depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oxidative damage is associated with the aging process, while markers of oxidative stress correlate with the decreased activity of an enzyme called telomerase. This enzyme is responsible for extending the length of telomeres. When telomerase is absent, the telomeres shorten faster. Thus, the link between the depression and accelerated aging can partly be explained by an increased cellular oxidative stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal studies have also been conducted in order to elucidate the mechanisms underlying major depressive disorder-mediated accelerated aging. For instance, in one study, the researchers exposed rats to mild chronic stress in order to induce the symptoms of major depressive disorder. The animals that developed these symptoms were found to have shorter telomeres and decreased telomerase activity, along with an increase in oxidative damage and decreased antioxidant enzyme activity. In addition, damaged mitochondria and reduced mitochondrial DNA content were also reported in rats with depressive symptoms. This research provided clear cellular evidence of accelerated aging associated with major depressive disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group of researchers proposed that early treatment (i.e., in the first half of life) of psychiatric disorders, including depression, could extend life expectancy and significantly reduce the burden of age-related disorders (such as cardiovascular disease, cerebrovascular disease, and cancer). They demonstrated that the persistence of some psychiatric disorder from the ages of 11 to 38 years led to the dose-dependent shortening of telomere length by the age of 38. Analyses of blood samples collected at the age of 26 and 38 revealed an accelerated erosion of telomeric ends in males diagnosed with the psychiatric disorder such as depression. Interestingly, there was no such association in females with a psychiatric disorder in the interim assessment at the age of 26. This research points to the link between psychiatric disorders and accelerated biological aging, which may be particularly emphasized in men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, one study investigated the association between major depressive disorder and age-related changes of the basal ganglia. The basal ganglia are a set of subcortical structures involved in reward processing, which is often dysfunctional in subjects with major depressive disorder. Based on images from the brains of patients with depression and healthy controls, the authors assessed the grey matter volume of basal ganglia in their different parts. They found a negative correlation between the size of the putamen (a region of the basal ganglia located in the base of the forebrain) and age. Importantly, this association was twice as big in patients with major depressive disorder in comparison with healthy subjects. The finding of a greater age-related volume decrease in the depressed subjects, suggests that major depressive syndrome is clearly associated with accelerated aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that although various biochemical mediators are responsible for the clear association between depression and accelerated aging, oxidative stress is the largest contributor to this phenomenon. Thus, it is most likely that cellular oxidative damage caused by different psychological and physical stressors represents the underlying mechanism of depression-related accelerated aging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lin, P.Y., Huang, Y.C., Hung, C.F. (2016) Shortened telomere length in patients with depression: A meta-analytic study. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Psychiatric Research&lt;/em&gt;. 76: 84-93. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2016.01.015&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.jpsychires.2016.01.015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vance, M.C., Bui, E., Hoeppner, S.S., et al. (2018) Prospective association between major depressive disorder and leukocyte telomere length over two years. &lt;em&gt;Psychoneuroendocrinology&lt;/em&gt;. 90: 157-164. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2018.02.015&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.psyneuen.2018.02.015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolkowitz, O.M., Reus, V.I., Mellon, S.H. (2011) Of sound mind and body: depression, disease, and accelerated aging. &lt;em&gt;Dialogues in Clinical Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. 13(1): 25-39. PMID: 21485744&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xie, X., Chen, Y., Ma, L., Shen, Q., Huang, L., Zhao, B., Wu, T., Fu, Z. (2017) Major depressive disorder mediates accelerated aging in rats subjected to chronic mild stress. &lt;em&gt;Behavioural Brain Research&lt;/em&gt;. 329: 96-103. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2017.04.022&quot;&gt;10.1016/j.bbr.2017.04.022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shalev, I., Moffitt, T.E., Braithwaite, A.W., et al. (2014) Internalizing disorders and leukocyte telomere erosion: a prospective study of depression, generalized anxiety disorder, and post-traumatic stress disorder. &lt;em&gt;Molecular Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;. 19(11): 1163-1170. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/mp.2013.183&quot;&gt;10.1038/mp.2013.183&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacchet, M.D., Camacho, M.C., Livermore, E.E., Thomas, E.A.C, Gotlib, I.H. (2017) Accelerated aging of the putamen in patients with major depressive disorder. Journal of Psychiatry and Neuroscience. 42(3): 164-171. PMID: 27749245&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/Snap_it-1125834/&quot;&gt;Snap_it&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new AI can focus on one voice in a crowd</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-ai-can-focus-one-voice-crowd</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-ai-can-focus-one-voice-crowd</link>
	<description>The artificial intelligence can ignore background noise in videos and focus on what a particular person is saying.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_MT_cocktail-party-ai_feat.jpg?itok=bN8Jw5Pl" length="36064" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Have you seen more detail in PLOS ONE retraction notices? You’re welcome</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66471</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/11/have-you-seen-more-detail-in-plos-one-retraction-notices-youre-welcome/</link>
	<description>If you’ve been pausing at some detailed PLOS ONE notices lately — such as one issued last month for a cancer paper that lists 21 shortcomings — you’re not alone. According to a spokesperson for the publisher, the journal has been progressively pushing towards more transparency in its notices — in part, because it was … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/11/have-you-seen-more-detail-in-plos-one-retraction-notices-youre-welcome/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Have you seen more detail in PLOS ONE retraction notices? You’re welcome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: The sun shrinks a teensy bit when it’s feeling active</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-shrinks-teensy-bit-when-its-feeling-active</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/sun-shrinks-teensy-bit-when-its-feeling-active</link>
	<description>The radius of the sun gets slightly smaller during periods of high solar activity, researchers say.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060618_EC_sun-shrinking_feat.jpg?itok=BvQEmW6b" length="23684" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Reverse Nearest Neighbor Queries: emergence and implementation issues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-06-11:/2018/06/11/on-reverse-nearest-neighbor-queries-emergence-and-implementation-issues.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/06/11/on-reverse-nearest-neighbor-queries-emergence-and-implementation-issues.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;K-Nearest Neighbor, KNN is well-known tool in data mining. KNN query returns objects in a data set that are nearest to a query object-q.  One of the shortcomings of KNN is that it is asymmetric. That is, the fact that a query point q has a data point p as its nearest neighbor does not imply that p’s nearest neighbor is q.  There may be the case in decision support system where we concern on finding influence set for a query object q. For example, opening  a new outlet of company A at particular location is more based on the segment of customers of company B ( competitor of A) who are likely to find new outlet more convenient that the location of B.  Such segments of customers can loosely refer as influence set and the reverse relationship is addressed by reverse nearest neighbor, RNN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Deepak will go through some of the papers on the implementation of RNN queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 15/06/2018 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 16:00 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: LB252&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 09:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: &quot;The Love of Neuroscience&quot; and the Neuroscience of Love</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9552</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9552</link>
	<description>There is a growing research literature on the 'Neuroscience of Love'. But what exactly is this 'love' that is being studied?





Sociologist Gabriel Abend asks these questions in a new paper called The Love of Neuroscience published in Sociological Theory. Last year I discussed one of Abend's previous papers which asked more general questions about how neuroscientists define the objects they study. In the new paper, Abend looks specifically at 'love' and how this word has been understood</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 15:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Scientists citing themselves; gender and clinical trials; jail after plagiarism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66482</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/09/weekend-reads-scientists-citing-themselves-gender-and-clinical-trials-jail-after-plagiarism/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction Watch featured allegations of text reuse by a Harvard professor, news about … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/09/weekend-reads-scientists-citing-themselves-gender-and-clinical-trials-jail-after-plagiarism/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Scientists citing themselves; gender and clinical trials; jail after plagiarism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 13:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Kids with food allergies are twice as likely to have autism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/kids-food-allergies-are-twice-likely-have-autism</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/kids-food-allergies-are-twice-likely-have-autism</link>
	<description>Children with food allergies are more likely to have autism than kids without, a study finds. But that doesn’t mean a child will develop the disorder.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 20:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_AC_autism-food-allergy_feat.jpg?itok=6S9rrvxe" length="41763" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: If you thought the most recent flu season was bad, you were right</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-thought-most-recent-flu-season-was-bad-you-were-right</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-you-thought-most-recent-flu-season-was-bad-you-were-right</link>
	<description>The recent U.S. flu season was classified as highly severe overall, the third time since 2003 that the seasonal outbreak has earned that designation.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_AC_flu-season_feat.jpg?itok=EV1PMcXz" length="38449" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: PLOS ONE and Children’s Tumor Foundation partnership announce second cycle of DDIRR Awards</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8233</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/C33JDGXkqLE/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;The Children’s Tumor Foundation (CTF), the largest non-governmental funder of neurofibromatosis (NF) research, and PLOS ONE, a leading peer-reviewed scientific journal, are pleased to announce the successful completion of the first funding cycle of the Drug Discovery Initiative Registered Report (DDIRR) 2017 Awards, a funder-publisher partnership integrating the Registered Reports model into the grant application process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered Reports pre-determine the research questions, methodology and design of a study to be carried out, and are designed to enhance the rigor, reproducibility and transparency of the science produced. CTF and PLOS ONE partnered together to review the 2017 DDIRR applications and granted three awards: Dr. Andrea McClatchey of Massachusetts General Hospital, Dr. Lei Xu of Massachusetts General Hospital, and Dr. Aaron Schindeler from the University of Sydney. The researchers also obtained an in-principle acceptance (IPA) to publication in the journal PLOS ONE. Provided the study is conducted according to plan, acceptance in principle is honored regardless of study outcome – thereby eliminating publication bias and maximizing the transparency of the funded work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reports are being placed on the Open Science Framework registered report portal (&lt;a href=&quot;https://osf.io/rr/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://osf.io/rr/&lt;/a&gt;), where authors will have the opportunity to make public or embargo their reports until publication of results. The awards have a duration of 12 months and will conclude in May 2019. As soon as results are added to the registered report, PLOS ONE will review compliance with the proposed protocol and publish their results, even if they are negative. By securing publication before they start their research, applicants can eliminate the bias of a result-based approach. The process was designed to maintain independence of funding and publishing decisions, while at the same time optimizing processes, thereby avoiding duplication and preventing research waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new award constitutes an evolution of the Drug Discovery Initiative (DDI) Awards that CTF had introduced in 2006 as a funding program for promising ideas that could lead to larger studies or move drugs into the clinic. Feedback on the new DDIRR program from both applicants and reviewers has been unanimously positive, and the Foundation together with PLOS ONE editors have also announced a new cycle for DDIRR in 2018-2019. The Foundation will invite applicants to submit their proposals starting on September 24, 2018, with the anticipated assignment of new awards in the first quarter of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The overall outcome of this first round of DDIRR has been very positive. Reviewers have focused their attention to protocols and study designs, allowing researchers to have their statistics ready for publication,” said Salvatore La Rosa, Ph.D., Vice President of Research and Development for the Children’s Tumor Foundation. “As this particular grant program focuses on hypothesis-testing research, the quality and rigor of the applications are critical to soundly move proof-of-concept experiments from the lab into the clinic. This new program increases our ability to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted to continue our collaboration with CTF on the Registered Reports model for the DDI Awards. We hope this can serve as a model for other funders. The Registered Reports provide researchers with peer reviewed study designs and an in-principle acceptance of the completed study at PLOS ONE. The deposited reports at the Open Science Framework portal ensure full transparency of the research project – a win for everyone involved,” adds Joerg Heber, Editor-in-Chief of PLOS ONE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctf.org/news/first-funding-cycle-of-the-ddirr-awards-announced&quot;&gt;First Funding Cycle of the Drug Discovery Initiative Registered Report (DDIRR) Awards Announced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/C33JDGXkqLE&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 14:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Journals flag two papers by prominent researcher — who is also on trial for domestic abuse</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66452</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/08/journals-flag-two-papers-by-prominent-researcher-who-is-also-on-trial-for-domestic-abuse/</link>
	<description>Adeel Safdar was once a rising star in the field of kinesiology. After completing his doctorate degree at McMaster University in Canada, working with one of the titans of his field, Safdar took a postdoc at Harvard, then accepted a newly created chair position at another university in Ontario. That all came crashing down last … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/08/journals-flag-two-papers-by-prominent-researcher-who-is-also-on-trial-for-domestic-abuse/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Journals flag two papers by prominent researcher — who is also on trial for domestic abuse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: This theory suggests few workers were needed to cap Easter Island statues</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/theory-workers-easter-island-statues-hats</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/theory-workers-easter-island-statues-hats</link>
	<description>A small workforce may have put huge stones on the heads of Easter Island statues.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_bb_pukao_feat.jpg?itok=mp78Nx9r" length="35619" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OUPblog - Psychology and Neuroscience: Studying mass murder</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.oup.com/?p=138474</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/550863108/0/oupblogpsychology/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;In the twentieth century, 40 to 60 million defenseless people were massacred in episodes of genocide. The 21st century is not faring much better, with mass murder ongoing e.g. in Myanmar and Syria. Many of these cases have been studied well, both in detailed case studies and in comparative perspectives, but studying mass murder is no picnic. Scholars have also examined how &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.ucpress.edu/book.php?isbn=9780520089945&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;conducting research&lt;/a&gt;, including ethnographic fieldwork, archival investigation, and oral history interviews, can affect the researcher in profound ways. Among a broader set of difficulties that obstruct research on this wretched subject, two stand out in particular: political constraints and psychological attrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political constraints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All social research operates in a dense political field. Of all the political actors constraining research on mass murder, states stand out. They often have a vested interest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://books.google.nl/books?id=A0QlDwAAQBAJ&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;misrepresenting the truth&lt;/a&gt;, because for many, the memory of a genocide (or its denial), is part and parcel of their collective identity. States that consider themselves heirs to perpetrator regimes, such as Turkey, Russia, Indonesia, China, or Serbia, make great effort to influence the scholarship on episodes of mass violence. They deny access to archival collections and libraries, intimidate and prohibit them from conducting field work. (The opposite is also possible: governments may try to foster or manipulate research by funding politically useful research, by pushing for the establishment of academic chairs at home or abroad, or by offering scholarships.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having to contend with the taboos, restrictions, prescriptions, and outright threats of authoritarian regimes keeps scholars working on these topics under &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ssqu.2016.97.issue-4/issuetoc&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;permanent threat&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers bold enough to travel into these societies to visit sites, uncover evidence, interview witnesses, and have got to fear the security services and intelligence agencies of these states. One consequence of this discouraging atmosphere is that, in general, less research is carried out on those instances and episodes of mass murder, an undesirable blind spot due to the importance of the events. (Some researchers ingratiate themselves with the authorities for privileged access.) A second consequence poses a methodological dilemma: due to such constraints, does one launch a sting operation, like undercover journalism? Or does one use informants, fixers, and mediators on the ground? Does one pay the possible interviewees for taking the risks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt; We may not be willing or able to change our research topics, but we do need our colleagues and audience to be aware of these challenges. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological consequences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are significant emotional consequences of studying mass murder. All social research also operates in a dense emotional and moral field. As a general problem in the academy, involvement and detachment has been dealt with at some length, but the study of mass violence is particularly relevant from this perspective. Though a certain amount of passion and involvement can facilitate one’s commitment to the topic, it requires a great deal of detachment to sift through documents and memoirs containing very intimate details of killing. Detachment is even more challenging in &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~www.upenn.edu/pennpress/book/14525.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ethnographic fieldwork and oral history interviews&lt;/a&gt;, as empathy can transmit to scholars the interviewees’ powerful negative emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the Syrian crisis, I began interviewing Syrians about their experiences with violence, as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://niod.nl/en/news/new-research-project-syrians%E2%80%99-experiences-mass-violence-and-dynamic-violent-conflict&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a large-scale oral history project&lt;/a&gt; we are launching in the Netherlands. Having interviewed about 80 survivors and eye witnesses so far, their emotions of anger, sadness, fear, survivor guilt, and anxiety has affected me irreversibly. These types of interviews can be an alienating and isolating experience: the more one is absorbed into the stories of the eye witnesses, the more one is also drawn into their emotions. As a general rule of thumb, I felt compassion when interviewing victims, and indignation when interviewing perpetrators. But the interviews left a mark long after I stopped recording. When one young woman from Aleppo told me that she was raped in an ambush and witnessed a beheading up close, I was aghast at that moment. Ever since, I have not mustered my courage to go over those particular interview transcripts and notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the risks of political threats and psychological attrition need to be taken seriously by academic institutions, journals, and colleagues. These constraints can produce setbacks and potentially lower productivity, even with &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2017/11/on-burnout-trauma-erin-jessee/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;appropriate self-care&lt;/a&gt;. We may not be willing or able to change our research topics, but we do need our colleagues and audience to be aware of these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Flowers in a Khmer Rouge jail cell by alex.ch. CC BY 2.0 via &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.flickr.com/photos/alex-photos/408951646/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flickr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/studying-mass-murder/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Studying mass murder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/550863108/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/550863108/oupblogpsychology,&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/550863108/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/etymology-gleanings-may-2018-part-2/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Etymology gleanings: May 2018 [Part 2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/safe-supportive-schools-lgbtq-gnc-students/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/plastic-pollution/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What you need to know about plastic pollution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 09:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/">OUPblog » Psychology</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Suicide rates have shot up in almost every U.S. state</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/suicide-rates-have-shot-almost-every-us-state</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/suicide-rates-have-shot-almost-every-us-state</link>
	<description>Suicide rates increased sharply in nearly all 50 states from 1999 to 2016, according to a new government report.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 22:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_AC_suicide-rates-rising_feat.jpg?itok=Hd4YnGg_" length="40430" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Bees join an exclusive crew of animals that get the concept of zero</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bees-join-exclusive-crew-animals-get-concept-zero</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/bees-join-exclusive-crew-animals-get-concept-zero</link>
	<description>Honeybees can pass a test of ranking ‘nothing’ as less than one.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 20:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060718_SM_honeybees_feat.jpg?itok=-wsknmeh" length="16508" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Why using genetic genealogy to solve crimes could pose problems</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-police-using-genetic-geneaology-solve-crimes-poses-problems</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/why-police-using-genetic-geneaology-solve-crimes-poses-problems</link>
	<description>Rules governing how police can use DNA searches in genealogy databases aren’t clear, raising civil rights and privacy concerns.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060618_TS_dna-crime_feat_REV.jpg?itok=no-UMo0B" length="47690" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Curiosity finds that Mars’ methane changes with the seasons</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-finds-mars-methane-changes-seasons</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/curiosity-finds-mars-methane-changes-seasons</link>
	<description>The Curiosity rover found seasonally changing methane in Mars’ atmosphere and more signs of organic molecules in an ancient lake bed.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060618_lg_methane-mars_feat_free.jpg?itok=ushyuJaZ" length="35817" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: In a conservation catch-22, efforts to save quolls might endanger them</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conservation-catch-22-efforts-save-quolls-might-endanger-them</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/conservation-catch-22-efforts-save-quolls-might-endanger-them</link>
	<description>After 13 generations isolated from predators, the endangered northern quoll lost its fear of them.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 16:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060618_lr_quoll_feat.jpg?itok=SZwUaggX" length="44998" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: Science Exchange First &amp; Only R&amp;D Outsourcing Platform to Achieve HIPAA Compliance</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1355</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/science-exchange-first-only-rd-outsourcing-platform-to-achieve-hipaa-compliance/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/HIPAA-PR-Social-Image-1200x628.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;HIPAA Compliance at Science Exchange&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1356&quot; height=&quot;156&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/HIPAA-PR-Social-Image-1200x628-300x156.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;HIPAA Compliance Demonstrates Commitment by Science Exchange to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Protection and Privacy of Protected Health Information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;PALO ALTO CA, June 7, 2018 –&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Science Exchange&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; today announced that it is the first R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform to achieve HIPAA compliance as required by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services under 45 C.F.R. 164. This achievement demonstrates the company’s commitment to the protection and privacy of Protected Health Information (PHI) as defined by 45 CFR §160.103 and shared by its customers and scientific research providers on the Science Exchange platform. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; “Protecting sensitive patient health information is a top priority for our clients and research providers,” said Elizabeth Iorns, Ph.D., co-founder and CEO of Science Exchange. “Achieving HIPAA compliance was a crucial step for Science Exchange, given the increasing portability and complexity of data processed by our software platform.”  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;HIPAA and HITECH: Noncompliance costing millions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) and the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health (HITECH) Act limit the disclosure of patient PHI, including data processed by any provider, technology platform, or other contractor. Since 2010, enforcement of HIPAA and HITECH has increased — with individual fines for noncompliance as high as $2 million. HIPAA compliance helps protect Science Exchange’s clients from these potential consequences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Science Exchange achieved HIPAA compliance by:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Establishing Business Associate Agreements for proper use and disclosure of PHI: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Business Associate Agreements are required agreements between covered entities and their business associates, such as Science Exchange, whose activities involve access to PHI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Implementing administrative, physical and technical safeguards against improper disclosures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Training every employee on protecting information subject to HIPAA and HIPAA requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Adopting best practices for limiting information use and sharing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Industry leaders in data privacy, security, and quality assurance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In addition to being the only HIPAA-compliant R&amp;amp;D outsourcing platform, Science Exchange is also the only outsourcing platform to have earned EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework certification. This certification ensures compliance with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/gdpr-plan&quot;&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) regulations&lt;/a&gt; that went into effect on May 25, 2018, thereby protecting the many R&amp;amp;D organizations that have enterprise-level agreements with Science Exchange. Science Exchange is also SOC 2-compliant and ISO 9001-certified.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about how Science Exchange protects your data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceexchange.com/enterprise#security&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Learn More&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1357&quot; height=&quot;41&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/LEARN-MORE-button-e1528384407482.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 15:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: At-home telomere testing is not a reliable marker of aging, researcher says</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/home-telomere-testing-not-reliable-marker-aging-researcher-says</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/home-telomere-testing-not-reliable-marker-aging-researcher-says</link>
	<description>Telomere testing for consumers offers a poor measure of “biological age,” says Johns Hopkins oncologist Mary Armanios.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/052418_CV_notebook_soapbox_feat.jpg?itok=IcvBPxKx" length="19922" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Elsevier CIO in Forbes: “Machine learning is the catalyst, but …”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-cio-in-forbes-machine-learning-is-the-catalyst-but</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/elsevier-cio-in-forbes-machine-learning-is-the-catalyst-but</link>
	<description>CIO Hall of Famer Dan Olley talks about tech trends, symbiotic technology – and a new era of “augmented intelligence”</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 13:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Karolinska told a journal to retract a paper by Macchiarini. It refused. The story didn’t end there.</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66417</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-told-a-journal-to-retract-a-paper-by-macchiarini-it-refused-the-story-didnt-end-there/</link>
	<description>The president of the Karolinska Institutet (KI) is frustrated. At the beginning of the year, Ole Petter Ottersen informed a journal that one of its papers — co-authored by former superstar Paolo Macchiarini — had been tainted by misconduct. But the journal declined to retract it. Despite the fact that KI had conducted its own … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-told-a-journal-to-retract-a-paper-by-macchiarini-it-refused-the-story-didnt-end-there/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska told a journal to retract a paper by Macchiarini. It refused. The story didn’t end there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: 50 years ago, NASA astronauts prepared to return to space</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-astronauts-prepared-return-space</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/50-years-ago-nasa-astronauts-prepared-return-space</link>
	<description>Apollo 7 crewmembers underwent their first major tests 50 years ago. Today, U.S. astronauts struggle to get into space.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/042619_dg_50ya_apollo.jpg?itok=ySbQYCvr" length="41845" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: Karolinska gets taught German medical ethics</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24388</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-gets-taught-german-medical-ethics/</link>
	<description>A most bizarre thing happened. In the aftermath of the scandal around the thoracic surgeon and regenerative medicine enthusiast Paolo Macchiarini, which left many patients dead, his former employer Karolinska Institutet (KI) in Stockholm, Sweden, requested a retraction of one of his papers. It was not about a trachea transplant, but about unethical and painful … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/07/karolinska-gets-taught-german-medical-ethics/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Karolinska gets taught German medical ethics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>OUPblog - Psychology and Neuroscience: Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.oup.com/?p=138297</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/550638442/0/oupblogpsychology/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Within its first month, the Trump administration revoked federal guidelines designed to promote protections for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or gender non-conforming youth (LGBTQ-GNC) public school students. This move received significant media attention, much of which focused on the challenges of growing up LGBTQ-GNC, and the unique role of schools as places that should be safe and supportive for all students. At issue is defining the rights of students to be protected based on LGBT-GNC identity or status. And yet these rights are regularly compromised through: harassment and victimization that is unchecked; unfair, punitive, and exclusionary discipline practices; and unequal access to supports, services, and curriculum that validate their identities and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The groundbreaking study, &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://www.hrw.org/reports/2001/uslgbt/toc.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hatred in the Hallways&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;documented pervasive human rights violations perpetrated against LGBT youth in US schools. More recently, through an international convening and report, The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) firmly documented homophobic and transphobic violence as a global issue that has critical implications for positive development, health, and academic success of children and adolescence. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~en.unesco.org/themes/school-violence-and-bullying/homophobic-transphobic-violence&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UNESCO report&lt;/a&gt; argued that bullying generally, and bullying related to sexual orientation and gender identity (SOGI) specifically, comprise a threat to the universal right to education established in the 1948 Universal Declaration of Human Rights by the United Nations. This groundbreaking report provided a comprehensive review of the international literature on SOGI-related bullying in schools and documented the disproportionate rates of bullying for LGBTQ-GNC youth in countries on every continent across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these social and cultural norms and conventions impact the rights of all LGBTQ-GNC people, they are especially salient in relation to young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the landscape regarding human rights affordances, constraints, and abuses related to sexual orientation and gender identity (SOGI) is constantly in flux, any discussion of the SOGI rights of young people must take into account this larger global context. The rights of LGBTQ-GNC youth in countries where the expression of same-sex sexuality is criminalized are virtually non-existent; further, human rights violations against LGBTQ-GNC youth occur within most countries across the globe and are often justified by cultural and social norms and conventions regarding “acceptable or normal” definitions of sexuality and gender. While these social and cultural norms and conventions impact the rights of all LGBTQ-GNC people, they are especially salient in relation to young people. While several advances have been made in the last decade to advance the rights of LGBTQ-GNC people across the globe (for example see the 2006 Yogykarta Principles and the 2011 Human Rights Council’s resolution on LGBTQ-GNC rights) these documents rarely attend to specific SOGI rights of &lt;em&gt;young people&lt;/em&gt; or put forth any particular considerations regarding children and youth (a notable exception is in relation to access to education).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding intersecting forms of oppression—such as the ways that structural oppression related to gender and sexuality and its intersections with race, ethnicity, class, and religion affect young people, their parents, and educators in schools—is essential for designing and implementing effective processes, strategies, programs, and advocacy aimed at creating positive change within school contexts. Many of the SOGI-related inequities evidenced in schools can be traced, in part, to narrow definitions of masculinity and femininity, rigid frameworks regarding gender and gender roles, and hegemonic structures in schools that mark heterosexuality as not only compulsory but also the sole valid expression of sexuality. Other forms of structural oppression rooted in racism, religious, or social class bias, are intertwined with SOGI issues in schools through inequitable discipline practices, religious control of public education, or economic disparities across schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because SOGI issues in schools are embedded within larger systems of oppression, it is critical that research, practice, and policy engage with social justice and anti-oppressive education frameworks. Such approaches bring to the fore the ways that power, privilege, and bias structure schools in ways that tacitly sanction a range of educational inequities such as bullying, access to resources and services, and safety for young people in relation to sexual orientation and gender identity. As we continue to do this work, it has become increasingly evident that the SOGI safe schools movement is “inextricably linked” to broader education justice concerns. It is critical for the safe schools movement to work with others through intersectional, multi-issue coalitions—at the nexus of research, policy and practice—to ensure that all students’ educational rights, regardless of social position, are upheld. This type of cross-issue organizing, advocacy, and research takes time and needs to be grounded in the principals of the worth and dignity of all people, and that ensuring the rights of specific groups expands the rights of everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Featured image credit: Class by NeONBRAND. Public domain via &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://unsplash.com/photos/zFSo6bnZJTw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/safe-supportive-schools-lgbtq-gnc-students/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Safe and supportive schools for LGBTQ-GNC students&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/t/0/0/oupblogpsychology/~https://blog.oup.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;OUPblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; hspace=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/550638442/0/oupblogpsychology&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; float: left; margin: 0; padding: 0; width: 1px!important; height: 1px!important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear: both; padding-top: 0.2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/2/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/28/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/30/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/googleplus20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/16/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/linkedin20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/29/550638442/oupblogpsychology,&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/pinterest20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/1/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/reddit20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/24/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/twitter20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/19/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedblitz.com/_/20/550638442/oupblogpsychology&quot;&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;20&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0; margin: 0; padding: 0;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;clear: left; padding-top: 10px;&quot;&gt;Related Stories&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/stroboscopic-medicine/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Stroboscopic medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/defining-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Defining a network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.oup.com/2018/06/double-helix-editing-levels-scientific-paper/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Levels of editing of a scientific paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 09:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://blog.oup.com/category/science_medicine/psychology/feed/">OUPblog » Psychology</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: There are benefits to prenatal yoga, but lingering questions remain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/there-are-benefits-prenatal-yoga-lingering-questions-remain</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/growth-curve/there-are-benefits-prenatal-yoga-lingering-questions-remain</link>
	<description>Prenatal yoga offers benefits to pregnant women, but a bigger and more rigorous body of research is needed.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/052518_ls_gc_yoga_feat_free.jpg?itok=Du-0FohJ" length="28578" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A new 3-D printer builds temporary electronics on your skin</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-3d-printer-builds-temporary-electronics-on-your-skin</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/new-3d-printer-builds-temporary-electronics-on-your-skin</link>
	<description>A new 3-D printer that tracks and compensates for your slightest twitch can precisely print simple electronic devices onto your skin.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060518_MT_3d-printing_feat.jpg?itok=TSrUdYPw" length="22636" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Tropical cyclones have slowed over the last 70 years</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tropical-cyclones-have-slowed-over-last-70-years</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/tropical-cyclones-have-slowed-over-last-70-years</link>
	<description>Tropical cyclones are moving 10 percent slower, on average, than they did in the mid-20th century, potentially making them more dangerous.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 17:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060618_cg_cyclone_feat_free.jpg?itok=aT7gB97b" length="32034" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: If real, dark fusion could help demystify this physics puzzle</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-real-dark-fusion-could-help-demystify-physics-puzzle</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/if-real-dark-fusion-could-help-demystify-physics-puzzle</link>
	<description>Fusing dark matter particles might explain why galaxy cores have evenly distributed dark matter.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 13:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060518_EC_dark-fusion_feat.jpg?itok=Y3uOpl-t" length="38154" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Elsevier Connect: Cancer Essentials — explore research on DNA repair</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elsevier.com/connect/cancer-essentials-dna-repair</guid>
	<link>https://www.elsevier.com/connect/cancer-essentials-dna-repair</link>
	<description>From experimental tools and methods, to pathways and signaling, genome instability, new drugs and clinical translation</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://www.elsevier.com/connect/feed">Elsevier Connect</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Misconduct probe of once rising star prompts retraction of cat’s meow paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66378</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/06/misconduct-probe-of-once-rising-star-prompts-retraction-of-cats-meow-paper/</link>
	<description>A group of Australian researchers who studied the cat’s meow as a model for urinary incontinence and other motor-neural issues in people have lost a 2015 paper in the wake of a misconduct investigation. The target of the inquiry was Hari Subramanian, a former senior research fellow at the Queensland Brain Institute, part of the … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/06/misconduct-probe-of-once-rising-star-prompts-retraction-of-cats-meow-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Misconduct probe of once rising star prompts retraction of cat’s meow paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A big analysis of environmental data strengthens the case for plant-based diets</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-based-diets-greenhouse-gases-environment</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/plant-based-diets-greenhouse-gases-environment</link>
	<description>A new study calculates the bonus for the planet of choosing more foods from plants.</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/053118_sm_foodco2_feat_free.jpg?itok=pMzpFG1x" length="61379" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Dogs carry a surprising variety of flu viruses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dogs-carry-surprising-variety-flu-viruses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/dogs-carry-surprising-variety-flu-viruses</link>
	<description>Dogs in China carry a wider variety of flu viruses than previously thought, and may be capable of passing the flu to humans.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 18:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060518_TS_dog-flu_feat.jpg?itok=WK4LoaV4" length="40727" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What we know — and don’t know — about a new migraine drug</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-we-know-and-dont-know-about-new-migraine-drug</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/what-we-know-and-dont-know-about-new-migraine-drug</link>
	<description>A migraine prevention drug was recently approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. But some questions about the therapy remain.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 18:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060418_LR_migrane_feat.jpg?itok=O3lXC4hk" length="18885" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s a look at the world’s deadliest volcanoes — and the ways they kill</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/worlds-deadliest-volcanoes-and-how-they-kill</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/worlds-deadliest-volcanoes-and-how-they-kill</link>
	<description>Scientists gathered data on nearly 280,000 global volcano deaths from 1500 to 2017 and sorted fatalities by cause of death, such as lava flows or gas.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 17:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060418_aw_guatemalavocano_feat.jpg?itok=fcpsregl" length="33807" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: New Horizons wakes up to begin Kuiper Belt exploration</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-wakes-begin-kuiper-belt-exploration</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/new-horizons-wakes-begin-kuiper-belt-exploration</link>
	<description>The New Horizons spacecraft just woke up to get ready for its New Year’s Day flyby of the distant space rock Ultima Thule.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 14:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/blogposts/060418_LG_new-horizon_feat.jpg?itok=gFLD1c2h" length="16763" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Brain Blogger: Acupuncture and Pain</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainblogger.com/?p=23733</guid>
	<link>http://brainblogger.com/2018/06/05/acupuncture-and-pain/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is one of the oldest systems of traditional medicine. With roots in China, this medical system is more than 2000 years old. It differs from various other medical systems as it does not involve taking any herbs or substances. Instead, it involves inserting small needles at specific predefined points. From the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century onwards, it has continued to gain prominence in the Western world, although many remain skeptical about efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, researchers want to know the exact mechanism of action of any medical system. They only trust the therapy if it has been proven as effective in randomized placebo-controlled clinical trials. Acupuncture has been the subject of many such trials, and its usefulness has been established in certain pain-associated conditions, mood disorders, and even in some diseases of internal organs. This led to the recognition of this medical system by many healthcare providers and medical organizations. In the US, acupuncture is recognized as complementary medicine. The WHO also recommends it for a number of specific medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical evidence of efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of clinical trials provide evidence of &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2014/10/21/the-science-of-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;the effectiveness of acupuncture&lt;/a&gt; in various medical conditions. Among the most relevant trials are the so-called German mega-trials named ARC, ART, COMP, and GERAC. The primary focus of these trials has been pain relief in various musculoskeletal conditions. GERAC and ART were high quality random clinical trials investigating low back pain. These trials compared real acupuncture with sham acupuncture and standard care. Sham acupuncture involved needling without the use of conventional acupuncture points. Whereas standard care included the use of physiotherapy, exercise therapy, and NSAIDs (non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs). Results were measured after three months, and the response was defined as adequate if there was an improvement of more than 33% on the pain scale (the Von Korff Chronic Pain Grade Scale). After 6-months, the response rate with real acupuncture was 47.6%, while it was 44.2% with sham acupuncture, and 27.4% with standard care. Though these trials clearly demonstrated the efficacy of acupuncture, they also showed &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2008/07/29/there-is-no-sham-in-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;the effectiveness of sham acupuncture&lt;/a&gt;. Researchers think that this phenomenon is linked to psychogenic factors involved with back pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, similar results were also demonstrated in various trials in the US. Though these trials show the usefulness of acupuncture in painful conditions, they also illustrate the value of psychogenic factors. Therefore, it is not surprising that acupuncture had also proven its utility in treating mood disorders and sleep disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chinese medicine, the use of acupuncture is not limited to pain-related conditions. Thus, there is need for more extensive trials across a diverse range of diseases. The existing data do indicate that acupuncture may be an alternative approach for many difficult to treat chronic ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possible mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the areas of debate regarding acupuncture has been the difficulty in explaining its mechanism of action. As per traditional explanation, acupuncture is used to correct the flow of energy (Qi) in the body. This life energy flows through the fixed paths or highways in our body called &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2009/02/03/a-primer-on-acupuncture/&quot;&gt;meridians&lt;/a&gt;. Practitioners of acupuncture believe that in disease conditions there is a blockade of energy highways or meridians. Acupuncture is about creating the balance between the internal forces called Yin and Yang. However, the trouble is that modern science is not able to demonstrate or even understand the concepts of Qi, Yin, Yang, and Meridians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few decades, practitioners of modern science have made various attempts to explain the mechanism of action of acupuncture, and they came up with multiple theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurable effects of acupuncture&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the explanations is that needling does cause local changes and alterations in reflexes. It also has systemic effects, as it changes the working of the autonomous nervous system. Thus, acupuncture affects blood pressure, heart rate, levels of various hormones, and changes the levels of neurotransmitters. All of this results in &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/05/01/mind-over-matter-mindfulness-meditation-for-pain-management/&quot;&gt;pain relief&lt;/a&gt; and other beneficial effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local mechanotransduction&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a theory promoted by a French physician in 1961, who wrote that acupuncture points have lower local resistance when compared to surrounding skin. He wrote that while normal dry skin has a resistance of 200,000 to 2 million Ohms, acupuncture points have a resistance of just 50,000 Ohms. The believers in this theory say that acupuncture causes minute traumas at the points of needle insertion and thus stimulates survival mechanisms of the body. Needling stimulates homeostasis, anti-inflammatory responses, tissue regeneration, and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neurohumoral theory&lt;/strong&gt;: it has been demonstrated that acupuncture is useful in pain relief, and naloxone blocks its analgesic effect. Thus, researchers propose that needling at specific points leads to the release of endogenous painkilling &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainblogger.com/2016/11/03/why-sugar-is-so-addictive/&quot;&gt;opiate-like substances&lt;/a&gt; such as enkephalins, endorphins, dynorphins and some other neurotransmitters like serotonin and noradrenaline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gate-control theory&lt;/strong&gt;: This theory states that needling stimulates large myelinated nerve fibers. These fibers carry tingling sensations and feelings of warmth, and can inhibit the painful sensation that is transmitted to the brain by much smaller C-fibers via spinal tracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postsynaptic inhibition&lt;/strong&gt;: This is another explanation, which states that acupuncture results in the inhibition of pain through a central mechanism via disinhibition of RAF. This phenomenon typically works in cases of extreme trauma like loss of limb. This central mechanism has a role in protecting the body from extreme stress and pain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomous nervous system&lt;/strong&gt;: Proponents of this theory suggest that acupuncture works by changing the balance of sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morphogenetic singularity theory&lt;/strong&gt;: This is one of the more complicated hypotheses that tries to explain the existence of meridians. Advocates of this theory explain the presence of non-neural communication pathways in the body. During embryonic development, when neurons are not yet formed, cells must communicate among themselves to direct development. Meridians are just the remains of these early communication paths, which are still present in the adult body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;: In recent years, fMRI methods have advanced a lot, and in many clinical studies it has been demonstrated that stimulation of various acupuncture points by needling results in activation of different brain centers, thus explaining the mechanism of action of acupuncture. It is believed that both the elements of morphogenetic singularity theory (meridians) and components of the neurohumoral response are involved in the stimulation of the brain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is obvious that various theories have been used to describe the mechanism of action of acupuncture, and most probably there is more than one mechanism is involved. Clinical trials do seem to indicate that acupuncture is beneficial in specific health conditions. But the way it works still remains a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dong, B., Chen, Z., Yin, X., Li, D., Ma, J., Yin, P., … Xu, S. (2017. The Efficacy of Acupuncture for Treating Depression-Related Insomnia Compared with a Control Group: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. &lt;em&gt;BioMed Research International&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;2017&lt;/em&gt;, 9614810. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/9614810&quot;&gt;10.1155/2017/9614810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kawakita, K., &amp;amp; Okada, K. (2014) Acupuncture therapy: mechanism of action, efficacy, and safety: a potential intervention for psychogenic disorders? &lt;em&gt;Biopsychosocial Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, 4. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1186/1751-0759-8-4&quot;&gt;10.1186/1751-0759-8-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White, A., &amp;amp; Ernst, E. (2004) A brief history of acupuncture. &lt;em&gt;Rheumatology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(5), 662–663. doi: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1093/rheumatology/keg005&quot;&gt;10.1093/rheumatology/keg005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wong MC, Shen HJ (2010) Science-based Mechanisms to Explain the Action of Acupuncture. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Association of Traditional Chinese Medicine (UK),&lt;/em&gt; 17(2), 5-10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/users/AusAcu-5549293/&quot;&gt;AusAcu&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://brainblogger.com/feed/">Brain Blogger</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Congrats! Your paper was accepted. (Except if the acceptance letter was forged.)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66341</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/05/congrats-your-paper-was-accepted-or-was-it/</link>
	<description>You’ve worked hard on your research, spent time writing it up, and finally, the good news comes: The journal you submitted to has accepted your paper. Trouble is, for multiple authors, that good news turns bad — the acceptance was fake. Recently, in Scholarly Kitchen, Angela Cochran,  Associate Publisher, American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE), … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/05/congrats-your-paper-was-accepted-or-was-it/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Congrats! Your paper was accepted. (Except if the acceptance letter was forged.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 12:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>For Better Science: David Latchman, the reckless Master of Birkbeck</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forbetterscience.com/?p=24288</guid>
	<link>https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/05/david-latchman-the-reckless-master-of-birkbeck/</link>
	<description>This is a story of David Latchman, Master of Birkbeck at University of London, professor of genetics at UCL and Commander of the Order of the British Empire. All this he achieved also by his impressive publishing record, part of which will be discussed below by my regular contributor Smut Clyde. Just part of it, … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://forbetterscience.com/2018/06/05/david-latchman-the-reckless-master-of-birkbeck/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;David Latchman, the reckless Master of Birkbeck&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;meta-nav&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 11:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://forbetterscience.com/feed/">For Better Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Privacy and consumer genetic testing don’t always mix</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/privacy-and-consumer-genetic-testing-dont-always-mix</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-public/privacy-and-consumer-genetic-testing-dont-always-mix</link>
	<description>Interested in taking a direct-to-consumer genetic test? Here are some things you should know.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/blogposts/052918_CM_genetic-privacy_feat.jpg?itok=89NikrQD" length="16571" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: How a salmon gets its spots</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10231</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/05/how-a-salmon-gets-its-spots/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/HI-034040-140x110.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now know that it is something in the farming environment that makes the salmon there have many spots, but we have yet to find out exactly how the spots are triggered. It could be anything from the lighting regime, temperature, diet, to the fish density or growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated whether a specific breed of domesticated salmon had different numbers of spots depending on whether it had been hatched in a river or lived on a salmon farm its entire life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We planted domesticated salmon into the Guddal river, Norway, where it hatched and stayed for 2-4 years before we took the salmon out of the river as smolts (juveniles) and moved it to our research station at Matre. After spending two years in land based tanks there, these salmon were still seven times less spotty than domesticated salmon that had lived its entire life at Matre under standard farming conditions, even though the salmon were the same breed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10234&quot; style=&quot;width: 650px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-large wp-image-10234&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/Fig-spots-1024x483.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Photographed by Monica F Solberg and edited by Katarina Jørgensen&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both domesticated and wild salmon growing up in a farm environment had many spots, while all the salmon, both domesticated and wild, that were reared in the river had few spots. This means that we can be certain that it’s the environment that decides how many spots a salmon gets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we also identified a region on salmon chromosome, a quantitative trait locus (QTL), containing genes linked to the degree of spottiness. So, genetics does play a role, but it is small compared to the effect of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the wild salmon and the domesticated salmon from the Guddal river had few spots even though these salmon lived for two years in land based tanks at the research station at Matre. This indicates that the spots were established on the salmon before it was removed from the river at smolting. That the salmon receive their distinguishing marks before they have time to escape is a useful observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many spots are nevertheless a safe indicator of an escaped farmed salmon if you catch one in a river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cleaning rivers of escaped farmed salmon currently happens based on visible traits such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://lakselva.no/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Salmopedia-h%C3%A5ndbok.pdf&quot;&gt;body shape, the wear of fins and spots&lt;/a&gt;. If farmed salmon survive for long in nature, they start to resemble wild salmon. Spots on salmon have been shown in &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jfb.13491&quot;&gt;several studies&lt;/a&gt; to be stable over time, so they probably don’t disappear upon escaping, although this is not what we have tested here. Many spots are nevertheless a safe indicator of an escaped farmed salmon if you catch one in a river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, experiments in Zebrafish show that when their stripes are disrupted experimentally they grow back in a way that is consistent with Alan Turing’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/329/5999/1616&quot;&gt;theory of how biological patterns form&lt;/a&gt;. Turing patterns are known for allowing the environment to influence the pattern in ways which create individuality in each one – &lt;a href=&quot;https://tbiomed.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1742-4682-8-24&quot;&gt;like in human fingerprints&lt;/a&gt;. Finding environmentally determined patterns in a well characterized species like Atlantic salmon points to new opportunities for studying biological pattern formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuality of patterns together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/jfb.13491&quot;&gt;spot stability over time&lt;/a&gt; also suggests that spot patterns could be used for identifying individual fish using video surveillance, which may be used to monitor the environment in both fish farms and rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/05/how-a-salmon-gets-its-spots/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How a salmon gets its spots&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/06/HI-034040-125x125.png" length="" type="image/png"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Science Exchange Blog: The Fastest Path to Freedom</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.scienceexchange.com/?p=1348</guid>
	<link>https://blog.scienceexchange.com/2018/06/the-fastest-path-to-freedom/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Fastest-Path-banner.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fastest Path banner&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1353&quot; height=&quot;133&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Fastest-Path-banner-300x66.png&quot; width=&quot;605&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Chandreyee Das, Ph.D., Science Exchange, b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;ased on an interview with Mareb Hamed, (MBChB, MSc, PhD), University of Mosul&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Scientific research is challenging enough. But for Dr. Mareb Hamed, geopolitical upheaval in her home country of Iraq threatened not only her research, but also her survival.&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Flag-map_of_Iraq.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1349 alignright&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Flag-map_of_Iraq-300x300.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed’s story, and how Science Exchange became a part of that story, inspires our team to keep doing what we do — helping scientists connect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;Studying Growth-Restricted Fetuses in War-Torn Iraq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Mareb Hamed graduated at the top of her class from the Medical University in Mosul, Iraq, a city which was, at its peak, a cultural and educational center. In the 1990s, the political situation worsened under the regime of Saddam Hussein, and Dr. Hamed and her husband left Iraq and moved to Libya. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;When war started in Libya, Dr. Hamed returned to Iraq but could not re-obtain her former position of assistant professor, much to her frustration.“So I enrolled in the PhD program,” she explained, “in order to advance my career and because I liked research.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed began her research project in 2014, investigating the effect of intrauterine growth restriction (IUGR) on placental biomarkers. IUGR can be caused by multiple factors and is a leading cause of neonatal deaths. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;From Researcher to Refugee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed had collected a number of placenta samples from local hospitals when the Arabs entered Mosul, killing or forcing the departure of countless scientists, engineers, doctors, lawyers, journalists, and other professionals.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“I became a refugee in Erbil city,” recounted Dr. Hamed. “I lost everything. My house, my car..even the placenta samples that I was collecting.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“But I knew I had to complete my PhD — I knew I had to start over and complete my research. So I continued my research at the University of Erbil, renting a small condo so that I could start working.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400; color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;Erbil to St. Louis: Science Exchange Opens Gateway to Collaboration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;At the University of Kurdistan in Erbil, Dr. Hamed started collecting placentas again, and she was able to complete the histology and the immunohistochemistry on these samples. But the remaining analysis, which required electron microscopy, proved very difficult and cost-prohibitive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“I started searching on the internet,” she continued, “and I found Science Exchange, and through Science Exchange, a provider who could do the microscopy for me.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed started sending her placenta capsule samples through DHL to the provider, an academic core laboratory at Washington University in St. Louis. The provider lab did the sectioning and the staining, and started sending Dr. Hamed the images by email. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“The microscopy images they sent me were very nice,” said Dr. Hamed. “Even during the defense of my thesis, I was told, “You have very nice pictures.”  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #338dc8;&quot;&gt;The Surprise, and the Legacy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Mareb-Acknowledgment.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mareb Acknowledgment&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1351 alignright&quot; height=&quot;262&quot; src=&quot;http://thebenchapp.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Mareb-Acknowledgment-300x262.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Then, I got a surprise,” said Dr. Hamed, “and I am very grateful to Washington University for this. When I told the lab my story, about how I was a refugee from Mosul, and how they had taken everything, they performed the service without requiring any payment. They did not take even one dollar from me! Only I have paid the cost of sending the samples by DHL.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dr. Hamed successfully defended her thesis, in which she acknowledged Science Exchange and her collaborators in St. Louis. She has since gone on to continue her research in Mosul and also provide medical assistance and training to other dislocated and disadvantaged Iraqis — showing that the power of scientific connections goes far beyond an electron microscope.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 05:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://blog.scienceexchange.com/feed/">The Science Exchange Blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Famous Harvard economist reused parts of 2002 paper multiple times, says journal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66336</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/famous-harvard-economist-reused-parts-of-2002-paper-multiple-times-says-journal/</link>
	<description>A former Harvard economist and co-founder of a massive repository of free papers in social sciences has been accused of reusing similar material over multiple papers. The three papers share the same title. According to an investigation by one of the journals, two papers by Michael Jensen, now an emeritus faculty member at Harvard, are … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/famous-harvard-economist-reused-parts-of-2002-paper-multiple-times-says-journal/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Famous Harvard economist reused parts of 2002 paper multiple times, says journal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 15:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Take a virtual trip to an alien world</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/take-virtual-trip-alien-world</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/blog/science-ticker/take-virtual-trip-alien-world</link>
	<description>NASA’s Exoplanet Travel Bureau website lets you view what alien landscapes might look like.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/blogposts/052518_lg_exoplanettravel_feat.jpg?itok=CtZI23SV" length="37622" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>BMC Series blog: EAPC2018: Integration and scare of Palliative Care</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/?p=10219</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/04/eapc2018-integration-scare-palliative-care/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;110&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/20180531_150109-140x110.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;140&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 2500 Palliative Care researchers and clinicians traveled to the UNESCO World Heritage Site Bern to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eapcnet.eu/research2018/&quot;&gt;EAPC2018&lt;/a&gt;. With a stunning view of the Swiss Alps, the congress commenced with a musical interlude by members of the youthful local string ensemble &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cellobass.ch/Cellobass/PRJOJEKT.html&quot;&gt;CELLOBASS&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a welcome from the President of the Swiss Science Foundation, and the Mayor of the City of Bern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time for celebration!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s congress was marked by a double celebration, namely the 30th anniversary of the European Association for Palliative Care, as well as the commemoration of the 100th birthday of &lt;a href=&quot;https://cicelysaundersinternational.org/dame-cicely-saunders/&quot;&gt;Dame Cicely Saunders&lt;/a&gt;, widely regarded as the founder of palliative care as we know it today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cicely trained as a nurse, social worker and physician, dedicating her work to pain and symptom relief through holistic care that not only addresses the physical needs of patients, but also meets the social, psychosocial and spiritual needs of patients, family and carers. She was involved in the foundation and running of the world’s first purpose-build hospice St. Christopher’s Hospice in London, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cicelysaundersinternational.org/&quot;&gt;Cicely Saunders Institute&lt;/a&gt;, a charitable organisation which promotes research to improve care and treatment for all patients with progressive illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hot topics in palliative (s)care research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference was broadly divided into three major topics: cancer and palliative care, public health and policy, and ageing and palliative care. Furthermore, the first day saw a special Swiss session, which discussed controversial topics such as the wish to die and hastening of death, voluntary stopping of eating and drinking, and continuous deep sedation, as well as topics on palliative care services in Switzerland and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free standing sessions were also held, addressing various topics including family carers, palliative care in diverse chronic illnesses, advance care planning, education research, and research methods discussions. However, two themes emerged in talks across all sections: 1. the increasing requirements of palliative care needs worldwide, and 2. the recommendation to integrate palliative care alongside clinical care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term palliative care has become an unspeakable metaphor for one’s own death.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter topic was addressed in two talks by the winner of this year’s Clinical Impact Award &lt;a href=&quot;https://medicine.duke.edu/faculty/thomas-william-leblanc-md&quot;&gt;Thomas LeBlanc MD&lt;/a&gt;, who discussed his own work on integrating palliative care in the clinical treatment of patients suffering from haemato-oncological diseases. His slip of the tongue “Palliative Scare” was an unintended example of how the service is often feared by medical professionals and patients as an end-of-the-line treatment. This thought was also emphasized by Early Researcher Award winner &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thegroundswellproject.com/anna-collins/&quot;&gt;Anna Collins&lt;/a&gt;, who stated that the term palliative care has become an unspeakable metaphor for one’s own death, and discussed the communication between patients and doctors about death, dying and the introduction of palliative care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These and other discussions at EAPC2018 indicated that integrating palliative care in the treatment of terminal (cancer) patients at an earlier stage helps relieve unaddressed symptoms, lessens psychosocial distress, and improves overall quality of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palliative care for the many and the few&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several talks at EAPC2018 addressed the specialist palliative care needs and requirements for minority groups. The variety in minority groups resulted in diverse topics discussing different aspects and needs of palliative care, including the spiritual needs of religious people in secular countries, and the cultural and linguistic barriers between carers and patients of different ethnicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children form another minority group in palliative care, and their specialized needs can sometimes be overlooked by palliative care researchers and carers. In an excellent talk by Post Doctoral Award winner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.york.ac.uk/healthsciences/our-staff/lorna-fraser/&quot;&gt;Lorna Fraser&lt;/a&gt;, various data sets were linked to provide a better insight in the access to palliative care for children and young adults with progressive or terminal disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite was an insightful talk by Mary Turner on palliative care for dying prisoners, and in particular the difficulties faced by prison officers responsible for their care. The shortage of palliative carers in UK prisons means that most palliative support is provided by prison officers who are not trained to deal with the psychological aftermath of caring for the terminally ill. Furthermore, the facilities in UK prisons often do not allow for the installments of hospital beds, wheelchairs may not fit through doors, and palliative care resources are lacking. The lack of time, resources, and training relating to palliative care for dying inmates contributes to the general stress and job-related ill health of prison officers across the UK, and a poor quality of life for dying inmates. An open meeting to discuss a taskforce for care provision for prisoners in Europe was also part of the EAPC2018 program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal reflections&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; id=&quot;attachment_10222&quot; style=&quot;width: 322px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-10222&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/hospice-1821429_960_720-300x200.jpg&quot; width=&quot;312&quot; /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--caption&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;attachment-image--source&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EAPC2018 was a very interesting conference that covered a wide range of thought-provoking, and sometimes controversial topics, and I would certainly recommend this congress to anyone with interest in the field. I would like to congratulate &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpalliatcare.biomedcentral.com/&quot;&gt;BMC Palliative Care&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Associate Editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://research4kids.ucalgary.ca/profiles/shane-sinclair&quot;&gt;Shane Sinclair&lt;/a&gt; for receiving the Paper of the Year Award, and I would like to commend the organisers for handing out sturdy, reusable plastic cups, which greatly reduced the amount of plastic waste that I have experienced at other conferences. I am certainly looking forward to the 11th World Research Congress of the EAPC in Palermo, Italy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/2018/06/04/eapc2018-integration-scare-palliative-care/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EAPC2018: Integration and scare of Palliative Care&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BMC Series blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 13:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/wp-content/uploads/sites/9/2018/05/20180531_150109-125x125.jpg" length="" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url="http://blogs.biomedcentral.com/bmcseriesblog/feed/">BMC Series blog</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: ‘Outbreak’ puts the life cycle of an epidemic on display</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/outbreak-exhibit-puts-life-cycle-epidemic-display</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/outbreak-exhibit-puts-life-cycle-epidemic-display</link>
	<description>At the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History, the exhibit “Outbreak” highlights how infectious diseases shape our world.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060918_LH_exhibit_outbreak_feat.jpg?itok=zVTVaGpa" length="41697" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: See a paper you like? PubPeer wants to help you create a “journal” around it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66298</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/see-a-paper-you-like-pubpeer-wants-to-help-you-create-a-journal-around-it/</link>
	<description>Not everyone is happy with journals these days — researchers in artificial intelligence have announced they were boycotting a new Nature journal for being subscription-only, and universities are cancelling subscriptions over fees. The founders of PubPeer — a site dedicated to commentary about already published papers — are trying a different approach. Today, the PubPeer … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/04/see-a-paper-you-like-pubpeer-wants-to-help-you-create-a-journal-around-it/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;See a paper you like? PubPeer wants to help you create a “journal” around it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Yourbrainhealth: Where is all the women’s brain health research?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/?p=5526</guid>
	<link>http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/where-is-all-the-womens-brain-health-research/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/argonne/4534362371&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-5529&quot; height=&quot;665&quot; src=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/wp/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/4534362371_3da9090e51_b-1024x680.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Photo by George Joch / courtesy Argonne National Laboratory.&quot; width=&quot;1002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt from the Introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/book/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade writing about brain science, I’ve developed a tried and tested method for researching an unfamiliar topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I’ll read the appropriate chapter in &lt;em&gt;Principles of Neural Science,&lt;/em&gt; the neuro-bible beloved by brain geeks the world over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll run a quick search on PubMed, an online search engine of biomedical literature, to find a recent review of the topic, typically written by a top scientist in the particular field, which will give me a feel for the topic’s controversies and consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll feel confident enough to read and understand original research papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’ll seek out the experts themselves – the scientists, doctors and specialists, who, despite their busy schedules, usually give generously of their time to answer my questions and fill in the gaps of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, describing the neurobiology of women’s everyday lives hasn’t always been as straightforward as I expected when I began writing my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My meander through the world of women’s health often left me bewildered. Time and time again I’d open the textbooks or scan the literature to find scant research on some of the questions I’d been most curious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I assumed the literature would be replete with information on how the oral contraceptive pill affects women’s brains. A 2014 review summed up the current state of affairs with the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4139599/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;50 Years of Hormonal Contraception. Time to Find Out What It Does to the Brain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I proudly announced to Facebook the day I finally dived into the neurobiology of multiple orgasms. But it was not a deep dive. PubMed spat out only five literature reviews, three of which were devoted to the possibility of multiple orgasms in men. One was amusingly titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2050052115000542&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple Orgasms in Men. What We Know So Far&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (FYI: Orgasms don’t rate a mention in neuroscience textbooks and we don’t know much so far about women’s orgasm either).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my best efforts, I was unable to pin down the statistics for how many women suffer emotional turmoil in the days leading up to their period, aka premenstrual syndrome (PMS). I eventually narrowed the range down to somewhere between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3972521/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twelve &lt;/a&gt;per cent and ninety per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was positive I’d be able to tell my mid-life readers whether or HRT would help protect against dementia or clear away their brain fog. Oestrogen protects the ageing brain, but we simply don’t have enough information about the benefits for brain health for any recommendations to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is the literature so sparse when it comes to neurobiology and women’s health?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, preclinical research (research conducted on lab animals such as rats, mice or monkeys) has mostly been conducted on male animals. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3008499/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2009 survey&lt;/a&gt; of over 2000 animal studies found a significant male bias in eight out of ten biological disciplines. The bias was most pronounced in the field of neuroscience where five and a half males were studied for every one female. Worryingly, pharmacology (the study of drugs) shares similar statistics, with five males studied to every one female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinical research (investigations conducted on humans) hasn’t fared much better. There are a few large, all-female projects such as the Women’s Health Study which I’ll discuss in later chapters, but for many years women were excluded from clinical studies and drug trials altogether. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4714546/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one critic notes&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many medical professionals can attest to the fact that for decades, the default human model subject was a 70-kg male.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is alarming because diagnoses for anxiety and depression are more than twice as common in women than in men, women have more strokes than men, twice as many women suffer from multiple sclerosis, and women have a higher susceptibility to adverse drug reactions compared with men. Indeed, between 1997 and 2000, eight out of ten drugs withdrawn from the USA market were, in part, due to more severe adverse effects in women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cumulative effect of excluding women from research studies, or assuming that biologically women are ‘little men’, is destructive. As has been pointed out in the journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20535186&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, medical care as it is currently applied to women is less evidence-based or ‘robust’ than that being applied to men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d be tempted to believe the straightforward sexism permeates the hallowed halls and ivory towers as readily as other global institutions. It does, but sexism isn’t the only reason for lack of gender equality. There are some legitimate reasons to skew the ratios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason is safety because if women fall pregnant during a drug trial there is the potential for harming the unborn baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that females – both animals and humans – complicate data gathering. Our cyclical reproductive hormones, especially during the fertile years between puberty and menopause, make our biology intrinsically more fickle than males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The menstrual cycle was once&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=cahill+L+2017++an+issue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; likened&lt;/a&gt; to “a pesky sort of feature essentially of the female, an unnecessary source of additional variability and one wisest to avoid.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further complicate matters, in humans, biological sex (anatomy and physiology) and gender (characteristics that a society or culture defines as masculine or feminine) are tightly entwined and hard to tease apart. It’s extraordinarily difficult to make statements such as, ‘It’s due to her hormones’, or ‘It’s all to do with cultural expectations’. Rather than tackle the intricacies of female sex and gender, female hormones and culture, researchers often choose the easier route of focussing on males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, research on sex and gender has been for a long time been almost taboo. This is especially so in the neurosciences where many researchers were deeply concerned that their findings could be hijacked to support outdated and inaccurate stereotypes and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fears are not unfounded. Women’s brains have historically been found wanting or biologically inferior compared to males, and such &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/how-neurosexism-is-holding-back-gender-equality-and-science-itself-67597&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; has been co-opted to “keep women in their place”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neuroscientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=cahill+L+2017++an+issue&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt; that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…exploring sex differences was once “a terrific way for a brain scientist not studying reproductive functions to lose credibility at best and, at worst, become a pariah in the eyes of the neuroscience mainstream.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spoke to another who said she once believed including sex as a biological variable was ‘lazy’. This was before she came to the conclusion that studying the impact of a woman’s menstrual cycle on the brain might add a valuable dimension to her research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the research community is taking steps to address the dearth of neurobiological research in women, and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hachette.com.au/dr-sarah-mckay/female-brain-book&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Women’s Brain Book&lt;/a&gt; you’ll meet some of the researchers at the forefront of the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Institutions such as the National Institutes of Health (NIH) in the United States and academic publications such as the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Neuroscience Research&lt;/em&gt; now mandate the inclusion of sex as a biological variable in all research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) clearly states the research into the health of women and girls is a particular priority. Here in Australia, we have the Australian Longitudinal Study on Women’s Health, a survey of the physical, mental and psychosocial health of over 58,000 women across their lifespan. Finally, there are some fabulous research initiatives such as Stanford University’s Gendered Innovations project that exist to ‘harness the creative power of sex and gender analysis for innovation and discovery’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from the Introduction to The Women’s Brain Book. The neuroscience of health, hormones and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hachette.com.au/dr-sarah-mckay/female-brain-book&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Find out how to get your copy here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/where-is-all-the-womens-brain-health-research/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Where is all the women’s brain health research?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbrainhealth.com.au&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Your Brain Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 01:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://yourbrainhealth.com.au/feed/">Your Brain Health</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: What consumer DNA data can and can’t tell you about your risk for certain diseases</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/health-dna-genetic-testing-disease</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/health-dna-genetic-testing-disease</link>
	<description>Consumers face lots of choices and unanswered questions when they get personal genomic information related to disease risk from the Internet.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/060918_genetics_lara-diamond_feat_1200.jpg?itok=HfOEsqL_" length="15219" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Discovery magazine - Neuroskeptic: The Philosophy of Roseanne's Ambien Tweet</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9539</guid>
	<link>http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/neuroskeptic/?p=9539</link>
	<description>As everyone knows, Roseanne Barr posted a racist tweet. She claimed that the sleeping medication Ambien affected her behavior, but her show got cancelled anyway.



Now, I think this scandal raises some surprisingly interesting philosophical questions about moral responsibility and the nature of self-control. What follows is a dialogue between two hypothetical speakers exploring some of these questions. To be clear, this is a post about philosophy, not about Roseanne. I don't know or care if</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 18:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.feedburner.com/neuro-skeptic">Neuroskeptic</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>PLOS Neuroscience Community: Closing the loop for brain imaging in depression: What have we learned and where are we heading? By David Mehler</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/?p=19587</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~3/9Vnf2s_Zh4I/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/06/DepressionImaging_larger-1-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depression can have a profound impact on affected individuals and those around them. It is one of the most common mental health conditions, and its symptoms include sustained feeling of sadness, hopelessness, and guilt. In severe cases, these symptoms may be aggravated by suicidal thoughts, or even attempts. The odds of experiencing a depressive episode are relatively high: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcpsychiatry.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-244X-9-19&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at least&lt;/a&gt; one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/196765&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;six&lt;/a&gt; individuals will experience an episode in their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the term &lt;em&gt;depression&lt;/em&gt; suggests that it represents a single psychiatric condition, patients vary tremendously in their symptoms, risk factors, and response to available treatment. Risk factors include not only genetic variations and hormonal changes, but also destructive thinking patterns, or stressful and traumatising experiences. Current treatments primarily include medication and psychotherapy. Medication prescribed in depression targets different brain chemical systems, involving neurotransmitters that include serotonin and dopamine. These are involved in communication between nerve cells and, more generally, in the feeling of well-being. Psychotherapy aims to help patients develop effective coping strategies to use when they are faced with challenges and setbacks. Most depressed individuals will eventually recover – however, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ajp.psychiatryonline.org/doi/abs/10.1176/ajp.2006.163.11.1905&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;up to one third&lt;/a&gt; may not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One branch of depression research focuses on finding biomarkers that can identify individuals that will most likely benefit from a specific therapy. The field also works on developing innovative treatments. However, both goals require a better understanding of the underlying biology. Brain imaging research, clinical psychology, and genetics have provided some fascinating answers, but have also posed new challenging questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We asked three experts and pioneers in depression research: &lt;em&gt;How do you study clinical depression, what role does brain imaging play in your research, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;and what challenges lie ahead for the field? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/group/mood/cgi-bin/wordpress/?p=243&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ian H. Gotlib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Professor of Psychology, Department of Psychology, Stanford University):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Over the past two decades, we have learned that depression is a heterogeneous disorder, with wide variations in symptom presentation, age of onset, number and duration of episodes, and causal factors. In my lab, we take this heterogeneity seriously – we administer structured diagnostic interviews to every participant in our studies. And perhaps more important, we conduct multimodal assessments of depression – we examine &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-02062-y&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;brain structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, function, and connectivity; endocrine function, both under acute stress and throughout the day; cognitive functioning, including biases in attention, interpretation, and memory; and digital phenotyping of depressed children, adolescents, and adults. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The number of brain imaging studies has grown exponentially, and there is now a burgeoning literature examining brain structure, function, and connectivity in depressed individuals. Neuroimaging studies have helped to elucidate the neural circuitry involved in reward processing and the processing of emotional experiences. Because the two cardinal symptoms of depression in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM) involve the persistent experience of negative affect and anhedonia, researchers studying depression have focused on examining their neural underpinnings. From these investigations we are learning about anomalous neural characteristics of depressed individuals that may be related to difficulties in daily functioning and that may serve as intervention targets. We know far less, however, about aspects of brain structure, function, and connectivity that place individuals at risk for developing depression, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/article-abstract/2675295?redirect=true&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;that keep high-risk persons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; from experiencing depression, and that influence the maintenance of and recovery from this disorder. We also know relatively little about the developmental trajectories of these anomalous neural characteristics, knowledge that is critical in understanding differences between children and adults in the presentation of depression.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mountsinai.org/profiles/helen-s-mayberg&quot;&gt;Helen Mayberg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Professor of Neurology, Neurosurgery, Psychiatry and Neuroscience, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Our lab takes a circuit approach to the study of major depression&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Studies integrate &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;multimodal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; neuroimaging strategies and quantitative behavioral and psychophysiological metrics within experimental clinical trial protocols to define brain mechanisms &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;that &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;mediat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; anti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;–&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;depre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;sant treatments. The overarching goal is to develop imaging biomarkers and algorithms that will &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;identify&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; patient subgroups and optimize treatment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;s for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;individual patients. This work &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;also &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;serves as a basis for ongoing testing and refinement of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4413475/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;deep brain stimulation (DBS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;of the subcallosal cingulate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a technique that our lab is investigating&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; for treatment resistant depression. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imaging has provided new perspectives on understanding the pathogenesis of depression, as well as treatment mechanisms. Studies have systematically defined a core set of consistent regional abnormalities, correlations between symptoms and abnormal function of specific brain regions, and evidence of putative depression subtypes. Multimodal imaging and advanced analytic methods have further provided strategies to build depression circuit models that directly test &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4336918/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;treatment selection biomarkers&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The challenge for the ‘field’ will be to define what method(s) are ‘good enough’ to warrant meaningful replication studies of an encouraging finding. Balancing a useful clinical biomarker that might improve treatment selection or response assessment from those addressing fundamental mechanisms of circuit dysfunction and pathophysiology require different strategies and standards.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/lindend.php&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David EJ Linden&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(Professor of Translational Neuroscience, Cardiff University and Maastricht University):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;One of the main research techniques used in my group is real-time functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) neurofeedback training. fMRI allows researchers to trace activation patterns that are associated with external stimuli or internal mental states in real time, and we can feed these activation changes back to patients, so they can learn to regulate them themselves. This opens up interesting potential therapeutic avenues, for example, for &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24733975&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;emotion regulation training in depression&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, but also &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.braintrainproject.eu/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;other mental disorders&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functional brain mapping with fMRI has provided crucial new insights in the neural representations of affect and its disturbances. It has become clear that there are strong links between classical emotion and motivation areas, implemented through functional anatomical links between the limbic system and the basal ganglia, for example, in the ventral striatum. This has sparked renewed interest in the role of reward mechanisms in depression. A future challenge will be to work on the standardisation of imaging protocols across sites and conduct formal studies of the potential diagnostic and predictive value of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;these functional imaging patterns in order to produce clinically useful biomarkers.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers and clinicians agree that depression can manifest differently in each individual. Neuroimaging and multimodal studies allow investigators to examine underlying mechanisms of such variability, although &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/fullarticle/2579940&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;identifying robust biomarkers&lt;/a&gt; remains challenging. This knowledge informs translational research into new brain circuit-based interventions, including clinical trials of DBS and neurofeedback treatment.  Thereby, the field may “close the loop,” yielding more effective and individually tailored treatments for depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dunlop BW, Mayberg HS (2014). Neuroimaging-based biomarkers for treatment selection in major depressive disorder. &lt;em&gt;Dialogues Clin Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 16: 479–490.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holtzheimer PE, Mayberg HS (2011). Deep Brain Stimulation for Psychiatric Disorders. &lt;em&gt;Annu Rev Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 34: 289–307.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Koretz D, Merikangas KR, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; (2003). The Epidemiology of Major. &lt;em&gt;Am Med Assoc&lt;/em&gt; 289: 3095–3105.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linden DEJ (2014). Neurofeedback and networks of depression. &lt;em&gt;Dialogues Clin Neurosci&lt;/em&gt; 16: 103–112.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Müller VI, Cieslik EC, Serbanescu I, Laird AR, Fox PT, Eickhoff SB (2017). Altered brain activity in unipolar depression revisited: Meta-analyses of neuroimaging studies. &lt;em&gt;JAMA Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 74: 47–55.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patten SB (2009). Accumulation of major depressive episodes over time in a prospective study indicates that retrospectively assessed lifetime prevalence estimates are too low. &lt;em&gt;BMC Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 9: 2–5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rush AJ, Trivedi MH, Wisniewski SR, Nierenberg AA, Stewart JW, Warden D, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt; (2006). Acute and longer-term outcomes in depressed outpatients requiring one or several treatment steps: a STAR*D report. &lt;em&gt;Am J Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt; 163: 1905–17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacchet MD, Gotlib IH (2017). Myelination of the brain in major depressive disorder: An in vivo quantitative magnetic resonance imaging study. &lt;em&gt;Sci Rep&lt;/em&gt; 7: 1–14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image modified from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0010945217303015#fig1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tianlu Wang et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00041/full&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alamian et al. 2017&lt;/a&gt; according to the Creative Commons license (CC-BY). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Any views expressed are those of the author, and do not necessarily reflect those of PLOS. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/01/David.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-19529&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/neuro/files/2018/01/David-137x150.png&quot; width=&quot;137&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psych.cf.ac.uk/contactsandpeople/mehlerd.php&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Mehler&lt;/a&gt; is an MD/PhD student at Cardiff University (UK) and the University of Muenster (Germany). He is a member of the Communications Committee for the Organization for Human Brain Mapping (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanbrainmapping.org/i4a/pages/index.cfm?pageid=3267&amp;amp;activateFull=false&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OHBM&lt;/a&gt;). He tweets as &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neuroccino&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@neuroccino&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/blogs/neuro/~4/9Vnf2s_Zh4I&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 18:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://feeds.plos.org/plos/blogs/neuro">PLOS Neuroscience Community</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Weekend reads: Ghostwritten thesis apps; discriminatory authorship rules; group up to 14 retractions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66290</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/02/weekend-reads-ghostwritten-thesis-apps-discriminatory-authorship-rules-group-up-to-14-retractions/</link>
	<description>Before we present this week’s Weekend Reads, a question: Do you enjoy our weekly roundup? If so, we could really use your help. Would you consider a tax-deductible donation to support Weekend Reads, and our daily work? Thanks in advance. The week at Retraction featured a paper by Kim Kardashian, four retractions for an author who … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/02/weekend-reads-ghostwritten-thesis-apps-discriminatory-authorship-rules-group-up-to-14-retractions/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Weekend reads: Ghostwritten thesis apps; discriminatory authorship rules; group up to 14 retractions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Blame opioids for a fifth of young adult deaths in the United States</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cdc-opioids-fifth-young-adult-deaths-united-states</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/cdc-opioids-fifth-young-adult-deaths-united-states</link>
	<description>Of young adults aged 25 to 34 who died in 2016, 20 percent of those deaths were opioid-related.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 20:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060118_AC_opioid-death_feat.jpg?itok=uFIwDtNE" length="51586" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Mysterious neutrino surplus hints at the existence of new particles</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-neutrino-surplus-hints-existence-new-particles</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/mysterious-neutrino-surplus-hints-existence-new-particles</link>
	<description>Neutrinos show up in greater numbers than expected in an experiment, possibly bolstering the idea of a fourth type of the particle.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 19:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060118_EC_neutrino-excess_feat.jpg?itok=ixioxvJ0" length="48364" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: A neutron star crash may have spawned a black hole</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-crash-may-have-spawned-black-hole</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/neutron-star-crash-may-have-spawned-black-hole</link>
	<description>The neutron collision that took the astronomical community by storm last year probably created a black hole, researchers say.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/06/main/articles/060118_MT_neutron-star-merger.jpg?itok=STnkHtoA" length="50154" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Future smart clothes could pack serious gadgetry</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-smart-clothes-could-pack-serious-gadgetry</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/future-smart-clothes-could-pack-serious-gadgetry</link>
	<description>Casual daywear may someday contain some serious tech. But engineers have to take conventional electronics and make them comfortable to wear.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 14:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/060918_wearable_feat.jpg?itok=N9O3itJT" length="25247" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: How much cancer stems from diabetes, obesity? Lancet journal swaps high-profile paper</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66260</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/01/how-much-cancer-stems-from-diabetes-obesity-lancet-journal-swaps-high-profile-paper/</link>
	<description>Six months ago, the media was ablaze with the findings of a new paper, showing that nearly six percent of cancer cases are caused, at least in part, by obesity and diabetes. But this week, the journal retracted that paper — and replaced it with a revised version. The new paper doesn’t change the main … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/06/01/how-much-cancer-stems-from-diabetes-obesity-lancet-journal-swaps-high-profile-paper/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;How much cancer stems from diabetes, obesity? Lancet journal swaps high-profile paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Here’s why scientists are questioning whether ‘sonic attacks’ are real</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-are-questioning-whether-sonic-attacks-are-real</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/scientists-are-questioning-whether-sonic-attacks-are-real</link>
	<description>Sonic attacks would be hard to pull off and a terrible way of incapacitating diplomats, experts say.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/052518_TS_sonic-attack_feat.jpg?itok=uhTTEUvs" length="28492" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: We’re taking a short break</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34008</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/were-taking-a-short-break/</link>
	<description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-507875425.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34009&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34009&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Canon EOS 350D DIGITAL&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Dogs and cats sleeping together.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1289921583&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;bodza2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;232&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.002&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Cat pillow, dog blanket&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Cat pillow, dog blanket&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;3543,2644&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/were-taking-a-short-break/cat-pillow-dog-blanket/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-507875425.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;We’re taking a break. Normal service will resume June 18, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 09:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: A new study claims that, under pressure, imposter syndrome hits men harder than women</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34000</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/a-new-study-claims-that-under-pressure-imposter-syndrome-hits-men-harder-than-women/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-936097644.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34005&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34005&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images\/iStockphoto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1494399003&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;250&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.008&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Tired and overworked stylish red bearded manager sitting in front of computer and trying to concentrate, his eyes are dry and hurt&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/a-new-study-claims-that-under-pressure-imposter-syndrome-hits-men-harder-than-women/tired-and-overworked-stylish-red-bearded-manager-sitting-in-front-of-computer-and-trying-to-concentrate-his-eyes-are-dry-and-hurt/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-936097644.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that some of us experience “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thepsychologist.bps.org.uk/volume-23/edition-5/feeling-fraud&quot;&gt;imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;” was first mooted in the 1970s by two US clinical psychologists who noticed the preponderance of high-achieving women who felt they had somehow cheated or fluked their way to success and feared being found out. Research on the syndrome has since exploded and it’s become clear that many men also experience similar fraudulent feelings. In fact, in their new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886918302435&quot;&gt;exploratory paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Personality and Individual Differences&lt;/em&gt;, a team of US and German researchers claim that, under pressure, imposter syndrome may hit men harder than women, triggering more anxiety and worse performance – a difference they speculate may be due to traditional gender norms that place a greater expectation on men to be competent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34000&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Badawy and her colleagues recruited hundreds of female and male undergrads studying communication or business in northeastern USA. They measured their levels of imposter syndrome with an established scale that includes items like “Sometimes I’m afraid others will discover how much knowledge or ability I really lack”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one study, the researchers gave the students two sets of five verbal and numerical Graduate Record Exam questions (the GRE is used in the US to select students for graduate programmes). After the first set of questions, the researchers ramped up the pressure for half the students, giving them fake feedback that stated they had answered all of the first five questions incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although imposter feelings were overall higher among women, this harsh feedback seemed to especially affect male students with high imposter feelings – they reported higher anxiety, made less effort (as measured by time taken on the task), and showed a trend towards poorer performance, as compared to others given positive feedback. In contrast, female students with high imposter feelings responded to harsh feedback by increasing their effort and showing superior performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was similar in a second study in which heightened pressure was placed on half the students by telling them that their results on five Graduate Record Exam questions would be shown to a professor on their course (the researchers called this a “high accountability” situation). In this context, men with higher imposter syndrome scores again showed increased anxiety, reduced effort and a tendency toward worse performance, as compared with others who were told their scores would be shown anonymously to a stranger. In contrast, women with imposter feelings were largely unaffected (in terms of anxiety, effort or performance) by the increased accountability situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increase in anxiety, and reduction in effort, shown by men with imposter feelings could be interpreted as reflecting their fear of being found out, combined with a “self-handicapping” strategy – reducing their effort so that they can use this as an excuse to explain the poor performance that they are anticipating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Assuming that traditional gender norms hold, males [with imposter syndrome] may have exhibited  stronger negative reactions because they believe that society at large values males who demonstrate high competence and at the same time, do not believe that they can fulfil this standard,” the researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the women with imposter feelings appeared less sensitive to the negative feedback and expectation of review by a professor – if anything, they arguably responded to negative feedback in an adaptive way by increasing their effort. The researchers linked this with the traditional cultural expectation that women should be warm rather than competent.  “Being less constrained by gender norm violations and backlash (i.e. they were already expected to perform poorly on competence-based tasks like exam questions), females [with imposter feelings] may have felt freer to attempt to improve their performance (and risk failure) rather than excusing it with lack of time or effort invested,” they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to know if and how these findings might relate to real-world situations in an  academic setting or workplace. Badawy and her team admit their findings are exploratory and may not generalise. In particular, if their explanation based around gender norms is accurate, one can imagine these norms might vary not just across international cultures, but even between different sub-cultures in the same country – depending, for instance, on the specific gender-based attitudes, beliefs and pressures in different occupations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues aside, Badawy and her colleagues suggest their key finding – of particular male vulnerability to imposter syndrome under pressure – may have practical implications for managers. “If managers of organisational specialists observe evidence of imposter syndrome in male workers currently performing at high levels, they may benefit from making attempts to restore those workers’ sense of agency if they are placed under high accountability situations,” they said. They added that mentoring by professors or managers, skills training and stretch assignments could be potential beneficial strategies (find &lt;a href=&quot;https://99u.adobe.com/articles/54774/how-to-beat-the-imposter-syndrome-feeling&quot;&gt;more ways to combat imposter syndrome in this 99U article&lt;/a&gt;). However, they warned these will only work “if mentors are trained to down regulate their own gender role expectations”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886918302435&quot;&gt;Are all impostors created equal? Exploring gender differences in the impostor phenomenon-performance link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologywriter.org.uk/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christian Jarrett&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; (&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/psych_Writer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;@Psych_Writer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;) is Editor of &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 08:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Sending a supportive text to your partner can reduce their physiological stress levels, but only if you’re subtle about it</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=34002</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/sending-a-supportive-text-to-your-partner-can-reduce-their-physiological-stress-levels-but-only-if-youre-subtle-about-it/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;GettyImages-865821668.jpg&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-34003&quot; data-attachment-id=&quot;34003&quot; data-comments-opened=&quot;1&quot; data-image-description=&quot;&quot; data-image-meta=&quot;{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Getty Images&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;NIKON D800&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;A Muslim woman is outdoors on a sunny day. She is wearing casual clothing and a head scarf. She is standing near a road and sending a message with her smartphone.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1505852785&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;This content is subject to copyright.&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;85&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;100&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Using Technology&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}&quot; data-image-title=&quot;Using Technology&quot; data-large-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845?w=845&quot; data-medium-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845?w=300&quot; data-orig-file=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845&quot; data-orig-size=&quot;2120,1414&quot; data-permalink=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/06/01/sending-a-supportive-text-to-your-partner-can-reduce-their-physiological-stress-levels-but-only-if-youre-subtle-about-it/using-technology/&quot; src=&quot;https://researchdigest.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/gettyimages-865821668.jpg?w=845&quot; /&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average young adult sends more than 100 texts per day, mainly to offer social support to friends and family. But until now, there has been little evidence whether it helps the recipient or not. New &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218300918&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;i&gt;Computers in Human Behavior&lt;/i&gt; confirms that sending a comforting text to a partner confronted with a difficult task really can make them feel supported. But more surprisingly, the study suggests that to actually reduce their stress, it’s better to send a message that isn’t explicitly supportive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-34002&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emily Hooker and colleagues from the University of California asked 75 women to attempt a stressful set of tasks involving mental mathematics and public speaking. At the start of the experiment they were fitted with a blood pressure cuff to capture information about blood flow and heart rate. While waiting to perform, some participants received texts from their romantic partner who was waiting in the other room. Crucially, some of the partners sent texts (scripted by the researchers) that were comforting (e.g. “Don’t worry. It’s just a psych study. You’ll be fine.”) whereas others sent more mundane texts that were not explicitly supportive (e.g. “It’s cold in here.”). Participants also received a second reinforcing text with the same tone as the first (i.e. either supportive or mundane) while they prepared for their challenge (other participants acted as a baseline control group and received no texts at any point).&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After delivering the task, participants who’d earlier received a comforting text reported feeling more supported by their partner (compared with the controls). However, it was only those participants who’d earlier received mundane texts who showed a physical reduction in their stress response, as shown by lower systolic blood pressure during preparation and the task itself.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is evidence that attempts to support other people that give the impression of social evaluation – “I can see that you’re struggling” – are ineffective at reducing stress, and Hooker’s team conjecture that the supportive texts, by making direct references to the stressful tasks, may have inadvertently triggered this effect, although this was not explicitly tested for in the study. If so, it adds to research suggesting that “invisible” support – like offering unrelated humour – can be one of the more effective forms of reducing stress through social support. In this case, simply the reminder that the boyfriend was next door, grumbling about the cold, affirmed that the person was not alone, and could receive comfort or validation should that be needed (e.g. if the stressful event went badly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This finding certainly needs follow-up research to figure out what are the ingredients in different forms of text-based social contact to affect how we feel. It’s worth noting that the effect of the mundane messages also involved a slower recovery to blood pressure baseline than the supportive text or the control condition. So it may be that different kinds of messages can have selective effects on different phases of the stress response. Studies have begun to show downsides of heavy texting use, such as school performance and sleep, although in many cases these may be confounded by use of mobile phones in general. It’s useful, then, to see evidence of something many of us assume and hope for – that contact with loved ones via text can provide them with a sense of being supported during stressful events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563218300918&quot;&gt;It just takes a text: Partner text messages can reduce cardiovascular responses to stress in females&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 08:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Never-before-seen dunes on Pluto spotted in New Horizons images</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/never-seen-dunes-pluto-spotted-new-horizons-images</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/never-seen-dunes-pluto-spotted-new-horizons-images</link>
	<description>Images from the New Horizons spacecraft reveal dunes on Pluto — but the sand-sized grains must have had an unusual boost to get moving.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 18:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/053118_lg_pluto-dunes_feat_free.jpg?itok=khEz8qdE" length="59671" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The Official PLOS Blog: PLOS Responds to Ebola Outbreak with New Channel &amp; Expedited Peer Review</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.plos.org/plos/?p=8227</guid>
	<link>http://feeds.plos.org/~r/plos/Blog/~3/rfBzjXO3fqo/</link>
	<description>&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;webfeedsFeaturedVisual wp-post-image&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/plos/files/2018/05/Ebola_Blogs_690x320-150x150.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin-bottom: 5px; clear: both;&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early sharing and expedited peer review of relevant research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the ongoing Ebola &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/ebola/en/&quot;&gt;outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; we are creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://channels.plos.org/ebola&quot;&gt;PLOS Channel for Ebola Research&lt;/a&gt;.  The Channel will make it easy for researchers to keep up with developments and important research related to the outbreak. We will work with authors and our editorial boards to provide rapid review and facilitate the responsible dissemination of preprints. We believe these responses are urgently needed during serious and rapidly developing threats to public health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All relevant articles published across PLOS will be included in the Ebola Channel, alongside major contributions curated from the broader literature. You can also send any questions or content recommendations to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ebola@plos.org&quot;&gt;ebola@plos.org&lt;/a&gt; or tweet us @PLOSChannels using the hashtag #PLOSEbola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I make my Ebola research available quickly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve created a taskforce to identify editors and reviewers, and to manage an expedited review process across all our journals and platforms.  For authors, we recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to share a single observation (no more than 1 figure or table with commentary) submit to PLOS Currents: Outbreaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submit any other research to one of the 7 PLOS journals; all Ebola-related submissions will be prioritized. (Note that&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plos.org/fee-assistance#loc-fee-assistance-programs&quot;&gt;fee waiver assistance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; is available as needed)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share your data and manuscript ahead of submission: large datasets should be deposited in a relevant repository, and manuscripts submitted to a preprint server. Include the DOIs or accession numbers for datasets and preprint in your submission. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to expediting research publications, PLOS believes all data on the Ebola outbreak should be shared as rapidly and openly as possible. We endorse the Wellcome Trust’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://wellcome.ac.uk/what-we-do/our-work/sharing-research-findings-and-data-relevant-ebola-outbreak-drc&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;statement&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;demanding availability of data and research on Ebola. Editorial consideration of research submissions to PLOS journals will not be prejudiced by the early sharing of data or preprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lessons learned: delivering rapid responses to emergency outbreaks &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLOS saw surges in submissions in previous outbreaks, notably the Ebola outbreak of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2014/09/05/plos-resources-ebola/&quot;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt; and the Zika outbreak of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.plos.org/speakingofmedicine/2016/01/07/will-zika-become-the-2016-ntd-of-the-year/&quot;&gt;2015/2016&lt;/a&gt;. In each emergency, we provided resources to serve the community. In addition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/news/data-sharing-make-outbreak-research-open-access-1.16966&quot;&gt;concerns&lt;/a&gt; about data sharing during the 2014 Ebola outbreak led PLOS and other journal editors to issue a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/medicines/ebola-treatment/blueprint_phe_data-share-results/en/&quot;&gt;joint statement&lt;/a&gt; encouraging early data sharing. A recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1002549&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;PLOS Medicine&lt;/em&gt; showed that, while increased use of preprints in the 2016 Zika outbreak accelerated the dissemination of research results, the proportion of published articles on Zika that were preceded by preprints remained low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our shared responsibility in public health emergencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe research, healthcare, and publishing communities have a responsibility to work together to respond rapidly to public health emergencies. PLOS is committed to disseminating new research findings as efficiently and effectively as possible. We appreciate the opportunity to facilitate access to your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/plos/Blog/~4/rfBzjXO3fqo&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://www.plos.org/cms/blog/feed">Public Library of Science</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Experts advise: Start colorectal screening at 45, not 50</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/experts-advise-start-colorectal-screening-45-not-50</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/experts-advise-start-colorectal-screening-45-not-50</link>
	<description>The American Cancer Society recommends that colorectal screening begin at the age of 45 for average-risk individuals.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 14:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/053018_AC_colorectal_feat.jpg?itok=ws5LeVvP" length="30673" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Two-faced star reveals a pulsar’s surprising bulk</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-faced-star-reveals-pulsars-surprising-bulk</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/two-faced-star-reveals-pulsars-surprising-bulk</link>
	<description>An ultramassive pulsar is frying its stellar companion so that the star shows two different temperatures.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/052918_LG_two-toned-star_feat.jpg?itok=zeN0ZN4s" length="27817" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Retraction watch: Dental journal pulls a dozen papers for recycled images and “unreliable data”</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://retractionwatch.com/?p=66214</guid>
	<link>https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/31/dental-journal-pulls-a-dozen-papers-for-recycled-images-and-unreliable-data/</link>
	<description>A leading orthodontics journal has retracted 12 papers after determining that they contained either reused images, questionable data or both. Several of the articles involved experiments conducted in dogs — and one person familiar with the case told us that the duplication was an attempt to avoid sacrificing more animals than necessary for the research. … &lt;a class=&quot;more-link&quot; href=&quot;https://retractionwatch.com/2018/05/31/dental-journal-pulls-a-dozen-papers-for-recycled-images-and-unreliable-data/&quot;&gt;Continue reading &lt;span class=&quot;screen-reader-text&quot;&gt;Dental journal pulls a dozen papers for recycled images and “unreliable data”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 12:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://retractionwatch.com/feed/">Retraction Watch</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Open Position: PhD studentship in Biocomputation Research Group</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-05-31:/2018/05/31/open-position-phd-studentship-in-biocomputation-research-group.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/05/31/open-position-phd-studentship-in-biocomputation-research-group.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for a PhD studentship on Computational frameworks for
high-dimensional neural data with Dr. Shabnam Kadir in the Biocomputation
Research Group in the Centre for Computer Science and Informatics Research,
University of Hertfordshire, U.K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New developments in experimental technology have led to petabytes of raw data
being produced by experimental neuroscientists, which are increasingly publicly
available, e.g. Allen Institute data (&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.brain-map.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.brain-map.org/&lt;/a&gt;). In particular,
we are in the realm where population recordings of tens of thousands of neurons
are feasible thanks to, e.g. a new generation of large dense probes for
electrophysiological recordings, imaging using 2-photon microscopy coupled with
calcium fluorescent sensors. Large scale neuronal recordings require novel
approaches for both processing and quantitative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as using techniques from high-dimensional statistics, machine learning,
information theory, we aim to explore new approaches from mathematical fields
outside statistics, such as algebraic topology. The study of networks is a
particularly important topic in neuroscience: neurons communicate with each
other electrically via synapses, forming intricate networks. These networks can
be studied using techniques from computational topology (e.g. persistent
homology, clique topology). These could be used to extract information about
subnetworks and assemblies, both from large scale recordings, and via
connectomics derived from simulations (Blue Brain Project).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aim in this project to go beyond spike sorting and develop new tools and
computational frameworks which would help interpret high dimensional data and
interrogate how information is being processed by the brain, e.g.  How are
sensory stimuli (location in environment, visual and auditory stimuli) encoded?
How can we characterise the neural activity associated with memory, attention,
decision making and motor control?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall be collaborating with labs at Imperial, Pennsylvania State University
and UCL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information can be found here:
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/187455/Dec2017-computational-frameworks-for-high-dimensional-neural-data.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/187455/Dec2017-computational-frameworks-for-high-dimensional-neural-data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for candidates with the following profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong first degree in a quantitative field such as mathematics, physics,
computer science, engineering, computational neuroscience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong programming skills (e.g. Python, MATLAB, C++).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in neuroscience and biology would be helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A studentship from the PhD Programme in Computer Science provides approximately
£14,750 per annum bursary plus the payment of student fees. Applicants from
outside the UK or EU are eligible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in Computer Science at the University of Hertfordshire has been
recognised as excellent in the latest Research Excellence Framework Assessment
(2014), with 50% of the research submitted rated as internationally excellent
or world-leading. The Centre for Computer Science and Informatics Research
provides a very stimulating environment, offering a large number of specialised
and interdisciplinary seminars as well as general training and researcher
development opportunities. The University is situated in Hatfield, in the green
belt just north of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please contact Dr Shabnam Kadir (&lt;code&gt;s.kadir2 AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;) for informal enquiries.
Application forms are available under
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&quot;&gt;http://www.herts.ac.uk/apply/schools-of-study/computer-science/our-research/the-phd-programme-in-computer-science&lt;/a&gt;
and should be returned to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Emma Thorogood, &lt;br /&gt;
Research Student Administrator, &lt;br /&gt;
University of Hertfordshire, College Lane, &lt;br /&gt;
Hatfield, Herts, AL10 9AB, &lt;br /&gt;
Tel: 01707 286083 &lt;br /&gt;
E-mail: &lt;code&gt;doctoralcollegeadmissions AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short-listing process will begin on 25th June 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 11:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>UH Biocomputation group: Open Position: Professorship in Computational Neuroscience</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:biocomputation.herts.ac.uk,2018-05-31:/2018/05/31/professorship-in-computational-neuroscience.html</guid>
	<link>http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/2018/05/31/professorship-in-computational-neuroscience.html</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;School of Computer Science, &lt;br /&gt;
University of Hertfordshire, &lt;br /&gt;
College Lane Campus, Hatfield, UK &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary: £58,293 to £67,437 p.a. depending on skills and experience. &lt;br /&gt;
FTE: Full time position working 37 hours per week (1.0 FTE). &lt;br /&gt;
Duration of contract: Permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing date: 24 July 2018. &lt;br /&gt;
Interview date: Week commencing 17 September 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;docutils&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications are invited for an exceptionally well qualified Professor of
Computational Neuroscience of international standing, who shares our commitment
to research-informed teaching, embraces the research impact agenda, and values
collegiality. Applicants will strengthen existing activity within the School
and develop it further, enhancing the research strengths and external
reputation of the School of Computer Science and contributing significantly to
its performance in future research assessments and collaborations with
commercial and public partners. The successful applicant will complement the
research conducted by the Biocomputation Research Group within the Centre for
Computer Science and Informatics Research. As well as providing research
supervision at PhD and MSc level, the School of Computer Science offers modules
in neural computing and machine learning on the BSc and MSc programmes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applicants must hold a PhD (or equivalent) in a relevant subject, possess
excellent communication skills in English, an internationally excellent
research record and reputation, including publications of the highest quality
suitable for submission to the REF. Applicants must show evidence of experience
and success in research/commercial income generation, engagement with the
research impact agenda, engagement with key stakeholders in the Computational
Neuroscience community, and management and leadership ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The university offers a range of benefits including a pension scheme,
professional development, family friendly policies, child care vouchers, a fee
waiver of 50% for all children of staff under the age of 21 at the start of the
course, discounted memberships at the Hertfordshire Sports Village and generous
annual leave. The University  is situated in Hatfield, in the green belt just
north of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications must be made online at:
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&quot;&gt;https://www.herts.ac.uk/contact-us/jobs-and-vacancies/academic-vacancies&lt;/a&gt;,
reference &lt;code&gt;016195&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For informal enquiries please contact Dr Volker Steuber (&lt;code&gt;v DOT steuber
AT herts DOT ac DOT uk&lt;/code&gt;, Head of Biocomputation Research Group, Associate Dean
- Research) or Prof William Clocksin (&lt;code&gt;w DOT clocksin AT herts DOT ac DOT
uk&lt;/code&gt;, Dean of School of Computer Science).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 11:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="http://biocomputation.herts.ac.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml">UH Biocomputation Group</source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Science News: Guidelines call for limits to whole genome testing for fetuses</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencenews.org/article/guidelines-call-limits-whole-genome-testing-fetuses</guid>
	<link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/guidelines-call-limits-whole-genome-testing-fetuses</link>
	<description>Powerful tests offer unprecedented detail about fetal genomes. But whole-genome tests aren’t ready for widespread use yet, doctors caution.</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <enclosure url="http://www.sciencenews.org/sites/default/files/styles/620px_wide/public/2018/05/main/articles/052318_genetics_prenatal_feat.jpg?itok=zd_G48JN" length="18632" type="image/jpeg"/>
  <source url=""></source>
</item>
<item>
	<title>The British Psychological Society - Research Digest: Taking a photo of something impairs your memory of it, but the reasons remain largely mysterious</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digest.bps.org.uk/?p=33997</guid>
	<link>https://digest.bps.org.uk/2018/05/31/taking-a-photo-of-something-impairs-your-memory-of-it-but-the-reasons-remain-largely-mysterious/</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;By&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avid photographers celebrate the viewfinder as a means of helping us see the world anew. But psychology research has shown that under some conditions taking a photo of something actually makes it harder to remember. One possible reason is that we give less attention to an experience when we know that it will be safely stored in a photograph. But in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211368117301687&quot;&gt;new paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Applied Research in Memory and Cognition&lt;/i&gt;, Julia Soares and Benjamin Storm from the University of California show that the photo-taker’s memory will suffer whether they expect to keep the photo or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-33997&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work aimed to replicate and extend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24311477&quot;&gt;a study&lt;/a&gt; by Linda Henkel that showed that taking photos of paintings in a museum could lead to poorer recall of those paintings. To make sense of this, Henkel drew on the body of research on&lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2014/07/29/remembering-together-how-long-term-couples-develop-interconnected-memory-systems/&quot;&gt; transactive memory&lt;/a&gt;, which shows that longtime partners or friends distribute memory demands between them, creating a “shared” system where one will remember certain things so the other doesn’t need to. Henkel thought that in a similar fashion we may be treating the camera as a memory partner and offloading the effort onto it. Soares and Storm tested this explanation by separating photo taking from photo having.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main experiment was a computerised version of Henkel’s museum task. Around 50 undergraduates viewed paintings one at a time onscreen. In one block, participants took a photo of each painting with a smartphone, and then had 15 seconds to look at the painting itself. In a second experimental block, the participants took a photo of each painting, deleted the photo immediately (so they knew it could never been accessed in the future), then had 15 seconds to look at the painting. Finally, in another experimental block, they took no photos and simply viewed each painting for 15 seconds.&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a ten minute delay (during which phones were confiscated) came a multiple- choice memory test probing what the participants remembered about the various paintings. Compared to paintings that were simply viewed, performance was poorer for paintings that were photographed. Critically, this was true both for the condition where the photo was stored, and for the condition where it was deleted, meaning the participant knew they could not rely on it as a future memory partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggests that offloading may not be the cause of the memory disadvantage associated with taking photos. One alternative explanation is that using a camera forces us to disengage from properly taking in the stimulus, as our attention flows to the mechanics of operating buttons, checking brightness, exposure etc. This is something commonly reported by people as part of their photo-taking experience, and also tallies with the fact that automatic wearable cameras that store images for later don’t produce the memory impairment. However, in the current experiment, after taking pictures (or not), every participant had the same amount of time to take in the paintings without use of equipment, so any distraction effect would need to include some sort of delayed effect on memory processing even after the act of taking a photo was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soares and Storm have a speculative second interpretation. They suggest that the effort involved in taking a photo – getting the framing right, ensuring the lens is in focus – leads to the sense that you’ve done a good job of encoding the object itself, even though you have been focusing more on peripheral features. So you’re not mentally slacking-off because you think the camera has it covered – but because you think you already have. It may be relevant that people who take photographs at events &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/2016/07/25/taking-photos-will-boost-your-enjoyment-of-experiences-researchers-say/&quot;&gt;report afterwards&lt;/a&gt; feeling more immersed in the experience, which would tally more with this explanation than the disengagement-due-to-fiddling idea. In any case this is further evidence that those of us who approach exciting life events through the lenses of our electronic devices may be distancing ourselves from fuller participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211368117301687&quot;&gt;Forget in a Flash: A Further Investigation of the Photo-Taking-Impairment Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alexfradera.net/&quot;&gt;Alex Fradera&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexfradera&quot;&gt;@alexfradera&lt;/a&gt;) is Staff Writer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://digest.bps.org.uk/&quot;&gt;BPS Research Digest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 10:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <source url="https://digest.bps.org.uk/feed/">Research Digest</source>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
